<bill session="117" type="s" number="463" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPUBLIC Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require congressional approval of national emergency declarations and to repeal the emergency powers and authorities most susceptible to abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Emergency Powers to Uphold the Balances and Limitations Inherent in the Constitution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPUBLIC Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-02T13:57:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reforming Emergency Powers to Uphold the Balances and Limitations Inherent in the Constitution Act or the REPUBLIC Act

This bill terminates a declaration of national&#160;emergency made by the President after 72 hours unless Congress enacts a joint resolution to renew the declaration. It also bars subsequent presidential declarations of emergency during the remainder of a presidential term of office based on the same circumstances if Congress does not enact a resolution of approval.

Under the bill, an emergency declaration that is approved by Congress expires 90 days after the issuance of the presidential declaration of emergency unless renewed.

The bill exempts presidential powers under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA) from the requirements of this bill.

The bill also (1) repeals presidential authority to unilaterally control communications, including the internet, cell phone service, and television and radio broadcasts; and (2) terminates all existing national emergency declarations that do not specify IEEPA as the source of presidential authority.</summary>
</bill>
