<bill session="118" type="h" number="9769" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-10T15:05:07-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-10T15:05:07-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act</title>
    <title type="short">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the security and integrity of United States critical infrastructure by establishing an interagency task force and requiring a comprehensive report on the targeting of United States critical infrastructure by People's Republic of China state-sponsored cyber actors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2024-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 118-859.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-10" calendar="Union" number="698">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 698.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:58:39-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Green (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:58:53-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6562-6564" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T14:58:55-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 9769.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-10T15:05:07-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6562-6563" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10T15:05:09-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Discharged, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-12T15:05:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Cyber Resilience Against State-Sponsored Threats Act

The bill creates a joint interagency task force to facilitate agency collaboration&#160;on efforts to respond to&#160;Chinese state-sponsored cyber actors, including Volt Typhoon.&#160;

The task force shall be established and led by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA), an agency within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). The task force shall facilitate collaboration and coordination among the Sector Risk Management Agencies&#160;(SRMAs) specified in the President's National Security Memorandum- 22 (e.g.,&#160;the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, and the Department of Agriculture) to detect, analyze, and respond to Chinese state-sponsored cyber actors&#160;by ensuring that such agencies&#226;&#8364;&#8482; actions are aligned and mutually reinforcing.

The bill directs&#160;DHS, CISA, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and specified SRMAs&#160;to provide the task force with analysis, inspections, audits, and other relevant information that is necessary for&#160;the task force to carry out its responsibilities.&#160;The production and use of information must comply with all applicable statutes, regulations, and executive orders, and task force members must have appropriate security clearances to access classified information.

The task force must&#160;provide annual reports and briefings to Congress detailing its assessment of cyber threats and recommendations to improve the detection and mitigation of the cybersecurity threat posed by Chinese state-sponsored cyber actors.

The first report must be provided no later than 540 days after the establishment of the task force, and additional reports must be provided annually thereafter for six years.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-859</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
