<bill session="109" type="h" number="3694" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:15Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Veterans Services Outreach Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide grants to rural counties to ensure they are able to offer a sufficient level of advice and casework services to help veterans learn about and obtain the benefits they have earned, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Veterans Services Outreach Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000793"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-26T20:44:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Veterans Services Outreach Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants for financial assistance to eligible counties to assist in the employment of county veterans service officers. Limits grant amounts to $12,000 for a 12-month period.

Defines as an eligible county a county: (1) in which not less than 1,000 veterans reside; (2) in which no more than one veterans service organization provides advice and casework services for veterans' benefits; and (3) which consists entirely outside of territory classified as an urban area.

Expresses the sense of Congress that appropriate officials in counties with one or more county veterans service officers should encourage and facilitate such officer(s) in obtaining certification with respect to professional qualifications to perform such functions.</summary>
</bill>
