<bill session="116" type="h" number="7949" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Government Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sensible Management of Archives, Records, and Technologies Government Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Government Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the chief information officer of each agency to increase efforts to manage data centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001118"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2020-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Libraries and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-14T18:30:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Sensible Management of Archives, Records, and Technologies Government Act or the SMART Government Act

This bill directs the chief information officer (CIO) of each federal agency to take specified steps with respect to the management of data centers.

Specifically, each CIO shall (1) develop and publish a strategic plan to consolidate and optimize data centers at the agency, and (2) inventory software applications used in the information technology systems of the entity.

Each agency, in coordination with the Office of the Archivist of the United States, shall create copies of all records controlled by the agency and transfer such copies to a records center maintained and operated by such office.

By September 30, 2020, such office shall (1) develop standards for each agency to create copies of the records, (2) develop guidelines for each agency to store metadata with respect to such records and transfer such copies, and (3) make exemptions to the standards developed.

The bill requires each agency to designate a senior official to manage records and lists such official's duties.</summary>
</bill>
