<bill session="118" type="s" number="2746" updated="2025-11-19T01:43:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Bus Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Bus Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue rules requiring the inclusion of new safety equipment in school buses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="10022" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-30T12:38:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Bus Safety Act of&#160;2023

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue rules requiring school buses to have certain safety features.&#160;DOT must also establish a grant program to assist in the implementation of the requirements.

Specifically, DOT must issue rules requiring school buses to include

three-point safety belts for all seats,a fire suppression system which addresses engine fires,a firewall between the engine and passenger compartment&#160;that prevents hazardous quantities of gas or flames from passing through the firewall,increased&#160;performance standards for interior flammability and smoke emissions,an automatic emergency braking system,an event data recorder, andan electronic stability control system.DOT must also require at least eight hours of behind-the-wheel training for school bus operators that meets specified requirements.

Further, the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) must issue rules on&#160;the evaluation of safety sensitive personnel for moderate-to-severe obstructive sleep apnea.

NHTSA&#160;must also study the benefits of requiring school buses manufactured in, or imported into, the United States to be equipped with a motion-activated detection system that is capable of&#160;detecting road users (e.g., pedestrians and bicyclists) and alerting the bus operator of their presence.&#160;NHTSA must issue rules implementing such a requirement.

Finally, DOT must establish a grant program to assist local educational agencies in (1) purchasing school buses equipped with three-point safety belts or any of the other safety features required under this bill, and (2) modifying&#160;existing school buses.</summary>
</bill>
