<bill session="116" type="h" number="8239" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forensic Science Research and Standards Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forensic Science Research and Standards Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the development and distribution of forensic science standards by establishing in the National Institute of Standards and Technology the Organization of Scientific Area Committees for Forensic Science, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2020-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4568" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-27T15:09:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Forensic Science Research and Standards Act of 2020

This bill establishes various entities to develop and distribute forensic science standards.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall establish an interagency working group to coordinate federal investments related to, and develop a research strategy for, forensic science and publish such strategy once every two years.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) shall establish the Organization of Scientific Area Committees for Forensic Science to facilitate the development of forensic science standards. NIST shall establish scientific area committees to carry out the work of the organization and a Forensic Science Standards Board to oversee the operation of the organization and its committees.

NIST shall conduct foundational studies to (1) identify and document the technical merit and validity of select forensic science methods, practices, and disciplines; and (2) identify opportunities for advancements in forensic methods, practices, and disciplines through additional research and improvements to practice.</summary>
</bill>
