<bill session="116" type="s" number="4588" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Broadband and Emerging Information Technology Enhancement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Broadband and Emerging Information Technology Enhancement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve programs of the Small Business Administration to better assist small business customers in accessing broadband technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2020-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-04T19:47:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Broadband and Emerging Information Technology Enhancement Act of 2020

This bill directs the Small Business Administration (SBA) to designate a senior Office of Investment and Innovation employee as broadband and emerging information technology coordinator, and it establishes measures to aid the competitiveness and productivity of small businesses through broadband access and other emerging information technologies.

The coordinator's responsibilities shall include (1) identifying best practices relating to broadband and emerging information technology that may help small businesses; and (2) coordinating SBA programs that assist small businesses in adopting, making innovations in, and using broadband and other information technologies. The SBA must also provide training to familiarize its employees with broadband and other emerging technologies.

Further, the SBA must report on (1) its programs and activities relating to broadband and emerging information technologies, and (2) the impact of broadband and emerging information technology deployment on small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
