<bill session="119" type="h" number="331" updated="2025-11-19T04:03:25Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-13T16:23:10-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-05-13T16:23:10-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act to clarify a provision relating to conveyances for aquifer recharge purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act to clarify a provision relating to conveyances for aquifer recharge purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife and Fisheries Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 119-60.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-04-17" calendar="Union" number="37">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 37.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T16:19:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T16:19:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1969-1970" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T16:19:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 331.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-05-13T16:23:10-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1969" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13T16:23:12-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1254" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-01T19:11:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill modifies the Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act to expand provisions concerning authorizations (e.g., rights-of-way) to transport water across public land administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) for aquifer recharge purposes.

Under the Aquifer Recharge Flexibility Act, the holder of existing rights-of-way, easements, permits, or other authorizations to transport water across BLM land may transport the water for aquifer recharge purposes without additional authorization from the Department of the Interior so long as the use does not expand or modify the operation of such authorizations across public land.

The bill allows the holders of such authorizations to act not only on behalf of themselves, but also on behalf of states, Indian Tribes, or public entities, to use the existing authorizations for aquifer recharge without additional authorization from the Department of the Interior. Further, the bill states that this use may not be considered an expansion, modification, major federal action, or substantial deviation.

Additionally, the bill exempts holders from paying additional rents to the BLM for any use of such authorizations; however, the exemption does not apply to for-profit uses of aquifer recharge or for-profit entities.&#160;

Finally, holders of rights-of-way or other authorizations must provide notice to the&#160;BLM of the intended use of authorization as specified by the bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-60</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
