<bill session="117" type="s" number="612" updated="2023-02-14T14:28:47Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Under Secretary for Health of the Department of Veterans Affairs to provide certain information to medical center staff and homelessness service providers of the Department regarding the coordinated entry processes for housing and services operated under the Continuum of Care Program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="876" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-07T19:10:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Housing Outcomes for Veterans Act of 2021

This bill requires the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) to provide medical center staff and homelessness service providers of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) with information related to best practices for the collaboration on centralized or coordinated assessment systems established and operated by Continuums of Care. The VA must also ensure that the information and related resources are accessible to VA medical center staff and homelessness service providers.

Additionally, the bill requires the VHA to communicate with VA employees who have responsibilities related to homelessness assistance programs regarding (1) the measurement of performance by the VA's Homeless Program Office, and (2) how to obtain and provide feedback about the performance measures.</summary>
</bill>
