<bill session="115" type="h" number="6574" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:55Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to determine, on behalf of Medicare beneficiaries, covered part D drug prices for certain covered part D drugs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-05T18:22:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Fair Drug Pricing Act of 2018

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to negotiate with drug manufacturers in determining the price that may be charged for prescription drugs under the Medicare prescription drug benefit.

Under current law, the CMS may not interfere with negotiations between drug manufacturers and prescription drug plan (PDP) sponsors. The bill creates an exception to this prohibition with respect to specified drugs that: (1) are single-source or biological, (2) are not both manufactured by more than two drug manufacturers&#160;and manufactured by at least one manufacturer as a generic drug, and (3) meet other specified requirements. The CMS must promulgate regulations regarding the identification of such drugs.

With respect to&#160;these drugs, the CMS shall negotiate the price that may be charged to PDP sponsors and Medicare Advantage (MA) organizations for Medicare and MA enrollees. The bill establishes processes for negotiation and price determination in the initial plan year and subsequent plan years.

A manufacturer must participate in the negotiation process as a condition of coverage under the Medicare prescription drug benefit.</summary>
</bill>
