<bill session="117" type="s" number="1849" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:01Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Leadership in Global Tech Standards Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program to support the participation of small businesses in meetings and proceedings of international standards organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leadership in Global Tech Standards Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4956" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-30T20:54:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Leadership in Global Tech Standards Act of 2021

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a program that supports the participation of U.S. small businesses in meetings and proceedings of standards development organizations to develop voluntary technical standards.

To carry out this program, the SBA must award grants to small businesses for the reasonable costs of participation in standards development organizations.

These grants may only be awarded to small businesses that (1) demonstrate technical expertise in key emerging technologies and technical standards (e.g., artificial intelligence), (2) commit personnel with such expertise to regular participation in international bodies responsible for developing standards for those technologies, and (3) agree to coordinate between the public and private sectors to ensure protection of national security interests in the setting of international standards.</summary>
</bill>
