<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>521</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T22:48:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T22:48:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-03-05</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
        <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Other</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2003-05-15T23:17:57Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2003-04-10T16:12:06Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-03-05T16:13:59Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 108-48</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-05-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 99.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-05-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-48.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-05-15</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-48.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-03-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3171-3172)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-03-05</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3171)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-03-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000077</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Campbell, Ben Nighthorse [R-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>BEN</firstName>
        <lastName>CAMPBELL</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <middleName>NIGHTHORSE</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-03-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-04-28T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 521, Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/14417</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs on April 10, 2003&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-04-28T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 521, Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/14417</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs on April 10, 2003</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arizona</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gas pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian lands</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian water rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Leases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Montana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oregon</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rent</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water supply</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Native Americans</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-03-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003 - Amends Federal law to permit, upon approval of the Secretary of the Interior and for public, religious, educational, recreational, residential, or business purposes, the leasing of restricted Indian lands for terms of up to 99 years (subject to specified conditions) for: (1) land located on the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Indian Reservation or on the Burns Paiute Reservation; and (2) land held in trust for the Yurok Tribe or for the Hopland Band of Pomo Indians of the Hopland Rancheria.<p>Permits (under specified conditions) the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation (Tribes) to lease to the Northern Border Pipeline Company tribally-owned land on the Fort Peck Indian Reservation for interstate gas pipelines.<p>Authorizes the Tribes, upon approval of the Secretary, to enter into a lease or other temporary conveyance of water rights recognized under the Fort Peck-Montana Compact for the purpose of meeting water needs of the Dry Prairie Rural Water Association, Incorporated.<p>Amends Federal law to exempt Indian Tribes from the requirement to obtain approval of the Secretary to enter into leases of specified restricted lands (except mineral leases) for terms that do not exceed 99 years, if the Tribe provides written notice in the original leasing documents that stipulates the Tribe has the unilateral right to terminate such a lease in any case in which the tribe does not waive sovereign immunity from civil action brought by a party of the lease for just compensation resulting from such a termination. Authorizes any party to such a lease to bring a civil action to enforce it.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-05-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends Federal law to permit, upon approval of the Secretary of the Interior (Secretary) and for public, religious, educational, recreational, residential, or business purposes, the leasing of restricted Indian lands for terms of up to 99 years (subject to specified conditions) for: (1) land located on the Confederated Tribes of the Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Burns Paiute Reservation, or on the Muckleshoot Indian Reservation; and (2) land held in trust for the Yurok Tribe, the Hopland Band of Pomo Indians of the Hopland Rancheria, or the Muckleshoot Indian Tribe.<p>(Sec. 3) Permits (under specified conditions) the Assiniboine and Sioux Tribes of the Fort Peck Reservation (Tribes) to lease to the Northern Border Pipeline Company, tribally-owned land on the Fort Peck Indian Reservation for interstate gas pipelines.<p>(Sec. 4) Declares that any rental proceeds from the lease of lands acquired from loans provided by the Secretary of Agriculture from the Farmers Home Administration Direct Loan Account to any Indian tribe shall constitute the rental value of that land and satisfy the requirement for appraisal of the land.<p>(Sec. 5) Authorizes the Reservation, upon approval of the Secretary, to enter into a lease or other temporary conveyance of water rights recognized under the Fort Peck-Montana Compact for the purpose of meeting water needs of the Dry Prairie Rural Water Association, Incorporated.<p>(Sec. 6) Amends Federal law to permit federally recognized Indian tribes to lease restricted tribal land for up to 99 years (subject to specified conditions) for public, religious, educational, recreational, residential, or business purposes (except for exploration, development, or extraction of any mineral resource) without specific approval of the Secretary if the lease is executed under tribal regulations approved by the Secretary under in this Act.<p>Requires the Secretary to review proposed tribal regulations from a federally recognized tribe and to approve or disapprove them based upon their consistency with existing regulations.<p>Requires Indian tribes to provide to the Secretary a copy of the lease and documentation of payments to the tribe from such a lease for land leased without the Secretary's specific approval. Exempts the United States from liability for any loss sustained by any party to such a lease.<p>Authorizes any person, upon exhaustion of tribal remedies, to petition the Secretary to review a tribe's compliance with its own approved regulations. Requires the Secretary, on completion of the review, to take action to compel compliance with such regulations if they have been breached.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Act of August 9, 1955, to extend the terms of leases of certain restricted Indian land, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>1890</number>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:36:48Z</updateDate>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>C000077</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Campbell, Ben Nighthorse [R-CO]</fullName>
            <firstName>BEN</firstName>
            <lastName>CAMPBELL</lastName>
            <party>R</party>
            <state>CO</state>
            <middleName>NIGHTHORSE</middleName>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <submittedDate>2003-10-21T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>108</congress>
          <type>S</type>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <number>521</number>
          <title>Indian Land Leasing Act of 2003</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T22:48:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>2</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2003-10-21</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2003-05-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-03-05T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-05-15</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 99.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
