<bill session="118" type="s" number="450" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP Iran Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sanctioning Transfers and Outbound Products to Iran Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Iran Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen export controls for emerging and foundational technologies that bolster the destabilizing activities of the Islamic Republic of Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-30T21:39:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sanctioning Transfers and Outbound Products to Iran Act of 2023 or the STOP Iran Act of 2023

This bill mandates that the Department of Commerce require a license for the export, reexport, or in-country transfer of emerging and foundational technologies to certain Iranian persons. (Generally, such technologies are those identified by a federal interagency process to be&#160;essential&#160;to U.S. national security.)

The Iranian persons subject to this bill are Iranian individuals or entities that are subject to U.S. sanctions and provide support to certain organizations, including (1) the Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps and the Armed Forces of Iran, (2) any organization designated as a foreign terrorist organization, and (3) any entity engaged in hostilities with a partner or ally of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
