<bill session="109" type="s" number="3949" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:04Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Illegal Immigration Source Study and Focus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to study the geographic areas in Mexico from which illegal immigrants are entering the United States and to develop plans to address the social, political, and economic conditions that are contributing to such illegal immigration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Illegal Immigration Source Study and Focus Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10289-10290"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10291" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-30T20:37:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Illegal Immigration Source Study and Focus Act - Directs the Secretary of State to conduct a study and report to Congress every five years respecting: (1) the geographic areas in Mexico from which large numbers of residents and large percentages of the population are leaving to illegally enter the United States; and (2) the social, political, and economic conditions in such areas that contribute to such illegal immigration.

Directs the United States Agency for International Development (USAID): (1) in consultation with the Secretary, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and appropriate Mexican officials, to designate up to four geographic areas within Mexico as Immigration Impact Focus Areas; and (2) in consultation with the Secretary, to develop a plan to concentrate economic development and humanitarian assistance provided to Mexico in such Areas.</summary>
</bill>
