<bill session="117" type="h" number="5217" updated="2022-12-30T11:18:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Acquisition E-Commerce Fairness and Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 846 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to expand the testing program for e-commerce portal models, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Acquisition E-Commerce Fairness and Competition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2021-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-23T20:12:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Acquisition E-Commerce Fairness and Competition Act

This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to expand the testing program for e-commerce portal models.

Specifically, the GSA must (1) expand the proof-of-concept testing program by testing at least three commercial e-commerce portal models, including the E-Commerce Model, the E-Procurement Model, and the E-Marketplace Model (as described in a GSA implementation plan published in March 2018), to ensure that such program is representative of available commercial e-commerce portal models that qualify for the program; and (2) report to Congress.

The GSA must ensure that a commercial e-commerce portal provider awarded a contract that is owned or controlled by a person or entity with a market capitalization greater than $600 billion at any time in the two years preceding this bill's enactment (e.g., Amazon) does not sell products through the commercial e-commerce portal that compete with products sold by any third-party supplier through such portal.</summary>
</bill>
