<bill session="111" type="s" number="1701" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bridge Life Extension Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to require corrosion mitigation and prevention plans for bridges receiving Federal funding, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bridge Life Extension Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1682" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-07T22:23:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bridge Life Extension Act of 2009 - Requires a state, as a condition of receiving federal-aid highway funding, to develop and implement a highway bridge management system that meets certain requirements.

Requires a state, in developing and implementing such a system, to: (1) identify corrosion mitigation and prevention methods to preserve its highway bridges; (2) establish a project maintenance program to extend the life of such bridges; and (3) ensure that maintenance individuals are qualified and all highway bridge engineers and inspectors implementing the system are trained, and certified by the state, in corrosion mitigation and prevention techniques.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a minimum federal standard for corrosion mitigation and prevention training and certification for such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
