<bill session="116" type="h" number="7548" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Made in America: Preparation for a Pandemic Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 41, United States Code, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, to ensure availability of personal protective equipment during pandemics and other public health emergencies through stockpile requirements and domestic manufacturing incentives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Made in America: Preparation for a Pandemic Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2020-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-23T19:58:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Made in America: Preparation for a Pandemic Act of 2020

This bill establishes a pandemic preparation tax credit and a requirement to maintain in the Strategic National Stockpile a specified amount of personal protective equipment (PPE).

The pandemic preparation tax credit is an amount equal to 20% of the qualified expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer for purposes of producing PPE that qualifies for addition to the Strategic National Stockpile.

The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) shall ensure that the stockpile includes an amount of PPE sufficient to meet the health security needs of the United States for one year during a pandemic or other emergency.

The bill requires that at least 25% of the PPE in the stockpile be produced domestically, with exceptions. If the OMB determines that the requirement is not satisfied, it shall (1) notify specified congressional committees on a quarterly basis, and (2) post each notification on a General Services Administration website.</summary>
</bill>
