<bill session="117" type="h" number="3790" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to guarantee investments that will open new markets for forest owners in rural areas of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2021-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2021-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2021-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000480" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1107" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-16T14:36:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Forest Markets Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish the Rural Forest Market Investment Program to guarantee investments to finance certain projects that will enable rural private forest landowners to participate in an innovative market for forest carbon or other products.

In establishing the program, USDA must consider ways to ensure that the program minimizes disruptions to traditional forest products markets.

Eligible projects are projects developed by a private entity or a publicly supported, charitable nonprofit organization engaged in the aggregation of sustainable forestry practices implemented by rural private forest landowners to facilitate the sale of credits in the voluntary carbon market or other environmental market using a methodology approved by a credible, third-party entity.

USDA may guarantee up to $150 million with respect to each investment.

Authority to carry out the program terminates on September 30, 2023.</summary>
</bill>
