<bill session="118" type="h" number="6367" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Armed Conflict Migration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Armed Conflict Migration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Armed Conflict Migration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to provide financial assistance to countries that receive an influx of civilian, non-combatant displaced persons stemming from the armed conflict that has resulted from Hamas's October 2023 terrorism in Israel, to be used for humanitarian aid for the displaced persons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-329.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-19" calendar="Union" number="268">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 268.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-15T16:54:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Armed Conflict Migration Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at each international financial institution to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to support the provision of financial assistance to countries that receive an influx of civilian, non-combatant displaced persons as a result of the armed conflict from Hamas' October 2023 attacks in Israel.

The requirement sunsets on the earlier of (1) seven years after the date of enactment, or (2) the date Treasury certifies to specified congressional committees that the requirement is no longer in the national interest or that such influx has ceased.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-329</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
