<bill session="118" type="h" number="6833" updated="2025-11-19T03:44:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improve and Enhance the Work Opportunity Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improve and Enhance the Work Opportunity Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve and enhance the work opportunity tax credit, to encourage longer-service employment, and to modernize the credit to make it more effective as a hiring incentive for targeted workers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001066" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2024-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2024-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2024-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5370" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-23T15:41:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Improve and Enhance the Work Opportunity Tax Credit Act 

This bill increases the work opportunity tax credit (WOTC) for wages paid during the first year of employment to certain employees. The bill also eliminates the maximum age limit applicable to Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefit recipients for purposes of the WOTC.

Under current law, an employer generally may claim a WOTC in the amount of 40% of up to $6,000 (or of up to $24,000 for certain veterans, $3,000 for summer youth employees, and $10,000 for long-term family aid recipients) of qualified wages paid during the first year of employment to an employee who is a member of a targeted group. (Exceptions and limitations apply.)

The bill increases the WOTC to (1) 50% of up to $6,000 (or of up to $24,000 for certain veterans) of qualified first-year wages paid to an employee who is a member of a targeted group (other than a summer youth employee or recipient of long-term family aid), and (2) 50% of up to $12,000 (or of up to $48,000 for certain veterans) of qualified wages paid during the first year of employment to such employee if the employee works at least 400 hours during the year.

Finally, the bill eliminates the maximum age limit applicable to SNAP benefit recipients and, thus, allows an employer to claim the WOTC for qualified first-year wages paid to an employee who is at least 18 years old and receiving SNAP benefits for a certain period of time.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
