<bill session="118" type="h" number="7762" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Food Access for All Americans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Food Access for All Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a new tax credit and grant program to stimulate investment and healthy nutrition options in food deserts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2024-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-18T14:47:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Healthy Food Access for All Americans Act 

This bill allows tax credits and grants for activities that provide access to healthy food in food deserts, which are communities that have limited or no access to grocery stores and meet income requirements.

For entities that are certified by the Department of the Treasury as special access food providers using specified criteria, the bill allows tax credits for operating a new grocery store or renovating an existing grocery store in a food desert. The bill also authorizes grants for a portion of (1) the construction costs of building a permanent food bank in a food desert, and (2) the annual operating costs of temporary access merchants (mobile markets, farmers markets, and food banks).

Treasury, in coordination with the Department of Agriculture (USDA), must annually allocate the tax credits and grants to special access food providers. Grants authorized by this bill are not considered gross income for tax purposes.

The bill also requires USDA to update the Food Access Research Atlas at least annually to account for food retailers that are placed in service during that year.</summary>
</bill>
