<bill session="117" type="s" number="3945" updated="2023-09-01T13:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Shareholder Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Shareholder Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to address the solicitation of proxy with respect to securities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000601"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-13T17:20:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Shareholder Transparency Act of 2022 

This bill limits corporate shareholder proposals and revises proxy voting protocols for shareholders. Current shareholder proposal rules address who is eligible to submit shareholder proposals for a vote and the dissemination of information to voters through a proxy statement.

Under the bill, a company is not required to comply with these shareholder proposal rules. Instead, a company may opt-in to these rules.

The bill also revises these rules to require a shareholder hold at least 1% of the market value of the company's securities in order to submit a shareholder proposal. Under current rules, a shareholder's ability to submit a proposal depends upon the dollar amount of shares held and the length of time the shares have been held. It also revises these rules to provide that a company's allowed bases for exclusion of a proposal apply without regard to whether the proposal relates to a significant social policy issue. Under current guidance, a shareholder proposal may overcome a company's exclusion if the proposal is of social policy significance.

Finally, the bill generally prohibits proxy voting advice furnished by a person who provides such advice for a fee.</summary>
</bill>
