<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6051</number>
    <updateDate>2022-01-06T17:18:07Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-01-06T17:18:07Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-06-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mrs. BONO MACK:H.R. 6051.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto clause 3 of section 8 of article I of the Constitution.[Page H4605]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif17</systemCode>
            <name>Innovation, Data, and Commerce Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2012-06-29T14:28:02Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-06-28T14:03:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>MAP-21</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>14</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-03-21</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Natural Resources, Energy and Commerce, Agriculture, Science, Space, and Technology, the Budget, Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>MAP-21</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>4348</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-07-06</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 112-141.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Mariah's Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1449</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-12-21</actionDate>
          <text>By Senator Rockefeller from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 112-261.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>MAP-21</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>1813</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-04-24</actionDate>
          <text>See also H.R. 4348.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-06-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif17</systemCode>
            <name>Innovation, Data, and Commerce Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-06-28</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-06-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-06-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001228</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Bono Mack, Mary [R-CA-45]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARY</firstName>
        <lastName>BONO MACK</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>45</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accidents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Bankruptcy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Business records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child safety and welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computers and information technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy efficiency and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet and video services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet, web applications, social media</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Product safety and quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Retail and wholesale trades</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science and engineering education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology transfer and commercialization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trade restrictions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-06-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-09-24T18:50:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2012 - Repeals the prohibition against a motor vehicle safety standard's requiring or allowing a manufacturer to comply with it by using a buzzer designed to indicate a safety belt is not in use, except a buzzer that operates only during the eight-second period after the ignition is turned to the &quot;start&quot; or &quot;on&quot; position. (Thus allows manufacturers to comply with the standard by using any sort of buzzer.)</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT), with respect to odometer disclosures required when ownership of a motor vehicle is transferred, to prescribe regulations permitting any written disclosures or notices and related matters to be provided electronically.</p> <p>Increases civil penalties (including damages) for violations of federal prohibitions against tampering with odometers. </p> <p>Prohibits a person from selling, offering for sale, introducing in interstate commerce, or importing into the United States motor vehicles or equipment about which a notice of a defect or order of noncompliance with federal motor vehicle safety requirements has been issued. </p> <p>Prescribes conditions on the importation of vehicles and equipment.</p> <p>Requires an officer or employee designated by the Secretary to enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) for inspections and sampling of motor vehicle equipment being offered for import to determine compliance with federal transportation law.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to: (1) require motor vehicle safety recall information be made available to the public on the Internet, and (2) publicize the means for contacting a National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) motor vehicle safety defect hotline for manufacturer, dealer, and mechanic personnel.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to issue regulations to require passenger motor vehicle manufacturers to affix, in a readily accessible location, a device that provides information on how to submit a safety-related motor vehicle defect complaint to NHTSA.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on the quality of data collected through the National Automotive Sampling System, including the Special Crash Investigations Program.</p> <p>Declares that filing for bankruptcy shall not negate a manufacturer's duty to comply with motor vehicle safety requirements for the recall of defective motor vehicle and motor vehicle equipment. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish within NHTSA a Council for Vehicle Electronics, Vehicle Software, and Emerging Technologies. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to complete an examination of the need for safety standards with regard to electronic systems in passenger motor vehicles.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to modify federal motor vehicle safety standards to: (1) improve the protection of children seated in child restraint systems during side impact crashes, (2) improve the ease of use of child restraint anchorage systems, and (3) provide a safety belt use warning system for designated seating positions in the rear seat.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend certain provisions of title 49, United States Code, relating to motor vehicle safety, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2012-06-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr6051ih/xml/BILLS-112hr6051ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-06-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
