<bill session="111" type="h" number="4472" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Close All Routes and Prevent Asian Carp Today Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army to take action with respect to the Chicago waterway system to prevent the migration of bighead and silver carps into Lake Michigan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close All Routes and Prevent Asian Carp Today Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2010-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000594" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001178" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2010-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2946" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-01T19:47:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Close All Routes and Prevent Asian Carp Today Act of 2010 - Requires the Secretary of the Army to take actions to ensure: (1) the immediate closure and ceasing of operation of the locks at the O'Brien Lock and Dam and the Chicago Controlling Works until a strategy relating to controlled lock operations is developed; (2) the installation of structures in the North Shore Channel and the Grand Calumet and Little Calumet Rivers to prevent the migration of bighead and silver carps into Lake Michigan; (3) the installation of interim barriers in the Chicago waterway system between the Des Plaines River and the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal and the Illinois and Michigan Canal and the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal to prevent bighead and silver carps from entering the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal during a flood event; (4) the operation of the Electrical Disbursal Barrier System at optimal operating power and the expedited completion of proposed barrier IIB of such system; (5) the comprehensive monitoring of the Chicago Sanitary and Ship Canal and all connected waterways for the presence and location of bighead and silver carps; (6) the eradication of any bighead or silver carps discovered in the Chicago waterway system; (7) the upgrading and making permanent of barrier I of the Electrical Disbursal Barrier System in a location and with the features and operations determined to be the most effective; (8) the implementation of measures recommended in the efficacy study authorized under the Water Resources Development Act of 2007 or provided in related interim reports; (9) the implementation of emergency measures to prevent bighead and silver carps from dispersing into the Great Lakes; and (10) the acquisition of real estate necessary for the construction, operation, and maintenance of the Electrical Disbursal Barrier System.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on strategies for addressing any effects with respect to commerce and flood control resulting from such actions.</summary>
</bill>
