<bill session="116" type="s" number="902" updated="2022-11-01T18:32:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Hiring Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Hiring Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the non-applicability of non-Department of Veterans Affairs covenants not to compete to the appointment of physicians in the Veterans Health Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1163" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T16:30:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">VA Hiring Enhancement Act

This bill modifies requirements and procedures related to the hiring of physicians at the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Specifically, the bill negates enforcement of a noncompete agreement that an applicant for a physician position in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) has entered into with a non-VA facility or entity. As a condition of terminating the noncompete agreement, the physician must agree to serve at the VHA for one year or until the expiration of the noncompete agreement, whichever is later.

The bill also authorizes the VA to offer a contingent physician's appointment to a person if the person will have completed a residency program leading to board eligibility in a specialty and met other requirements for the appointment within two years after the VA offer.

Eligibility requirements for a VA physician's appointment are revised to require completion of a residency program rather than an internship.</summary>
</bill>
