<bill session="118" type="h" number="1693" updated="2025-03-03T20:01:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPORT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000371"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the National Intelligence Enterprise.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HLIG06" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="National Intelligence Enterprise" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="945" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-12T20:41:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2023 or the REPORT Act of 2023

This bill requires specified federal agencies to report to Congress concerning any act of terrorism that occurs in the United States.

Whenever an act of terrorism occurs, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of Justice (DOJ), the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and, as appropriate, the National Counterterrorism Center (NCC), must submit to Congress an unclassified report. Such report shall be posted on a publicly available website of the primary government agency.

Such report shall (1) include a statement of the facts of the act of terrorism, (2) identify any gaps in homeland or national security to prevent future acts of terrorism, and (3) include any recommendations for additional measures to improve homeland or national security.

If the reporting agencies determine that any information required to be reported could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution, such agencies may withhold such information from reporting and shall notify Congress of that determination.

This bill shall terminate five years after its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
