<bill session="110" type="s" number="2479" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Catalyst to Better Diabetes Care Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Catalyst to Better Diabetes Care Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to catalyze change in the care and treatment of diabetes in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2007-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2008-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2008-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2008-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15469"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3373" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3544" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-03-07T15:18:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Catalyst to Better Diabetes Care Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to: (1) review uptake and utilization of diabetes screening benefits to identify and address problems with utilization and data collection mechanisms; (2) establish an outreach program to identify existing efforts to increase awareness among seniors and providers of such benefits; and (3) maximize cost-effectiveness in increasing utilization of such benefits.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an advisory group to examine and recommend best practices of employee wellness and disease management programs.

Directs the Secretary to prepare, biennially, a diabetes report card for the nation and for each state.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) promote the education and training of physicians on how to properly complete birth and death certificates and the importance of such data; (2) encourage state adoption of the latest standard revisions of birth and death certificates; and (3) work with states to reengineer their vital statistics systems to provide cost-effective, timely, and vital systems data. Allows the Secretary to promote improvements to the collection of diabetes mortality data.

Requires the Secretary to conduct a study of the impact of diabetes on the practice of medicine in the United Sates and the level of diabetes medical education that should be required prior to licensure, board certification, and board recertification.</summary>
</bill>
