<bill session="117" type="h" number="9064" updated="2023-09-12T18:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jamal Khashoggi Protection for Dissidents and Journalists Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jamal Khashoggi Protection for Dissidents and Journalists Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enshrine the legacy of Jamal Khashoggi by protecting dissidents and journalists, codifying the Khashoggi Ban, and introducing the Khashoggi Amendment to the Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1010"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T18:31:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Jamal Khashoggi Protection for Dissidents and Journalists Act of 2022

 This bill strips away sovereign immunity from a foreign state in certain legal proceedings where the plaintiff is seeking money damages for injuries or death caused by that foreign state's counter-dissident activities. (Generally, foreign states are immune from the jurisdiction of U.S. courts, including state courts, except in certain situations, such as when the foreign state has waived immunity.)

The bill also makes inadmissible into the United States a non-U.S. national (alien under federal law) who has engaged in certain serious and extraterritorial counter-dissident activities on behalf of a foreign government, including actions to harass or harm journalists or activists.</summary>
</bill>
