<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1128" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4310" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-05-18T10:35:53-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-05-18"/>
  <description>At the end of subtitle D of title XII of division A of the bill, add the following:    SEC. 12xx. LIMITATION ON FUNDS FOR INSTITUTIONS OR ORGANIZATIONS ESTABLISHED BY THE UNITED NATIONS CONVENTION ON THE LAW OF THE SEA.    None of the funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act may be made available for any institution or organization established by the United Nations Convention on the Law of the Sea, including the International Seabed Authority, the International Tribunal for the Law of the Sea, and the Commission on the Limits of the Continental Shelf.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 47 printed in House Report 112-485 to limit funds authorized to be appropriated by this Act to any institution or organization established by the Convention on the Law of the Sea, including the International Seabed Authority, the International Tribunal for the Law of the Sea, and the Commission on the Limits of the Continental Shelf.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-05-18T10:35:53-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="283">
      <text>On agreeing to the Duncan (SC) amendment (A030) Agreed to by recorded vote: 229 - 193 (Roll no. 283).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3118-3119" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18T00:18:34-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A030) offered by Mr. Duncan (SC).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/17/2012 H3081" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 5/17/2012 H3081" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18T10:35:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18T10:35:53-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18T10:35:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Duncan (SC) amendment (A030) Agreed to by recorded vote: 229 - 193 (Roll no. 283).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3118-3119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18T00:18:34-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A030) offered by Mr. Duncan (SC).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/17/2012 H3081" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 5/17/2012 H3081" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
