<bill session="117" type="h" number="6305" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Biomedical Research Enterprise Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Biomedical Research Enterprise Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the security of biomedical research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2021-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-28T18:29:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect America's Biomedical Research Enterprise Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to evaluate ways to better protect intellectual property, sensitive medical information, and similar information used in biomedical research and development from national security risks and related threats.

In particular, HHS must identify national security risks and potential misuse of proprietary information and develop strategies to prevent or mitigate such risks and misuse in federally funded biomedical research and development. HHS must also develop a framework to identify areas of federally funded biomedical research and development that are emerging areas of interest to state actors and regularly review its recommendations and policies related to the protection of biomedical research and development.

In carrying out these activities, HHS must collaborate with relevant federal agencies (such as the Federal Bureau of Investigation) and consult with research institutions, research advocacy organizations, and other experts.</summary>
</bill>
