<bill session="118" type="h" number="3794" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLASH Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fast-track Logistics for Acquiring Supplies in a Hurry Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLASH Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority to award follow-on production contracts or transactions, procure supplies for experimental or test purposes, and acquire innovative commercial products and commercial services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3077"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-26T18:48:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Fast-track Logistics for Acquiring Supplies in a Hurry Act of 2023 or the FLASH Act of 2023

This bill expands federal contracting and other authorities to support the development and acquisition of products and supplies that are necessary for national public health and health security.

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may use noncompetitive procedures to procure medical countermeasures (e.g., vaccines), chemical materials and reagents, manufacturing supplies, and similar items that are needed to develop products for national public health and health security.

Additionally, HHS may acquire, subject to dollar limits and other conditions, innovative commercial products and services by soliciting proposals and selecting proposals through peer review.

Further, the bill expands the activities of the Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA) to include supporting the design and development of prototypes for products to diagnose, mitigate, prevent, treat, or otherwise respond to biological, chemical, radiological, or nuclear threats, including pandemics or epidemics. If BARDA enters an initial transaction to design or develop such a test or prototype using competitive procedures, BARDA may use noncompetitive procedures for a follow-on transaction to produce the test or prototype.</summary>
</bill>
