<bill session="117" type="s" number="1330" updated="2023-07-31T18:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Facilitating Federal Employee Reskilling Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the reskilling of Federal employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Facilitating Federal Employee Reskilling Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Facilitating Federal Employee Reskilling Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2021-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-204.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-11-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="556">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 556.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-31T18:01:58Z" status="Reported to Senate">Facilitating Federal Employee Reskilling Act

This bill establishes certain standards for federal reskilling programs. The bill defines federal reskilling program as a program established by an executive agency, or the Office of Personnel Management, to provide employees with technical skills or expertise that would qualify them to serve in different positions.

The bill requires such programs to use merit-based principles with respect to employees' participation. Participating employees must also be given the option to return to their original positions, particularly if they are unsuccessful in their new positions. Additionally, employees are entitled to the same grades in their new positions as in their original positions; new positions must also utilize employees' newly acquired skills or expertise.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-204</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
