<bill session="117" type="s" number="4592" updated="2023-08-29T15:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Quantum Computing Cybersecurity Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quantum Computing Cybersecurity Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Quantum Computing Cybersecurity Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage the migration of Federal Government information technology systems to quantum-resistant cryptography, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2022-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2022-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2022-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment. With written report No. 117-251.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="635">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7535" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-22T20:37:30Z" status="Reported to Senate">Quantum Computing Cybersecurity Preparedness Act

This bill addresses the migration of executive agencies information technology systems to post-quantum cryptography. Post-quantum cryptography is encryption strong enough to resist attacks from quantum computers developed in the future.

Not later than one year after the National Institutes of Standards and Technology has issued post-quantum cryptography standards, the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) shall begin to prioritize the migration of agency information technology systems to post-quantum cryptography.

Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this bill, the OMB shall submit to Congress a report on

 a strategy to address the risk posed by the vulnerabilities of agency information technology systems to the potential capability of a quantum computer; the funding necessary to secure such information technology systems from the threat posed by adversarial access to quantum computers; and a description of federal coordination efforts to develop standards for post-quantum cryptography, including any federal Information Processing Standards.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-251</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
