<bill session="116" type="h" number="8572" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:33Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Nuclear Waste Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Nuclear Waste Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, to conduct a study, and submit to Congress a report, on an auction process or other system for selecting and entering into contracts with non-Federal entities for consolidated interim storage facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2020-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2020-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-13T18:05:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing America's Nuclear Waste Act

This bill addresses storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste in the United States.

Specifically, the bill requires

 the Government Accountability Office to report on the risks to current storage locations for spent nuclear fuel, including spent nuclear fuel from civilian nuclear power reactors, and high-level radioactive waste, including risks that are related to global weather patterns and geography; the Office of Management and Budget to report on the economic benefits of consolidated interim storage of spent nuclear fuel and high-level radioactive waste, including economic benefits associated with job growth and redeveloping sites of decommissioned civilian nuclear power reactors; and the Department of Energy to study and report on an auction process or other system for selecting and entering into contracts with nonfederal entities for consolidated interim storage facilities that are located at a site without an operating nuclear reactor, and for which such entities will hold a license issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</summary>
</bill>
