<bill session="108" type="h" number="4645" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRIDE Plus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Army to provide Federal assistance for environmental infrastructure projects in northern and northeastern Kentucky.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIDE Plus Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000558"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-01T19:18:34Z" status="Introduced in House">PRIDE Plus Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to establish a program to provide environmental assistance to non-Federal interests in specified counties in northern and northeastern Kentucky. Permits such assistance to be in the form of design and construction assistance for publicly owned water-related environmental infrastructure and resource protection and development projects, including projects for wastewater treatment, water supply, environmental restoration, and surface water resource protection and development.

Requires the Secretary to enter into a local cooperation agreement with a non-Federal interest to provide for design and construction of a project, which provides for: (1) development by the Secretary of a facilities or resource protection and development plan; and (2) establishment of legal and institutional structures to ensure the effective long-term operation of the project by the non-Federal interest.

Sets the Federal share of the project costs under each local cooperation agreement at 75 percent. Directs that the non-Federal interest receive specified credit for design work, interest, land, easements, rights-of-way, and relocations. Sets the non-Federal share of project operation and maintenance costs at 100 percent.</summary>
</bill>
