<bill session="117" type="s" number="4720" updated="2023-03-09T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8237" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2617" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-08T10:57:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2023

 This bill provides FY2023 appropriations for the legislative branch, including the Senate and joint items such as

 the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, the Office of the Attending Physician, and the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services. In addition, the bill provides FY2023 appropriations for

 the Capitol Police; the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; the Congressional Budget Office; the Architect of the Capitol; the Library of Congress, including the Congressional Research Service and the Copyright Office; the Government Publishing Office; the Government Accountability Office; Congressional Office for International Leadership Fund; and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. (Pursuant to the longstanding practice of each chamber of Congress determining its own requirements, funds for the House of Representatives are not included in the Senate bill.)

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
