<bill session="117" type="h" number="3242" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">USA Civics Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve the American History for Freedom grant program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Understanding and Studying American Civics Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USA Civics Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1814" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="879" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4384" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4403" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-25T22:19:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Understanding and Studying American Civics Act of 2021 or the USA Civics Act of 2021

This bill reauthorizes through FY2026 and revises the American History for Freedom grant program.

The bill renames the program as the American Civics Education Program.

The bill authorizes the Department of Education to award grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) once every three years to establish or strengthen academic programs to promote American political thought and history; the history, achievements, and impact of American representative democracy and constitutional democracies globally; and the means of participation in political and civic life. Currently, these grants are awarded to IHEs for three years and are focused on traditional American history and the history and achievements of Western civilization.

IHEs may use grants to support additional activities, such as collaborating with federal or state humanities programs and using open educational resources.</summary>
</bill>
