<bill session="108" type="h" number="5400" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare PPO Fairness Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for reimbursement of enrollees in the Medicare PPO Demonstration Project for expenses inappropriately incurred in being provided coverage through out-of-network providers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare PPO Fairness Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 E2115"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Preferred provider organizations (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-06T21:42:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare PPO Fairness Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide written notice to each individual who is, or has been, enrolled in the Medicare PPO Demonstration Project of the following: (1) the fact that the enrollees are, and have been, eligible for coverage of services whether the services were provided by in-network or out-of-network providers; and (2) there is a procedure for reimbursement for claims for services that should be (or have been) covered but were not covered because of their provision by an out-of-network provider.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a procedure for reimbursement of enrollees under the Medicare PPO Demonstration Project for claims for services furnished before January 1, 2005, that should be (or have been) covered but were not covered because of their provision by an out-of-network provider; and (2) provide for an adjustment in the capitation rates for plans under the project for months in 2005 so as to reduce payment under such rates, in the aggregate, by the aggregate amount of payments the Secretary estimates will be paid under such procedure.</summary>
</bill>
