<bill session="108" type="s" number="2173" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:09Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further the purposes of the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2000.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2004-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2304"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2304" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-626.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/22/04 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-323.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="679">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 679.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9352-9353" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9352-9353" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:04:16-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4562" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-30T19:38:29Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Trust Act of 2004 - Authorizes the United States to take into trust certain land (formerly known as the Dawson Ranch) in Kiowa County, Colorado, owned by the Cheyenne and Arapaho Indian Tribes of Oklahoma (property). Directs the Tribes to convey title to the property to the United States. Declares that all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property (except specified facilities) are to be held in trust by the United States for the Tribes.

Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) acquire by donation the improvements in fee; and (2) construct a facility on the property only after obtaining the agreement of the Cheyenne and Arapaho Tribes, the Northern Cheyenne Tribe, and the Northern Arapaho Tribe. Permits the use of Federal funds to be expended only on improvements or facilities that are owned in fee by the United States.

Directs the Secretary to cause a survey to be conducted by the Office of Cadastral Survey of the Bureau of Land Management of the boundary lines and the description to be published in the Federal Register.

 Requires the property to be administered in perpetuity by the Secretary as part of the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site, only for historical, traditional, cultural, or other uses in accordance with the Sand Creek Massacre National Historic Site Establishment Act of 2000.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-323</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
