<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2703" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:22Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="95" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-03-11">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-03-09"/>
  <description>To reduce debt and require the industries responsible for producing products that contaminate toxic waste sites and industries who are exempt from liability for such contamination, to help pay for the cleanup by reinstating the Superfund polluter pays fees, and to reduce the deficit.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-03-11" how="roll" result="fail" roll="45">
      <text>Amendment SA 2703 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 44 - 52. Record Vote Number: 45.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Amendment SA 2703 proposed by Senator Lautenberg. (consideration: CR S2629-2630, S2638-2640, S2644; text: CR S2629-2630) To reduce debt and require the industries responsible for producing products that contaminate toxic waste sites and industries who are exempt from liability for such contamination, to help pay for the cleanup by reinstating the Superfund polluter pays fees, and to reduce the deficit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 2703 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 44 - 52. Record Vote Number: 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 2703 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 44 - 52. Record Vote Number: 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2703 proposed by Senator Lautenberg.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2629-2630, S2638-2640, S2644" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2629-2630" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
