<bill session="112" type="h" number="1217" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:16Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13T17:42:53-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-04-13T17:42:53-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To repeal the Prevention and Public Health Fund.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the Prevention and Public Health Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2011-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2011-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2011-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-09">
      <text>Mr. Walden asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Energy and Commerce have until midnight on April 11 to file a report on H.R. 1217. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-11">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 112-57.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-04-11" calendar="Union" number="29">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 29.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-04-12T19:57:23-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 219 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1217 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report. All points of order against the amendments are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:04:38-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 219 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:19:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 219.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2633-2647" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2640" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:20:04-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1217 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. The resolution waives all points of order against consideration of the bill. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report. All points of order against the amendments are waived.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:20:19-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 219 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:20:20-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable K. Michael Conaway to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T15:20:29-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T16:10:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 219, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T16:17:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 219, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor amendment no. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T16:25:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Castor(FL) amendment no. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Castor(FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T16:26:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 219, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castor amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T16:34:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Castor(FL)amendment no. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Castor(FL) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:08:31-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1217.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:09:19-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2645" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:09:29-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:09:57-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Loebsack moved to recommit with instructions to Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2645-2646" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2645-2646" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:10:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Loebsack motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a provision that would preserve the Prevention and Public Health Fund for prevention, wellness, and public health activities for individuals 65 years or older. A point of order was reserved, but was subsequently removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:19:53-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2646" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:36:11-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 189 - 234 (Roll no. 263).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="264" datetime="2011-04-13T17:42:53-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 236 - 183 (Roll no. 264).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13T17:42:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4628" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="hr" number="219" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h255"/>
    <amendment number="h254"/>
    <amendment number="h253"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2012-05-24T17:29:39Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Amends the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to repeal provisions establishing and appropriating funds to the Prevention and Public Health Fund (a Fund to provide for expanded and sustained national investment in prevention and public health programs to improve health and help restrain the rate of growth in private and public sector health care costs). Rescinds any unobligated balances appropriated to such Fund.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-57</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
