<bill session="118" type="h" number="4962" updated="2025-11-19T04:14:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">JETSET Costs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JETSET Costs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justification and Examination of Transportation Staff's Executive Travel Costs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the use of Department of Transportation aircraft for travel by the Secretary of Transportation or the Secretary's executive staff, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001301"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2126" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-20T18:03:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Justification and Examination of Transportation Staff's Executive Travel Costs Act of 2023 or the JETSET Costs Act of 2023

This bill restricts the use of Department of Transportation (DOT) aircraft by the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary's executive staff.

Specifically, the bill&#160;prohibits the Secretary and the Secretary's executive staff from traveling on a DOT aircraft unless it is determined that the cost of the flight is at least 5% less than the cost of a flight on a commercial airline. A DOT aircraft is any aircraft owned, operated, or maintained by DOT.

This restriction does not apply when emergency travel is required and commercial service is unavailable. The DOT Office of Inspector General (OIG) and Congress must be notified in writing within seven days after such emergency travel is completed.

Further, the Federal Aviation Administration must revise Order 2500.36N (Application of Flight Hour Rates) to reflect the true cost of flight operations. When calculating per-seat costs of a flight, DOT (1) may not charge different rates to non-DOT officials, and (2) must use the actual and full cost of a flight on a DOT aircraft when comparing such flight to any commercial alternative.

DOT's OIG must submit an annual report to Congress that includes an itemization and justification of each trip and flight in which the Secretary or the Secretary's executive staff traveled on a DOT aircraft.

The bill also prohibits the Secretary or the Secretary's executive staff from traveling on a DOT aircraft for any trip that involves personal or political activities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
