<bill session="111" type="h" number="5172" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:04Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Instructional Leadership Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.) to authorize competitive grants to train school principals in instructional leadership skills and to promote the incorporation of standards of instructional leadership into State-level principal certification or licensure.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Instructional Leadership Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2010-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E700"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-07T18:43:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Instructional Leadership Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states, local educational agencies (LEAs), nonprofit organizations, institutions of higher education, or partnerships or consortia which include at least one of those entities to develop and implement innovative programs and sites (such as leadership development schools) to train school principals in instructional leadership skills.

Requires the Secretary to award additional competitive grants to states or partnerships or consortia which include states for pilot programs that evaluate and promote the incorporation of instructional leadership standards into state principal certification or licensure.

 Directs the Secretary to establish a definition of "highly-qualified principal" that is based on reports from this Act's grantees and emphasizes instructional leadership standards.

Requires the Secretary to award competitive grants to states and high-need LEAs or partnerships between such LEAs and certain educational entities to develop state-of-the-art principal induction programs that provide new principals a minimum of three years of extensive, high-quality, comprehensive induction into the field of school administration.</summary>
</bill>
