<bill session="111" type="h" number="2898" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wounded Warrior Caregiver Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide support services for family caregivers of disabled veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wounded Warrior Caregiver Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001044"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-18">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on Health Prior to Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-20T15:10:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Wounded Warrior Caregiver Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to make interactive training sessions available for family caregivers and individuals who provide such caregivers support (including respite care providers, nursing care providers, and counselors).

Directs the Secretary to provide family caregivers with information concerning public, private, and nonprofit agencies that offer support to such caregivers, including by contracting with a private entity to provide family caregivers with an Internet-based service with: (1) a directory of county level services; (2) message boards and other tools that allow interaction to foster peer support and the creation of support networks; and (3) comprehensive information explaining relevant health-related topics and issues.

Directs the Secretary to conduct outreach to inform disabled veterans and their families of these services.

Makes family caregivers eligible for counseling, training, and mental health services under existing provisions.

Authorizes the Secretary to furnish respite care to a veteran who receives care from a family caregiver under existing provisions.</summary>
</bill>
