<bill session="118" type="s" number="483" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:02Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet PACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet PACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Platform Accountability and Consumer Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require transparency, accountability, and protections for consumers online.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-25T14:53:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Internet Platform Accountability and Consumer Transparency Act or the Internet PACT Act

This bill requires providers of interactive computer services (e.g., social media companies) to publish their policy explaining the types of content that is permissible on the service and provide a system for users to submit complaints about content that may violate the policy or involve illegal content.

Further, providers must establish a process for removing certain content that violates their policies and notifying the information content provider about the removal, including a mechanism to appeal the removal. Providers also must publish a report every six months that details the instances in which the company took action with respect to content, including removing content, deprioritizing content, and suspending content provider accounts. The bill removes certain liability protections for providers if the provider has actual knowledge of illegal content on its service and does not remove the content within specified time frames.

The bill provides for enforcement of these requirements by the Federal Trade Commission.</summary>
</bill>
