<bill session="116" type="s" number="2779" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Luke and Alex School Safety Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Luke and Alex School Safety Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Luke and Alex School Safety Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2020-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2019-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-06">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with amendments. With written report No. 116-193.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-01-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="402">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 402.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5229" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-23T15:54:23Z" status="Reported to Senate">Luke and Alex School Safety Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices for use by state and local educational and law-enforcement agencies, institutions of higher education, health professionals, and the public.

DHS shall, among other things

 collect clearinghouse data analytics, user feedback on the implementation of best practices and recommendations identified by the clearinghouse, and any evaluations conducted on these best practices and recommendations; and coordinate with the Department of Education, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Department of Justice to assess and identify best practices and recommendations and establish an advisory board to provide feedback and propose additional recommendations. The bill specifies the criteria for best practices and recommendations of the clearinghouse, including evidence that the best practice or recommendation has had a significant effect on improving the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings.

The bill provides for grant program review.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-193</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
