<bill session="111" type="s" number="1242" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:38Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Government Ownership Exit Plan Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Federal Government from holding ownership interests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Ownership Exit Plan Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000382" joined="2009-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000560" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2009-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2009-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6533-6534, S6549-6550"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2904" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-04T22:15:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Government Ownership Exit Plan Act of 2009 - Prohibits the federal government from acquiring, directly or indirectly, any ownership interest in a troubled asset described in the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA) that was purchased from a financial institution by the Secretary of the Treasury.

 Requires the Secretary to divest the government of any such interest not later than July 1, 2010, with exceptions allowing ownership interests of not more than six months if: (1) divestiture would have a significant adverse impact on taxpayers; and (2) there is a reasonable expectation that a waiver would allow recovery of the cost of acquiring such interest.

Amends EESA to state that the limit of authority to purchase troubled assets is $700 billion (under current law, such limitation, reduced by $1.259 billion, is described as "outstanding at any one time").

Requires all repayments of obligations arising under EESA, and all proceeds from the sale of assets acquired by the government under that Act, to be paid into the general fund of the Treasury for reduction of the public debt.

Makes it unlawful for an officer or employee of the executive branch to knowingly make, with the intent to influence, a communication regarding a significant management decision of a recipient of EESA assistance to any officer or employee of the recipient.

Makes the Financial Stability Oversight Board responsible for reviewing the ownership interest termination provisions of this Act.

Establishes requirements for reports by the Secretary on: (1) ownership interests; (2) plans for compliance with this Act, including for winding down and divestiture; and (3) ending conservatorship and direct ownership by the government of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac, respectively).</summary>
</bill>
