<bill session="108" type="s" number="2666" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:31Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2005, Legislative Branch</title>
    <title type="popular">Legislative Branch FY2005 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="display">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2005, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-08">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Legislative Branch. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-543.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Campbell. With written report No. 108-307.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="635">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 635.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9423-9426" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>The bill was read the third time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 635.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S9426" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 4755 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>See also H.R. 4755.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSAP08" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Legislative Branch" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4755" relation="related document"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4818" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Air conditioning"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Architect of the Capitol"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Botanical gardens"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Capitol (Washington, D.C.)"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional allowances"/>
    <term name="Congressional chaplains"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Congressional office buildings"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional pages"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="General Accounting Office"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Japanese Americans"/>
    <term name="Joint Economic"/>
    <term name="Joint Taxation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leadership"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Legal research"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative bodies"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Lincoln Administration"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Patriotism"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Physicians' assistants"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Refrigeration"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3667"/>
    <amendment number="s3666"/>
    <amendment number="s3665"/>
    <amendment number="s3664"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-09-30T21:29:48Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2005 - Title I: Legislative Branch Appropriations - Makes FY 2005 appropriations for the Senate for: (1) expense allowances; (2) representation allowances for the Majority and Minority Leaders; (3) salaries of specified officers, employees, and committees (including the Committee on Appropriations); (4) agency contributions for employee benefits; (5) inquiries and investigations; (6) the U.S. Senate Caucus on International Narcotics Control; (7) the Offices of the Secretary and of the Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper (Sergeant at Arms) of the Senate; (8) miscellaneous items; (9) the Senators' Official Personnel and Office Expense Account; and (10) official mail costs.

 (Sec. 2) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1977 to increase from eight to nine the number of individual consultants the Majority and Minority Leaders may each appoint. (Sec. 3) Amends Public Law 101-302 to extend through FY 2005 and each fiscal year thereafter the authorization of funds within the Senate contingent fund for expenses of the U.S. Senate Collection. (Sec. 4) Amends the Legislative Appropriations Act, 2003 to extend the Office of the President Pro Tempore Emeritus of the Senate into the 109th Congress. (Sec. 6) Amends the Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1987 to repeal the requirement that the Secretary of the Senate first receive approval of the Senate Appropriations Committee before transferring to the general expense allowance account certain funds made available for activities concerning foreign parliamentary groups or other visiting foreign officials. Requires only notice to such Committee. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the payment of reasonable expenses in connection with sending or transporting official records and papers of a Senator from the District of Columbia to the Senator's State. Requires the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate to provide for the most economical means of sending or transporting such items. (Sec. 8) Authorizes the Sergeant at Arms of the Senate to retain funds received as compensation for damage to, loss of, or loss of use of property of the Sergeant of Arms. (Sec. 9) Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1970 to increase the minimum age of Senate pages from 14 to 16. (Sec. 10) States that the Office of the Sergeant of Arms of the Senate and any officer, employee, or agent of the Office shall not be treated as acquiring possession, custody, or control of electronic mail or other electronic communication, data, or information by reason of its being transmitted, processed, or stored (temporarily or otherwise) through the use of an electronic system established, maintained, or operated, or the use of electronic services provided, in whole or in part by the Office. Makes FY 2005 appropriations for salaries and/or expenses of: (1) the Joint Economic and Taxation Committees; (2) the Office of the Attending Physician; (3) the Capitol Guide Service and Special Services Office; (4) the preparation of statements of appropriations for both the House and the Senate; and (5) the Capitol Police.

(Sec. 1002) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2004 to: (1) authorize the Chief of the Capitol Police to hire individuals as Capitol Police officers for detail to the Library of Congress other than those submitted for hiring by the Librarian of Congress; (2) establish FY 2005 limits on the number of Capitol Police officers to be hired for Library of Congress duty; and (3) authorize the Chief to detail such individuals on a nonreimbursable basis.

 (Sec. 1003) Requires any amounts received by the Capitol Police as compensation for damage to, loss of, or loss of use of property of the Capitol Police to be credited the Capitol Police general expenses account.

(Sec. 1004) Requires the Office of Personnel Management to provide for the participation of Capitol Police employees in the voluntary transfer of leave with employees of other agencies.

(Sec. 1005) Amends the Revised Statutes to: (1) give the Capitol Police Board (currently, the Sergeants at Arms of the House and of the Senate) authority for selecting Capitol Police uniforms; and (2) authorize Capitol Police officers to carry weapons not purchased with Capitol Police appropriations, both on and off Capitol grounds, as authorized by the Board.

(Sec. 1006) Authorizes the release of security information in the possession of the Capitol Police to other entities only if the Capitol Police Board has determined that such release will not compromise the security and safety of the Capitol building and grounds or any individuals whose protection and safety is under Capitol Police jurisdiction.

(Sec. 1007) Authorizes the Capitol Police to accept donations of animals for use in its canine or equine units.

(Sec. 1008) Authorizes the Chief of the Capitol Police to settle and pay claims for damages under the Federal Tort Claims Act (FTCA) and the Military Personnel and Civilian Employees' Claims Act; except that the Chairman of the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration must approve any proposed resolution of FTCA claims within the jurisdiction of the Senate.

(Sec. 1009) Authorizes the Capitol Police, subject to Board approval, to travel with and assist overseas congressional delegations in a security advisory and liaison role, including advance security liaison preparations for such travel.

Makes FY 2005 appropriations for: (1) salaries and/or expenses of the Office of Compliance; (2) the Congressional Budget Office; (3) the Architect of the Capitol, including for the care and operation of Capitol buildings and grounds, Senate office buildings, the Capitol power plant, Library of Congress buildings and grounds, Capitol Police buildings and grounds, the Botanic Garden (but not for construction of the National Garden); and (4) the Library of Congress for salaries and expenses, the Copyright Office, Congressional Research Service, and Books for the Blind and Physically Handicapped.

(Sec. 1102) Increases (from the FY 2004 level) the obligational authority of the Library for FY 2005 for reimbursable and revolving fund activities funded from sources other than appropriations.

(Sec. 1103) Amends the Miscellaneous Appropriations Act, 2001 to extend to March 31, 2010, the availability of funds for the National Digital Information Infrastructure and Preservation Program. (Sec. 1104) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act for payment of fees charged by the Department of State for the construction of U.S. diplomatic facilities. (Sec. 1105) Extends through FY 2005 authorizations for the National Film Preservation Board and the National Film Preservation Foundation. Makes FY 2005 appropriations to the Government Printing Office (GPO) for: (1) congressional printing and binding (including transfer of funds); (2) the Office of Superintendent of Documents for salaries and expenses (including transfer of funds); and (3) the GPO revolving fund. (Sec. 1301) Authorizes the Superintendent of Documents to determine discounts for sales copies of GPO publications. Makes FY 2005 appropriations for the Government Accountability Office for salaries and expenses. (Sec. 1401) Requires heads of executive agencies and the Mayor of the District of Columbia to transmit to the Comptroller General, on the same date that such reports are transmitted to the President and Congress, copies of reports of violations of specified Federal laws limiting obligations, expenditures, and voluntary activities of officers and employees of those agencies or the District. Makes FY 2005 appropriations for a payment to the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund. Title II: General Provisions - Sets forth authorized or prohibited uses of funds appropriated by this Act identical or similar to corresponding provisions of the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2004. (Sec. 208) Makes legislative branch agency compliance with the General Services Administration's Governmentwide eTravel Service program discretionary, to be determined by each agency head.

(Sec. 209) Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2003 to remove the limitation to 100 percent of donated funds currently placed on appropriations to provide congressional recognition for excellence in arts education under the Congressional Award Act.

(Sec. 210) Transfers jurisdiction over certain parcels of Federal real property near the Japanese American Patriotism Memorial to the Architect of the Capitol, without consideration.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-307</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
