<bill session="118" type="h" number="4197" updated="2025-11-19T02:58:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to reauthorize the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2023-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2024-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="202" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-16T00:27:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program Reauthorization Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes and expands the Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration program, which helps fund collaborative and community-based forest management.

To be eligible for support, a collaborative forest landscape restoration proposal must describe plans to prevent, remediate, or control invasions of pathogens.

For each proposal nominated for selection by a Forest Service regional office, the office must provide a federal government staffing plan for providing support to collaboratives.

In selecting proposals, the Department of Agriculture must give special consideration to proposals that seek to

 use innovative implementation mechanisms, including conservation finance agreements and good neighbor agreements; reduce the risk of uncharacteristic wildfire or increase ecological restoration activities within areas across land ownerships and within the wildland-urban interface; and enhance watershed health and drinking water sources. The bill increases the number of proposals that may be funded during any fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
