<bill session="117" type="h" number="3388" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Critical Infrastructure Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to increase penalties for certain computer fraud and related offenses that involve critical infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Critical Infrastructure Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000246"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2021-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-12T16:02:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Critical Infrastructure Act of 2021

This bill increases federal criminal penalties for computer fraud and abuse offenses that involve critical infrastructure. The term critical infrastructure means systems and assets, physical or virtual, so vital to the United States that the incapacity or destruction of such systems and assets would have a debilitating impact on security, national economic security, national public health and safety, or any combination of those matters.

Specifically, the bill imposes a fine, a mandatory minimum prison term of 30 years, or both for a computer fraud or abuse offense that involves critical infrastructure.

Additionally, the bill directs the President to impose asset- and visa-blocking sanctions on foreign individuals and entities that access or attempt to access critical infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
