<bill session="119" type="h" number="3352" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:19Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-23T16:28:46-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-23T16:28:46-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HALOS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">HALOS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">HALOS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">HALOS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise rules relating to general solicitation or general advertising to allow for presentations or other communication made by or on behalf of an issuer at certain events, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">HALOS Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2025-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2025-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 50 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 119-123.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-06-03" calendar="Union" number="93">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 93.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T16:18:32-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Wagner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T16:18:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2866-2868" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T16:18:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3352.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-06-23T16:28:46-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2866-2867" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-06-23T16:28:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-23T16:50:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Angels Lead Our Startups Act of 2025 or the HALOS Act of 2025

This bill directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to exempt presentations and communications (e.g., product demonstrations) made at certain events from advertising and solicitation restrictions under Regulation D. (Regulation D exempts certain securities offerings from SEC registration requirements but prohibits general solicitation or general advertising with respect to such offerings.)

Under the bill, this prohibition does not apply to events where presentations or communications are made by or on behalf of an issuer, if

the advertising does not refer to any specific offering of securities by the issuer;the event sponsor does not provide investment recommendations or advice to attendees, engage in investment negotiations with attendees, charge certain fees, or receive certain compensation; andno specific information regarding a securities offering is communicated beyond&#160;the type and amount of securities being offered, the unsubscribed amount, and the intended use of proceeds from the offering.Exempt events must involve participation by more than one issuer and must be sponsored by specified entity types, including angel investor groups unconnected to broker dealers or investment advisors. Such events generally may not be held in facilities owned or operated by a religious organization. If such an event is virtual, online participation must be limited to investors associated with the sponsor organization, accredited investors, or individuals invited to the event based on industry or investment experience.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-123</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
