<bill session="118" type="s" number="1348" updated="2025-11-12T00:19:07Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-20">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wyoming Public Lands Initiative Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wyoming Public Lands Initiative Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wyoming Public Lands Initiative Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Wyoming Public Lands Initiative Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to redesignate land within certain wilderness study areas in the State of Wyoming, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-311.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-185.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="422">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 422.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7288-7297" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7288-7292" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:12:05-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4332" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-28T15:09:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wyoming Public Lands Initiative Act of 2023

This bill designates specified wilderness study areas, special management areas, a National Conservation Area, and other areas in Wyoming.

The bill designates the following areas as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System:

 certain land within the Encampment River Canyon Wilderness Study Area, to be known as the Encampment River Canyon Wilderness; certain land within the Prospect Mountain Wilderness Study Area, to be known as the Prospect Mountain Wilderness; certain land within the Sweetwater Canyon Wilderness Study Area, to be known as the Upper Sweetwater Canyon Wilderness and the Lower Sweetwater Canyon Wilderness; and certain land within the Bobcat Draw Wilderness Study Area, to be known as the Bobcat Draw Wilderness. The bill designates the following special management areas:

 Bennett Mountains, Black Cat, Sweetwater Rocks, and Cedar Mountain. The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) shall divide the land within the Dubois Badlands Wilderness Study Area into the Dubois Motorized Recreation Area and the Dubois Badlands National Conservation Area, separating the two with a fence.

The bill designates Fortification Creek, Fraker Mountain, and North Fork as management areas.

The proposed BLM rule titled Conservation and Landscape Health or any substantially similar rule shall not apply to the land covered by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-185</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
