<bill session="118" type="s" number="538" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FORCE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Oppression until the Reign of Castro Ends Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FORCE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the removal of Cuba from the list of state sponsors of terrorism until Cuba satisfies certain conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="314" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T17:14:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fighting Oppression until the Reign of Castro Ends Act or the FORCE Act

This bill imposes various prohibitions and requirements related to Cuba.

Specifically, the bill&#160;prohibits removing Cuba from the list of state sponsors of terrorism until the President determines that a transition government in Cuba is in power.

Furthermore, persons (individuals or entities) subject to U.S. jurisdiction may not engage in certain direct financial transactions with an entity under the control of or acting on behalf of the Cuban military, intelligence, or security services or personnel. Specifically, such a transaction is prohibited if it would disproportionately benefit the Cuban military, intelligence, or security services or personnel at the expense of the Cuban people or private enterprise in Cuba.

The Department of State must publish and annually update a list of the Cuban entities that are subject to these transaction restrictions.

The prohibition on financial transactions shall terminate 90 days after the President certifies that Cuba's government has (1) taken the steps necessary to begin transparent, free, and fair elections; and (2) met the requirements to allow for the termination of U.S. economic embargo on Cuba.

The bill also requires the State Department to notify Congress of any U.S. engagement with Cuba no later than 14 days after such engagement.</summary>
</bill>
