<bill session="117" type="h" number="7858" updated="2023-08-22T15:30:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Platform Commission Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Platform Commission Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a new Federal body to provide reasonable oversight and regulation of digital platforms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T15:27:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Platform Commission Act of 2022

This bill establishes a commission to regulate digital platforms. These are online services that facilitate interactions between users and between users and entities (including online services) that offer goods and services.

The bill provides the commission with rulemaking, investigative, and related authorities to regulate access to, competition among, and consumer protections for digital platforms. The bill also provides for administrative and judicial enforcement of the regulations.

The commission must establish a council of technical experts, representatives of digital platforms, and other experts (e.g., representatives of nonprofit public interest groups and academics) to recommend standards for algorithmic processes and other policies.

Additionally, the commission may designate systemically important digital platforms. The bill includes criteria for the commission to use when designating a platform as systemically important (e.g., whether its operations have significant nationwide economic, social, or political impacts).

The President must appoint an independent panel to evaluate the commission after five years and recommend whether to extend the commission.</summary>
</bill>
