<bill session="111" type="s" number="3072" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:14Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stationary Source Regulations Delay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to suspend, during the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, any Environmental Protection Agency action under the Clean Air Act with respect to carbon dioxide or methane pursuant to certain proceedings, other than with respect to motor vehicle emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stationary Source Regulations Delay Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000705" joined="2010-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2010-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2010-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2010-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000803" joined="2010-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4753" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-03T19:26:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stationary Source Regulations Delay Act - Prohibits the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), during the two-year period beginning after this Act's enactment, from taking any action under the Clean Air Act (CAA) with respect to any stationary source permitting requirement or requirement concerning standards of performance for new stationary sources relating to carbon dioxide or methane. Exempts from such prohibition: (1) any action under the CAA relating to the vehicle emissions standards contained in Docket No. EPA-HQ-OAR-2009-0171 or Docket No. EPA-HQ-OAR-2009-0472; (2) any action relating to the preparation of a report or the enforcement of a reporting requirement; or (3) any action relating to the provision of technical support at a state's request.

Provides that no action taken by the Administrator before the end of such period shall be considered to make carbon dioxide or methane a pollutant subject to regulation under the CAA for any source other than a new motor vehicle or new motor vehicle engine.</summary>
</bill>
