<bill session="116" type="h" number="2375" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:08Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics and Biosimilars Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit prescription drug companies from compensating other prescription drug companies to delay the entry of a generic drug, biosimilar biological product, or interchangeable biological product into the market.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics and Biosimilars Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics and Biosimilars Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2019-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001187" joined="2019-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-24">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-693, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Commerce discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-24" calendar="Union" number="576">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 576.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="64" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1344" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-01T19:17:39Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">Preserve Access to Affordable Generics and Biosimilars Act

This bill authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to initiate proceedings against parties to any agreement resolving or settling a patent infringement claim in connection with the sale of a drug or biological product. Such an agreement is presumed to have anticompetitive effects and is a violation of this bill if the filer of the generic drug or biosimilar application receives anything of value and agrees to limit or forego research, development, manufacturing, marketing, or sales of the generic drug or biosimilar. An agreement is exempted if the only consideration granted to the generic manufacturer is (1) the right to market its product prior to the expiration of any statutory exclusivity, (2) a payment for reasonable litigation expenses, or (3) a covenant not to sue on any claim that the generic drug or biosimilar infringes a patent. An agreement is also exempt if the agreement's pro-competitive benefits outweigh the anticompetitive effects.

 When a generic or biosimilar drug manufacturer enters into an agreement with another drug manufacturer related to the manufacturing, marketing, or sale of a drug, the manufacturers must certify that the material they have given the FTC concerning the agreement contains the complete agreement and any agreements related to that main agreement, including descriptions of any oral agreements or representations.

The bill imposes penalties for violations of this bill, including the forfeiture of the 180-day marketing exclusivity period for a generic drug.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-693</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
