<bill session="117" type="h" number="9003" updated="2023-09-12T17:30:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Empowering States to Deport Illegal Immigrants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering States to Deport Illegal Immigrants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To allow States to authorize State and local law enforcement officers to enforce the provisions of Federal immigration law relating to unlawful entry into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000565"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4948" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T17:20:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering States to Deport Illegal Immigrants Act

This bill authorizes states to take actions to enforce federal immigration law.

Specifically, the bill authorizes states to authorize state and local law enforcement to enforce certain provisions of federal immigration law, including provisions relating to unlawful entry and employing unauthorized non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law). State prosecutors&#160;must prosecute every case brought by a state under this bill.

The bill also abrogates a 2012 Supreme Court ruling that invalidated an Arizona law that made it a crime for unauthorized non-U.S. nationals to work in the state. Specifically, the court ruled that the Arizona law was preempted by federal immigration law.</summary>
</bill>
