<bill session="116" type="h" number="7938" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:30Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">USIA for Strategic Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Information Abroad for Strategic Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USIA for Strategic Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve and coordinate United States information statecraft strategy and capabilities for an era of strategic competition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2020-08-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-04T18:39:53Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Information Abroad for Strategic Competition Act or the USIA for Strategic Competition Act

This bill establishes measures to advance U.S. messaging and interests globally, including by requiring the Department of State to reconstitute for five years the Active Measures Working Group to create an information statecraft strategy for the U.S. government.

The purpose of the strategy shall be to reduce the ability of the Communist Party of China (CCP) to influence global discourse, and such strategy shall include an identification of (1) specific CCP narratives that contribute to its ability to influence global discourse, (2) counter-narratives that are most effective and most likely to reduce the ability of the CCP to influence global discourse, and (3) specific quantitative objectives for advancing such counter-narratives.

The State Department must also conduct regular research and evaluation of its public diplomacy programs and activities and ensure that such research and evaluation support strategic planning and resource allocation across all diplomacy bureaus and offices of the State Department.

Further, the bill makes permanent the U.S. Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy, revises the rating criteria used by the commission when evaluating certain public diplomacy and international broadcasting activities, and requires the commission to establish a Subcommittee on Research and Evaluation.</summary>
</bill>
