<bill session="117" type="h" number="3587" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Effective Consultation with Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prescribe procedures for effective consultation and coordination by Federal agencies with federally recognized Tribal Governments regarding Federal Government actions that impact Tribal lands and interests to ensure that meaningful Tribal input is an integral part of the Federal decision-making process.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Effective Consultation with Tribes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESPECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2021-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000273" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2021-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000172" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000619" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2022-04-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States Prior to Introduction and Referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-14T01:02:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Requirements, Expectations, and Standard Procedures for Effective Consultation with Tribes Act or the RESPECT Act

This bill establishes tribal consultation procedures for federal agencies.

Specifically, the bill requires federal agencies to consult with tribal governments (1) before undertaking any proposed federal activity or finalizing any federal regulatory action that may have a tribal impact, and (2) for all activities that would affect any part of federal land sharing a border with Indian land. Tribal impact refers to any federal action that may have an impact on tribal governments, including tribal cultural practices and tribal treaty-protected rights.

Agencies must prepare tribal impact statements to identify potential tribal impacts of a proposed activity or action. Agencies must also make a good faith effort to identify areas that contain sacred sites important to tribal governments.

The bill further outlines consultation requirements, including outreach and meeting arrangements. In general, the consultation shall conclude only upon the execution of a memorandum of agreement between the agency and the tribal government or the members of a designated tribal leader task force.

Next, the bill requires agencies to take certain actions during the decision stage for a proposed activity (e.g., public comment) and for a regulatory action.

Agencies must recognize and respect tribal self-government and sovereignty and grant tribal governments maximum discretion in the administration of federal statutes and regulations.

Tribal governments may seek judicial review of a determination of an agency under this bill if the tribal government has exhausted all other administrative remedies.</summary>
</bill>
