<bill session="117" type="h" number="2112" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Workforce Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to award funds to States to promote the skill acquisition, employment, and retention of individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Workforce Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2021-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-15T15:04:59Z" status="Introduced in House">American Workforce Recovery Act

This bill directs the Department of Labor to provide funding to states and local areas to expand their employment training programs for employed and unemployed individuals, displaced workers, and to meet particular employment needs of employers.

Specifically, the bill gives states funding to broaden training options such as remote or virtual for employees and employers by eligible providers of training services.

The bill also grants funds to local areas to establish a Pandemic Reskilling Fund for dislocated workers participating in specified training services and career services for adults and dislocated workers.

Local areas may also establish individual training accounts to support on-the-job training and supportive services.

These individual training accounts must pay for training provided by eligible entities. Any remaining funds in an individual's account may be paid in cash to the individual if such individual obtains full-time, unsubsidized employment within six weeks after completion of the training and has been so employed for six weeks. An individual who fails to meet these requirements must return such funds to the local government for redistribution.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate and report to Congress on (1) the flexibility provided through the individual training accounts; and (2) the overall effectiveness of the funds provided under this bill to promote the skill acquisition, employment, and retention of the individuals who were assisted with such funds, including individuals with barriers to employment.</summary>
</bill>
