<bill session="118" type="h" number="4866" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-29T19:02:22-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-29T19:02:22-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fire Weather Development Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fire Weather Development Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire Weather Development Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Fire Weather Development Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Fire Weather Development Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish a program to improve fire weather and fire environment forecasting, detection, and local collaboration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To direct the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administrator to improve fire weather and fire environment forecasting, detection, and local collaboration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-22">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 118-214.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-09-22" calendar="Union" number="174">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 174.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T16:17:12-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T16:17:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2646-2651" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T16:17:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4866.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T16:36:08-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T18:31:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2687-2688" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="153" datetime="2024-04-29T19:02:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 341 - 48 (Roll no. 153).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2646-2649" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T19:02:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29T19:02:28-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="369" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-06T19:45:39Z" status="Passed House">Fire Weather Development Act of 2024

This bill establishes several programs and requirements to address wildfire forecasting, detection, and management, particularly with respect to interagency collaboration.

For example, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must establish a program to improve collaboration between federal, state, and local entities with respect to wildfire management. Program goals include improving communication about wildfire spread, earlier detection of wildfires, and better understanding of the impact of climate change on fire weather environments. Authorized activities include research and development of communication tools, modeling systems, and other relevant technology to help with wildfire management, as well as education and training for researchers and enhancing data sharing capabilities between agencies.

NOAA may also (1) contract with private sector entities to obtain additional airborne and space-based data to support wildfire prediction and monitoring, and (2) conduct pilot programs to test the use of unmanned aircraft systems for fire weather observations.

The bill also establishes the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Wildfires (to assist state and local agencies with wildfire management while avoiding duplication of activities) and the National Advisory Committee on Wildfires (to advise the coordinating committee and other relevant entities on wildfire management).

Finally, the bill exempts incident meteorologists of the National Weather Service from premium pay limitations when responding to emergency wildfires. It also requires the National Institute of Standards and Technology to recommend ways to improve the standards of&#160;communication between wildfire first responders and fire management response officials.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-214</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
