<bill session="119" type="s" number="1508" updated="2025-11-18T19:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shivwits Band of Paiutes Jurisdictional Clarity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shivwits Band of Paiutes Jurisdictional Clarity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to confer jurisdiction on the State of Utah with respect to civil causes of action arising on or within the Indian lands of the Shivwits Band of Paiutes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3073" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-12T15:38:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shivwits Band of Paiutes Jurisdictional Clarity Act

This bill confers legal jurisdiction to the State of Utah over certain civil cases involving the Shivwits Band of Paiutes. It also allows the tribe to lease its land held in trust. The tribe is located in southwestern Utah.

Specifically, the bill confers jurisdiction to the State of Utah&#160;over any civil cause of action (1) to which the&#160;Shivwits Band of Paiutes is a party, and (2) that arises on or within Indian lands. Under the bill, Indian lands are lands of the tribe that are (1) held in trust for the benefit of the tribe, or (2) subject to restrictions by the United States against alienation (i.e., sale or transfer).

Additionally, the bill specifies that any cause of action arising from any contract or agreement (including a lease) to which the tribe is party or that affects or arises on these Indian lands shall be deemed a civil cause of action. Therefore, this bill allows the tribe and third parties to resolve contract disputes in state court.

The bill also authorizes the tribe to lease its land held in trust for a term of up to 99 years.</summary>
</bill>
