<bill session="118" type="h" number="2461" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">San Juan Southern Paiute Tribal Homelands Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Juan Southern Paiute Tribal Homelands Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ratify a Treaty between the San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe and the Navajo Nation, to provide for the creation of a reservation for the San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001132"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001133" joined="2023-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2023-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2023-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian and Insular Affairs .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-02T16:48:04Z" status="Introduced in House">San Juan Southern Paiute Tribal Homelands Act of 2023

This bill approves, ratifies, and confirms a specified treaty entered into by the Navajo Nation and the San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe, thus settling land claims and other disputes. (The San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe is a federally recognized tribe occupying lands within the Navajo Indian Reservation. In 2000, the tribes entered into a treaty to set aside lands for the exclusive use of the San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe and to address other matters. This treaty requires ratification and approval by Congress.)

The bill directs the Department of the Interior to approve, execute, and implement the treaty. Further, the bill delegates authority to Interior to approve amendments to the treaty without further action by Congress.

Additionally, the bill proclaims approximately 5,400 acres of land within the Navajo Indian Reservation (described in the treaty as the San Juan Paiute Northern Area and the San Juan Paiute Southern Area) as the San Juan Southern Paiute Reservation. These lands shall be held in trust as a reservation for the exclusive benefit of the San Juan Southern Paiute Tribe. Interior must survey, mark, and fence lands to establish the boundaries of the reservation.

The transfer of these lands shall also include the transfer of associated water rights, which shall be held in trust for the benefit of the tribe. The bill also outlines water rights associated with the San Juan Paiute Northern Area and the San Juan Paiute Southern Area.</summary>
</bill>
