<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="3106" updated="2021-08-12T21:11:51Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="14" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-08-10">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-08-10"/>
  <description>To protect owners of generationally-owned businesses, farms, and ranches so that they may continue to transfer ownership or operations to family members or others based upon the same tax principles that existed when they began operations and under which they currently operate, including the full benefit of the step-up in basis.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-08-10" how="roll" result="pass" roll="318">
      <text>Amendment SA 3106 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 318.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Amendment SA 3106 proposed by Senator Thune. (consideration: CR S6208-6209; text: CR S6209) To protect owners of generationally-owned businesses, farms, and ranches so that they may continue to transfer ownership or operations to family members or others based upon the same tax principles that existed when they began operations and under which they currently operate, including the full benefit of the step-up in basis.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10"/>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3106 proposed by Senator Thune.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6208-6209" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6209" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3106 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 318.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3106 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 99 - 0. Record Vote Number: 318.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
