<bill session="108" type="h" number="4899" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sustainable Drug Pricing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require agreements regarding the wholesale price of brand-name prescription drugs as a condition of the allowance of certain tax deductions and credits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sustainable Drug Pricing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2004-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Drug advertising"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-20T15:34:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Sustainable Drug Pricing Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into agreements with the manufacturers of brand name prescription drugs for four-year terms to establish a maximum wholesale price for such drugs. Defines brand name prescription drugs as FDA-approved prescription drugs with market exclusivity. Requires such agreements to specify a liquidated penalty that is sufficient to deter violations for failure to maintain substantial compliance. Allows the Secretary to notify the Secretary of the Treasury that there is no longer an effective agreement in place if such a penalty is not paid. Requires the Secretary to monitor prices to ensure compliance. Allows the Secretary to require manufacturers entering into such agreements to cooperate with such monitoring and to allow the Secretary access to relevant financial records.

Requires the Secretary to establish the Advisory Panel on Drug-Price Negotiations to advise the Secretary on establishing prices. Requires the Panel to provide the Secretary with recommended drug prices for 25 drugs that the Panel considers important to the public health and for an additional 25 drugs that are the most commonly prescribed drugs in the United States.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to disallow: (1) a deduction for advertising, promotion, or marketing of brand name prescription drugs without a qualified pricing agreement in effect for the entire taxable year; and (2) a foreign tax credit for such drugs manufactured by the taxpayer without a qualified pricing agreement in effect for the entire taxable year.</summary>
</bill>
