<bill session="108" type="h" number="4103" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:38Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend and modify the trade benefits under the African Growth and Opportunity Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001241" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000873" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000549" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000814" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000948" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000070" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2004-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000293" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000388" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000477" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000015" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000033" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000303" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2004-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000273" joined="2004-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 108-501.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-19" calendar="Union" number="285">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 285.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14T14:27:48-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thomas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14T14:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3884-3891" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14T14:28:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4103.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-06-14T15:00:46-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3884-3887" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-14T15:00:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-06-24" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/25/2004 S7496" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-07-01">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-07-13" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-274" type="public" datetime="2004-07-13">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-274.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2529" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Chambers of commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Diversification in industry"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic integration"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecotourism"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Handicraft"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-14T20:15:15Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on May 19, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004 - (Sec. 4) Declares the sense of Congress that the preferential market access opportunities for eligible sub-Saharan African countries (SSA countries) will be complemented and enhanced if those countries implement specified existing obligations under the World Trade Organization (WTO). Urges such countries to participate in and support mutual trade liberalization in ongoing negotiations under WTO auspices, recognizing that such commitments may need to reflect special and differential treatment for developing countries. States that eligible SSA countries will benefit from reduction of trade barriers in other developing countries. Urges all countries to make sanitary and phytosanitary decisions on the basis of sound science.

(Sec. 5) Expresses the sense of Congress that the executive branch, including specified Federal agencies, should enforce African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) provisions relating to preferential treatment of textile and apparel articles broadly in order to expand trade by maximizing opportunities for imports of such articles from eligible SSA countries.

(Sec. 7) Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to extend duty-free treatment for AGOA articles through FY 2015.

Modifies AGOA rules of origin to add to the inputs calculation for duty-free treatment former beneficiary SSA countries (defined as former SSA countries whose designation ceased by reason of entering into a free trade agreement with the United States).

Authorizes preferential treatment under the AGOA for apparel articles made from regional fabrics or yarns even if they include U.S. components. Extends preferential treatment for such articles and establishes applicable percentages for benefits.

Identifies as eligible for preferential treatment apparel made from fabrics or yarns listed in Annex 401 of the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) without regard to the origin of the fabrics or yarns. (Currently, such fabrics or yarns must be manufactured in the United States or in a beneficiary SSA country.)

Authorizes preferential treatment for ethnic printed fabric of an SSA country that meets certain conditions.

States that apparel articles eligible for preferential treatment under the AGOA may continue to use inputs from former SSA countries who have since entered into free trade agreements with the United States.

Sets forth special rules for the use of specified components in apparel products eligible for preferential treatment under the AGOA.

Raises from seven to ten percent of total article weight the de minimis level of permissible non-AGOA fibers or yarns in articles otherwise qualifying for preferential treatment under the AGOA.

(Sec. 8) Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, under specified conditions, to liquidate or reliquidate as free of duty and free of any quantitative restrictions, limitations, or consultative levels any entries of knit-to-shape apparel meeting AGOA requirements, retroactive to October 1, 2000.

(Sec. 9) Requires the President to study each eligible SSA country and: (1) identify sectors of its economy with the greatest potential for growth, including through export sales; (2) identify both domestic and international barriers impeding such growth; (3) make recommendations on how the Federal Government and the private sector can provide technical assistance to dismantle such barriers and promote investment in such sectors; and (4) disseminate information to appropriate Federal agencies on each such country.

(Sec. 10) Requires the President to develop and implement policies to encourage: (1) infrastructure projects to increase trade capacity and sustainable ecotourism in SSA countries; (2) transboundary cooperation among such countries to facilitate trade; (3) the provision of technical assistance to such countries to establish and sustain adequate trade capacity development; and (4) micro-, small-, and medium-sized enterprises in such countries to participate in ecotourism.

(Sec. 11) Requires the President to develop and implement policies to encourage the development of investment in SSA countries, particularly in: (1) infrastructure projects supporting development of land transport road and railroad networks and ports, and the continued upgrading and liberalization of the energy and telecommunications sectors; (2) establishment and expansion of modern information and communication technologies and practices to improve the ability of citizens to research and disseminate specified information; and (3) agriculture, particularly in processing and capacity enhancement.

(Sec. 12) Requires the President to foster improved port-to-port and airport-to-airport relationships in order to facilitate and increase trade flows between eligible SSA countries.

(Sec. 13) Requires the President to: (1) identify at least ten eligible SSA countries as having the greatest potential to increase marketable exports of agricultural products to the United States and the greatest need for technical assistance, particularly with respect to pest risk assessments and complying with U.S. sanitary and phytosanitary rules; and (2) assign at least 20 full-time personnel to provide assistance to such countries to ensure that their exports of agricultural products meet Federal law requirements.

(Sec. 14) Requires the President to convene the trade advisory committee on Africa established by Executive Order 11846 of March 27, 1975, under the Trade Act of 1974.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-501</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
