<bill session="118" type="h" number="4229" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Balloon Location and Identification Pronouncement Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balloon Location and Identification Pronouncement Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to conduct a study and submit a report on the effects of unmanned free balloons on aviation safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2023-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-15T12:58:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Balloon Location and Identification Pronouncement Study Act or the BLIPS Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to study the effects on aviation safety of domestically launched unmanned free balloons that do not emit a trackable electronic or radio signal.

DOD and the FAA must submit a report to Congress on the study. The report must include a discussion and recommendations on

 the efficacy, feasibility, technical specifications, and potential civil and military impacts of mandating that domestically launched unmanned free balloons be equipped with an electronic or radio emitter that can be tracked with near real-time, geolocational, and altitudinal precision, and which can transmit identifying information of the balloon or its owner; and how DOD and the FAA can collect the data and integrate it into a real-time or near real-time digital system that supports the operations of DOD and the FAA.</summary>
</bill>
