<bill session="119" type="s" number="582" updated="2025-11-05T12:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Astronaut Ground Travel Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Astronaut Ground Travel Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Astronaut Ground Travel Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the authorized use of Federal vehicle transportation by certain astronauts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2025-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cruz without amendment. With written report No. 119-82.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="193">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 193.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-10-29">
      <text>Star Print ordered on report 119-82.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="933" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-30T18:08:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Astronaut Ground Travel Support Act

This bill permits the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to use government-owned passenger vehicles to transport astronauts and other space flight participants to and from post-mission medical research and treatment activities. (After returning to earth, astronauts generally undergo a post-mission medical recovery program and may be prohibited from driving motor vehicles for varying periods of time.)&#160;

Under the bill, transportation may be provided to necessary post-mission activities including medical research and the monitoring, diagnosis, and treatment of an astronaut or space flight participant before they receive post-mission clearance to operate a motor vehicle. Only astronauts employed by the U.S. government, certain international partner astronauts, and other individuals carried in launch or reentry vehicles are eligible for transportation.&#160;

The bill also permits NASA to maintain, operate, and repair one or more passenger vehicles, including motor vehicles, aircraft, and other means of transportation, for the purpose of providing such post-mission transportation.&#160;

The cost of transporting international partner astronauts and space flight participants not employed by the U.S. government must be reimbursed to the Department of the Treasury.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-82</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
