<bill session="108" type="s" number="1029" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:21Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Israeli-Palestinian Peace Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance peace between the Israelis and Palestinians.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Israeli-Palestinian Peace Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5952-5953" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-19T14:54:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Israeli-Palestinian Peace Enhancement Act of 2003 - Calls for: (1) the Palestinian administration to take security related steps to implement a performance based road map to resolve the Israeli-Palestinian conflict; and (2) the U.S. administration to work toward the two states living in peace within secure and internationally recognized boundaries.

 Expresses the sense of Congress that a Palestinian state should not be recognized until the President makes specified determinations, including that new leadership of a Palestinian governing entity, not compromised by terrorism, has been elected and has taken appropriate measures to counter terrorism and terrorist financing in the West Bank and Gaza.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act to allow U.S. assistance to be provided to a Palestinian state only: (1) during the effective period of a presidential certification that a binding international peace agreement exists between Israel and the Palestinians and that the new Palestinian government has been democratically elected, has renounced violence against Israel, has dismantled any group that conducts terrorism against Israel, is demilitarized, and has no agreements that threaten Israel's security; and (2) if the President has provided advance notice to Congress.

Authorizes the President to provide assistance to a Palestinian state to support activities to substantially improve the economy and living conditions of the Palestinians.

Directs the Secretary of State to seek to convene donors conferences to gain commitments from other countries, multilateral institutions, and non-governmental organizations to provide economic assistance to Palestinians.</summary>
</bill>
