<bill session="119" type="h" number="737" updated="2025-06-13T18:07:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Extraordinary Measures Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Extraordinary Measures Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to issue reports with respect to extraordinary measures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-02T16:40:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Extraordinary Measures Transparency Act

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to report to Congress regarding extraordinary measures used to avoid exceeding the federal debt limit.

(The term extraordinary measures refers to a series of actions that Treasury may implement to allow the United States to borrow additional funds without exceeding the debt limit. The measures often include suspensions of debt sales and suspensions or redemptions of investments in certain government funds.)

If Treasury determines that the public debt will reach the limit in 30 days, Treasury must submit a report to Congress that includes

a description of the extraordinary measures that Treasury intends to use if the debt limit is not raised,an estimate of the cost of the measures,a projection of how long the measures will fund the federal government, anda projection of the administrative cost of taking the measures.Treasury must also submit specified daily reports to Congress when the measures are being used. After using the measures, Treasury must report to Congress regarding the measures that were used and the administrative cost of the measures.</summary>
</bill>
