<bill session="117" type="s" number="4157" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LEAD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEAD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lead Endangers Animals Daily Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, to promulgate regulations prohibiting the use of lead ammunition on all land and water under the jurisdiction and control of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and other for purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="405" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T15:41:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lead Endangers Animals Daily Act of 2022 or the LEAD Act of 2022

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to promulgate final regulations prohibiting the discharge of a firearm using ammunition other than nonlead ammunition included on the list established pursuant to this bill on all lands and waters under the jurisdiction and control of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service.

Interior shall establish and annually update a list of nonlead ammunition.

The prohibition shall not apply to (1) a government official or agent who is carrying out a statutory duty unrelated to the management of wildlife; (2) a state, local, tribal, or federal law enforcement officer, or the agent of such an officer, who is carrying out a statutory duty; or (3) an active member of the U.S. military who is carrying out official duties.

The regulations promulgated pursuant to this bill shall provide that any person that knowingly violates the prohibition may be assessed a civil penalty by Interior of (1) no more than $500 for the first violation, and (2) no less than $1,000 or more than $5,000 for each subsequent violation.</summary>
</bill>
