<bill session="109" type="s" number="2058" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:32Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Radio and Concert Disclosure and Competition Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote transparency and reduce anti-competitive practices in the radio and concert industries.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Radio and Concert Disclosure and Competition Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13367-13368"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13368-13369" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-25T19:44:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Radio and Concert Disclosure and Competition Act of 2005 - Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to modify its regulations concerning disclosure of payments made to broadcasters to prohibit the licensee or permittee (licensee) of any radio station from receiving money or other valuable consideration from a record company, recording artist, or music promoter or publisher (music representative) unless the licensee discloses at least monthly to the FCC and the public the receipt of such money or consideration.

Directs the FCC to: (1) require that all transactions between a licensee and a music representative be conducted at an arm's length basis, reduced to writing, and retained at least five years; and (2) review any such transaction upon petition.

Directs the FCC to prohibit a licensee from: (1) using its control over any non-advertising matter in a broadcast to extract or receive money from a music representative; (2) engaging or receiving concert services from a musician or recording artist unless the licensee does not discriminate about the broadcast of non-advertising matter and provides fair compensation for the services; or (3) owning or controlling a concert promoter or a venue used primarily for live performances.

Authorizes license revocations for violations of this Act.

Increases maximum penalties for nondisclosure of payments made in connection with broadcasts.</summary>
</bill>
