<bill session="108" type="sr" number="144" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States should declare its support for the right of the people of Kosova to determine their political future once Kosova has made requisite progress, as defined by United Nations benchmarks, in developing democratic institutions and human rights protections.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States should declare its support for the right of the people of Kosova to determine their political future once Kosova has made requisite progress, as defined by United Nations benchmarks, in developing democratic institutions and human rights protections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000444"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6515-6517"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6514-6515" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Kosovo"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Political violence"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Declares the sense of the Senate that the United States should: (1) recognize the danger that an unnecessary delay in the resolution of Kosova's final status would pose for the political and economic viability of Kosova and the stability of Southeast Europe; (2) publicly support the goal of a democratic government in Kosova in which human rights, including the rights of ethnic and religious minorities, are respected; (3) call for holding a referendum, under international supervision, on the future status of Kosova, once it has made further progress in developing institutions of democratic self-government, establishing the rule of law, facilitating the return and reintegration of refugees into local communities, and protecting ethnic minorities, in accordance with the benchmarks established by the United Nations; (4) work in conjunction with the United Nations, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization, the European Union, the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe, and other international organizations to assist Kosova to meet the UN benchmarks that are the necessary conditions for holding a referendum on the future status of Kosova and to facilitate the implementation of the form of government determined by the people of Kosova; and (5) continue to provide assistance, trade, and other programs to encourage the further development of democracy and a free market economic system in Kosova.</summary>
</bill>
