<bill session="111" type="s" number="2927" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wall Street Fair Share Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on certain securities transactions to fund job creation and deficit reduction, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wall Street Fair Share Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2009-12-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2009-12-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-12-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-28T23:09:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wall Street Fair Share Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on securities trading facilities, brokers, and purchasers for certain securities transactions. Sets such tax at .25% of the fair market value of the security traded. Defines "security" to include stock in a corporation, partnership interests, debt instruments, or interests in certain derivative financial instruments. Exempts from such tax an initial issue of securities, transactions in certain retirement, education, and health savings accounts, and transactions in mutual funds. Allows the purchaser of securities a credit against the excise tax for the lesser of the tax incurred or $250 ($500 for married couples filing joint tax returns). Requires withholding of excise tax amounts by the transferor of securities subject to the tax.</summary>
</bill>
