<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="489" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:58Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3854" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-10-29T16:29:49-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-10-29"/>
  <description>Amendment increases the maximum amount of stabilization loans in high unemployment areas to $75,000; delays repayment of stabilization loans in high unemployment areas for up to 18 months for new loans made after enactment of the bill and gives the SBA administrator authority to designate high unemployment areas as eligible for operating assistance grants under the new market venture capital program.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 13 printed in Part B of House Report 111-317 to increase the maximum amount of stabilization loans in high unemployment areas to $75,000 and delays repayment of stabilization loans in high unemployment areas to 18 months for new loans made after enactment of this act. It would give the SBA administrator ability to designate high unemployment areas as eligible for operating assistance grants under the new market venture capital program.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-10-29T16:29:49-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Peters amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T16:21:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Peters.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12109-12110" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12109" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T16:21:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Peters.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12109-12110" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H12109" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T16:29:49-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Peters amendment (A013) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29T16:29:49-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
