<bill session="119" type="s" number="1070" updated="2025-11-21T15:32:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National STEM Week Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National STEM Week Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National STEM Week to promote American innovation and enhance STEM education pathways for all students, including those in rural, urban, and underserved communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2104" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-04T15:40:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National STEM Week Act

This bill&#160;requires the National Science and Technology Council's&#160;Committee on STEM to designate a week each calendar year as National STEM Week. (STEM refers to science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.)

During this established week, the committee must encourage educational institutions (i.e., elementary schools, secondary schools, and institutions of higher education) to participate in the week and also encourage families of students&#160;attending these educational institutions to participate in STEM activities. Additionally, the committee must encourage STEM industries to (1) engage with students enrolled in educational institutions by providing mentorship programs, site visits, and guest lectures; and (2) support STEM education initiatives at these educational institutions through funding, resources, and expertise.

The committee must annually report to Congress on the activities conducted during the established week.</summary>
</bill>
