<bill session="117" type="h" number="9477" updated="2023-02-24T16:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SEAfood Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Science-based Equitable Aquaculture Food Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEAfood Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize studies and pilot programs related to the development and production of aquaculture in the exclusive economic zone of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2022-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2022-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-24T16:00:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Science-based Equitable Aquaculture Food Act or the SEAfood Act 

This bill addresses the development and production of aquaculture in the U.S. Exclusive Economic Zone.

For example, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to produce a report that examines aquaculture permitting, monitoring, and regulations during the 15-year period prior to the enactment of the bill.

Additionally, the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine must complete a study to develop the scientific basis for efficient and effective regulation of offshore aquaculture.

Further, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration must (1) establish an assessment program to evaluate offshore aquaculture, including the development of performance standards for offshore aquaculture operations; and (2) establish the Aquaculture Centers of Excellence program to award grants to assist certain institution in establishing or enhancing an aquaculture curriculum for undergraduate or graduate courses of study.</summary>
</bill>
