<bill session="116" type="s" number="1874" updated="2022-11-01T13:51:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-Efficiency Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRIGHT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-efficiency Technology Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-Efficiency Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 40, United States Code, to require the Administrator of General Services to procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficiency lighting products and to issue guidance on the efficiency, effectiveness, and economy of those products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-157.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-11-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="292">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 292.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-19T17:24:04Z" status="Reported to Senate">Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-efficiency Technology Act or the BRIGHT Act

This bill revises and sets forth provisions related to the procurement of lighting systems.

The General Services Administration (GSA) shall (1) issue guidance to federal agencies for the procurement and use of the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems; and (2) publish or otherwise make available to state, local, and tribal entities information on ways of improving efficiency, effectiveness, and economy by procuring and using such lighting systems.

The GSA must (1) procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems, and (2) ensure that procurements of lighting systems or their individual components maximize life-cycle cost effectiveness and energy efficiency.

Each public building that is constructed, altered, acquired, or leased by GSA must be equipped with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems. Each individual component of a lighting system that is replaced in the normal course of the maintenance of public buildings shall be replaced with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system possible.

The bill modifies requirements for the use of energy efficient lighting systems.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-157</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
