<bill session="118" type="s" number="2243" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Palliative Care and Hospice Education and Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the number of permanent faculty in palliative care at accredited allopathic and osteopathic medical schools, nursing schools and other programs, including social work, physician assistant, and chaplaincy education programs, to promote education and research in palliative care and hospice, and to support the development of faculty careers in academic palliative and hospice care.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Palliative Care and Hospice Education and Training Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2024-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-19T21:16:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Palliative Care and Hospice Education and Training Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to take a series of actions relating to palliative-care training.

Specifically, HHS&#160;must provide support for Palliative Care and Hospice Education Programs. The programs&#160;must support&#160;the training of health professionals in palliative and hospice&#160;care, including through traineeships or fellowships.

In addition,&#160;HHS&#160;may provide support to medical schools, teaching hospitals, and graduate medical-education programs for training physicians who plan to teach or practice&#160;palliative medicine.

HHS&#160;must also (1) provide Palliative Care&#160;and Hospice Academic Career Awards to health professional schools to promote the&#160;career development of academic hospice and palliative care specialists, (2)&#160;support individuals in specified fields who are pursuing an advanced degree in palliative care or related fields, and (3) award grants to nursing programs to train individuals in providing palliative care.

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality must provide for a national education and awareness campaign to inform patients, families, and health professionals about the benefits of palliative care.

The National Institutes of Health must expand national research programs in palliative care.</summary>
</bill>
