<bill session="118" type="h" number="2664" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Innovation Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Innovation Coordination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for coordination between Federal agencies regarding the decarbonization, development, certification, and deployment of aircraft, vessels, and medium and heavy duty transportation vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001214" joined="2023-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-29T16:29:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation Innovation Coordination Act

This bill directs the Joint Office of Energy and Transportation to study, plan, coordinate, and implement decarbonization of (1) aircraft, airports, and aviation; (2) maritime transportation; and (3) medium- and heavy-duty transportation vehicles. The joint office facilitates collaboration between the Department of Energy and the Department of Transportation.

Specifically, the bill requires the joint office to support decarbonization&#160;efforts such as

research and technical assistance related to the development, operation, and maintenance of sustainable aircraft, low- or zero-emission vessels, and medium- and heavy-duty transportation vehicles;data sharing on the installation, operation, and maintenance of charging and refueling infrastructure at airports, ports, and freight facilities;the development and deployment of workforce training programs related to charging and refueling infrastructure at airports and ports;the transition from leaded fuel usage by commercial and general aviation; andthe development and establishment of green maritime corridors.The joint office must also support research and funding related to the decarbonization of medium- and heavy-duty trucks and other freight transportation equipment and operations. This includes charging and fueling infrastructure, as well as the development and deployment of alternative sustainable low-carbon fuels, including biofuels, clean hydrogen, methanol, and ammonia, and associated powertrain technologies (e.g., batteries and hydrogen internal combustion engines).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
