<bill session="118" type="s" number="2632" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Visa Processing Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Visa Processing Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve visa processing times, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-23T19:05:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Visa Processing Improvement Act&#160;

This bill establishes measures to reduce processing times for certain nonimmigrant visas.

The bill authorizes domestic renewal of an unexpired B (temporary visitor) visa.

The bill also expands&#160;the authority of the Department of State to waive mandatory in-person interviews for certain nonimmigrant visa applicants, including for eligible individuals&#160;who (1) have previously traveled to the United States through the Visa Waiver Program, or (2) are renewing a visa less than 48 months after&#160;its expiration date.&#160;The bill also authorizes interviews for certain B visa applications to be conducted remotely (i.e., via teleconference technology) subject to various requirements, including requirements related to security.&#160;

If a&#160;first-time visa applicant is eligible for a waiver of the in-person interview requirement, that individual may pay for expedited processing of that application.

The bill also requires the State Department to establish, via rulemaking, standards for consulates for nonimmigrant visa processing times. The State Department must also&#160;assist consulates that do not meet these standards. Such assistance may include increasing staffing and implementing technological upgrades. Consulates must make interview wait time data publicly available and regularly update this information.

The bill also expands the Consular Fellows Program by 5% per year through FY2030 and requires fellows to be trained to conduct visa interviews in English.

&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
