<bill session="108" type="s" number="1073" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Grant Coordination and Simplification Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for homeland security grant coordination and simplification.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Grant Coordination and Simplification Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2003-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4333" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-17T17:58:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeland Security Grant Coordination and Simplification Act of 2003 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an Interagency Committee to Coordinate and Streamline Homeland Security Grant Programs that shall: (1) ensure coordination among the Federal agencies that provide funding or other assistance to or for State and local law enforcement agencies, fire and rescue operations, medical and emergency relief services, and State and local homeland security efforts; (2) eliminate duplication of requirements contained in emergency plans requested by Federal agencies; (3) simplify and coordinate applications for homeland security funding; (4) identify ways to streamline the process through which Federal agencies support community-based law enforcement, fire and rescue, and medical and emergency relief services; (5) collect information regarding State and local initiatives to promote interoperability of equipment; (6) develop coordinated plans to provide technical assistance to States to promote interoperable equipment; (7) provide coordinated assistance to help State and local governments prepare risk and vulnerability assessments; and (8) review State plan submissions to ensure that all relevant Federal interests are protected.</summary>
</bill>
