<bill session="108" type="s" number="431" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Municipal Solid Waste Interstate Transportation and Local Authority Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to impose certain limits on the receipt of out-of-State municipal solid waste.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Municipal Solid Waste Interstate Transportation and Local Authority Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2003-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2602-2603"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2603-2609" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compost"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Municipal solid waste"/>
    <term name="Perjury"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Recycling industry"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Municipal Solid Waste Interstate Transportation and Local Authority Act of 2003 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to prohibit a facility that received municipal solid waste (MSW) before this Acts's enactment from receiving out-of-State MSW for disposal unless the waste is received pursuant to a new or existing host community agreement or certain other State authorization. Sets forth requirements regarding the effect of host community agreements and receipt of waste by other facilities. Bars the receipt of such waste at any time the State determines that a facility is not in compliance with specified laws and regulations. Authorizes States in which facilities received more than 650,000 tons of out-of-State MSW in 1993 to establish limits on the quantity of such waste authorized to be received by facilities receiving such waste in 1993 in declining percentages of the 1993 quantity. Requires notification of such limits by a State to each State from which MSW was received in 1993. Prohibits a State from exercising the authority for general MSW limits if it exercises the authority for limits provided under this paragraph. Allows States to impose cost recovery surcharges on the processing of out-of-State MSW in the State. Imposes requirements regarding temporary waste storage. States conditions for: (1) permit denial; (2) State-imposed annual limitations, including on construction and demolition waste; and (3) the exercise of State or local flow control authority (directing materials to particular facilities). Prohibits a State or political subdivision from requiring any person to transport such waste or materials to any active portion of an MSW landfill if its contamination is a basis for listing on the National Priorities List established under the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, unless the person has been indemnified by the government or the owner-operator against all liability with respect to such materials. Provides for the enforceability of certain legally binding interim contracts that obligate the delivery of a minimum quantity of MSW or recyclables to a designated facility and obligate the government to pay or be liable for such materials.</summary>
</bill>
