<bill session="117" type="hr" number="309" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No IRRESPONSIBLE Spending Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit bills and joint resolutions that contain an appropriation or authorization of more than $100,000,000,000 relating to infrastructure that does not provide at least 50 percent of such funds to programs, initiatives, or projects that directly impact construction or maintenance of highways, roads, bridges, dams, passenger and freight railways, airports, waterways and ports, public schools, or the safety of such facilities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Irresponsible Recovery or Reinvestment Expenditures Supporting Priorities Outside Necessary Surface Infrastructure Built Legitimately and Expediently Spending Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No IRRESPONSIBLE Spending Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2021-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2021-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-10T15:11:09Z" status="Introduced in House">No Irresponsible Recovery or Reinvestment Expenditures Supporting Priorities Outside Necessary Surface Infrastructure Built Legitimately and Expediently Spending Act or the No IRRESPONSIBLE Spending Act

This resolution provides that it shall not be in order for the House of Representatives to consider a bill containing an appropriation or authorization of more than $100 billion relating to infrastructure if the bill does not provide at least 50% of those funds to specified programs, initiatives, or projects (e.g., the construction or maintenance of highways, railways, airports, and waterways). A question of order on this percentage may be raised at any time.</summary>
</bill>
