<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1515</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:18Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:18Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-09-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2012-08-28T17:51:38Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2012-05-16T15:24:54Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-09-06T23:01:27Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 112-205</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>2532</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-07-14</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-28</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 496.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2012 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-205.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-28</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Lieberman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2012 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 112-205.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-05-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-09-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000304</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lieberman, Joseph I. [ID-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOSEPH</firstName>
        <lastName>LIEBERMAN</lastName>
        <party>ID</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>I.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>District of Columbia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee benefits and pensions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement officers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Office of Personnel Management (OPM)</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-09-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-09-30T12:46:02Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2011 - Authorizes an individual who was appointed as an officer or member of the United States Secret Service Division or the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division during 1984, 1985, or 1986, who has actively performed duties other than clerical duties for 10 or more years directly related to the agency's protection mission, who is serving as an officer or member of the Secret Service Division or the Secret Service Uniformed Division, and who is participating in the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) on the date of enactment of this Act, to file an election to be covered by the District of Columbia Police and Firefighters Retirement and Disability System in the same manner as officers and members appointed prior to 1984. Requires such individual to cover transition costs to such System by using amounts in his or her Thrift Savings Fund. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-08-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-10-12T19:25:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2102 - (Sec. 2) Expresses the sense of the Senate that members of the U.S. Secret Service Division and the U.S. Secret Service Uniformed Division hired between January 1, 1984, and December 31, 1986, were promised that they would be eligible to participate in the District of Columbia Police and Firefighters Retirement System (DCPFRS). </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Amends the Policemen and Fireman's Retirement and Disability Act of the District of Columbia Official Code to allow certain covered employees of the U.S. Secret Service to elect participation in DCPFRS after notifying the Director of the Secret Service and providing certain information and assurances required by the Director. Requires covered employees to make a lump sum payment into a specified appropriations account of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) equal to the cost of transition into DCPFRS. </p> <p>Defines &quot;covered employee&quot; for purposes of this Act as an individual who: (1) was appointed during 1984, 1985, or 1986 as a member of the Secret Service Uniformed Division or as a criminal investigator; (2) has actively performed duties other than clerical for 10 or more years directly related to the protection mission of the Secret Service; (3) is serving as an officer or member of the Uniformed Division or is employed by the Secret Service as a criminal investigator, and (4) is covered under the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS) as of the enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Requires the Director of the Secret Service to notify each covered employee of eligibility for coverage under the D.C. Fireman's Retirement and Disability Act. Requires notification to such covered employees of the cost of transition from FERS to DCPFRS. </p> <p>Requires the Office of Pay and Retirement Services of the District of Columbia to determine the cost of transition to DCPFRS for each covered employee and authorizes such Office to enter into contracts for carrying out activities under this Act. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Requires a covered employee to forfeit all contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund made by an employing agency prior to the effective date of such employee's election under this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Makes covered employees who accept employment with another federal agency subject to the same pension offset rules that are applicable to reemployed annuitants under FERS and the Civil Service Retirement System.</p> (Sec. 6) Provides for compliance of the budgetary effects of this Act with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to permit certain members of the United States Secret Service and certain members of the United States Secret Service Uniformed Division who were appointed in 1984, 1985, or 1986 to elect to be covered under the District of Columbia Police and Firefighter Retirement and Disability System in the same manner as members appointed prior to 1984.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>United States Secret Service Retirement Act of 2012</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2012-08-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1515rs/xml/BILLS-112s1515rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-09-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1515is/xml/BILLS-112s1515is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-08-28</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 496.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
