<bill session="118" type="h" number="1103" updated="2025-11-19T04:58:30Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-10T14:10:09-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-10T14:10:09-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office (HKETO) Certification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office (HKETO) Certification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office (HKETO) Certification Act</title>
    <title type="display">Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office (HKETO) Certification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to remove the extension of certain privileges, exemptions, and immunities to the Hong Kong Economic and Trade Offices if Hong Kong no longer enjoys a high degree of autonomy from the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2023-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000197" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2023-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 39 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T17:36:34-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barr moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T17:36:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5068-5071" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T17:36:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1103.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T17:50:41-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5068-5069" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10T14:02:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5119" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="405" datetime="2024-09-10T14:10:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 413 - 3 (Roll no. 405).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10T14:10:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="527">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 527.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="490" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-27T13:12:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Hong Kong Economic and Trade Office (HKETO) Certification Act

This bill requires the President to periodically determine whether to allow the Hong Kong Economic and Trade Offices (HKETOs) to continue to operate in the United States. (The HKETOs are the official representative offices for Hong Kong, a semi-autonomous city that was established as a British colony in 1841. The United Kingdom transferred sovereignty over Hong Kong to China in 1997).

Under this bill, the President must periodically (at least once a year) certify to Congress a determination as to whether the HKETOs should be covered by the International Organizations Immunities Act. (The act provides immunities and privileges to certain international organizations, such as immunity from certain lawsuits and exemption from property taxes.)

If the President certifies that the HKETOs no longer merit receiving such privileges and immunities, the HKETOs must terminate operations in the United States no later than 180 days after the certification is delivered to Congress.

If the President certifies that the HKETOs continue to merit such privileges and immunities, the HKETOs may continue operations for another year, unless Congress enacts a joint resolution disapproving of the certification.

The President may also revoke the application of such privileges and immunities to the HKETOs.

A federal government entity may enter into an agreement or partnership with an HKETO only if the HKETOs are still authorized to operate in the United States under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
