<bill session="117" type="s" number="1376" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect America's Paper for Recycling Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the definition of municipal solid waste.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect America's Paper for Recycling Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2021-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2021-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2021-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3879" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-09T13:37:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect America's Paper for Recycling Act

This bill modifies the tax credit for producing electricity from renewable resources to revise the definition of municipal solid waste.

The bill specifies that municipal solid waste does not include paper that is commonly recycled and that has been segregated from other solid waste, or solid waste that is collected as part of a system that does not provide for the separate collection of paper that is commonly recycled from residential solid waste. The bill includes exceptions for incidental and residual waste.

In the case of a facility that produces electricity both from municipal solid waste and other solid waste that is not a qualified energy resource (1) the facility is a qualified facility if it otherwise meets the requirements for qualified facilities, and (2) the credit only applies to the portion of the electricity produced from municipal solid waste.</summary>
</bill>
