<bill session="112" type="s" number="1445" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:35Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Raechel and Jacqueline Houck Safe Rental Car Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain conduct by car and truck rental companies relating to motor vehicle safety defects and recalls as unfair and deceptive acts or practices to be regulated by the Federal Trade Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Raechel and Jacqueline Houck Safe Rental Car Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2011-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-09T20:18:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Raechel and Jacqueline Houck Safe Rental Car Act of 2011 - Makes it unlawful for a rental company, unless the defect or noncompliance has already been remedied, to rent, lease, or sell a covered vehicle on or after the earlier of: (1) the receipt by the company of a Secretary of Transportation (DOT) ordered notification from the manufacturer that the vehicle or equipment is defective or is noncompliant with federal motor vehicle safety standards; or (2) when the vehicle or equipment manufacturer gives notice to owners, purchasers, and dealers that the vehicle or equipment contains a defect or is noncompliant.

Requires a rental company that receives a notification of a vehicle or equipment defect or noncompliance during the vehicle rental or lease period to: (1) contact the renter or lessee and any authorized driver of the covered vehicle about the defect or noncompliance; and (2) offer to provide them, at no additional cost, with a comparable alternative vehicle until the defect or noncompliance has been remedied.

Treats violations of the requirements of this Act as unfair or deceptive acts or practices under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Subjects persons who violate such requirements to certain penalties.

Requires the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to report to Congress on: (1) sales of motor vehicles to rental companies without standard safety features, and (2) sales by rental companies of covered vehicles known to include safety defects before they are recalled.</summary>
</bill>
