<bill session="116" type="s" number="1017" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting America's Caregivers and Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting America's Caregivers and Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 in order to address the needs of caregivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2019-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2242-2243" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-18T23:55:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supporting America's Caregivers and Families Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2024, and modifies, programs for family caregivers of older adults, including with respect to caregiver assessment tools and capacity-building for aging networks. It also establishes the National Family Caregiver Resource and Technical Assistance Center to support state and local agencies, community-based providers, and family caregivers.

Specifically, the Administration on Aging must develop a strategy to increase the use of caregiver assessment tools and conduct a study that addresses, among other topics, the feasibility of mandating the use of such tools. Additionally, states must report on the mechanisms they use to assess the needs of caregivers.

The bill also provides statutory authority for certain activities to build the business acumen and related skills of aging networks to increase their capacity to serve older adults and caregivers.</summary>
</bill>
