<bill session="116" type="s" number="974" updated="2022-11-01T18:47:25Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to modify the authorized uses of certain property conveyed by the United States in Los Angeles, California.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the authorized uses of certain property conveyed by the United States in Los Angeles, California.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2016" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-12-20T15:42:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the portion of the property known as the Veterans' Administration Center Reservation in Los Angeles California, which was conveyed by the General Services Administration (GSA) to the state of California for a proposed National Guard Armory, to be used for purposes of meeting the needs of the homeless.

The bill directs the state to submit an application to the GSA for the use of such property to meet the needs of the homeless.

The GSA and the Department of Health and Human Services must jointly determine whether the use of the property described in the application is a use for meeting the needs of the homeless.

If it is determined that the proposed use of the property is for meeting the needs of the homeless, the GSA must modify the deed of conveyance for such property to authorize its use for homeless needs.</summary>
</bill>
