<bill session="116" type="s" number="3858" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:19Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic Response and Interstate Cost Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRICE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to become the sole owner and distributer of certain medical equipment in the event of a covered emergency; to establish a Joint Congressional Committee on Defense Production; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6662" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-10T15:03:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic Response and Interstate Cost Equity Act or the PRICE Act

This bill establishes the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) as the sole buyer, vendor, owner, and distributor of certain medical equipment obtained by the federal government in the event of a national health emergency and establishes a process for the pricing and distribution of such equipment.

Specifically, in the event of such an emergency, the Department of Health and Human Services shall assess available medical equipment and FEMA shall (1) become the sole owner and distributor of medical equipment obtained by the federal government for which the prevailing market price exceeds the fair market price by more than 15%, (2) contract with all persons capable of producing such equipment to produce such equipment, and (3) establish a price for such equipment and sell or otherwise distribute the equipment to the states or to persons that request it.

The bill establishes in Congress a Joint Committee on Defense Production.</summary>
</bill>
