<bill session="108" type="h" number="1075" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ephedra Public Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to dietary supplements containing natural or synthetic ephedrine group alkaloids, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ephedra Public Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2003-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000165" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2003-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Herbs"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicinal plants"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Ephedra Public Protection Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to classify a food as adulterated if it is a dietary supplement that contains any ephedrine group and is unsafe within the meaning of this Act.Classifies a new ephedrine supplement (a dietary supplement containing ephedrine alkaloids not generally recognized as safe) as unsafe if it has not received premarket approval from the Secretary of Health and Human Services. Directs the Secretary to approve supplements that do not present a significant or unreasonable risk of illness or injury under the recommended or ordinary conditions of use.Requires manufacturers of ephedrine supplements (dietary supplements containing any ephedrine group alkaloids), and packers and distributors of such supplements whose names appear on the label, to investigate each claim of a serious adverse experience and report to the Secretary as to whether the ephedrine supplement involved was a causal factor. Makes failure to comply with such reporting requirements a prohibited act.Directs the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register a proposed rule for good manufacturing practice regulations under the Act. States various elements the proposed rule shall contain, including that it shall require the testing of each production lot or batch of an ephedrine supplement to ensure the label's accuracy in stating the amount of ephedrine group alkaloids in such supplement. Classifies an ephedrine supplement as misbranded unless its label bears an expiration date.</summary>
</bill>
