<bill session="118" type="h" number="1481" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CRUDE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuing Robust and Uninhibited Drilling and Exporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRUDE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise the authority provided to the President to impose export licensing requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil from the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000246" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000134" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-19T17:57:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Continuing Robust and Uninhibited Drilling and Exporting Act or the CRUDE Act

This bill limits the President's authority to restrict the export of crude oil from the United States. Currently, the President may restrict the export of oil for up to a year if

 the President declares a national emergency; the restrictions apply to countries, persons, or organizations for reasons of national security; or the Department of Commerce finds and reports to the President that the export of crude oil has caused sustained material oil supply shortages or sustained oil prices significantly above world market levels and those shortages or price increases have caused or are likely to cause sustained material adverse employment effects. However, this bill only allows the President to make such restrictions if

 the restrictions apply to countries, persons, or organizations for reasons of national security; or the Department of Defense, the Department of Energy, and Commerce jointly make those findings and report them to the President and Congress.</summary>
</bill>
