<bill session="116" type="h" number="7611" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-14">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Legislative Branch for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2021, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-14">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-447, by Mr. Ryan.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-07-14" calendar="Union" number="359">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 359.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1085" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="133" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-15T19:00:09Z" status="Reported to House">Legislative Branch Appropriations Act, 2021

 This bill provides FY2021 appropriations for the legislative branch, including the House of Representatives and Joint Items such as

 the Joint Economic Committee, the Joint Committee on Taxation, the Office of the Attending Physician, and the Office of Congressional Accessibility Services. In addition, the bill provides FY2021 appropriations for

 the Capitol Police; the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights; the Congressional Budget Office; the Architect of the Capitol; the Library of Congress, including the Congressional Research Service and the Copyright Office; the Government Publishing Office; the Government Accountability Office; the Open World Leadership Center Trust Fund; and the John C. Stennis Center for Public Service Training and Development. (Pursuant to the longstanding practice of each chamber of Congress determining its own requirements, funds for the Senate are not included in the House bill.)

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-447</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
