<bill session="116" type="h" number="5733" updated="2022-02-09T03:42:22Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended to waive the application of the Act to agents representing foreign enterprises which are not under the control or direction of foreign governments or foreign political parties, to exclude agents who represent foreign governments which engage in a pattern of gross violations of human rights from the exemption provided under the Act for agents engaged in scholastic and certain other pursuits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Influence Registration Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2020-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-01T16:15:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Influence Registration Modernization Act or the FIRM Act

This bill revises provisions related to the registration of foreign agents, and it transfers certain oversight duties regarding lobbying to the Department of Justice (DOJ).

Current law exempts from foreign agent registration requirements any person engaging only in religious, scholastic, or scientific pursuits. The bill eliminates this exemption for agents of foreign principals that are known violators of human rights.

The bill also narrows the definition of foreign principal, waiving registration requirements for agents of foreign enterprises that are not under the control or direction of a foreign government or political party.

The bill further requires registration statements and supplements to be filed in a digitized format and stored in a searchable, sortable, and downloadable database.

In addition, the bill authorizes DOJ to enact a civil penalty of up to $200,000 for a violation of foreign agent registration requirements.

Lastly, the bill transfers administration of lobbyist registration, reporting, disclosure and enforcement, and penalties from Congress to DOJ.</summary>
</bill>
