<bill session="118" type="s" number="2798" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BUFFER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUFFER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Up Farmland Frontiers for Ecological Resilience Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to clarify land eligible for enrollment in the conservation reserve program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5466" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-29T14:08:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building Up Farmland Frontiers for Ecological Resilience Act or the BUFFER Act

This bill provides that certain land (that is under state regulations) is&#160;eligible to participate under the Conservation Reserve Program (CRP). Under CRP, the Department of Agriculture provides annual payments to agricultural producers to take highly erodible and environmentally sensitive land out of production and install resource-conserving practices.&#160;&#160;

Specifically, land otherwise eligible under the program remains eligible for enrollment even if a tribal, state, or other local law, ordinance, or other regulation requires any resource-conserving or environmental protection measure or practice. The bill includes an exception that makes the land ineligible&#160;under the program if the implementation&#160;requirement has been imposed by an administrative order or a court order.

Current regulations&#160;exclude from enrollment eligibility (with exceptions) land that is subject to tribal, state, or other local laws, ordinances, or other regulations that require any resource-conserving or environmental protection measures or practices.</summary>
</bill>
