<bill session="118" type="h" number="7167" updated="2024-10-02T08:06:35Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Banking for Human Traffickers Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Banking for Human Traffickers Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the role of the financial industry in combating human trafficking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2024-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2024-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2024-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-24T15:11:15Z" status="Introduced in House">End Banking for Human Traffickers Act of 2024

This bill establishes requirements for finance and banking entities to detect and prevent human trafficking.&#160;

The Financial Institutions Examination Council must review procedures to improve the capability of specified programs to target financial transactions relating to severe forms of human trafficking.&#160;The Interagency Task Force to Monitor and Combat Trafficking must submit to Congress recommendations for the revision of anti-money laundering programs specifically targeting severe forms of human trafficking.

The bill provides additional criteria to be considered by the Department of State to indicate a foreign country's serious and sustained efforts to eliminate human trafficking for purposes of certain foreign assistance. Specifically, the bill adds criteria regarding whether a foreign country has taken or is taking steps to implement a framework for preventing financial transactions involving severe forms of human trafficking.</summary>
</bill>
