<bill session="116" type="h" number="2106" updated="2022-11-01T19:17:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend section 100905 of title 54, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to require annual permits and assess annual fees for commercial filming activities on Federal land for film crews of 5 persons or fewer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 100905 of title 54, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to require annual permits and assess annual fees for commercial filming activities on Federal land for film crews of 5 persons or fewer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2019-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2019-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-14T19:04:02Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture (USDA) to assess an annual fee of up to $200 for any film crew of five persons or fewer to conduct commercial filming activities or similar projects on federal land administered by such departments and to require a one-year permit for such activities or projects that occur in areas designated for public use during public hours on federal land and waterways administered by such departments.

The bill also requires that the fee for a commercial filming activity or similar project in a unit of the National Park System be sufficient to cover the cost of a film permit and other administrative and personnel costs.

Interior and USDA must also assess an annual fee of up to $200 for still photography crews of five persons or fewer.

The bill repeals the requirement for collection by Interior and USDA of costs incurred as a result of filming activities or similar projects, including administrative and personnel costs, in addition to the reasonable fee assessed for commercial filming activities or similar projects in a system unit.</summary>
</bill>
