<bill session="109" type="s" number="2632" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Common Sense Cross-Border Travel and Security Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow United States citizens under 18 years of age to travel to Canada without a passport, to develop a system to enable United States citizens to take 24-hour excursions to Canada without a passport, to limit the cost of passport cards or similar alternatives to passports to $20, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Common Sense Cross-Border Travel and Security Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2006-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2006-04-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-18T15:33:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Common Sense Cross-Border Travel and Security Act of 2006 - Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to require that the travel document plan for U.S. citizens and others with waived document requirements traveling into the United States: (1) include a fee-free "day pass" system that would permit U.S. citizens to travel to Canada for a 24-hour period without a passport by completing a day pass application at any port of entry along the U.S.-Canadian land border, and certifying that there was not sufficient time to apply for a passport before the excursion; and (2) provide that U.S. citizens under 18 years of age who are accompanied by a parent or guardian shall not be required to present a passport when returning to the United States from Canada.

Limits fees to not more that $20 for any passport card or travel document issued pursuant to such plan.

Directs the Secretary of State to negotiate with the government of Canada to ensure the acceptance of such U.S. passport cards and day passes for travel to Canada.</summary>
</bill>
