<bill session="111" type="s" number="1165" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:39Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Health Care Purchasing Cooperatives Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the development of health care cooperatives that will help businesses to pool the health care purchasing power of employers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Health Care Purchasing Cooperatives Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2009-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5948-5949"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5949-5950" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-18T21:43:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Health Care Purchasing Cooperatives Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality (AHRQ), to award grants for the development of health care purchasing cooperatives by two or more self-insured employers.

 Sets forth requirements for cooperatives, including that they: (1) are nonprofit, wholly owned, and democratically governed by their member-employers; (2) exist solely to serve the membership base; (3) assist members in pooling their health care insurance purchasing power; (4) provide data to improve the ability of the members to make data-based decisions regarding their health plans; and (5) conduct activities to enhance quality improvement in the health care community. Requires the Secretary to carry out an identical grant program for eligible groups consisting of a consortium of two or more employers that each: (1) have 99 employees or fewer; and (2) purchase health insurance for their employees.</summary>
</bill>
