<bill session="108" type="s" number="2871" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Human Trafficking and Smuggling Penalty Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for enhanced criminal penalties for crimes related to slavery and alien smuggling.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Trafficking and Smuggling Penalty Enhancement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10068-10069"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Homicide"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-22T21:07:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Human Trafficking and Smuggling Penalty Enhancement Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for enhanced penalties, including the death penalty, for slavery.

Modifies alien smuggling prohibitions under the Immigration and Nationality Act to cover engaging in specified actions with knowledge that the violator is acting in reckless disregard of the fact that a person is an alien. Prohibits bringing or attempting to bring an alien to the United States at a place other than a designated port of entry or a place designated by the Under Secretary for Border and Transportation Security, regardless of: (1) whether the alien received prior official authorization to enter the United States; (2) whether the person bringing the alien intended to violate any criminal law; or (3) any future official action which may be taken with respect to that alien. Prohibits the commission of an offense with knowledge or reason to believe that the alien unlawfully brought to or into the United States has engaged in or intends to engage in terrorist activity.

Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend the Federal Sentencing Guidelines and related policy statements to implement this Act and to reflect the serious nature of the offenses and penalties referred to in this Act, the growing incidence of alien smuggling, and the need to deter, prevent, and punish such offenses.</summary>
</bill>
