<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4736</number>
    <updateDate>2023-03-30T14:49:59Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-03-30T14:49:59Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-08-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-08-02T21:21:06Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-08-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-08-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000383</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. King, Angus S., Jr. [I-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Angus</firstName>
        <lastName>King</lastName>
        <party>I</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2022-08-02</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-08-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-03-20T18:10:01Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Arctic Commitment Act</b></p> <p>This bill expands a variety of Arctic-focused provisions pertaining to national security, shipping, and trade.</p> <p>For example, the bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish the Arctic Shipping Federal Advisory Committee to advise DOT on matters related to Arctic maritime transportation, including Arctic seaway development. It also requires the Department of the Navy to ensure that the Port of Nome in Alaska is usable for the implementation of the National Strategy for the Arctic Region and military service strategies for the Arctic.</p> <p>Additionally, the U.S. Coast Guard and Navy must jointly submit to Congress a report that outlines the requirements to establish a persistent, year-round presence of the Navy and Coast Guard in the Arctic region, including at the Port of Nome and any other deepwater port that would facilitate such a presence.</p> <p>The bill also requires the Committee on Maritime Transportation System to submit to Congress a report that describes the control and influence of the Russian Federation on shipping in the Arctic and includes a plan for eliminating or preventing a Russian monopoly on shipping in the region to enable an increased U.S. presence in the Arctic shipping domain.</p> <p>Further, the bill expresses the sense of Congress that (1) Arctic countries are important partners of the United States, and (2) the United States International Development Finance Corporation should make investments in Arctic countries to facilitate technologies that contribute to energy security and sustainable opportunities for indigenous groups.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Arctic Commitment Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Arctic Commitment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Arctic Commitment Act</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to enhance United States standing as an Arctic nation by facilitating greater maritime accessibility, strong trading partners, and reliable infrastructure.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-08-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s4736is/xml/BILLS-117s4736is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-08-02</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
