<bill session="117" type="h" number="1778" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MORE DOT Grants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the Department of Transportation to certain counties in which the majority of land is owned or managed by the Federal Government and to other units of local government and Tribal governments in those counties, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE DOT Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from DOT Grants Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2021-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2021-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="649" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-19T11:10:35Z" status="Introduced in House">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from DOT Grants Act or the MORE DOT Grants Act 

This bill revises the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT) to high-density public land counties and any units of tribal and local governments within such counties. A high-density public land county is a county that has a population of not more than 100,000 people and in which more than 50% of the land is owned or managed by the federal government.

Any requirement for local matching funds under a qualifying grant program must be reduced by 50% with respect to such jurisdictions.

On request, DOT must provide additional technical assistance to such jurisdictions during the annual application period for each qualifying grant program.

DOT must also prioritize grant applications from such jurisdictions that have not received support under the qualifying grant program during the 10-year period preceding the date of the application.</summary>
</bill>
