<bill session="117" type="h" number="2559" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations relating to the authorization of foreign manufacturers of cylinders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2022-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2022-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5237" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-25T18:04:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Compressed Gas Cylinder Safety and Oversight Improvements Act of 2021

This bill expands requirements for foreign manufacturers of cylinders used for transporting hazardous materials in the United States (e.g., compressed gas cylinders).

Current regulations require foreign manufacturers to apply for authorization from the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration for testing such cylinders outside of the United States.

This bill requires that, to obtain an authorization, manufacturers must meet minimum levels of financial responsibility and answer in their applications specified questions, including whether the manufacturer is or has been subject to various civil or criminal penalties.

The administration must publish each application in the Federal Register for public comment and must also annually publish a list of authorized manufacturers online.

The bill limits an authorization to one year; however, the administration may extend an authorization for five years if the manufacturer (1) complies with applicable requirements for at least three years; and (2) meets conditions regarding the accuracy of its application, sufficiency of its financial responsibility, and other matters.

The administration may suspend or terminate an authorization if a manufacturer impedes an inspection or knowingly or intentionally provides inaccurate application information.

The administration must also establish a process whereby an interested party may petition for a reevaluation of an authorization if that party has evidence of inaccurate or fraudulent information in the manufacturer's application.</summary>
</bill>
