<bill session="117" type="s" number="473" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Bankruptcy Relief Extension Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the CARES Act to extend the sunset for the definition of a small business debtor, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Bankruptcy Relief Extension Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S900" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1651" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-14T15:09:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">COVID-19 Bankruptcy Relief Extension Act of 2021 

This bill extends existing provisions that provide relief to debtors in bankruptcy, including those related to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic.

These provisions (1) exclude certain COVID-19 aid payments from income for the purposes of bankruptcy, and (2) increase the debt eligibility threshold for businesses qualifying for certain types of Chapter 11 reorganization bankruptcy. Currently, these provisions expire March 27, 2021. The bill extends these provisions for one year.

The bill also allows for modification of a Chapter 13 repayment plan for plans confirmed before the date of enactment of this bill if the debtor is experiencing material financial hardship due to COVID-19. Currently, such a modification is only available for plans confirmed before March 27, 2020.

In addition, the bill extends through March 27, 2022, other bankruptcy protections that currently expire December 27, 2021. These provisions include those that (1) provide for discharge of certain debts, (2) prohibit denying a party COVID-related mortgage or eviction relief due to a party being a debtor in bankruptcy, and (3) protect against termination of utility services in certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
