<bill session="111" type="s" number="2785" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:06Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">After-School Partnerships Improve Results in Education (ASPIRE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants to improve after-school interdisciplinary education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">After-School Partnerships Improve Results in Education (ASPIRE) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2009-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2009-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Social Sciences and History"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-24T17:34:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Afterschool Partnerships Improve Results in Education (ASPIRE) Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to partnerships, composed of a state or local educational agency (LEA) and at least one college or nonprofit, community, tribal, business, labor, or career technical student organization, for the development of national model afterschool interdisciplinary education programs for secondary school students.

Directs the Secretary to allot grants to states for matching subgrants to other partnerships, composed of an LEA and at least one college or organization listed above, for the development of afterschool interdisciplinary education programs for secondary school students.

Gives grant and subgrant priority to programs targeting a high percentage of impoverished, struggling, or rural students and their families.

Requires each partnership grantee and subgrantee to include in its program: (1) at least one activity involving mathematics and science education, language arts, writing, and reading, or history, geography, or social studies; and (2) at least one activity involving career technical education, business and entrepreneurial education, health and wellness, the environment and conservation, or arts and music education.

Allows program activities to take place after school, before school, or at any other time that the school is not in session.

Directs the Secretary to carry out national activities, such as providing technical assistance to grantees and subgrantees, or conducting a national evaluation of such programs.</summary>
</bill>
