<bill session="118" type="s" number="2461" updated="2025-11-19T02:54:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COREY Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Operational Reporting of Emergencies Involving Teens and Young Adults Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COREY Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require reporting of certain accidents resulting in serious physical injuries or death at institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4903" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-03T19:39:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">College Operational Reporting of Emergencies Involving Teens and Young Adults Safety Act of 2023 or the COREY Safety Act of 2023

This bill expands reporting requirements included in the annual security report provided to current and prospective students and employees of each institution of higher education (IHE).

Specifically, the bill requires each IHE to include in its report statistics concerning the occurrence on campus of accidents that result in serious physical injury or death in the following categories:

transportation on foot or via bikes, scooters, skateboards,&#160;longboards, or motor vehicles;slips and falls, in the aggregate and from low heights, mid heights, and high heights;alcohol or drug overdoses;choking or drowning;any other specific category of accidents identified by the IHE; andall other accidents.The IHE must also include in the report (1) a description of any plans to address deficient or dangerous facilities on campus that have caused serious physical injury or death; and (2) a statement containing the names, addresses, and distances from campus of the closest trauma centers or other hospitals.

Additionally, the bill changes the name of the report from annual security report to annual campus safety report.

Further, the bill requires the annual report to be published on the&#160;IHE's public website. The report must be written and organized in a manner that is easily understandable by students and families.

The Department of Education must issue guidance to IHEs regarding the implementation of this bill. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
