<bill session="117" type="sr" number="86" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution recommitting the United States to the promotion of disability rights and to the values enshrined in the Prologue Room of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial in the District of Columbia, and recognizing the enduring contributions that individuals with disabilities have made throughout the history of the United States and the role of the disability community in the ongoing struggle for civil rights in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recommitting the United States to the promotion of disability rights and to the values enshrined in the Prologue Room of the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial in the District of Columbia, and recognizing the enduring contributions that individuals with disabilities have made throughout the history of the United States and the role of the disability community in the ongoing struggle for civil rights in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="183" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-30T14:59:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution calls on the United States to recommit itself to the promotion of disability rights and to the values enshrined in the Prologue Room at the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial on the occasion of the 20th anniversary of the dedication of the Prologue Room.

The resolution recognizes the important work of the disability community, and the historic campaign championed by that community, that led to the expansion of the memorial to include a statue that clearly and visibly depicts President Franklin Delano Roosevelt in a wheelchair.

Finally, the resolution calls on the National Park Service and the National Park Foundation to continue to increase access to the memorial for individuals with disabilities and to support the development of accessible educational materials to ensure awareness is raised about the history of the memorial and disability rights.</summary>
</bill>
