<bill session="117" type="s" number="2928" updated="2023-01-01T23:49:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 245 of title 18, United States Code, to expand protections for election workers, polling places, and other election infrastructure against threats and violence.</title>
    <title type="display">Election Worker and Polling Place Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Worker and Polling Place Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-09T15:21:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Election Worker and Polling Place Protection Act

This bill expands criminal civil rights offenses involving interference with federally protected activities.

Current law prohibits the use of force or threat of force to injure, intimidate, or interfere with an individual because of that individual's participation in certain enumerated federally protected activities (e.g., voting or jury duty).

This bill broadens the scope of prohibited conduct to include violence or threat of harm to any person or property to injure, intimidate, or interfere with an individual because of that individual's participation in a federally protected activity.

Additionally, with respect to voting activities, the bill extends protection to an individual who participates in an election as an agent, contractor, or vendor. Current law already protects an individual who participates as a candidate, voter, poll watcher, or election official.

Finally, the bill establishes new offenses involving physical damage to or threats to physically damage a polling place, tabulation center, or other election infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
