<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="545" updated="2021-09-30T00:34:08Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1054" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-05-15">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000105"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-05-14"/>
  <description>To eliminate the dividend and upper bracket tax cuts, which primarily benefit the wealthy, to provide the additional funds necessary for an adequate medicare prescription drug benefit, including assuring that the benefit is comprehensive, with no gaps or excessive cost-sharing, covers all medicare beneficiaries, provides special help for beneficiaries with low income, and does not undermine employer retirement coverage.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-05-15" how="roll" result="fail" roll="173">
      <text>Amendment SA 545 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 48 - 52. Record Vote Number: 173.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Amendment SA 545 proposed by Senator Kennedy. (consideration: CR S6437-6438; text: CR S6437) To eliminate the dividend and upper bracket tax cuts, which primarily benefit the wealthy, to provide the additional funds necessary for an adequate medicare prescription drug benefit, including assuring that the benefit is comprehensive, with no gaps or excessive cost-sharing, covers all medicare beneficiaries, provides special help for beneficiaries with low income, and does not undermine employer retirement coverage.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 545 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 48 - 52. Record Vote Number: 173.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 545 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 48 - 52. Record Vote Number: 173.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 545 proposed by Senator Kennedy.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6437-6438" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6437" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-14">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
