<bill session="119" type="s" number="2268" updated="2025-11-19T23:01:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agricultural Risk Review Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Risk Review Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Defense Production Act of 1950 to include the Secretary of Agriculture as a member of the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2025-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1576" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1713" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-30T12:56:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agricultural Risk Review Act of 2025

This bill makes changes to the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS), including by requiring CFIUS to determine whether a national security review is necessary for reportable agricultural land transactions that are referred by the Department of Agriculture (USDA). (CFIUS oversees the national security risks of certain foreign investment in the United States. CFIUS has the authority to review covered transactions, which include&#160;mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers that could result in foreign control of a U.S. business; certain investments in businesses involved in critical technologies, critical infrastructure, or sensitive personal data; and certain real estate transactions.)

Specifically, the bill directs CFIUS to, after receiving notification from USDA, determine (1) whether a reportable agricultural land transaction is a covered transaction, and (2) whether CFIUS should initiate a national security review or take another action with respect to the transaction.&#160;

Reportable agricultural land transaction means a transaction (1) that USDA has reason to believe&#160;is a covered transaction, based on information from or in cooperation with&#160;the intelligence community; (2) that involves the acquisition of an interest in agricultural land by a foreign person of China, North Korea, Russia, or Iran; and (3) with respect to which a foreign person is required to submit a report to USDA regarding their agricultural land transactions.

The bill also expands CFIUS to include the Secretary of Agriculture for covered transactions that involve agricultural land, agricultural biotechnology, or the agriculture industry (e.g., agricultural transportation, storage, and processing).</summary>
</bill>
