<bill session="116" type="h" number="7637" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New White House Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a New Executive Workgroup for the White House as an Iconic Treasure Expressing Honor, Obligation, Unity, Strength, and Excellence of our Nation (a New White House) to develop a plan to replace the existing White House with a new residence and working space for the President, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Executive Workgroup for the White House as an Iconic Treasure Expressing Honor, Obligation, Unity, Strength, and Excellence of our Nation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New White House Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-19T16:56:01Z" status="Introduced in House">New Executive Workgroup for the White House as an Iconic Treasure Expressing Honor, Obligation, Unity, Strength, and Excellence of our Nation Act or the New White House Act

This bill establishes the Commission for the Construction of a Modern Executive Mansion and Office Complex for the President.

The commission must develop a plan (1) to replace the existing White House with a new residence and work space for the President in the District of Columbia that meets modern security standards, (2) to preserve historic items from the existing White House, and (3) for the temporary relocation of the President and the President's staff while the new site is under construction. Commission members include specified subject matter experts, agency representatives, and former government officials, including all living former Presidents or their designees.</summary>
</bill>
