<bill session="119" type="s" number="120" updated="2025-05-23T18:50:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish a pilot program for the construction of temporary disaster assistance housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-23T18:50:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disaster Housing Reform for American Families Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to establish a five-year pilot program under the Individuals and Households Program (IHP) through which FEMA contracts to provide factory-built housing to serve disaster survivors until the disaster declaration terminates and then be utilized for affordable housing. It also authorizes&#160;FEMA to provide IHP grants for closing costs associated with obtaining certain mortgages.&#160;

Specifically,&#160;FEMA must enter into a contract with a producer or seller of manufactured or modular homes to construct such housing&#160;as a type of temporary housing assistance under IHP. The bill requires the housing to meet specified criteria, including that it must be available within 90 days (unless extended to 120 days) after the disaster declaration, have no more than four units, and provide a minimum level of protection from natural hazards. The housing must conform to various specified standards, but the bill authorizes the Department of Housing and Urban Development to waive any such requirement for construction under the pilot program.

Also, the bill requires&#160;FEMA to establish guidelines for transferring the housing to an affordable housing program after the termination of the relevant disaster declaration. However, the bill also authorizes it to become permanent housing after the declaration terminates.

In addition, the bill authorizes&#160;FEMA to provide IHP grants to disaster-impacted individuals or households purchasing residential property for closing costs associated with obtaining a mortgage from a federal program providing affordable financing options.</summary>
</bill>
