<bill session="117" type="h" number="358" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FRESH Trucking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom from Regulating Edible Supplies and Horticulture Trucking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FRESH Trucking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to modify regulations concerning hours of service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001214"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-11T16:25:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Freedom from Regulating Edible Supplies and Horticulture Trucking Act or the FRESH Trucking Act

This bill modifies service hour requirements for drivers transporting perishable agricultural, horticultural, or floricultural commodities.

The bill requires the Department of Transportation to establish that

 loading and unloading of commercial motor vehicles shall be excluded from on-duty time requirements, there shall be no requirement of a 30-minute rest break within the first 8 hours of&#160; the hours of service on-duty requirements and the carrier or driver may take breaks at any time during the&#160;trip, and such carrier or driver may complete a scheduled trip if they are over the hours of service maximum on-duty drive schedule and are within 150 miles of their scheduled delivery point.</summary>
</bill>
