<bill session="111" type="h" number="3417" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center to assist in preserving the archeological, anthropological, paleontological, zoological, and geological artifacts and archival documentation from the Rocky Mountain region through the construction of an on-site, secure collections facility for the Denver Museum of Nature &amp; Science in Denver, Colorado.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001172" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001158" joined="2009-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-10-27T16:51:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Rocky Mountain Science Collections Center Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to provide a grant to the Denver Museum of Nature &amp; Science in Denver, Colorado, to pay the federal share of the cost of: (1) constructing one or more on-site collection facilities that meet the standards of the Museum; and (2) obtaining goods and services required by the Museum, including the acquisition of designs, plans, furnishings, equipment, and other support for the Museum.

Requires the Museum, as a condition of receiving such assistance, to match any amounts provided to the Museum under this Act. States that, in order to meet such matching requirement, the Museum may provide to the Secretary cash, in-kind donations, and services.</summary>
</bill>
