<bill session="110" type="h" number="6096" updated="2021-06-07T20:03:48Z">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Child Abduction Progress Reports Act</title>
    <title type="display">International Child Abduction Progress Reports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress annual reports on the progress made by the United States in negotiating international agreements relating to international child abduction with countries that are not contracting parties to the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2008-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-08-08T18:23:27Z" status="Introduced in House">International Child Abduction Progress Reports Act - Directs the Secretary of State to report annually to Congress on progress made by the United States in negotiating and entering into bilateral treaties (or other international agreements) relating to international child abduction with countries that are not parties to the Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to include information on efforts to prohibit international child abduction in the annual human rights and security assistance reports to Congress.

Directs the Attorney General to report annually to Congress respecting each case involving a request for extradition to the United States of an individual alleged to have violated international parental kidnapping provisions.

Authorizes appropriations for extraditing individuals from foreign countries to the United States for violations of U.S. laws by unlawfully removing a child from the child's custodial parent.</summary>
</bill>
