<bill session="116" type="h" number="4427" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:56Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Energy to identify and convey to the State of Colorado land for use as a storage site for residual radioactive material, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy to identify and convey to the State of Colorado land for use as a storage site for residual radioactive material, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000470"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2019-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-06T20:51:07Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to identify a portion of federal land within the Durango disposal site that is suitable for conveyance to Colorado to be used as a storage site for residual radioactive materials as part of remediation activities carried out by the state related to properties in the vicinity of the Durango processing site.

DOE must ensure that the identified land is (1) approximately 0.25 acres, (2) located in the southwestern corner of the Durango disposal site, and (3) south of and bounded by County Road 212.

After DOE offers to convey the identified land to the state, and the state accepts the offer, DOE shall convey to the state all interest of the United States in and to such land.

As a condition of such conveyance, DOE must require the state to manage the conveyed land consistent with the requirements of the Uranium Mill Tailings Radiation Control Act of 1978 relating to the Durango disposal site, including after the use of it has ceased.</summary>
</bill>
