<bill session="118" type="s" number="2349" updated="2025-11-19T03:40:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jimmy Deal Trafficking Survivors Assistance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jimmy Deal Trafficking Survivors Assistance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist trafficking survivors who lack government issued identification in accessing air travel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2023-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5720" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-03T11:13:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Jimmy Deal Trafficking Survivors Assistance Act of 2023

This bill requires the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to&#160;provide air travel assistance for survivors of human trafficking who do not have the identification documents necessary for air travel.

Specifically, the TSA must establish the position of Trafficking Survivor Point of Contact (TSPoC) at every TSA screening airport. The TSPoC must liaise and establish relationships with service providers and provide air travel assistance for survivors of human trafficking.

The TSPoC must provide information to an eligible service provider and assist the provider or the individual (who does not have the identification documents necessary for air travel) throughout the vetting process, travel, and arrival at the destination airport. The bill directs a&#160;TSPoC to follow specific procedures.

Under the bill, a service provider is a nonprofit organization that provides services to individuals who are victims of human trafficking, including (1) emergency services, such as shelter, food, clothing, and transportation; (2) case management or wraparound services; (3) mental health care or other medical services; and (4) legal services.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
