<bill session="116" type="s" number="3915" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Reopening Businesses Recovering from COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Reopening Businesses Recovering from COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to exempt certain businesses from liability arising from claims relating to an individual contracting COVID-19 as a result of patronizing a business or healthcare entity</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000594"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-06T19:46:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Reopening Businesses Recovering from COVID-19 Act

This bill exempts businesses and certain medical entities from liability for damages arising from or relating to an individual contracting COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) during the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Specifically, this exemption applies to businesses, including nonprofit organizations and educational institutions, and medical entities that provide health care services related to COVID-19. Such entities are exempt from liability if they operate consistent with state or federal guidelines or requirements related to reopening and follow guidance from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and any other federal or state agency to mitigate the spread of COVID-19. However, this prohibition does not apply to acts that constitute gross negligence or actions brought by a government entity in a regulatory, supervisory, or enforcement capacity.</summary>
</bill>
