<bill session="116" type="s" number="764" updated="2022-11-01T17:32:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ARTICLE ONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">ARTICLE ONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Assuring that Robust, Thorough, and Informed Congressional Leadership is Exercised Over National Emergencies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ARTICLE ONE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assuring that Robust, Thorough, and Informed Congressional Leadership is Exercised Over National Emergencies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for congressional approval of national emergency declarations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2019-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-159.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="307">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 307.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1755" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1809" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-09T17:51:49Z" status="Reported to Senate">Assuring that Robust, Thorough, and Informed Congressional Leadership is Exercised Over National Emergencies Act or the ARTICLE ONE Act

This bill sets forth procedures for a presidential declaration of a national emergency.

The President is authorized to declare a national emergency by proclamation. Such proclamation must be immediately transmitted to Congress and published in the Federal Register. The President must specify the emergency provisions of law being invoked.

If Congress does not approve the emergency declaration, the President may not declare an emergency with respect to the same circumstances for the remainder of the term of office.

A declaration of emergency shall remain in effect for 30 days from the issuance of the proclamation and shall terminate thereafter unless Congress enacts a joint resolution of approval. If Congress is unable to convene during the 30-day period, such period does not begin until the first day Congress convenes.

Unless otherwise terminated by the President or Congress, a declaration of national emergency shall terminate after one year unless it is renewed by the President and approved by a joint resolution of Congress.

The bill sets forth procedures for congressional review of declarations of national emergencies and excludes from such procedures certain national emergencies invoking the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA).

The President shall (1) transmit specified information to Congress with any proclamation declaring or renewing a national emergency, including a description of the circumstances necessitating the declaration or renewal of a national emergency&#160;declaration&#160;and its estimated duration; and (2) report periodically on the status of the emergency.

The bill amends the IEEPA to prohibit the President from using any authorities of such Act to impose duties or tariff-rate quotas.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-159</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
