<bill session="117" type="s" number="5077" updated="2023-08-15T21:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Incorporated, is recognized as a Village Corporation under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Incorporated, is recognized as a Village Corporation under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9295" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T21:09:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill recognizes Alexander Creek, Incorporated, as an Alaska Native village corporation, subject to certain conditions,&#160;and Alexander Creek village as an Alaska Native village.

Alexander Creek, Incorporated, must submit to the Department of the Interior any amendments to its state corporate charter that are necessary to convert from a group corporation to a village corporation.

The bill requires Interior to offer to enter into negotiations with Alexander Creek, Incorporated, to settle aboriginal land claims and any other claims against the United States. As a condition of recognition as a village corporation, Alexander Creek, Incorporated must enter into such an agreement with Interior no later than 13 months after this bill's enactment.

Alexander Creek, Incorporated, must notify its members that (1) they will cease to receive benefits from Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, individually as at-large shareholders, and (2) all future resource payments shall be retained by Alexander Creek, Incorporated.</summary>
</bill>
