<bill session="118" type="s" number="3050" updated="2025-01-14T17:07:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Artificial Intelligence Advancement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a report on artificial intelligence regulation in the financial services industry, to establish artificial intelligence bug bounty programs, to require a vulnerability analysis study for artificial intelligence-enabled military applications, and to require a report on data sharing and coordination, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Artificial Intelligence Advancement Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2023-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2502" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-10T14:26:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Artificial Intelligence Advancement Act of 2023

This bill requires the development of a bug bounty program within the Department of Defense (DOD) and requires various studies and reports related to artificial intelligence.

The bill requires certain financial entities (e.g., the Federal Reserve System) to report on the knowledge gap on artificial intelligence.

The bill also requires the Chief Digital and Artificial Intelligence Office (CDAO) within DOD to develop a bug bounty program for foundational artificial intelligence models being integrated into DOD missions and operations. Generally, a bug bounty program provides incentives to individuals to discover and report on vulnerabilities in an organization's software or systems.

Not later than one year after the enactment of this bill, CDAO must brief Congress on the development of bug bounty programs and long-term plans with respect to such programs.

The bill also requires CDAO to study the vulnerabilities to the privacy, security, accuracy of, and capacity to assess, artificial intelligence-enabled military applications.

Finally, DOD must report on ways to improve data sharing, interoperability, and quality across DOD.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
