<bill session="118" type="h" number="7036" updated="2024-09-09T13:58:17Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to modify requirements relating to the regulation and examination of credit union organizations and service providers, to provide the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency with the authority to regulate the provision of services provided to the Government-sponsored enterprises and Federal Home Loan Banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-26T15:15:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Cybersecurity for the Financial Sector Act of 2024

This bill provides for the regulation and supervision of certain financial organizations and service providers.

The bill subjects credit union organizations to the same regulation and examination by the Board of Directors of the National Credit Union Administration as insured credit unions. In addition, if a credit union that is subject to examination by the board delegates or contracts for the performance of certain activities and services, this must be disclosed to the board and is subject to regulation and examination by the board.

Further, if the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, any Federal Home Loan Bank, or the Office of Finance of the Federal Home Loan Bank System delegates or contracts for the performance of certain activities and services, this must be disclosed and is subject to regulation and examination by the Federal Housing Finance Agency.</summary>
</bill>
