<bill session="119" type="s" number="1100" updated="2025-08-19T13:38:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nutritious SNAP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nutritious SNAP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act to modify the definition of food under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-19T13:37:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nutritious SNAP Act of 2025

This bill prohibits Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits from being used to purchase certain beverages (e.g., soda) and snack foods.

Specifically, SNAP benefits may only be used to purchase a beverage that is nonalcoholic and is&#160;(1) water, (2) cow's milk, (3) a milk-substitute beverage (e.g., almond milk, soy milk, and coconut milk), or (4) 100% juice.

Further, the bill prohibits the use of benefits to purchase&#160;snack and dessert food items which are included on the Food and Nutrition Service's Accessory Foods List that went into effect on March 5, 2018.&#160;Examples of snack and dessert foods on the list include potato and tortilla chips, ice cream, candy, snack cakes and pastries, and packaged baking mixes for cakes, brownies, and muffins.

In addition, on the request of a state agency, the Department of Agriculture must allow the state agency to prohibit the use of SNAP benefits to purchase food that the applicable&#160;state nutrition&#160;agency determines to be unhealthy food.</summary>
</bill>
