<bill session="116" type="s" number="2361" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Closing the Credit Gap Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Closing the Credit Gap Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to increase lending to underserved borrowers through the largest loan program of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5253" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7903" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-17T17:09:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Closing the Credit Gap Act

This bill establishes a Community Advantage Loan Program under which the Small Business Administration (SBA) may guarantee loans made by covered institutions to small business concerns in underserved markets.

Specifically, the bill makes the Community Advantage Pilot Program (CA) permanent and includes women and minorities as eligible groups for CA loans in addition to the other categories that are currently eligible. The bill requires at least 60% of loans made by a covered institution under the program be made to small business concerns in underserved markets, and it allows the SBA to waive the $250,000 cap on loan sizes up to $350,000. The bill further requires the SBA to provide both in-person and online training and technical assistance that is free or low-cost for covered institutions making loans under the program.

The SBA must establish a working group to develop recommendations for the SBA to effectively manage, support, and promote the program and its mission.

Lastly, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on program outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
