<bill session="110" type="s" number="3530" updated="2017-12-15T00:40:44Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal for organ donors and the family of organ donors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2008-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="7198" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="6950" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-03T20:11:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal Act of 2008 - Makes any organ donor, or the family of any organ donor, eligible for a Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medal.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to direct the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network to establish an application procedure, determine eligibility, and arrange for the presentation of medals.

Allows only one medal per family. Requires that such medal be presented to the donor or, in the case of a deceased donor, the family member who signed the consent form authorizing the organ donation.

Authorizes the Network to collect funds to offset expenditures relating to the issuance of medals.

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to design and strike the Stephanie Tubbs Jones Gift of Life Medals using certain specifications.

Provides that a medal under this Act shall not be treated as valuable consideration for purposes of prohibiting transferring human organs for valuable consideration.</summary>
</bill>
