<bill session="116" type="s" number="2709" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to modify the authority of the National Labor Relations Board with respect to rulemaking, issuance of complaints, and authority over unfair labor practices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-15T19:20:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting American Jobs Act 

This bill modifies provisions governing the National Labor Relations Board to

 repeal the authority of the General Counsel ofthe board, to issue, and prosecute before the board, complaints of unfair labor practices; limit the board's rulemaking authority to rules concerning the internal functions of the board; prohibit the board from promulgating regulations affecting the substantive or procedural rights of any person, employer, employee, or labor organization, including rules concerning unfair labor practices and representation elections; repeal the board's authority to prevent persons from engaging in unfair labor practices, limiting such authority to the investigation of allegations of such practices; and repeal the board's authority to petition courts for enforcement of its orders, seek injunctions, or hold hearings on jurisdictional strikes.</summary>
</bill>
