<bill session="117" type="h" number="8711" updated="2022-12-29T19:03:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States-Ecuador Partnership Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Ecuador Partnership Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the bilateral partnership between the United States and Ecuador in support of democratic institutions and rule of law, sustainable and inclusive economic growth, and conservation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2022-08-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere, Civilian Security, Migration and International Economic Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3591" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-02T18:01:31Z" status="Introduced in House">United States-Ecuador Partnership Act of 2022

This bill requires and authorizes actions to strengthen the U.S.-Ecuador relationship.

The President may transfer two excess Coast Guard vessels to Ecuador if there is sufficient capacity to maintain the vessels.

The Department of State must develop and implement a strategy to strengthen commercial and economic ties between the United States and Ecuador, including by (1) promoting cooperation and information sharing to increase trade and investment opportunities, and (2) supporting efforts by Ecuador's government to promote a more open and competitive business environment.

The State Department must also develop and implement a strategy to increase the capacity of Ecuador's justice system and law enforcement to combat crime, corruption, and the harmful influence of malign foreign and domestic actors.

The U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) must develop and implement a strategy to support inclusive economic development across Ecuador's national territory, including by facilitating increased access to financing and investment for small- and medium-sized businesses.

USAID must also, by working through appropriate nonprofit organizations, develop and implement programs to provide training and technical assistance to strengthen the National Assembly of Ecuador.

USAID must also develop and implement programs to improve ecosystem conservation and enhance the effective stewardship of Ecuador's natural resources.

The State Department and USAID must periodically report to Congress on the implementation of these strategies and programs.</summary>
</bill>
