<bill session="109" type="s" number="1560" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:21Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Commission on Expanding Social Service Delivery Options Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Congressional Commission on Expanding Social Service Delivery Options.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Commission on Expanding Social Service Delivery Options Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9476"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-31T15:29:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Congressional Commission on Expanding Social Service Delivery Options Act - Establishes a Congressional Commission on Expanding Social Service Delivery Options.

Directs the Commission to: (1) study all matters relating to increasing beneficiary-selected or beneficiary-directed options for social service delivery (delivery options) in federal social service programs, including certificate, scholarship, voucher, or other forms of indirect delivery; (2) review all relevant existing programs, including initiatives of the Corporation for National and Community Service; and (3) determine and recommend program areas for which it is appropriate and feasible to implement such delivery options fully or partially. Requires the Commission to promote goals of: (1) expanding consumer and beneficiary choice in such programs; (2) maximizing use of governmental resources in them; and (3) minimizing concerns relating to any precedent under the Constitution regarding participation in them of faith-based providers.</summary>
</bill>
