<bill session="116" type="h" number="8147" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:03Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TREAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Testing, Researching, and Expanding Alternative Treatments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TREAT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to expand an existing pilot program, and to establish a new pilot program, related to complementary and integrative health services for veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2020-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative treatments"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-06T15:45:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Testing, Researching, and Expanding Alternative Treatments Act or the TREAT Act

This bill addresses Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) pilot programs related to complementary and integrative health services.

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to expand the pilot program on using complementary and integrative health services (e.g., meditation) to complement pain management and mental health treatment for veterans.

The bill also requires the VA to implement a three-year pilot program to provide complementary and integrative health services (e.g., animal therapy) to eligible veterans for the treatment of post-traumatic stress disorder, depression, or anxiety. Eligible veterans are those who are enrolled in the VA health care system and have received care from the VA or rehabilitation or counseling services from a Vet Center within the last two years. The VA must enter agreements with academic researchers to study the effectiveness of the treatments in the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
