<bill session="116" type="s" number="3494" updated="2022-02-09T04:18:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Layoff Prevention Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Layoff Prevention Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for temporary financing of short-time compensation programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6379" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8213" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-06T15:17:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Layoff Prevention Act of 2020

This bill provides 100% of temporary federal financing of limited short-time compensation (STC) payments in states with existing or new STC programs. (STC, also known as work sharing, is a program within the federal-state unemployment system that provides pro-rated unemployment compensation to workers whose hours have been reduced in lieu of a layoff.)

Certain states without an STC program may enter into an agreement with the Department of Labor under which Labor will temporarily finance 50% of the state's STC payments. If such a state subsequently enacts a state law implementing a STC program that meets federal requirements it shall be ineligible for such 50% financing, but shall be eligible for the 100% financing. Federal financing of STC payments is limited to 260 weeks.

Labor must

 award grants to states that enact STC programs to implement or improve administration of such programs and promote and enroll employers in STC programs; develop and provide model legislative language for states&#160;to develop and enact STC programs, including periodically reviewing and revising such language; provide technical assistance and guidance in developing, enacting, and implementing STC programs; and establish certain STC reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
