<bill session="117" type="h" number="1421" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:01Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Territories College Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program that enables college-bound residents of outlying areas of the United States to have greater choices among institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Territories College Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000610"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-12T15:55:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Territories College Access Act

This bill establishes a grant program to cover the difference between in-state and out-of-state tuition and fees for students who are residents of an outlying area (i.e., American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, or the Virgin Islands) and who attend a public institution of higher education located in a state, the District of Columbia, or Puerto Rico.

A student on whose behalf a grant is made must maintain full-time employment within the outlying area for at least two years. Further, a student who completes less than the required two years of employment must repay the grant, or the grant must be treated as a loan that is subject to repayment.

Lastly, the Government Accountability Office must report on the program's effectiveness in expanding educational opportunities for these students.</summary>
</bill>
