<bill session="116" type="h" number="8365" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accurate Weather for Public Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Weather for Public Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To study the effects of new construction of obstructions on accurate weather forecasting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000238"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-09T14:34:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurate Weather for Public Safety Act

This bill requires a strategy and studies to address obstructions to accurate weather observations forecasting.

The bill expands notice requirements relating to structures that interfere with air commerce or national security to require public notice of the construction or expansion of a structure or sanitary landfill when such notice will promote the ability of any federal agency engaged in meteorological or atmospheric observations to accurately forecast weather.

The Department of Commerce must designate a senior official of the National Weather Service (NWS) and a lead organization of the NWS to serve as (1) the executive agent to carry out the strategy for addressing the weather forecasting and public safety impacts of certain Department of Transportation (DOT) projects, and (2) a clearinghouse to coordinate Commerce review of applications for such projects.

Commerce must develop a comprehensive strategy for addressing the weather forecasting and public safety impacts of such DOT projects.</summary>
</bill>
