<bill session="117" type="s" number="4687" updated="2023-09-01T14:00:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding the Homeland from the Threats Posed by Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding the Homeland from the Threats Posed by Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Safeguarding the Homeland from the Threats Posed by Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the authority granted to the Department of Homeland Security and Department of Justice with respect to unmanned aircraft systems and unmanned aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2022-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2022-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2022-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2022-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-277.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="676">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 676.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T13:33:41Z" status="Reported to Senate">Safeguarding the Homeland from the Threats Posed by Unmanned Aircraft Systems Act of 2022 

This bill provides statutory authority for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Department of Justice (DOJ) to authorize their personnel to act to detect, identify, monitor, track, and mitigate a credible threat that an unmanned aircraft system (i.e., drone) poses to the safety or security of certain facilities or assets.

For example, DHS and DOJ may carry out a pilot program to evaluate the potential benefits of state, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement agencies taking actions to mitigate credible unmanned aircraft system threats.

Additionally, DHS and DOJ must coordinate with the Federal Aviation Administration before carrying out any action authorized by the bill to ensure the action does not adversely impact or interfere with safe airport operations, navigation, air traffic services, or the safe and efficient operation of the national airspace system.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-277</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
