<bill session="118" type="s" number="1425" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Satellite Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Satellite Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Satellite Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a report on Federal support to the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-05">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-92.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-09-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="195">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 195.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-23T11:58:12Z" status="Reported to Senate">Satellite Cybersecurity Act

This bill requires the dissemination of information and other activities to address cybersecurity risks to commercial satellite systems.

Specifically, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must (1) maintain a publicly available clearinghouse of resources concerning the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems; and (2) consolidate voluntary recommendations for developing, maintaining, and operating those systems, including recommendations for protecting systems against cyber-related risks and attacks. To the extent practicable, CISA must implement these activities as a public-private partnership.

In addition, the National Space Council and the White House Office of the National Cyber Director must develop a national strategy for addressing and improving the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems.

Further, the Government Accountability Office must report on federal actions to support and improve the cybersecurity of commercial satellite systems, including actions taken to address the cybersecurity of critical infrastructure sectors. The report must cover, among other topics, the effectiveness of those actions and the reliance of federal agencies on commercial satellite systems (particularly those with ties to foreign countries).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-92</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
