<bill session="116" type="h" number="6212" updated="2022-02-16T16:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for the continuation of Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance benefits during emergency situations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continuation of Department of Veterans Affairs educational assistance benefits during emergency situations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-16T16:43:09Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to continue to provide educational assistance during the 180-day period after the enactment of this bill for programs of education that are offered by distance learning or have been converted to distance learning due to an emergency or health-related situation.

The VA is authorized to continue paying educational assistance and subsistence allowances for up to eight weeks to eligible veterans or persons enrolled in specified programs of education or training during periods when educational institutions are temporarily closed due to an emergency situation or based on an executive order. The bill defines emergency situation as a public health crisis, a declared state of emergency, or other situations as determined by the VA.</summary>
</bill>
