<bill session="119" type="h" number="2227" updated="2025-09-03T08:05:21Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WOLF Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WOLF Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WOlf and Livestock Fairness Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to provide emergency relief to producers of livestock with herds adversely affected by Mexican gray wolves, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001133" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000273" joined="2025-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2025-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-23T13:57:57Z" status="Introduced in House">WOlf and Livestock Fairness Act of 2025 or the WOLF Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide emergency relief to producers of livestock with herds adversely affected by Mexican gray wolves.

Specifically, the bill directs the Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-Raised Fish Program (ELAP)&#160;to provide emergency relief to producers of livestock with herds adversely affected by Mexican gray wolves. USDA must develop a formula to determine the amount of emergency relief to provide to a producer of livestock. Among other factors, the formula must take into consideration the herd size of the producer and the&#160;average annual&#160;increase in management costs for producers in the state due to Mexican gray wolves.

Additionally, the bill modifies USDA's Livestock Indemnity Program. In the case of attacks on livestock by Mexican gray wolves, the bill increases the&#160;payment rate from 75% to 100% of the market value of the affected livestock.</summary>
</bill>
