<bill session="118" type="h" number="68" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Women, Families with Children, Race, and Persons with Disabilities Housing Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-07-17" withdrawn="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2023-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2024-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2024-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2024-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000468" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2024-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2024-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2024-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-19T20:56:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans, Women, Families with Children, Race, and Persons with Disabilities Housing Fairness Act of 2023 or the Housing Fairness Act of 2023

This bill expands efforts to detect and address housing discrimination.

Specifically, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) must conduct a nationwide testing program to (1) detect and document differences in the treatment of prospective renters, homebuyers, or mortgage borrowers; (2) measure patterns of adverse treatment because of the race, color, religion, sex, familial status, disability status, or national origin of a renter, homebuyer, or borrower; and (3) measure the prevalence of such discriminatory practices across housing and mortgage lending markets.

The bill also reauthorizes through FY2027 the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, which supports organizations that provide direct assistance to individuals who have been victims of housing discrimination.

Additionally, HUD must implement a grant program to assist public and private nonprofit organizations in (1) conducting comprehensive studies on the causes or effects of housing discrimination and segregation, and (2) implementing pilot projects that test solutions to help prevent or alleviate housing discrimination and segregation.</summary>
</bill>
