<bill session="115" type="h" number="6492" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:58Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-06T18:06:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2018

The bill designates specified lands in Colorado managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the Forest Service as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill designates specified lands in Colorado administered by the BLM, Forest Service, and Bureau of Reclamation as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System and&#160;incorporates such lands into the West Elk Wilderness.

The Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, may conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this bill.

The bill designates specified lands managed by the BLM as potential wilderness areas, to be known as the Deep Creek Wilderness and the Pisgah Mountain Wilderness.

The bill provides for the securing, adjudication, and use of&#160; U.S. water rights for certain of the wilderness areas designated by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
