<bill session="118" type="h" number="3330" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CABLE Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CABLE Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting And Building Lines for Expedited Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to preserve cable franchising authority, provide for faster deployment of cable and other services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000589"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-18T20:10:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Connecting And Building Lines for Expedited Expansion Act or the CABLE Expansion Act

This bill modifies the requirements governing decisions about the placement, construction, or modification of equipment and related facilities that are used in or attached to cable communications systems.

Specifically, state or local governments, their instrumentalities, or franchise authorities (state or local entities that regulate certain aspects of cable operators) may not regulate the placement, construction, or modification of cable equipment or facilities in a manner that effectively prohibits a cable operator from providing or enhancing its service under a franchise granted by one of those entities.

Additionally, the bill requires those entities to approve or deny a complete request to place, construct, or modify cable equipment or facilities within specified time frames. Failure to respond to the request within the specified time frame deems it automatically approved. Further, the bill requires that any denial of a request must be in writing, supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record, and publicly released at the same time as the decision is made.

The bill also permits an entity to charge fees for considering requests provided that the fees are (1) nondiscriminatory, (2) publicly disclosed in advance, and (3) based on actual and direct costs.

The modifications concerning the time frames for decisions and the fees apply retroactively to requests that are submitted prior to the enactment of the bill but have not been approved or denied.</summary>
</bill>
