<bill session="118" type="h" number="9869" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gold Star Children Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gold Star Children Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make dependents of members of the Armed Forces who died while serving on active duty eligible for enrollment in Department of Defense Education Activity schools on a tuition-free, space-available basis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2024-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-15T16:15:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Gold Star Children Education Act of 2024

This bill provides eligibility for enrollment in schools operated by the Department of Defense Education Activity (DODEA) to dependents of certain deceased members of the Armed Forces.

Specifically, the bill provides eligibility to dependents of members of the Armed Forces who died while serving on active duty or active Guard and Reserve duty. Such dependents are eligible to enroll in DODEA schools regardless of (1) whether the dependent was enrolled on the date of the death of the member, or (2) the proximity of the school to the location where the dependent resided on the date of the death.

Enrollment of such dependents must be on a tuition-free and space-available basis.</summary>
</bill>
