<bill session="111" type="h" number="3088" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jeremy Warriner Consumer Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an automobile manufacturer that the Federal Government has an ownership interest in or that has an outstanding loan from the Federal Government to purchase liability insurance from an insurance company.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jeremy Warriner Consumer Protection Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2009-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001174" joined="2009-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-25T21:18:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Jeremy Warriner Consumer Protection Act of 2009 - Requires an automobile manufacturer to purchase liability insurance from an insurance company if: (1) the federal government has an ownership interest in the manaufacturer; or (2) the manufacturer has an outstanding federal loan.

Prescribes specifications for such product liability coverage.

Declares null and void any defense to a liability claim that is predicated upon bankruptcy by an automobile manufacturer that is a named insured under a liability insurance plan.

Requires the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA) to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to implement such insurance requirement.

Authorizes the Administrator to impose against any automobile manufacturer for non-compliance with this Act a civil penalty of up to five times the amount it would have cost such manufacturer to purchase the requisite liability insurance.</summary>
</bill>
