<bill session="116" type="s" number="4102" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">College Athlete Pandemic Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Athlete Pandemic Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that institutions of higher education take steps to protect their college athletes from COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-12T17:43:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">College Athlete Pandemic Safety Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to take certain health and safety actions to respond to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019), specifically for college athletes.

Specifically, the bill prohibits IHEs from (1) allowing any individual to agree to a liability waiver for any sporting activity, or (2) canceling a scholarship or any other financial aid provided to a college athlete who does not participate in team activities due to concerns about COVID-19.

Further, each IHE must inform its college athletes when a college athlete or a staff member of its athletic department tests positive for COVID-19, without revealing any personally identifiable information about the individual.

Additionally, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must, within 90 days, develop health and safety guidelines related to COVID-19 for athletic departments of IHEs. IHEs must comply with these guidelines.

The bill also provides a private right of action for individuals affected by violations of the bill.</summary>
</bill>
