<bill session="117" type="h" number="2825" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fort McClellan Health Registry Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a registry of certain veterans who were stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fort McClellan Health Registry Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2021-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3967" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-12T16:26:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Fort McClellan Health Registry Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish and maintain the Fort McClellan Health Registry, which must include a list of names of those who were stationed at Fort McClellan, Alabama, between January 1, 1935, and May 20, 1999, and are seeking specified health care or benefits from the VA.

Specifically, the registry must include those who

 apply for hospital, nursing home, domiciliary, or medical care from the VA; file a claim for compensation for service-connected disability; die and are survived by a spouse, child, or parent who files a claim for dependency and indemnity compensation; request a VA health examination; or receive a VA health examination and request to be included in the registry. The registry must also include relevant medical data of the listed individuals if they grant permission or are deceased at the time they are listed.

Individuals who have submitted applications, requests, or claims prior to the enactment of this bill must be included in the registry to the extent feasible.

The VA must periodically notify individuals listed in the registry of significant research developments on the health consequences of potential exposure to toxic substances or environmental hazards related to service at Fort McClellan. Additionally, the VA must reach out to individuals regarding the provision of health examinations and consultation and counseling services.

In establishing and maintaining the registry, the VA must consult with the Department of Defense to acquire necessary information.</summary>
</bill>
