<bill session="108" type="s" number="2065" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keep Our Promise to America's Military Retirees Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restore health care coverage to retired members of the uniformed services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep Our Promise to America's Military Retirees Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2004-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2004-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2004-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2004-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2004-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2004-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3474" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-03T21:12:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keep Our Promise to America's Military Retirees Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to enter into an agreement with the Office of Personnel Management to provide Federal Employees Health Benefits (FEHB) coverage to the following eligible beneficiaries: (1) a member or former member entitled to military retired or retainer pay; (2) an unremarried former spouse who was married to a member for at least 20 years, during which such member performed at least 20 years of retirement-creditable military service; (3) a dependent of a deceased qualifying member or former member; (4) a dependent of a living member or former member; and (5) a family member.

Directs the Secretary to reimburse such eligible persons for pharmacy benefits received from a pharmacy that is not a TRICARE (Department of Defense managed health care plan) network pharmacy in the same manner as the Secretary would reimburse such person for such benefits received from a TRICARE network pharmacy. Requires such persons, in order to receive such reimbursement, to submit a certification from their physician stating that the person does not have access to a TRICARE network pharmacy due to physical or medical constraints.

Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to waive the monthly part B premium (Supplementary Medical Insurance Benefits for the Aged and Disabled) with respect to: (1) an individual who is entitled to military retired or retainer pay based upon service that began before December 7, 1956; and (2) the spouse, widow, or widower of such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
