<bill session="117" type="h" number="7937" updated="2023-08-31T17:30:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RENEW Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RENEW Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revitalize, Enhance, and Nurture in Expanded Ways Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, to establish a program to facilitate coal mine reclamation and award grants to certain States and Indian Tribes to carry out coal mine reclamation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2022-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-21T19:27:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Revitalize, Enhance, and Nurture in Expanded Ways Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act or the RENEW Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act

This bill authorizes grants for states and Indian tribes to carry out reclamation projects on mining sites if there is a shortfall between the actual cost of reclamation and the value of any performance bonds forfeited by coal mining operators. The bill also phases out certain cost-sharing requirements for existing grants that support the development of state and tribal programs for regulating surface mining and reclamation.

Current law requires mining operators to reclaim land affected by their operations and demonstrate, through a performance bond, that they have adequate financial resources to carry out the reclamation. If the operator fails to complete the reclamation, the bond is forfeited to the state or tribal regulatory authority to cover reclamation costs.</summary>
</bill>
