<bill session="111" type="h" number="2280" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:17Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Funding for Schools Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the impact aid program under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Funding for Schools Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2009-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000794" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000369" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001165" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000169" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000571" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1073"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-27T19:35:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Funding for Schools Act of 2009 - Amends the Impact Aid program (which compensates local educational agencies (LEAs) for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their areas) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to alter the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for federal ownership of property when appropriations for a fiscal year are insufficient to provide them with full compensation.

Alters the formula for determining the payments due LEAs for eligible federally-connected children.

Includes not only children in average daily attendance, but also those enrolled pursuant to a state open enrollment policy. Continues an LEA's eligibility for such payments while activities associated with military base closures and realignments or force structure changes or relocations are ongoing. Allows the calculation of such payments using current student counts instead of prior fiscal year data when LEAs experience a specified influx of new students due to federal activities.

Requires the Secretary of Education to allow LEAs to count their federally-connected children using the date they register their students for the fiscal year for which their application is filed.

Alters the formula for determining the construction payments due LEAs that are eligible for other Impact Aid payments.

Divides 80% of the construction funds evenly between LEAs impacted by military dependent children and LEAs impacted by children residing on Indian lands, with the remainder reserved for emergency repair and modernization grants to LEAs serving Indian lands or experiencing a specified influx of new students due to federal activities.

Alters the formula for determining whether a state's plan for equalizing assistance to its LEAs will except it from the prohibition on state aid to LEAs being affected by Impact Aid payments.

Requires new LEAs applying for Impact Aid to have boundaries established by state law and the authority to tax or receive an imputed local tax.

Reauthorizes appropriations for the Impact Aid program.</summary>
</bill>
