<bill session="116" type="h" number="2956" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for the establishment of the Western Riverside County Wildlife Refuge.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of the Western Riverside County Wildlife Refuge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2019-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2019-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-629.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-08" calendar="Union" number="514">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 514.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-17T17:54:26Z" status="Reported to House">This bill directs the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) to establish the Western Riverside County National Wildlife Refuge in California.

 USFWS must include within the boundaries of the refuge the lands and waters within the Western Riverside County Multiple Species Habitat Conservation Plan Area that are owned by the federal government, a state, or a political subdivision of a state upon the establishment of the refuge.

 USFWS may enter into cooperative agreements with the State of California, any of its political subdivisions, or any other persons to (1) manage lands that are owned by California, the subdivision, or the other person and located within the refuge; (2) promote public awareness of the natural resources of the conservation area; or (3) encourage participation by the public in the conservation of such resources.

 USFWS may acquire by donation, purchase, or exchange the lands and waters or interests in them (including conservation easements) within the refuge, except those that are owned by California and its political subdivisions may be acquired by donation only.

 Federal property in the refuge must be assessed for inclusion in the refuge and must be transferred to USFWS if deemed suitable for inclusion.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-629</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
