<bill session="116" type="h" number="4596" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Loan Advocacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve service to students and other participants in the Federal student financial assistance programs, to establish the Office of the Borrower Advocate to replace the Student Loan Ombudsman, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Loan Advocacy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2019-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4627" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4674" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-08T14:31:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Loan Advocacy Act

This bill revises the purpose, authority, and management of the Office of Federal Student Aid (FSA), and it establishes the Office of the Borrower Advocate within the FSA to assist borrowers in resolving certain problems.

The FSA is the performance-based organization responsible for managing the administrative and oversight functions supporting federal student aid programs. The bill places certain transparency, oversight, and accountability requirements (e.g., data collection, sharing, and publication) on the FSA, and it revises requirements related to the FSA's performance plan and reporting on such performance.

The bill also establishes the Office of the Borrower Advocate to replace the Student Loan Ombudsman that is currently responsible for informally resolving complaints from student loan borrowers. This office shall (1) assist student loan borrowers in resolving problems with the FSA; (2) compile, analyze, publish, and attempt to resolve borrowers' complaints; and (3) make recommendations with respect to federal student loan programs and the experiences of borrowers in repayment under such programs. The bill also places additional requirements on the office such as making certain student loan oversight information available to the public.</summary>
</bill>
