<bill session="118" type="hr" number="1287" updated="2025-09-02T15:37:18Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-12T11:17:42-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-06-12T11:17:42-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8070) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2025 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year; relating to the consideration of House Report 118-527 and an accompanying resolution; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8070) to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2025 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year; relating to the consideration of House Report 118-527 and an accompanying resolution; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001189"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-11">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-551, by Mr. Scott, Austin.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-11T21:17:15-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8070 under a structured rule and the resolution accompanying House Report 118-527 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on each measure and one motion to recommit on H.R. 8070.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-11" calendar="House" number="82">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T09:15:54-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3730-3736" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T09:20:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1287.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T10:07:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1287, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Scanlon demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T10:30:39-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3737-3738" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T11:09:41-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 204 (Roll no. 250).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="251" datetime="2024-06-12T11:17:42-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 208 - 207 (Roll no. 251).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3730-3731" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12T11:17:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8070" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-02T15:37:08Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 8070 (Servicemember Quality of Life Improvement and National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2025, which authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies for Department of Defense programs and activities; military construction; the national security programs of the Department of Energy; the Maritime Administration; the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; and the Naval Petroleum Reserves).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-551</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
