<bill session="117" type="s" number="4122" updated="2023-09-06T19:30:04Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housatonic Wild and Scenic River Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housatonic Wild and Scenic River Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Housatonic River in the State of Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7551" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-10T15:38:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housatonic Wild and Scenic River Act of 2022

This bill designates specified segments of the Housatonic River in Connecticut as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

The designation of the river segments must not impact or alter the existing terms of permitting, licensing, or operation of

 the Falls Village Hydroelectric Generating Station located in Falls Village, Connecticut, or the Bulls Bridge Hydroelectric Generating Station located in New Milford, Connecticut. The designation of the river segments must also not preclude the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission from licensing, relicensing, or otherwise authorizing the operation or continued operation of those facilities.

The authority of the Department of the Interior to acquire lands for the river segments shall be

 limited to acquisition by donation or acquisition with the consent of the owner, and subject to the additional criteria set forth in the Housatonic River Management Plan. No land or interest in land may be acquired for the river segments by condemnation.</summary>
</bill>
