<bill session="118" type="s" number="3888" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TAME Extreme Weather Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TAME Extreme Weather Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transformational Artificial intelligence to Modernize the Economy against Extreme Weather Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to mandate the use of artificial intelligence by Federal agencies to adapt to extreme weather, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2024-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2024-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-24T19:54:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transformational Artificial intelligence to Modernize the Economy against Extreme Weather Act or the TAME Extreme Weather Act

This bill requires several agencies to develop programs that use artificial intelligence (AI) to support weather forecasting, environmental monitoring, and the energy grid.

For example, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must develop an Earth system reanalysis dataset that provides a record of past weather events so as to support AI weather forecast applications. NOAA must also develop an AI program that analyzes environmental data to support wildfire forecasts.&#160;

Additionally, the Department of Agriculture must use AI to analyze data with respect to deforestation, the movement of illegal wood products, and associated changes. The Department of Energy must establish an AI program to optimize energy grids with respect to energy production, stability, and efficiency.</summary>
</bill>
