<bill session="116" type="h" number="2589" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-26T13:58:55-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-09-26T13:58:55-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unifying DHS Intelligence Components Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a homeland intelligence doctrine for the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Unifying DHS Intelligence Components Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Unifying DHS Intelligence Enterprise Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 116-94.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-05-30" calendar="Union" number="69">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 69.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26T13:49:45-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Jackson Lee moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26T13:49:57-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8015-8019" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26T13:49:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2589.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-09-26T13:58:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8015-8016" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26T13:58:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-286.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-11-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="578">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 578.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8309" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-30T19:10:47Z" status="Reported to Senate">Unifying DHS Intelligence Components Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and disseminate written DHS-wide intelligence doctrine for the intelligence components of DHS and develop specified DHS-wide policies, standards, and programs.

Specifically, DHS must develop department-wide (1) policies, standards, and programs for training regarding the collection, processing, analysis, and dissemination of intelligence information, intelligence-related information, and terrorism information by personnel within the DHS intelligence components; and (2) policies for gathering and developing lessons learned, disseminating the lessons learned to personnel within the intelligence components, and using the lessons learned to inform the further development of the intelligence doctrine.

The intelligence doctrine, policies, standards, and programs must include, among other things (1) a description of the fundamental principles guiding the collection, processing, analysis, and dissemination of intelligence information by, and oversight of the intelligence activities of, the intelligence components; and (2) a standardized terminology.

The Government Accountability Office must submit a report to the congressional intelligence and homeland security committees that

 assesses the degree to which the DHS intelligence doctrine, policies, standards, and programs are implemented across DHS; evaluates the extent to which such intelligence doctrine, policies, standards, and programs are carried out to protect privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties; and incorporates an in-depth analysis, including an assessment of the effectiveness and possible areas for improvement, of specified DHS intelligence-related training programs. DHS must provide a staff with appropriate expertise and experience to the Office of the Chief Intelligence Officer to assist the office.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-94</report>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-286</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
