<bill session="117" type="h" number="7574" updated="2023-08-08T14:30:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense Budget Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Budget Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an independent study and report on the effect of pass-through budgeting on the Department of the Air Force, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2022-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T14:18:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Defense Budget Transparency Act of 2022

This bill requires research and specified action related to pass-through budgeting for military departments. Pass-through budgeting refers to the practice by which certain funds allocated for a military department are subject to the authority of other departments and agencies of the federal government but are included in the overall budget of the military department despite the department's lack of authority over the funds.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to seek to enter a contract with an independent research organization to conduct a study on the effects of pass-through budgeting on the Department of the Air Force and other DOD organizations and elements.

For each fiscal year beginning with FY2024, the budget justification materials submitted in support of the DOD budget must include separate line items for each military department to clearly identify any amounts requested that are subject to pass-through budgeting.</summary>
</bill>
