<bill session="112" type="h" number="4216" updated="2022-03-02T05:13:14Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Counterfeit Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Foreign Counterfeit Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the exchange of information related to trade enforcement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2012-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2012-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="6654" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-07-12T15:53:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Counterfeit Prevention Act - Amends the federal criminal code to provide that it shall not be a violation of the prohibition against a federal employee disclosing trade secrets or other confidential or proprietary information for an officer or employee of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP): (1) at the time that merchandise is presented for examination and thereafter, to provide the owner of a copyright or a registered mark or any person who may be injured by a circumvention of copyright protection systems with any information appearing on the merchandise, including its retail packaging, or a sample or image of such merchandise and its retail packaging, for the purposes of determining whether the merchandise or its packaging infringes the copyright, bears or consists of a counterfeit mark of the registered mark, or is a violation of copyright protection systems; or (2) after a determination is made that merchandise is in violation of copyright protection systems, to provide certain information to persons injured by such violation, including the date of importation, the U.S. port of entry at which the merchandise was seized, a description of the merchandise, the country of origin of the merchandise, the names and addresses of the foreign manufacturer, the exporter, and the importer of the merchandise, and a photographic or digital image of the merchandise.</summary>
</bill>
