<bill session="108" type="h" number="1763" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:04Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Competition in Radio and Concert Industries Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to facilitate an increase in programming and content on radio that is locally and independently produced, to facilitate competition in radio programming, radio advertising, and concerts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Competition in Radio and Concert Industries Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000792"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2003-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="221" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Direct broadcast satellites"/>
    <term name="Entertainers"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio programs"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Competition in Radio and Concert Industries Act of 2003 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to authorize the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to revoke any broadcast station license or construction permit for: (1) willful and repeated unfair or deceptive acts or practices that significantly hinder or prevent the broadcast of programming or content produced, promoted, or created by a person independent of the licensee or permittee; or (2) conviction or final adjudication of an antitrust unfair trade practice violation regarding concert venues or promotion.Directs the FCC to prescribe regulations which address: (1) improperly influencing the sale of satellite cable programming or content to any other radio station or unaffiliated concert venue, or of any song, work, or sound recording, programming, concert performance, or concert promotion to persons not affiliated with the licensee, permittee, or affiliate thereof; (2) discrimination against unaffiliated musicians or content providers; and (3) the making of exclusive contracts with musicians or providers which prevent other licensees or permittees from obtaining programming or content from such musicians or providers.Requires the FCC to: (1) designate for hearing any radio broadcasting application that would result in the applicant owning, operating, or controlling radio stations having a national audience reach exceeding 60 percent; (2) review the use of privately-controlled audience measurement systems for the determination of local markets of radio stations; (3) modify its rules concerning attributable interests in radio stations and limitations on local marketing agreements; and (4) prohibit the licensee of any radio station from using its control over broadcasting matter to extract or receive money or other valuable consideration from a record company, artist, concert promoter, or related entity.</summary>
</bill>
