<bill session="116" type="s" number="2953" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring a Durable Afghanistan Peace Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring a Durable Afghanistan Peace Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide congressional oversight of United States talks with Taliban officials and Afghanistan's comprehensive peace process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-26T15:46:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ensuring a Durable Afghanistan Peace Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of State and the President to report on any agreement with Taliban officials and the peace process in Afghanistan.

Specifically, the bill requires the State Department to submit to Congress any agreement with Taliban officials related to counterterrorism assurances by the Taliban, U.S. troop withdrawals from Afghanistan, and the status of intra-Afghan negotiations and a comprehensive cease-fire.

Following the finalization of an agreement with Taliban officials, the State Department must report on Taliban officials' compliance with obligations and commitments under the agreement, whether Taliban officials and the Haqqani Network have broken ties with&#160;Al Qaeda, the viability of the intra-Afghan governing agreement, and whether the terms of the cease-fire are being met by all sides in the conflict. In addition, the President must submit a biannual report assessing whether key tenets of such agreement with Taliban officials are preserved and honored.</summary>
</bill>
