<bill session="116" type="s" number="4118" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:06Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Pandemic Preparedness and Response Through Diplomacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Pandemic Preparedness and Response Through Diplomacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the President to appoint a Special Presidential Envoy for Pandemic Preparedness and Response, who shall develop and implement a diplomatic strategy to prepare for, detect, respond to, and recover from pandemics and other global outbreaks of infectious disease, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-13T22:07:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Pandemic Preparedness and Response Through Diplomacy Act

This bill requires the President to appoint a Special Presidential Envoy for Pandemic Preparedness and Response, who shall supervise diplomatic efforts to prepare for, detect, respond to, and recover from pandemics and other global outbreaks of infectious disease. The bill also requires the Department of the Treasury to remit all U.S.-assessed contributions to the World Health Organization.

The envoy must develop and implement a diplomatic strategy that addresses, among other things (1) the development of medical countermeasures for emerging infectious diseases; (2) zoonotic (animal-to-human transmission) disease prevention, detection, and response; (3) the development of disease surveillance systems; and (4) efforts to combat the spread of disinformation and discrimination related to the outbreak and spread of infectious disease.

The envoy shall regularly convene (1) an interagency steering committee to aid in the development, coordination, and implementation of this strategy; and (2) an outside panel of experts to advise on scientific, technical, and policy matters and to make recommendations for the diplomatic strategy.</summary>
</bill>
