<bill session="117" type="h" number="6982" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Lands Telecommunications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Lands Telecommunications Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support the establishment and improvement of communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands through the retention and use of rental fees associated with such sites, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2022-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2022-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T21:11:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Lands Telecommunications Act

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to establish separate special accounts for the National Park Service, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Bureau of Reclamation for the deposit of rental fees received by such agencies under communications use authorizations, which allow for the occupancy and use of federal lands for communications purposes.

The rental fees received by each agency shall

 be deposited in the agency's special account, and remain available for expenditure for agency activities related to communications sites (those areas of federal lands designated for telecommunications uses). The Departments of the Interior and Agriculture may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out activities related to communications sites.</summary>
</bill>
