<bill session="118" type="h" number="7630" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:10Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:41-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:41-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="display">ANCHOR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2024-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 38 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-23">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 118-521.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-05-23" calendar="Union" number="433">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 433.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:30:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:30:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5629-5631" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:30:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7630.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5629-5630" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="526">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 526.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3943" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-27T10:20:05Z" status="Passed House">Accelerating Networking, Cyberinfrastructure, and Hardware for Oceanic Research Act or the ANCHOR Act

This bill requires the National Science Foundation&#160;(NSF) to develop a plan to improve the cybersecurity and telecommunications of the U.S. Academic Research Fleet (ARF).&#160;The plan must be provided to Congress within one&#160;year after the bill is enacted.

ARF is comprised of U.S.-flagged vessels that provide at-sea laboratories where oceanographic scientists, educators, and students research and learn about marine science.&#160;

The bill requires a plan to include assessments of (1) telecommunications and networking needs of ARF, consistent with typical scientific missions; (2) cybersecurity needs appropriate for the ownership of ARF vessels and their typical functions; (3) the costs necessary to meet these needs; and (4) the time required to implement necessary upgrades. The plan must also include a spending plan and a proposal for adopting common solutions, consortial licensing agreements, or a solution for centralizing cybersecurity, telecommunications, and data systems at a single facility.

Among other factors specified in the bill, the NSF must consider approaches to align with international standards for encryption of sensitive information, requirements for controlled classified or unclassified information, and the network capabilities necessary to meet particular mission needs (such as to upload data to shoreside servers or to enable video communications with K-12 classrooms).

The NSF must provide Congress with a report on the plan's implementation within two years after the plan is&#160;provided to Congress.&#160;&#160;&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-521</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
