<bill session="111" type="h" number="5237" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:13Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Expatriation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To add joining a foreign terrorist organization or engaging in or supporting hostilities against the United States or its allies to the list of acts for which United States nationals would lose their nationality.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Expatriation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000362"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2010-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2010-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3327" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-10-13T16:31:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Terrorist Expatriation Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to include among those voluntary acts for which a U.S. national (by birth or naturalization) will be subject to loss of U.S. nationality: (1) providing material support or resources to a foreign terrorist organization as designated by the Secretary of State; (2) engaging in, or purposefully and materially supporting, hostilities against the United States; or (3) engaging in, or purposefully and materially supporting, hostilities against any country or armed force that is directly engaged along with, or that is providing direct operational support to, the United States in hostilities engaged in by the United States.</summary>
</bill>
