<bill session="116" type="h" number="8968" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Remote, Coastal, and Small Watersheds Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remote, Coastal, and Small Watersheds Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to recommend certain projects in remote, coastal, and small watersheds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2020-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-12T18:32:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Remote, Coastal, and Small Watersheds Act of 2020

This bill authorizes the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers in conducting a study of hurricane and storm damage reduction to recommend certain projects in remote, coastal, and small watersheds without the need to demonstrate that the projects are justified solely by national economic development benefits.

In considering whether to recommend a project, the Corps must consider the benefits of the project to (1) public health and safety of the local community and communities that are located in the region to be served by the project and that will rely on the project, (2) hurricane and storm damage effects on local and regional economic opportunities, (3) welfare of the regional population to be served by the project, or (4) social and cultural value to the local community and communities that are located in the region to be served by the project and that will rely on the project.</summary>
</bill>
