<bill session="118" type="s" number="419" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MATURE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Age-Verification Technology Uniform, Robust, and Effective Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MATURE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require social media platforms to verify that all individuals who create an account on the platform are age 16 or older, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-24T18:50:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Making Age-Verification Technology Uniform, Robust, and Effective Act or the MATURE Act

This bill requires social media platforms to verify that individuals who create an account on the platform are at least 16 years old. The verification process must require individuals to submit a copy of their government-issued identification. Social media platforms may not allow individuals under 16 to create an account.

Additionally, at least once every six months, the Federal Trade Commission must audit large social media platforms (i.e., platforms that average more than 1 million monthly users or have more than 1 million total accounts) to determine whether each platform is in compliance with the bill's requirements. The bill also provides the commission with enforcement authority.</summary>
</bill>
