<bill session="117" type="s" number="4482" updated="2022-12-29T17:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coordinating Substance Use and Homelessness Care Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinating Substance Use and Homelessness Care Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to help persons in the United States experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, by authorizing a grant program within the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist State and local governments, Continuums of Care, community-based organizations that administer both health and homelessness services, and providers of services to people experiencing homelessness, better coordinate health care and homelessness services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3164" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7716" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-06T17:46:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coordinating Substance Use and Homelessness Care Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development to award competitive grants to improve coordination of health care and homelessness services for individuals who are homeless, have significant behavioral health issues (e.g., substance use disorders), and voluntarily seek assistance. Entities eligible for these grants include local and tribal governments, public housing agencies that administer housing choice vouchers, and certain nonprofits.</summary>
</bill>
