<bill session="118" type="s" number="2828" updated="2025-11-19T04:11:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Hunting Heritage and Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Hunting Heritage and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to clarify that the prohibition on the use of Federal education funds for certain weapons does not apply to the use of such weapons in certain programs for activities such as archery, hunting, other shooting sports, or culinary arts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2735" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5110" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-10T18:54:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Hunting Heritage and Education Act

This bill authorizes the use of federal elementary and secondary education funds to purchase or use dangerous weapons for purposes of providing students with educational instruction or educational enrichment activities, such as archery, hunting, other shooting sports, or culinary arts.

Current law prohibits the use of these funds to provide any person with a dangerous weapon or training in the use of a dangerous weapon. The bill specifies that this prohibition shall not apply to the use of these funds for permissible program activities that provide students with educational instruction or educational enrichment activities, such as archery, hunting, other shooting sports, or culinary arts.</summary>
</bill>
