<bill session="118" type="s" number="1129" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Relief for Allies of Dictators Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Relief for Allies of Dictators Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revoke the visas of, and impose visa restrictions on, certain individuals located in the United States and abroad who are associated with regimes in Venezuela, Cuba, Nicaragua, and Bolivia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-09T19:18:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Relief for Allies of Dictators Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of State to deny or revoke visas for certain individuals associated with the Hugo Chavez or Nicolas Maduro regimes of Venezuela, the Fidel or Raul Castro regime of Cuba, the Daniel Ortega regime or Sandinista party of Nicaragua, or the Evo Morales regime of Bolivia.

Specifically, the State Department must deny or revoke the visas of certain foreign persons associated with these regimes (for example, current and former officials) if they (1) have participated in human rights violations or activities to undermine democracy in one of these four countries, or (2) are described in certain laws or executive orders related to activities such as narcotics trafficking and corrupt practices. The spouse and children of such an individual are also subject to visa denial and revocation under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
