<bill session="108" type="s" number="107" updated="2023-01-15T21:19:32Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Southern Border Air Quality Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the exportation of natural gas from the United States to Mexico for use in electric energy generation units near the United States border that do not comply with air quality control requirements that provide air quality protection that is at least equivalent to the protection provided by requirements applicable in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Border Air Quality Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S153"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Southern Border Air Quality Protection Act - Prohibits natural gas from being exported to Mexico for the purpose of electric energy generation by certain electric energy generation units: (1) located within 50 miles of the United States; (2) whose generation capacity is greater than 50 megawatts; and (3) that do not comply with specified air quality control requirements.Directs the President to exercise certain authority granted under the Export Administration Act of 1979 and Executive Order No. 12924 in order to implement this Act.Establishes penalties for noncompliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
