<bill session="118" type="h" number="1665" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Charging Electrical Bikes and Scooters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Charging Electrical Bikes and Scooters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a program to provide grants to local governments to install publicly accessible safety charging stations for electric bicycles and scooters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2023-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2023-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-18T11:38:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Charging Electrical Bikes and Scooters Act

This bill establishes a program to provide grants for the installation of publicly accessible lithium-ion battery power charging stations for electric bicycles and scooters.

Under the program, the Department of Transportation (DOT) may award grants to local governments for the acquisition or installation of safe lithium-ion battery power stations and storage for electric bicycles or scooters in public places. Public places include any public road or other publicly accessible location, such as parking facilities at public buildings and public parks or publicly accessible parking facilities owned or managed by private entities.

DOT must also develop a publicly available educational program about the health and safety risks related to these types of lithium-ion batteries and how to buy, store, and charge the batteries.

Further, DOT must conduct a study on the number of uncertified lithium-ion batteries for electric bicycles and scooters that are currently available in the U.S. market. DOT must report on the study and provide recommendations for legislative or regulatory action to ensure the availability of certified and affordable lithium-ion batteries in the U.S. market.</summary>
</bill>
