<bill session="116" type="s" number="2126" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROMISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROMISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Robust Opportunities for Minority Institutions and Strengthening Entrepreneurship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Small Business Administration to report on assistance provided to historically Black colleges or universities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-16T13:05:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Robust Opportunities for Minority Institutions and Strengthening Entrepreneurship Act or the PROMISE Act

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to report on various aspects of its relationship with historically black colleges and universities (HBCUs), including

 the number of small business development centers located at HBCUs, the number of women's business centers and Veteran Business Outreach Centers that have partnerships with HBCUs, and the number of hours of training and education provided by a program overseen by the Office of Entrepreneurial Development of the SBA to students and graduates of HBCUs. In addition, the SBA is directed to promote entrepreneurship and small business opportunities at HBCUs by conducting outreach and providing access to programs, resources, and opportunities offered by the SBA.</summary>
</bill>
