<bill session="118" type="s" number="2602" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Limiting CDC to Disease Control Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limiting CDC to Disease Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the scope of regulations issued by the Secretary of Health and Human Services to control communicable diseases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T16:26:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Limiting CDC to Disease Control Act

This bill modifies and limits the authority of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue regulations to control communicable diseases.

Current law authorizes HHS to make and enforce regulations to prevent the introduction or spread of communicable diseases. In particular, current law provides that HHS may make and enforce regulations addressing (1) isolation and quarantine of infected individuals (subject to certain restrictions); and (2) inspection, fumigation, disinfection, sanitation, pest extermination, destruction of infected animals or articles, and other measures that the department determines may be necessary. HHS has delegated this authority to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC).

This bill eliminates the authority of the CDC to make and enforce regulations that provide for other measures it determines may be necessary to prevent the spread of communicable diseases, thereby limiting the scope of its regulations to the other specific purposes set out in current law.</summary>
</bill>
