<bill session="111" type="h" number="5601" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gulf Coast Homeowners Relief Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide relief to homeowners with mortgages insured by the FHA who are economically affected as a result of the discharge of oil in the Gulf of Mexico caused by the explosion on and sinking of the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gulf Coast Homeowners Relief Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2010-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-01T19:48:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Gulf Coast Homeowners Relief Act of 2010 - Applies through FY2011 certain provisions of Mortgagee Letter 2002-17 of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), relating to Type I Special Forbearance, to mortgagees of specified mortgages insured by the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) whose mortgagors suffered a loss of income or an increase in living expenses as a result of the explosion on and sinking of the mobile offshore drilling unit Deepwater Horizon, the ensuing discharge of oil in the Gulf of Mexico, or the effects of such discharge on the economy in affected areas.

Directs the Secretary of HUD to develop and submit to the Congress: (1) a list of HUD-administered programs and resources that will be made immediately available to assist homeowners of one- to four-family dwelling, and communities, that have suffered negative economic consequences as a result of such incident or the discharge of oil caused by it; and (2) a long-term plan to assist such homeowners.</summary>
</bill>
