<bill session="109" type="h" number="5760" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:39Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Giant Sequoia National Monument Transition Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To fulfill President Clinton's commitments made as part of the designation of the Giant Sequoia National Monument by presidential proclamation to provide a transition from the timber sale program in effect before the designation to the more restrictive management anticipated for the national monument, to promote the Kings River Research Project in the Sierra National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Giant Sequoia National Monument Transition Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000004" joined="2006-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Owls"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-21T17:52:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Giant Sequoia National Monument Transition Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to proceed with and complete each timber sale located within the boundaries of the Giant Sequoia National Monument: (1) that was under contract as of April 15, 2000, the date of the designation of the Monument; or (2) for which a decision notice was signed after January 1, 1999, but prior to December 31, 1999.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) designate the Kings River Demonstration Project in the Sierra National Forest as the "Kings River Research Project" as a means to address disputes over fuels reduction projects and the benefits and impacts related to wildlife, watershed, and other resources; (2) provide, under the Project, for research about the potential positive and negative impacts of fuel reduction and forest health treatments on the Pacific fisher, California spotted owl, and the Kings River watershed; and (3) complete the final environmental impact statement and issue the record of decision for the Project by not later than October 31, 2006. Deems the final environmental impact statement and record of decision, along with all actions implementing the Project, to be in compliance with specified environmental laws, so long as any timber removed under the Project is removed using uneven-aged silvicultural treatments.</summary>
</bill>
