<bill session="118" type="h" number="6042" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BUILDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building U.S. Infrastructure by Leveraging Demands for Skills</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUILDS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Labor to award grants for promoting industry or sector partnerships to encourage industry growth and competitiveness and to improve worker training, retention, and advancement as part of an infrastructure investment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2023-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4205" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-28T18:54:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Building U.S. Infrastructure by Leveraging Demands for Skills or the BUILDS Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to award implementation or renewal grants to eligible industry or sector partnerships to achieve certain job training and employment objectives with respect to targeted infrastructure industries (e.g., transportation, construction, energy, information technology, or utilities industries). Partnerships may include representatives of businesses, labor organizations, and education or training institutions.

Eligible grant activities include evaluating workforce needs in a local area, developing work-based learning programs, recruiting individuals with barriers to employment for such programs, and providing employment support services.</summary>
</bill>
