<bill session="117" type="h" number="9651" updated="2023-03-15T19:30:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LIFT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LIFT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Infrastructure Funding &amp; Technical assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote long-term economic recovery and job creation in underserved communities by providing for investment in catalytic local predevelopment projects for resilient climate infrastructure innovation and to provide assistance to support State and local project development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001125"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2552" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-15T19:17:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Infrastructure Funding &amp; Technical Assistance Act or the LIFT Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Commerce to provide grants under the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 for predevelopment projects&#8212;measures required to be completed before construction of resilient climate infrastructure occurs&#8212;and related technical assistance. Grants may be provided to economic development districts, states, Indian tribes, local governments, institutions of higher education, individuals, and other organizations as specified by the bill.</summary>
</bill>
