<bill session="115" type="h" number="6617" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:53Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preserving American Privacy Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a legal framework for the operation of public unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving American Privacy Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2018-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-12T16:02:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving American Privacy Act of 2018

This bill restricts the use of public unmanned aircraft systems (i.e., drones) to limit, to the maximum extent practicable, the disclosure of information collected by drones that is reasonably likely to enable identification of an individual or information about an individual's property that is not in plain view (covered information).

The bill requires a governmental entity applying for a license to operate a drone to submit to the Department of Justice a data collection statement describing the purpose for which the drone will be used.

The bill also prohibits the use of covered information collected by drones in legal proceedings and limits its use for law enforcement purposes. A governmental entity may only disclose such information for law enforcement purposes pursuant to a warrant, a court order, or in emergency circumstances.

The bill prohibits: (1) the use of private drones to capture images of individuals in private activities who have a reasonable expectation of privacy, and (2) any investigative or law enforcement officer or private individual from operating a drone that is armed with a firearm.</summary>
</bill>
