<bill session="118" type="h" number="6148" updated="2025-11-18T21:43:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing Tribal Parity on Public Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Tribal Parity on Public Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect Native cultural sites located on Federal land, to improve consultation with Indian Tribes, to bring parity to Indian Tribes with regard to Federal public land management laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2024-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3186" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-29T13:27:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Tribal Parity on Public Land Act

This bill addresses tribal interests in the disposal and management of public land.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the federal government from disposing of public land or National Forest System land unless the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA) determines, through consultation with any interested Indian tribe, that such disposal would not impact the rights and interests of any interested tribe and would not impair access to a reservation.

Interested Indian tribe means an Indian tribe with (1) historic, precontact, cultural, or religious connection to a cultural site located on the tract of public land; (2) a former reservation located on the tract of public land; or (3) treaty rights or other reserved rights associated with the tract of public land.

Interior and USDA must, prior to conducting a sale of a tract of public land, notify all tribes of the availability of land for sale. Further, Interior and USDA must sell the tract of land to an interested Indian tribe that submits a bid at fair market value. Land acquired by an interested tribe shall be taken into trust by Interior for the benefit of the tribe.

Additionally, the bill revises various public land provisions, including to add the interests of tribes to the list of considerations for land exchanges.

The bill also requires each public land advisory board to include at least one representative of an interested Indian tribe.</summary>
</bill>
