<bill session="108" type="h" number="2749" updated="2023-01-15T05:47:36Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Presidential Succession Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 19 of title 3, United States Code, to allow the President to choose between possible successors in case of the event that, by reason of certain circumstances, there is neither a President nor Vice President to discharge the powers and duties of the office of President, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Succession Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001229" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2003-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2003-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional leadership"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Presidential succession"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-09T15:16:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Presidential Succession Act of 2003 - Revises provisions concerning presidential succession. Requires the President to submit to: (1) the Clerk of the House of Representatives notification in writing of the designation of either the Speaker of the House of Representatives or the office of the Minority Leader of the House as the office designated as the highest on the presidential succession list; and (2) the Secretary of the Senate notification in writing of the designation of either the Office of the Majority Leader of the Senate or the office of the Minority Leader of the Senate as next highest on such list.

Includes, following the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security on the list.</summary>
</bill>
