<bill session="118" type="h" number="4939" updated="2024-07-24T15:20:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To authorize livestock producers and their employees to take crested caracaras in order to prevent the death of or injury or destruction to livestock, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize livestock producers and their employees to take crested caracaras in order to prevent the death of or injury or destruction to livestock, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2023-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-24T15:51:04Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill allows livestock producers and their employees to take certain actions against crested caracaras to protect livestock. (Crested caracaras&#160;are protected under the Migratory Bird Treaty Act.)

Specifically, livestock producers and their employees may (1) take (i.e., capture, kill, disperse, or transport) a crested caracara that they reasonably believe will cause death, injury, or destruction to livestock; or (2) in the course of taking or attempting to take the crested caracara, cause injury to the bird.

Livestock producers and their employees must submit an annual report to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS) on crested caracaras taken under this bill. The FWS must make this reporting form available on its website.

Currently, the FWS has a special permit process under the Migratory Bird Treaty Act for the taking of&#160;crested caracaras.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
