<bill session="115" type="h" number="5759" updated="2023-11-28T17:27:41Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve executive agency digital services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">21st Century IDEA</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000389"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001105" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001106" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000464" joined="2018-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001048" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000601" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2018-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000604" joined="2018-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2018-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2018-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2018-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2018-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 115-1055.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-29" calendar="Union" number="821">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 821.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29T17:43:34-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Comer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29T17:43:44-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9720-9722" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29T17:43:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5759.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-11-29T17:49:35-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9720-9721" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-11-29T17:49:36-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2018-12-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7453" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2018-12-13">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2018-12-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-336" type="public" datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-336.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3050" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-06T19:33:57Z" status="Public Law">21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act or the 21st Century IDEA

(Sec. 3) This bill requires an executive agency that creates a public website or digital service, or that redesigns an existing public legacy website or digital service, to ensure that the website or service:

 is accessible to individuals with disabilities, has a consistent appearance, does not overlap with or duplicate any legacy websites; contains a search function, is provided through an industry standard secure connection, is designed around user needs, provides users with the option for a more customized digital experience that allows users to complete digital transactions in an efficient and accurate manner, and is fully functional and usable on common mobile devices. Each agency that maintains a public website or digital service shall report: (1) to Congress on those websites and services, including the cost of modernization, and (2) annually to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) on the agency's progress in implementing the requirements.

Agencies must ensure that Intranets established after enactment of this bill conform to the requirements for public websites.

Any website of an agency that is made available to the public after enactment shall be in compliance with the website standards of the Technology Transformation Services of the General Services Administration (GSA).

(Sec. 4) The OMB shall issue guidance to each agency to: (1) identify public nondigital, paper-based, or in person government services; and (2) include in the agency's budget request a list of nondigital services with the greatest impact that could be made available to the public through an online, mobile-friendly, digital service option in a manner that decreases cost, increases digital conversion rates, and improves customer experience, and an estimation of the cost and schedule associated with carrying out such modernization.

Agencies must make forms used by the public available digitally and report on forms, services, and processes that cannot be digitized. Each agency shall maintain an accessible method of completing digital services through in-person, paper-based, or other means, such that individuals without the ability to use digital services are not deprived of, or impeded in, access to such services.

(Sec. 5) Each agency shall submit to the OMB and Congress a plan to accelerate the use of electronic signatures.

(Sec. 6) Each agency's Chief Information Officer shall:

 coordinate and ensure alignment of the internal and external customer experience programs and strategy of the agency, coordinate with the management leaders of the agency to ensure proper funding to support this bill's implementation, continually examine the agency's public digital service delivery strategy and submit recommendations providing guidance and best practices, identify areas of concern that need improvement using data relating to customer experience and satisfaction, and coordinate and ensure compliance with requirements for federal websites to be mobile friendly. (Sec. 7) Each agency shall: (1) seek to maintain as much standardization and commonality with other agencies as practicable in implementing this bill's requirements to best enable future transitions to centralized shared services; and (2) coordinate the implementation of such requirements, including the development of standards and commonalities.

The GSA must make available under a Federal Supply Schedule the systems and services necessary to fulfill this bill's requirements. Such schedule shall ensure interoperability between agencies, compliance with industry standards, and adherence to best practices for design, accessibility, and information security.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1055</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
