<bill session="117" type="hr" number="1331" updated="2023-03-30T14:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Moving Our Democracy and Congressional Operations Towards Modernization Resolution of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Moving Our Democracy and Congressional Operations Towards Modernization Resolution of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Carrying out recommendations issued by the Select Committee on the Modernization of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2022-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2022-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000480" joined="2022-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Rules, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-27T16:52:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Moving Our Democracy and Congressional Operations Towards Modernization Resolution of 2022

This resolution implements recommendations made by the House Select Committee on the Modernization of Congress.

The recommendations include

 enhancing bipartisan collaboration by, for example, establishing a space in the U.S. Capitol for bipartisan gathering and encouraging committees to experiment with alternative hearing formats; revising various administrative matters, such as authorizing the use of bulk purchases for supplies and services for Member offices, requiring offices to establish continuity of operations plans, and implementing secure information transfer practices; supporting efforts related to workforce and human resource management in the House; and improving accessibility of congressional spaces and websites for individuals with disabilities. The resolution also requires (1) reevaluating the method of calculating Representational Allowances (funds provided to Members for operating their offices and carrying out their official and representational duties), and (2) publishing information about the expenditures and staffing of eligible Congressional Member Organizations (groups of Members that register with the Committee on House Administration in support of a common legislative objective).</summary>
</bill>
