<bill session="117" type="h" number="5959" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHOICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Hope and Opportunity for Individuals and Communities through Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand opportunity through greater choice in education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000471" joined="2021-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2021-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="74" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-26T16:17:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Hope and Opportunity for Individuals and Communities through Education Act or the CHOICE Act

This bill expands school choice programs for elementary and secondary school students.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Education (ED) to award grants to support the design and implementation of state programs that allow the parent of a child with a disability to choose the appropriate public or private school for their child. It also outlines the requirements for program eligibility.

Further, if the state has established a program that allows parents to use public or private funds to assist with the cost of their child attending a private school, then the state may supplement those funds with federal special education funds.

Additionally, the Department of Defense must carry out a five-year pilot program to award scholarships to enable military dependent students who live on military installations to attend the public or private elementary or secondary schools their parents choose.

The bill also requires ED to return to the Treasury specified amounts made available for salaries and expenses.</summary>
</bill>
