<bill session="112" type="s" number="2216" updated="2019-11-15T21:44:05Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Energy Savings Program Act</title>
    <title type="display">Rural Energy Savings Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans to certain entities that will use the funds to make loans to consumers to implement cost-effective energy efficiency measures to promote energy cost savings and rural development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2012-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3111" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1658" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3240" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-26T21:32:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Energy Savings Program Act - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA), through the Rural Utilities Service, to make interest-free loans to eligible entities (public power districts, public utility districts, or specified electric cooperatives that borrowed and repaid, prepaid, or are paying an electric loan made or guaranteed by the Rural Utilities Service) for loans to consumers to implement energy efficient measures.

Provides a special advance for start-up activities.

Authorizes the Secretary to contract with a qualified entity to provide verification and measurement activities and employee technical assistance and training.

Directs the Secretary to offer to enter into agreements with eligible entities, or groups of eligible entities, that have specified energy efficiency programs to establish energy efficiency loan demonstration projects.</summary>
</bill>
