<bill session="111" type="h" number="2036" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:32Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Students Education Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to expand grant programs for gifted and talented students.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Students Education Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000021"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2009-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-27T15:32:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Students Education Enhancement Act - Creates a part E (Gifted and Talented Students) under title II of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.

Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to, or contract with, states, local educational agencies (LEAs), institutions of higher education (IHEs), and other public or private agencies and organizations to assist them in meeting the educational needs of gifted and talented students, including by training school personnel in the identification and education of gifted and talented students.

Requires the Secretary to establish a National Research Center for the Education of Gifted and Talented Children and Youth through grants to, or contracts with, one or more IHEs, states, or a combination or consortium of such entities and other public or private agencies and organizations.

Directs the Secretary to make grants to states, based on each state's share of individuals aged 5-17, to fund competitive subgrants to LEAs for the development or expansion of gifted and talented education programs.

Gives highest part E funding priority to programs and projects designed to develop new information that: (1) improves the capability of schools to identify and serve gifted and talented students; and (2) assists schools in identifying and providing services to gifted and talented students who may not be identified and served through traditional assessment methods.</summary>
</bill>
