<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4138</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:23:00Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:23:00Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-03-05</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Ms. LEE of California:H.R. 4138.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:This bill is enacted pursuant to the power granted toCongress under Article I of the United States Constitutionand its subsequent amendments, and further clarified andinterpreted by the Supreme Court of the United States.[Page H1153]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
            <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2012-03-09T18:32:36Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-03-05T17:04:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif14</systemCode>
            <name>Health Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-05</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000551</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Lee, Barbara [D-CA-9]</fullName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <lastName>LEE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>9</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Neurological disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-03-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-06-22T20:21:11Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that there is a need to: (1) establish and coordinate a multicenter research effort to comprehensively study the causes of neuromyelitis optica (NMO) and identify potential biomarkers; and (2) encourage a collaborative effort among academic medical centers with epidemiological study groups to investigate environmental, nutritional, and genetic factors with respect to, and the pathological and epidemiological characteristics of, NMO.</p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), in coordination with the Director of the National Institute on Minority Health and Health Disparities, to establish, administer, and coordinate a National Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium to: (1) provide five-year grants to eligible consortia to conduct research regarding the causes of, and the risk factors and biomarkers associated with, NMO; (2) assemble a panel of experts to provide guidance and recommendations for the development of a common study design, standard methods for collecting a minimum data set from study participants, specific analytical methods for examining data, provisions for consensus review of enrolled cases, and an integrated data collection network; and (3) designate a central laboratory to collect, analyze, and aggregate data with respect to funded research and to make such data and analysis available to researchers.</p> <p>Requires a consortium (a partnership of two or more universities, health care organizations, or government agencies, or any combination of such entities, serving a designated catchment area), to be eligible for a grant, to demonstrate that: (1) it has the capability to enroll as research participants a minimum of 25 individuals with a diagnosis of NMO from the consortium's designated catchment area, and (2) such area does not overlap with the designated catchment area of another consortium already receiving a grant under this Act. </p> <p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Public Health Service Act to create a National Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium to provide grants and coordinate research with respect to the causes of, and risk factors associated with, neuromyelitis optica, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Neuromyelitis Optica Consortium Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2012-03-05T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr4138ih/xml/BILLS-112hr4138ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-03-09</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
