<bill session="116" type="s" number="3247" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fracking Ban Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fracking Ban Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ban the practice of hydraulic fracturing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5857" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-10T15:14:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fracking Ban Act

This bill phases out hydraulic fracturing for oil and natural gas. Hydraulic fracturing or fracking is a process to extract underground resources such as oil or gas from a geologic formation by injecting water, a propping agent (e.g., sand), and chemical additives into a well under enough pressure to fracture the geological formation.

The bill prohibits federal agencies from issuing permits for the expansion of fracking or fracked oil and natural gas infrastructure, including infrastructure intended to extract, transport, or burn natural gas or oil.

In addition, the bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency to complete a survey of all oil and natural gas wells to identify the wells where fracking is, or has been, used. The survey must include a variety of data, including data on the proximity of fracking operations to inhabited structures (e.g., homes or schools).

Beginning on February 1, 2021, the bill revokes permits for wells where fracking is, or has been, used within 2,500 feet of inhabited structures. The bill bans all fracking on onshore and offshore land by 2025.

Finally, the bill requires the Department of Labor to establish a Just Transition Committee to make recommendations on ensuring the health and safety of individuals residing in, and the prosperity of, natural gas- and oil-producing regions during the phaseout of fracking.</summary>
</bill>
