<bill session="117" type="h" number="3027" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Improved Access to Care Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the VA MISSION Act of 2018 to expand reporting on hiring in the Veterans Health Administration, and to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to expedite the onboarding process for new medical providers of the Veterans Health Administration, to reduce the duration of the hiring process for such medical providers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Improved Access to Care Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001186" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-17T16:07:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Improved Access to Care Act of 2021

This bill addresses the administration of the hiring process for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) personnel.

Under current law, the VA is required to publish on a VA website specified information related to staffing and the duration of the hiring process for certain health care appointees, such as physicians. The bill requires the VA Office of Inspector General to review the administration of such website annually instead of the current semiannual requirement.

The VA must implement a two-year pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of expediting the Veterans Health Administration's onboarding process for new medical providers.

Finally, the bill requires the VA to submit a strategy to reduce by half the duration of the VA's hiring process for licensed professional medical providers.</summary>
</bill>
