<bill session="109" type="h" number="4170" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:52Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fugitive Apprehension Assistance Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide administrative subpoena authority to apprehend fugitives.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fugitive Apprehension Assistance Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000023" joined="2006-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000364" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000517" joined="2005-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2006-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-27T19:34:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Fugitive Apprehension Assistance Act of 2005 - Amends the federal criminal code to authorize the Attorney General, in any investigation with respect to the apprehension of a fugitive, to subpoena witnesses for the production of records that are relevant to discerning the fugitive's whereabouts. Authorizes requiring the attendance of witnesses and the production of records from any place subject to U.S. jurisdiction, except that a witness shall not be required to appear more than 500 miles from the person's residence or the place where the witness was served.

Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) service of process to natural persons and corporations; (2) subpoena enforcement; and (3) the rights of subpoena recipients.

Directs the Attorney General to issue guidelines governing the issuance of administrative subpoenas.

Authorizes: (1) the Attorney General, where a subpoena is issued to a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service or to a financial institution for financial records, to delay notice to the subscriber or customer to whom the records pertain if the court determines that there is reason to believe that notification of the subpoena's existence may have an adverse result; and (2) the court to require the party to whom the subpoena is directed to refrain from notifying any other party of the subpoena's existence for 30 days (with extensions under specified circumstances). Grants immunity from civil liability for good faith compliance with the terms of a court order for the production of records or for nondisclosure to the customer.</summary>
</bill>
