<bill session="116" type="h" number="7546" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Minority Community Public Health Emergency Response Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to ensure that minority and medically underserved communities have meaningful and immediate access to public health interventions and medically necessary health care services during the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Community Public Health Emergency Response Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3910" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4944" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-16T23:34:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Minority Community Public Health Emergency Response Act of 2020

This bill establishes a grant program for COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) preparedness and response in medically underserved communities where the disease disproportionally affects racial and ethnic minority groups. It also modifies the scope and administration of demonstration models carried out by the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation (CMMI) to address health inequity.

With respect to the grant program, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must award grants to government entities, giving priority to local governments and county health departments, for contact tracing, other public health activities, and the provision of nutrition assistance and quarantine housing. HHS may also support planning activities for entities that intend to apply for these grants.

As a condition for receiving funding, grantees must establish, or designate an existing body as, a COVID-19/infectious disease planning council. The council must reflect the demographics of the populations most impacted by COVID-19, and its responsibilities shall include developing a plan for the delivery of health care and support services to address COVID-19 and establishing priorities for allocating funding.

In addition, the CMMI must test a payment model that addresses social determinants of health and health disparities, particularly with respect to minorities, underserved areas, and high-risk individuals. The bill also generally incorporates consideration of such factors into the selection, implementation, and evaluation of other models, including the decision as to whether to expand a model's duration and scope.</summary>
</bill>
