<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="480" updated="2022-02-03T06:02:01Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2601" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-07-20T13:46:13-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000794"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  <description>Page 312, after line 8, insert the following: \   SEC. 1110A. STATEMENT OF POLICY REGARDING TRANSFER OF CHARLES TAYLOR FOR TRIAL FOR WAR CRIMES. \   It shall be the policy of the United States Government to seek the expeditious transfer of Charles Ghankay Taylor, former President of the Republic of Liberia, to the jurisdiction of the Special Court for Sierra Leone to undergo a fair and open trial for war crimes, crimes against humanity, and other serious violations of international humanitarian law.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 28 printed in part B of House Report 109-175 to state that it shall be the policy of the U.S. Government to seek the expeditious transfer of Charles Ghankay Taylor, former President of the Republic of Liberia, to the jurisdiction of the Special Court for Sierra Leone to undergo a fair and open trial for war crimes, crimes against humanity, and other serious violations of international humanitarian law.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-07-20T13:46:13-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="394">
      <text>On agreeing to the Watson amendment (A027) Agreed to by recorded vote: 422 - 2 (Roll no. 394).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20T12:28:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A027) offered by Ms. Watson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6130-6135, H6139-6140" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6130" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20T12:28:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A027) offered by Ms. Watson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6130-6135, H6139-6140" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6130" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20T13:46:13-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Watson amendment (A027) Agreed to by recorded vote: 422 - 2 (Roll no. 394).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20T13:46:13-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20T13:46:13-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
