<bill session="117" type="h" number="5816" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Informed Consent Exemption (NICE) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Informed Consent Exemption (NICE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Federal Government, or State or local government or other entity receiving Federal funding, from requiring any citizen to be vaccinated, including Federal agencies from requiring its employees to take any vaccination, without the citizen being fully advised in writing of all known potential risks from the vaccine and consultation with a physician followed by the voluntary informed consent of the citizen, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2022-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-31T18:48:49Z" status="Introduced in House">National Informed Consent Exemption (NICE) Act

This bill restricts the federal government and federally funded entities from mandating that U.S. citizens receive a vaccination or a test for an infectious disease in order to participate in federal programs or activities such as travel. It also specifies that laws, regulations, or policies that discriminate on the basis of a citizen's vaccination status are unenforceable, subject to limited exceptions.

The bill establishes a national vaccination exemption that may be exercised by any individual, including on behalf of the individual's children or dependents. Further, the bill prohibits vaccinating a child without the consent of each parent or guardian. One parent or guardian may consent if the other parent or guardian received, at least three days prior, written notice of the child's vaccination appointment.

The bill's provisions do not apply (1) to lawfully incarcerated or institutionalized individuals, (2) to a specific individual subject to an individualized court order that meets due process protections, or (3) during declared emergencies if the jurisdiction's governing authority formally applies to the President for an exception to the national vaccination exemption that meets specified standards.

An aggrieved individual may enforce the bill through a private right of action. Additionally, an entity that provides false information to influence an individual's decision about receiving a vaccine shall be liable for damages resulting from the vaccination.

The Surgeon General must establish an independent commission to evaluate the safety of COVID-19 vaccines and other vaccines recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</summary>
</bill>
