<bill session="118" type="h" number="380" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Student Loan Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Student Loan Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit abuse of the authority of the Secretary of Education under the HEROES Act in connection with the COVID-19 national emergency declaration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2023-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2023-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-03T19:29:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Student Loan Integrity Act

This bill limits the authority of the Department of Education (ED) to waive or modify statutes and regulations in response to military contingencies or national emergencies, including by prohibiting ED from further using this authority in connection with the COVID-19 national emergency.

Under the Higher Education Relief Opportunities for Students (HEROES) Act of 2003, ED may waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to federal student-aid programs as ED deems necessary in connection with a war or other military operation or national emergency. This bill prohibits ED from issuing a waiver or modification that (1) provides for a period that exceeds 30 days during which payments of principal or interest due on federal student loans are suspended or interest does not accrue on such loans, or (2) results in the discharge or cancellation of any outstanding balance owed on federal student loans.

Further, the bill prohibits ED from using this authority to waive or modify any statutory or regulatory provision applicable to federal student-aid programs in connection with the national emergency declared by the President on March 13, 2020, to respond to COVID-19.</summary>
</bill>
