<bill session="118" type="h" number="3200" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gateway Community and Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gateway Community and Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to carry out certain activities to enhance recreational opportunities for gateway communities, to amend the Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act to provide for the establishment of a digital National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000619" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-19T16:16:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Gateway Community and Recreation Enhancement Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior and the Forest Service to carry out activities to enhance recreational opportunities for gateway communities and provides for the establishment of a digital National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass.

Gateway community means a community that serves as an entry point or is adjacent to a recreation destination at which there is consistently high seasonal or year-round visitation.

Specifically, Interior and the Forest Service must collaborate with relevant stakeholders to identify needs and economic impacts in gateway communities, including

 housing shortages, demands on existing municipal infrastructure, accommodation and management of sustainable visitation, and the expansion and diversification of visitor experiences by bolstering visitation at certain nearby underutilized locations or lesser-known recreation sites. The Rural Business-Cooperative Service shall provide to businesses in gateway communities assistance to establish, operate, or expand infrastructure to accommodate and manage sustainable visitation.

Before taking action that will reduce access to a national park (excluding actions due to incident specific events that present a health and safety risk), the office of the superintendent of the affected park must conduct public meetings, consult local stakeholders, and provide an opportunity for public comments.

Interior and the Forest Service must (1) establish a single visitation data reporting system to report accurate annual visitation data, and (2) carry out a Real-time Data Pilot Program.</summary>
</bill>
