<bill session="119" type="h" number="2182" updated="2025-06-12T08:07:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pre-Pilot Pathway Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pre-Pilot Pathway Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish an apprenticeship program for students at flight training providers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2025-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T14:23:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Pre-Pilot Pathway Act 

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish an apprenticeship program with flight training providers (e.g., flight schools) in order to establish a commercial pilot pipeline; DOT must issue any necessary regulations to implement the program within one year of the bill's enactment.

Each flight training provider participating in the program may select up to eight applicants (or more applicants based on a determination by DOT) per academic year to serve as apprentices.

DOT must take appropriate actions to develop methods to incentivize pilots, including retired pilots, to become flight school instructors, mentors, or program advisors at participating flight training providers. This includes developing pathway programs for pilots to gain initial qualifications or concurrent qualifications as certified flight instructors.

Further, DOT must conduct an annual review of the apprenticeship program&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s effectiveness, including the impact on addressing pilot shortages.</summary>
</bill>
