<bill session="108" type="s" number="2041" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that pay for Members of Congress be reduced following any fiscal year in which there is a Federal deficit.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce,  and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA03" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3736" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-07T13:56:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2004 - Provides that, if there is a deficit in a fiscal year, then: (1) any pay adjustment for Members of Congress scheduled to take effect in the succeeding calendar year shall be null and void; and (2) effective as of the first day of the first pay period beginning in such year, rates of pay for Members shall be reduced (from the rate in effect as of the day before the start of such year) by the amount determined in this Act, but not below zero.

Varies the mandatory pay rate reduction from five percent, if it takes effect in a calendar year that does not immediately follow another calendar year in which a reduction was made, to ten percent, if it takes effect in a calendar year that immediately follows another calendar year in which a reduction was made.

Specifies conditions for restoration of the original pay rate, together with otherwise scheduled adjustments.

Vests authority in the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to make determinations of whether or not a deficit exists in any fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
