<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="3626" updated="2021-08-13T15:22:17Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="14" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-08-11">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-08-10"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to restricting United States funding to international organizations, such as the United Nations Human Rights Council, until the Department of State certifies that no members of the organization are state sponsors of terrorism, which may include a report from the Department of the Treasury on the prevalence of sanctioned entities in the organization.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-08-11" how="roll" result="fail" roll="354">
      <text>Amendment SA 3626 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 354.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Amendment SA 3626 proposed by Senator Sullivan. (consideration: CR S6235-6236; text: CR S6235) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to restricting United States funding to international organizations, such as the United Nations Human Rights Council, until the Department of State certifies that no members of the organization are state sponsors of terrorism, which may include a report from the Department of the Treasury on the prevalence of sanctioned entities in the organization.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10"/>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3626 proposed by Senator Sullivan.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6235-6236" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6235" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3626 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 354.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 3626 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 49 - 50. Record Vote Number: 354.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
