<bill session="116" type="s" number="3401" updated="2022-02-09T00:29:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Equal Treatment of Public Servants Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Treatment of Public Servants Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to replace the windfall elimination provision with a formula equalizing benefits for certain individuals with noncovered employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2020-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3934" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-08T14:49:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Equal Treatment of Public Servants Act of 2020

This bill phases in a new funding formula for determining benefit amounts under the windfall elimination provision (WEP). (The WEP reduces Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance benefits for those who receive pensions for certain non-covered employment.)

The new formula adjusts an individual's total lifetime earnings based on the proportion of those earnings subject to Social Security payroll taxes. It applies to individuals who (1) become eligible for old-age or disability benefits after 2060, and (2) have earnings from non-covered service performed in a year after 1977. Beneficiaries who become eligible for benefits between 2022 and 2060 receive the higher of their benefit calculated under the existing WEP or the new formula. In addition, certain beneficiaries currently impacted by the WEP receive an additional payment.

The Social Security Administration must include non-covered earnings in Social Security account statements and must study the feasibility of partnering with certain pension systems to address data sharing issues related to non-covered pensions.</summary>
</bill>
