<bill session="119" type="h" number="1671" updated="2025-09-02T17:48:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice for Vaccine Injured Veterans Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Vaccine Injured Veterans Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a presumption of service-connection under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for certain diseases associated with the COVID-19 vaccine that become manifest during the one-year period following the receipt of the vaccine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000246" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001184" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2025-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-15T21:28:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for Vaccine Injured Veterans Act of 2025

This bill establishes a presumption of service-connection for certain conditions that become manifest in a member of the Armed Forces who received a COVID-19 vaccine under orders any time from August 24, 2021, through January 10, 2023. Under a presumption of service-connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.

Specifically, the bill establishes a presumption of service-connection, regardless of whether there is a record of evidence of the condition during a servicemember's&#160;period of service, for myocarditis, pericarditis, thrombosis with thrombocytopenia syndrome, Guillain-Barre Syndrome, and any other condition the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) determines is warranted based on a positive association with the COVID-19 vaccine. Under the bill, if the VA determines an additional condition should be specified, it must submit a notice of such determination to Congress.

The VA must also report to Congress every 60 days for four&#160;years regarding claims for compensation related to a condition associated with the COVID-19 vaccine. Such reports must be made publicly available.</summary>
</bill>
