<bill session="116" type="h" number="5681" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Communities from Hospital Closures Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to require hospitals to submit notice to the Secretary of Health and Human Services before closing all or certain units or departments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Communities from Hospital Closures Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001296"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-05T19:55:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Communities from Hospital Closures Act of 2020

This bill prohibits hospitals from closing unless pursuant to a plan approved by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).

Specifically, a&#160;hospital must (1) notify HHS before closing most or all of its units or departments or specific units or departments where the closure may significantly impact the health and welfare of a community (e.g., emergency departments or labor and delivery units), and (2) provide a closure plan that addresses specified issues related to continuity of patient care and the health and safety needs of the community served by the departments or units. HHS may reject, approve, or require modification of the plan.

The bill provides for certain judicial remedies in the event of closures that occur without an approved plan or in violation of an approved plan.</summary>
</bill>
