<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="647" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4437" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-12-15T20:27:09-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001247"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <description>At the end of title VI, insert the following new section: \   SEC. 615. DECLARATION OF CONGRESS. \   Congress condemns rapes by smugglers along the international land border of the United States and urges in the strongest possible terms the Government of Mexico to work in coordination with United States Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security take immediate action to prevent such rapes from occurring.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in Part B of House Report 109-347 to insert a new section declaring that Congress condemns rapes by smugglers along the international land border of the U.S. and urges in the strongest possible terms the government of Mexico to work in coordination with the U.S. Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security to take immediate action to prevent such rapes from occurring.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-12-15T20:27:09-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Brown-Waite, Ginny amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T20:18:29-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Brown-Waite, Ginny.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11851-11852" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11851" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T20:18:29-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Brown-Waite, Ginny.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11851-11852" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H11851" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T20:27:09-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15T20:27:09-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Brown-Waite, Ginny amendment (A010) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
