<bill session="118" type="s" number="1764" updated="2025-11-19T03:27:18Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Western Wildfire Support Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Wildfire Support Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Western Wildfire Support Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal activities relating to wildfires, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-311.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="582">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 582.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="482" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-31T20:55:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Western Wildfire Support Act of 2023

This bill establishes activities to address wildfires.

The bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior to establish spatial fire management plans before the end of FY2026.

The bill establishes

 accounts in the Treasury for addressing wildfires, a program to train and certify citizens who wish to be able to volunteer to assist USDA or Interior during a wildland fire incident, a program to award grants to eligible states or units of local government to acquire slip-on tank and pump units for a surge capacity of resources for fire suppression, the Theodore Roosevelt Genius Prize for the management of wildfire-related invasive species, and the Management of Wildfire-Related Invasive Species Technology Advisory Board. The bill also

 requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to reimburse a state or federal agency for the costs of wildfire suppression as a result of a fire caused by DOD activity, requires the Joint Fire Science Program to work with unmanned aircraft test ranges to carry out research and development of unmanned aircraft system fire applications, requires federal and state disaster preparedness programs to include postdisaster assistance, and authorizes the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide funding to a state agency to establish and operate a website to provide information relating to postfire recovery funding and resources to a community or an individual impacted by a wildland fire.</summary>
</bill>
