<bill session="118" type="s" number="2543" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Language Education Data Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Language Education Data Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Education Sciences Reform Act of 2002 to require the National Center for Education Statistics to collect, acquire, compile, and disseminate student attainment in languages other than English, and to require the National Center for Education Research to support research on attainment in languages other than English.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-20T12:59:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Language Education Data Enhancement Act

This bill requires research and reporting on attainment in languages other than English. Language other than English means any spoken or unspoken language other than English, including a Native American language and American Sign Language.

Specifically, the bill requires the National Center for Education Research to support research on attainment in languages other than English.&#160;

The bill requires the National Center for Education Statistics to collect, acquire, compile, and disseminate data on student enrollment in courses in languages other than English, the number and certification of teachers employed in teaching languages other than English, and the number and distribution of courses offered in languages other than English at all levels of education. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
