<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1229" updated="2022-02-03T05:59:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5325" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-06-06">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-06-06"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC. __. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used by the Assistant Secretary for Fossil Energy to implement or administer any change to the requirement in section 9.104 1(d) of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on January 19, 2001), that to be determined responsible, a prospective contractor must have a record of satisfactory compliance with antitrust laws.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to be used by the Assistant Secretary for Fossil Energy to implement or administer any change to the requirement in section 9.104-1(d) of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, that to be determined responsible, a prospective contractor must have a record of satisfactory compliance with anti-trust laws.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T12:51:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Frelinghuysen raised a point of order against the DeFazio amendment (A060). Mr. Frelinghuysen stated that the amendment sought to change existing law and violated clause 2 of Rule XXI. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T12:45:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A060) offered by Mr. DeFazio.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3492-3493" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3492" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T12:45:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A060) offered by Mr. DeFazio.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3492-3493" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3492" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
