<bill session="118" type="h" number="432" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Buy Low and Sell High Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Buy Low and Sell High Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To lower consumer fuel prices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="293" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4020" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-15T15:01:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Buy Low and Sell High Act

This bill revises requirements concerning the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) and sets forth provisions to reduce the demand for petroleum fuel and increase fuel supply.

For example, the bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish within the SPR an Economic Petroleum Reserve of up to 350 million barrels of crude oil.

DOE must also establish a national network of Strategic Refined Petroleum Product Reserves to store up to 250 million barrels of gasoline and diesel fuel, which may be sold when there is a severe fuel supply interruption within the district in which the reserve is located.

In addition, the bill increases the cap on the amount of barrels of petroleum distillate that may be stored in the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve from two million to four million.

It also establishes limits on the sale and exportation of petroleum products from such reserves.

Further, the bill establishes provisions concerning electrifying the transportation sector, zero-emission vehicles, and a program to increase the amount of crude oil refined in oil refineries in certain countries in the Western Hemisphere.</summary>
</bill>
