<bill session="116" type="s" number="1765" updated="2022-11-01T06:47:28Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to sustain economic development and recreational use of National Forest System land in the State of Montana, to add certain land to the National Wilderness Preservation System, to designate new areas for recreation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-380.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-18T14:42:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Blackfoot Clearwater Stewardship Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to complete a landscape assessment of the Seeley Lake Ranger District of the Lolo National Forest in Montana, designates areas in the forest for recreation and as wildnerness, and otherwise revises provisions related to the forest.

A collaboratively developed restoration project within the district may be carried out in accordance with certain hazardous fuel reduction projects.

USDA shall, if, a local collaborative group submits a proposal to improve motorized and nonmotorized recreational trail opportunities within the district, analyze the environmental effects of the proposal. It&#160;may also&#160;provide for the construction of any of the routes included in such proposal.

The bill designates specified federal land in the forest as (1) the Otatsy Recreation Management Area, and (2) the Spread Mountain Recreation Area.

The bill designates specified wilderness additions in the forest as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.</summary>
</bill>
