<bill session="110" type="s" number="1653" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:47Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage Contingent Cost Allocation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage Contingent Cost Allocation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2007-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-03T17:47:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage Contingent Cost Allocation Act - Declares that certain funds designated under provisions (commonly known as the Price-Anderson Act) of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to provide indemnification shall be used to cover the contingent cost resulting from any nuclear incident for which such funds would be available to compensate for public liability (Price-Anderson incident).

States that certain funds made available to the United States under the Convention on Supplementary Compensation for Nuclear Damage shall be used to satisfy public liability resulting from a Price-Anderson incident.

Requires participation by each nuclear supplier in a retrospective risk pooling program to cover the contingent cost resulting from a nuclear incident outside the United States that is not a Price-Anderson incident.

Requires the Secretary of Energy to report to Congress every five years on whether there is a need for continuation or amendment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
