<bill session="114" type="h" number="1838" updated="2023-01-11T13:27:41Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-05T20:41:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-05T20:41:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To establish the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in San Benito and Fresno Counties, California, to designate the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness in such counties, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in San Benito and Fresno Counties, California, to designate the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness in such counties, to designate additional components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2015-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2015-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2015-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-05-23">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 114-585.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-05-23" calendar="Union" number="455">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 455.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:26:09-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Lummis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:26:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4253-4255" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:26:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1838.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2016-07-05T20:41:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4253-4254" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:41:48-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T20:41:52-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 114-509.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-07-12T14:24:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Clear Creek National Recreation Area and Conservation Act



Establishes the Clear Creek National Recreation Area in the state of California to promote environmentally responsible off-highway vehicle recreation and to support other public recreational uses, including hunting, hiking, and rock and gem collecting. Instructs the Department of the Interior to use the 2005 Clear Creek Management Area Travel Management Plan as modified by this bill or by Interior to incorporate natural resource protection information unavailable in 2005 as the basis for an interim management plan to govern off-highway vehicle recreation in the Recreation Area.

Requires Interior to create a comprehensive management plan for the Recreation Area within two years of the enactment of this bill.

Requires landowners to be provided with adequate access to inholdings within the Recreation Area.

Permits livestock grazing to continue in areas of the Recreation Area in which it is allowed as of the enactment of this bill.

Designates approximately 21,000 acres of identified federal lands in Fresno and San Benito Counties, California, to be known as the Joaquin Rocks Wilderness, as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to add the Larious Canyon, San Carlos Creek, Cantua Creek, Picacho Creek, and White Creek and its tributaries as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System.

Releases the San Benito Mountain Wilderness Study Area from specified requirements applicable to public lands subject to a wilderness review.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-585</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
