<bill session="116" type="h" number="6307" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:28Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Easing Disruption for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Small Contractor Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide contracting flexibility to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Easing Disruption for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Small Contractor Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6312" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3554" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-03T13:58:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Easing Disruption for America's Small Contractor Act of 2020

This bill requires a federal agency to provide a small business contractor with additional time to perform its responsibilities and to pay such contractor regardless of any delay or interruption that is due to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, a small business that is party to a contract with a federal agency and which experiences an adverse impact to its operations as a result of COVID-19 shall be provided with 90 additional days, or such additional time as deemed appropriate, to carry out its responsibilities under the contract.

Further, if such performance of a federal goods or services contract is unavoidably delayed or interrupted by the inability of the small business's employees to access government facilities or resources due to restrictions related to COVID-19, the government shall pay the entity, upon submission of required documentation, the prices stipulated in the contract for goods or services as if performance had been rendered.</summary>
</bill>
