<bill session="116" type="s" number="2299" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:22Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PIPES Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">PIPES Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">PIPES Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PIPES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">PIPES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to enhance the safety and reliability of pipeline transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Wicker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-217.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-02-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="427">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 427.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5348-5354" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5354"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2020-08-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5337-5345" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-08-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14T14:03:58-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14T14:26:40-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2139" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1097" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2642"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-01-21T14:42:07Z" status="Passed Senate">Protecting our Infrastructure of Pipelines and Enhancing Safety Act of 2020 or the PIPES Act of 2020

TITLE I--IMPROVING PIPELINE SAFETY INFRASTRUCTURE

This title addresses pipeline safety and infrastructure with respect to natural gas and hazardous liquid pipelines. It authorizes appropriations through FY2023 for specified pipelines safety programs under the Pipelines Safety Improvement Act of 2002 and related enactments.

Among other provisions, the title

 requires fees for compliance reviews of liquefied natural gas (LNG) facilities; authorizes the establishment of limited safety-enhancing testing programs to evaluate innovative technologies and operation practices testing the safe operation of natural gas or hazardous liquid pipeline facilities; sets forth requirements for idled natural or other gas transmission and hazardous liquid pipelines; updates the standards for LNG facilities; establishes the National Center of Excellence for Liquefied Natural Gas Safety and Training to include a repository of information on best practices relating to LNG operations; requires advanced leak-detection technologies and practices that include a schedule for repairing or replacing each leaking pipe, except a pipe with a leak so small that it poses no potential hazard, with appropriate deadlines; directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to finalize a rule on gas gathering lines; and allows the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration to use the Transportation Technology Center in Pueblo, Colorado, for research and development relating to transportation safety improvements that will advance the safe and efficient transportation of hazardous materials and energy products. TITLE II--LEONEL RONDON PIPELINE SAFETY ACT

Leonel Rondon Pipeline Safety Act

This title addresses pipeline safety with respect to gas distribution systems.

Among other provisions, the title directs DOT to require

 each distribution integrity plan developed by an operator of a gas distribution pipeline to include the risks from the presence of cast iron pipes and mains and risks that may result from the operation of a low-pressure distribution system; operators to establish protocols for communicating with fire, police, and other relevant public officials after a disaster that includes fires, explosions, or one or more fatalities; procedural manuals for operations, maintenance, and emergencies to include certain written procedures; operators to identify and manage traceable, reliable, and complete, records that are critical to ensuring proper pressure control for a gas distribution system; and the development of standards that promote sufficient staffing for monitoring and regulating gas pressure levels by each operator.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-217</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
