<bill session="112" type="h" number="3062" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:20Z">
  <state datetime="2011-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dairy Security Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program for dairy producers under which producers can offset reductions in producer income when the margin between milk prices and feed costs is less than a specified amount, to establish a dairy market stabilization program for producers participating in the margin protection program, to provide for the amendment of Federal milk marketing orders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dairy Security Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000258"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2011-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2012-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2011-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2011-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2011-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3111" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1658" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-15T17:23:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Dairy Security Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a dairy producer margin protection program to protect dairy producer income by paying participating producers: (1) basic margin protection payments when actual dairy producer margins are less than the threshold levels for such payments, and (2) supplemental margin protection payments if purchased by a participating producer.

Makes all registering U.S. dairy producers eligible for such program.

Authorizes a producer to purchase supplemental margin protection at the time of program registration.

Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) a dairy market stabilization program for all U.S. dairy producers in order to balance the supply of milk with demand when dairy producers are experiencing low or negative operating margins, and (2) a board of directors for the program.

 Requires milk handlers to reduce payments to each participating producer from whom the handler receives milk during any month in which stabilization program payment reductions are in effect.

Directs the Secretary to conduct the margin protection and stabilization programs from January 1, 2012, through December 31, 2017.

Directs the Secretary to amend each federal milk marketing order as provided for by this Act.

Eliminates the: (1) dairy product price support program, (2) the milk income loss contract program, (3) permanent price support authority for milk, and (4) the dairy export incentive program.</summary>
</bill>
