<bill session="109" type="hr" number="140" updated="2022-02-03T05:36:07Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-09T11:26:31-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-03-09T11:26:31-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3) to authorize funds for Federal-aid highways, highway safety programs, and transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3) to authorize funds for Federal-aid highways, highway safety programs, and transit programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-14, by Mrs. Capito.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08T21:32:17-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against the consideration of the bill are waived. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole. The bill, as amended, shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule. After disposition of the amendments in part B, the Committee shall rise without motion. No further consideration of the bill shall be in order except pursuant to a subsequent order of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-03-08" calendar="House" number="9">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 9.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09T10:55:06-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1034-1038" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09T10:55:23-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 140.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09T11:26:28-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2005-03-09T11:26:31-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1035" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-03-09T11:26:38-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="144" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-14T21:15:11Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3) to authorize funds for Federal-aid highways, highway safety programs, and transit programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-14</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
