<amendment session="112" chamber="s" number="2103" updated="2022-02-08T17:28:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2072" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-05-15">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <description>To clarify the requirement that the Export-Import Bank of the United States not make or guarantee loans that are subordinate to other loans, to restrict financing of certain fossil fuel projects in foreign countries, and to prohibit financing of renewable energy products manufactured in foreign countries.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-05-15" how="roll" result="fail" roll="94">
      <text>Amendment SA 2103, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 61. Record Vote Number: 94.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Amendment SA 2103 proposed by Senator Vitter. (consideration: CR S3150-3152, S3157; text: CR S3150-3151) To clarify the requirement that the Export-Import Bank of the United States not make or guarantee loans that are subordinate to other loans, to restrict financing of certain fossil fuel projects in foreign countries, and to prohibit financing of renewable energy products manufactured in foreign countries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2103 proposed by Senator Vitter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3150-3152, S3157" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3150-3151" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 2103, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 61. Record Vote Number: 94.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 2103, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 61. Record Vote Number: 94.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
