<bill session="109" type="h" number="174" updated="2019-11-15T21:28:57Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Geothermal Energy Initiative Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Geothermal Energy Initiative Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage greater use of geothermal energy resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000714"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-18T16:37:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Geothermal Energy Initiative Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) review and publish annually the available assessments of geothermal energy resources available within the United States; and (2) undertake new assessments as necessary, taking into account changes in market conditions, available technologies, and other relevant factors.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to expedite development of geothermal energy in making revisions to certain land use plans for public lands and National Forest System lands, respectively.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to report to Congress any recommendations for statutory or regulatory changes that would assist geothermal energy development on Federal land, including: (1) a five-year plan for encouraging such development; and (2) a list, developed in consultation with the Secretaries of Energy and of Defense, of lands under their jurisdictions, that would be suitable for development for geothermal energy, as well as recommended statutory and regulatory mechanisms for such development.

Instructs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to enter into and submit to Congress a memorandum of understanding regarding leasing (including a five-year leasing plan) and permitting for geothermal development of public lands under their respective jurisdictions.

Amends the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to reimburse certain persons through royalty credits for reasonable amounts paid for preparation by the Secretary (or a Secretary-selected contractor or other person) of project-level analysis, documentation, or related study required under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 with respect to the lease.</summary>
</bill>
