<bill session="116" type="h" number="8813" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency for Wounded Warriors Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency for Wounded Warriors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide to a member of the uniformed services who is denied a traumatic injury protection claim under Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance certain information related to that denial.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2020-11-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8257" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7105" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T17:00:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency for Wounded Warriors Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide specified information to a member of the uniformed services regarding a denial for traumatic injury benefits under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance program. Specifically, the bill requires the VA to provide the member with (1) the reason for the denial, including a description of all the information upon which the denial is based; and (2) an explanation and citation of the applicable laws, regulations, or policies upon which the denial is based. The bill also requires the VA to provide each favorable finding, which shall be binding on all subsequent reviews or appeals of the denial unless clear and convincing evidence is provided to rebut the finding.</summary>
</bill>
