<bill session="118" type="s" number="1862" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS International Cyber Partner Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS International Cyber Partner Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="display">DHS International Cyber Partner Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide explicit authority for the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to work with international partners on cybersecurity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2023-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-268.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="671">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 671.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-14T16:46:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS International Cyber Partner Act of 2023

This bill provides statutory authority for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to work with international partners on cybersecurity.

Specifically, DHS, with the concurrence of the Department of State, may assign personnel to a duty station located outside the United States at which it determines representation of the department is necessary to accomplish its cybersecurity and infrastructure security missions and to carry out duties and activities as assigned by DHS.

The activities of DHS personnel who are assigned shall be

 performed with the concurrence of the chief of mission to the foreign country to which such personnel are assigned, and consistent with the duties and powers of the State Department and the chief of mission for a foreign country. Further, CISA may enter into agreements or arrangements with foreign governments and foreign owners and operators of critical infrastructure that would further the homeland security interests of the United States and enhance the ability of a foreign government or foreign owner or operator of critical infrastructure to work cooperatively with the United States to advance U.S. homeland security interests.

The bill establishes provisions regarding (1) reimbursement of expenses, and (2) receipts credited as offsetting collections.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-268</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
