<bill session="118" type="h" number="5439" updated="2024-08-07T15:10:54Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Risk Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Risk Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a national risk management process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2023-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="824" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-01T20:43:39Z" status="Introduced in House">National Risk Management Act of 2023

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a recurring process to identify and assess risks to critical infrastructure and requires the President to deliver to Congress a national critical infrastructure resilience strategy designed to address the risks identified.

The process must include elements to

 collect relevant information from Sector Risk Management Agencies relating to the threats, vulnerabilities, and consequences related to the particular sectors of such agencies; allow critical infrastructure owners and operators to submit relevant information to DHS for consideration; and outline how DHS will solicit input from other federal departments and agencies. DHS must brief the Senate and House homeland security committees on (1) the national risk management process activities undertaken pursuant to the strategy, and (2) the amounts and timeline for funding that DHS has determined would be necessary to address risks of cybersecurity threats and physical threats and successfully execute the full range of activities proposed by the strategy.</summary>
</bill>
