<bill session="116" type="s" number="2269" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a competitive bidding process for the relocation of the headquarters of Executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-07T18:37:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act of 2019 or the SWAMP Act

This bill repeals the requirement that all offices attached to the seat of government be exercised in the District of Columbia, and not elsewhere. It prohibits new construction or major renovation of certain executive agency headquarters in the Washington Metropolitan area.

The General Services Administration (GSA) must (1) establish a process to allow an executive agency to request GSA to issue a solicitation for the relocation of its headquarters; (2) allow any state to submit a proposal for the relocation of the agency's headquarters; and (3) in consultation with the executive agency, select a state for the relocation of the agency's headquarters using a competitive bidding procedure based on certain considerations.</summary>
</bill>
