<bill session="118" type="s" number="1067" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Timely Access to Generics Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Ensuring Timely Access to Generics Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Timely Access to Generics Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to citizen petitions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Sanders with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="107">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 107.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1269" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-03T14:01:43Z" status="Reported to Senate">Ensuring Timely Access to Generics Act of 2023

This bill establishes additional requirements related to citizen petitions concerning applications for generic drug or biosimilar market approval. (Citizen petitions are petitions submitted by third parties requesting that the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) take certain actions, such as requiring additional warnings on a drug.)

Under the bill, the FDA may deny a citizen petition that (1) was submitted primarily to delay the approval of the relevant application, or (2) does not on its face raise valid scientific or regulatory issues. Currently, the FDA may deny a petition as an attempt at delay only if the petition meets both of these requirements.

The bill also expressly requires a third party, before filing a lawsuit to force the FDA to set aside or prevent market approval of a generic drug or biosimilar, to first file a citizen petition with the information and arguments that form the basis of the lawsuit. A citizen petition must be filed within 60 days of when the filer knew or reasonably should have known the information that forms the basis of the petition.</summary>
</bill>
