<bill session="117" type="s" number="3582" updated="2022-12-30T04:48:37Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Political CRIMES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Political Corruption Review of Infractions for Misconduct by Executive Servants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Political CRIMES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Independent Counsel on Pernicious Political Activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5120" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-22T19:39:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Political Corruption Review of Infractions for Misconduct by Executive Servants Act or the Political CRIMES Act

This bill addresses unlawful political activity by specified federal officials and revises the penalties for unlawful political activity by executive branch employees.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to conduct a preliminary investigation when it receives information sufficient to constitute grounds to investigate whether the President, Vice President, or other senior officials violated laws regarding political activities between January 20, 2009, and January 21, 2021. If further investigation is warranted, DOJ must apply for the appointment of an independent counsel.

The bill limits the political activity of the President and Vice President while on federal property.

Additionally, the bill increases criminal penalties for Hatch Act violations. The Hatch Act prohibits civil service employees in the executive branch of the federal government from engaging in some forms of political activity (e.g., advocating for or against a partisan political party while on duty). The purpose of the act is to maintain a federal workforce free from partisan political influence or coercion.

The bill establishes an Inspector General for the Office of Special Counsel.

The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on certain reimbursable political events held at the White House or on the White House grounds.</summary>
</bill>
