<bill session="111" type="h" number="2812" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:51Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish certain standards for the adjudication of United States passport applications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000107"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000170" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000568" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-21T21:19:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Western Hemisphere Travel Initiative Improvement Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of State to adjudicate U.S. passport applications in an individualized, evidence-based manner.

Requires the passport application adjudicatory process to be based on an assessment of individual circumstances and evidence.

Prohibits an applicant's race, ethnicity, or ancestry from being taken into account in the passport application adjudicatory process.

Requires: (1) an applicant to establish by a preponderance of the evidence that the applicant is a U.S. citizen or national; (2) the preponderance of the evidence standard to be applied in a uniform and consistent manner to all passport applications; and (3) any determination that an applicant has not met the burden of proving U.S. citizenship or nationality by a preponderance of the evidence to be made in writing, state the reasons for the determination, and be provided to the applicant in a timely manner.

States that a birth certificate signed by a person authorized under state law to sign such a document, or a previously-issued U.S. passport, shall constitute prima facie evidence of U.S. citizenship or nationality and, absent individualized evidence that a birth did not take place in the United States, shall satisfy the preponderance of the evidence standard.</summary>
</bill>
