<bill session="116" type="h" number="1937" updated="2022-11-01T18:32:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Native American Business Development, Trade Promotion, and Tourism Act of 2000, the Buy Indian Act, and the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to provide industry and economic development opportunities to Indian communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2020-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2019-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="212" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-27T16:10:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Indian Community Economic Enhancement Act of 2019

This bill makes several revisions related to economic development for Native American communities.

Specifically, the bill establishes duties for the Office of Native American Business Development, including (1) advising the Department of Commerce regarding the relationship between the United States and Indian tribes; and (2) serving as the point of contact for tribes, tribal organizations, and members of tribes regarding economic development and doing business in Indian lands.

The bill also requires coordination between Commerce, the Department of the Interior, and the Department of the Treasury to support economic development in Native American communities.

 Under the bill, assistance from the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund benefiting Native American institutions does not require matching funds.

The bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to use Native American labor and purchase Native American industry products, unless Interior or HHS determines it would be impracticable and unreasonable to do so. Among other requirements, HHS and Interior must conduct outreach to Indian industrial entities in the implementation of enterprise development.

Additionally, the bill authorizes the Administration for Native Americans (ANA) to provide financial assistance to Native American community development financial institutions. ANA must give priority for financial assistance to applicants whose programs seek to develop (1) tribal codes and court systems relating to economic development, (2) tribal business structures, (3) community development financial institutions, or (4) tribal master plans for community and economic development and infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
