<bill session="118" type="h" number="2867" updated="2024-07-03T08:05:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bruce&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bruce&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an awareness campaign related to the lethality of fentanyl and fentanyl-contaminated drugs, to establish a Federal Interagency Work Group on Fentanyl Contamination of Drugs, and to provide community-based coalition enhancement grants to mitigate the effects of drug use.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000477" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2023-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000603" joined="2024-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2024-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000619" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2024-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2023-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1235" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-22T19:58:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Bruce's Law

This bill reauthorizes certain grants through FY2028 and sets out other activities to address the dangers of fentanyl-related drug overdoses, with a particular focus on drug contamination with fentanyl or other synthetic opioids.

Specifically, the bill (1) reauthorizes grants that are available through the White House Office of National Drug Control Policy (ONDCP) for community-based coalitions to address local drug crises, and (2) authorizes new grants for coalitions to implement education and prevention strategies in communities that face significant levels of drug overdoses related to fentanyl and other synthetic opioids. The ONDCP may delegate authority to execute the new grants to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.

Additionally, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must carry out a campaign to increase public awareness of the dangers of fentanyl, including the risk of contamination of counterfeit drugs with fentanyl or other synthetic drugs.

The bill also establishes an interagency work group to coordinate and improve federal efforts to reduce and prevent drug overdoses involving contamination with fentanyl or other synthetic opioids. Work group members include the ONDCP, HHS, the Department of Justice, and the Department of State.</summary>
</bill>
