<bill session="112" type="s" number="3054" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:58Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Army Arsenal Strategic Workload Enhancement Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Army Arsenal Strategic Workload Enhancement Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide strategic workload to Army arsenals in their function as a critical component of the organic defense industrial base.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2012-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3076"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3046" label="text of measure as intoduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="5706" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-22T19:23:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Army Arsenal Strategic Workload Enhancement Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) to develop and promulgate guidelines for the Department of Defense (DOD), defense agencies, and military services to have supplies, components, end items, parts, assemblies, and sub-assemblies (supplies and parts) made in factories or arsenals owned by the United States, to the extent that such factories or arsenals can make such supplies and parts on an economical basis while preserving the ability to provide an effective and timely response to mobilizations, national defense contingency situations, and other emergency requirements.

Requires the Secretary of the Army to: (1) assign government-owned and operated Army factories and arsenals sufficient workload to ensure cost efficiency and technical competence in peacetime, while preserving the response ability described above; and (2) make Army arsenals available to DOD, the defense agencies, and military services for the procurement of supplies, components, parts, systems, and subsystems.

Directs: (1) the Secretary to report annually to Congress on Army arsenal capabilities, workload, performance, and required capital investments; and (2) the Comptroller General to review each report for completeness and compliance and provide findings to the congressional defense committees.</summary>
</bill>
