<bill session="116" type="h" number="4571" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:45Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conduct of demonstration projects to test the effectiveness of subsidized employment for TANF recipients.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2019-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2019-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2019-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2019-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Worker and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-05T22:23:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Accelerating Individuals into the Workforce Act

This bill requires the Administration for Children and Families (ACF) to make grants to states for demonstration projects that provide wage subsidies to enable low-income individuals to enter and retain employment.

States may use grant funds to subsidize an individual's wages for up to 12 months. The subsidy may be up to 50% of an individual's wages. Individuals are eligible for subsidized wages if they (1) are recipients of Temporary Assistance for Needy Families or similar state assistance or a noncustodial parent of a child receiving such assistance, and (2) are unemployed when the subsidy begins or have an income below 200% of the poverty line.

States must ensure that participants in subsidized job programs do not displace current workers.

The ACF must reserve funding to carry out this bill from amounts in the Contingency Fund for State Welfare Programs.</summary>
</bill>
