<bill session="117" type="h" number="1857" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Access to Safe and Effective Medicines Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to clarify the meaning of a new chemical entity.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Access to Safe and Effective Medicines Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2021-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="19" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-25T14:05:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Access to Safe and Effective Medicines Act of 2021

This bill provides statutory authority for the existing Food and Drug Administration (FDA) practice of defining active ingredient more narrowly as active moiety in certain situations, such as when determining whether a new drug is entitled to a market exclusivity period or providing priority review of drugs for treating rare pediatric diseases.

Generally, the FDA defines active moiety as the core molecule or ion in a drug responsible for the relevant physiological or pharmacological action. By contrast, the FDA defines an active ingredient as a component in a drug that is intended to furnish pharmacological activity or other direct effect. The FDA's existing practice of interpreting active ingredient as active moiety in certain situations, as statutorily authorized by this bill, tends to exclude some drugs from market exclusivity.

The bill replaces references to active ingredient with active moiety in various statutes authorizing FDA activities.</summary>
</bill>
