<bill session="111" type="h" number="5793" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:55Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Close Foreign Tax Loopholes: Make it in America Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to close foreign tax loopholes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close Foreign Tax Loopholes: Make it in America Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001178" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5893" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5982" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-06T15:24:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Close Foreign Tax Loopholes: Make it in America Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of foreign income and the foreign tax credit, to: (1) suspend the recognition of foreign tax credits until the related foreign income is taken into account for U.S. tax purposes; (2) deny a foreign tax credit for foreign income not subject to U.S. taxation due to a covered asset acquisition (defined as an acquisition that results in an increase in tax basis for U.S. tax purposes but not for foreign tax purposes); (3) apply a separate foreign tax credit limitation for each item of income that would be treated as derived from sources within the United States and that would be treated as arising from sources outside the United States under a treaty obligation (if the taxpayer chooses the benefits of such treaty); (4) limit the amount of foreign tax credits that may be claimed by a U.S. domestic corporation with respect to a deemed dividend paid by a foreign subsidiary; (5) prevent a reduction in earnings in profits of a foreign corporation in an acquisition if more than 50% of the dividends arising from such acquisition would not be subject to U.S. taxation or would be includible in the earnings and profits of a controlled foreign corporation; (6) treat a foreign corporation as a member of an affiliated group for interest allocation and apportionment purposes if more than 50% of its gross income is effectively connected with a U.S. trade or business and at least 80% of either the vote or value of its outstanding stock is owned directly or indirectly by members of the affiliated group; (7) repeal tax rules exempting foreign source income attributable to the active conduct of a foreign trade or business from withholding of tax requirements; (8) treat as income received in the United States amounts received from noncorporate residents or domestic corporations with respect to guarantees and amounts paid by any foreign person if such amounts are connected with income that is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business in the United States; and (9) provide that the statute of limitations for assessing any tax on certain foreign transactions shall apply only to items related to a failure to provide information to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) due to reasonable cause and not willful neglect.</summary>
</bill>
