<bill session="117" type="h" number="8375" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To establish the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in the State of Illinois, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in the State of Illinois, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4525" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-22T16:43:47Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill establishes the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in Illinois. The park is established in order to assist in the preservation and interpretation of and education concerning Prairie du Rocher and the French Colonial Historic District.

The historical park shall consist of certain lands and specified structures.

The Department of the Interior shall manage the park in such a manner as will preserve resources and cultural landscapes related to the history of the historic district and to enhance public understanding of the cultural heritage of the historic district.

The bill authorizes Interior to

 construct on federal land or lease space to operate and to maintain an interpretive visitor center complex to provide for the general information and orientation needs of the park and the historic district and serve the needs of the park; enter into cooperative agreements for the development of the interpretive visitor center complex, educational programs, and other materials to facilitate public use of the park and historic district; and acquire lands and interests within the park's boundaries by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, and exchange, except that lands and interests within the park that are owned by Illinois or any political subdivision of Illinois may be acquired only by donation or exchange.</summary>
</bill>
