<bill session="117" type="sr" number="513" updated="2023-08-15T17:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing the growing threats against women and children, religious and ethnic minorities, and LGBTQI persons in Afghanistan and against allies of such individuals, such as civil society leaders and activists, scholars, former government officials, journalists, and media workers, and expressing solidarity with and reaffirming the dire need to protect vulnerable and minority populations and their allies in Afghanistan under Taliban rule.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the growing threats against women and children, religious and ethnic minorities, and LGBTQI persons in Afghanistan and against allies of such individuals, such as civil society leaders and activists, scholars, former government officials, journalists, and media workers, and expressing solidarity with and reaffirming the dire need to protect vulnerable and minority populations and their allies in Afghanistan under Taliban rule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="926" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T17:37:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution expresses that the Senate

 stands in solidarity with the people of Afghanistan and with vulnerable groups, including women and children; religious and ethnic minorities; lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI) persons; civil society actors; journalists; and other at-risk populations in Afghanistan; calls on the Taliban to uphold the protection of universal human rights, including the commitments set forth in the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and enshrined in the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, to which Afghanistan is a party; calls for the international community to condemn human rights violations committed by the Taliban; and calls on the U.S. government to work closely with the international community and nongovernmental organizations, particularly such organizations based in Afghanistan, to support at-risk Afghan minority populations and other vulnerable communities.</summary>
</bill>
