<bill session="109" type="h" number="1263" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:29Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect and enhance consumer privacy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2005-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-09T14:32:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Privacy Protection Act of 2005 - Requires data collection organizations, under specified conditions, to notify consumers: (1) at the time of collection that their personally identifiable information may be used for an unrelated transaction purpose; and (2) of any material change in the organization's privacy policy statement immediately after each change.

Requires such organizations to establish a privacy policy with respect to the collection, sale, disclosure for consideration, or use of the consumer's information.

Requires an organization to provide consumers, without charge, the opportunity to preclude the sale or disclosure of their information to any organization that is not an information-sharing partner. Prescribes requirements for opportunities an organization may give consumers to limit other information practices of the organization.

Directs an organization to prepare and implement an information security policy that prevents the unauthorized disclosure or release of a consumer's information.

Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to presume that an organization is in compliance with this Act if it participates in an approved five-year self-regulatory program. Prescribes requirements for a self-regulatory consumer dispute resolution process.

Directs the FTC to: (1) facilitate electronic and promote the use of common identity theft affidavits; (2) require the timely resolution of identity theft disputes; (3) utilize the Identity Theft Clearinghouse to transmit information to appropriate entities for protective action and to mitigate losses; and (4) provide change of address protection for consumers.

Requires: (1) the Comptroller General to analyze the impact on U.S. interstate and foreign commerce of information privacy laws, regulations, or agreements enacted, promulgated, or adopted by other nations, and whether the enforcement mechanisms or procedures of them result in discriminatory treatment of U.S. entities; and (2) the Secretary of Commerce, based on such results, to take steps to mitigate against such discriminatory impact.

Directs the Secretary to seek harmonization of this Act with other international privacy laws, regulations, and agreements for the advancement of transnational and electronic commerce.</summary>
</bill>
