<bill session="111" type="s" number="3558" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:45Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Child Left Behind Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Child Left Behind Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5701-5702"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Social Sciences and History"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-16T14:44:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Child Left Behind Reform Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to allow states to include measures of individual or cohort growth over time in determining whether students are making adequate yearly progress (AYP) toward state academic performance standards. Eliminates the consideration of student attendance rates.

Allows schools to be given credit for performing well on measures other than test scores when calculating student achievement.

Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award competitive: (1) grants to state educational agencies to develop or increase the capacity of data systems for accountability purposes; and (2) subgrants to increase the capacity of local educational agencies to upgrade, create, or manage information databases for the purpose of measuring AYP.

 Revises the definition of highly qualified teacher to authorize states to: (1) use a generalist exam for middle school teachers; and (2) issue certificates that qualify teachers to teach a number of subjects in social studies or in science.</summary>
</bill>
