<bill session="109" type="s" number="1801" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Partnership to End Homelessness Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to reauthorize the Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Partnership to End Homelessness Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2005-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2005-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2005-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10749"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10749-10758" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Subcommittee on Housing, Transportation and Community Development. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-872.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK09" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="Housing, Transportation, and Community Development" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5041" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on Homelessness"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-08T22:21:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Partnership to End Homelessness Act of 2005 - Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (the Act) to state as the mission of the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness to develop and coordinate the implementation of a national strategy to prevent and end homelessness while maximizing federal government contributions toward such end. Adds to the membership of such Council the Commissioner of Social Security, the U.S. Attorney General, and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB). Directs the Council to develop and submit to the President and Congress a national strategic plan to end homelessness.

Requires a collaborative applicant (a representative community homeless assistance planning body) to be established for a geographic area to lead a collaborative planning process to design and evaluate programs, policies, and practices to prevent and end homelessness. Requires: (1) the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make technical assistance available to collaborative applicants and other homelessness prevention project sponsors; (2) an annual performance report from collaborative applicants to the Secretary; and (3) secretarial monitoring of collaborative applicants.

Directs the Secretary to make grants to: (1) state and local governments for assistance in providing specified homelessness services and activities; and (2) collaborative applicants to carry out homeless assistance and prevention projects. Includes within the latter grants incentives to promote the creation of new permanent housing through either construction or acquisition and rehabilitation.

Directs the Secretary to promote: (1) permanent housing development activities for homeless individuals with disabilities, homeless families that include a disabled individual, and non-disabled homeless families; and (2) certain homelessness prevention activities.

Earmarks funds under the Act for renewing expiring contracts for permanent housing within the Homeless Assistance Grants Account.</summary>
</bill>
