<bill session="118" type="s" number="3706" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Victims' VOICES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Victims' VOICES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Victims' Voices Outside and Inside the Courtroom Effectiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Victims' VOICES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Victims' Voices Outside and Inside the Courtroom Effectiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short">Victims' VOICES Act</title>
    <title type="short">Victims' Voices Outside and Inside the Courtroom Effectiveness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 3663A of title 18, United States Code, to clarify that restitution includes necessary and reasonable expenses incurred by a person who has assumed the victim's rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2024-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-29">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-02-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1090" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S1090" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-01T10:03:07-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-01T10:09:57-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:44:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4654-4656" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:44:01-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Hageman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:44:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 3706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:53:51-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T10:53:20-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4742-4743" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="361" datetime="2024-07-23T10:59:34-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 408 - 2 (Roll no. 361).</text>
      <reference ref="07/22/2024 CR H4654" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T10:59:35-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-07-25">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-07-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-77" type="public" datetime="2024-07-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-77.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-18T14:24:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Victims' Voices Outside and Inside the Courtroom Effectiveness Act or the Victims' VOICES Act

This bill makes a person who has assumed a victim's rights eligible to receive restitution for certain expenses from a convicted defendant. The bill applies to a person (i.e., legal guardian, representative of the victim's estate, another family member, or any other person appointed as suitable by the court) who has assumed the rights of a victim because such victim is under 18 years of age, incompetent, incapacitated, or deceased.

Under the Mandatory Victims Restitution Act of 1996, federal courts must order defendants who are convicted of certain crimes to pay restitution to their victims. This restitution must include the costs to reimburse the victim for lost income and necessary child care, transportation, and other expenses incurred while participating in the investigation or prosecution of the offense or attending proceedings relating to the offense, as well as medical and nonmedical care and treatment, and other associated costs.

This bill specifies that, in ordering restitution, a court must order the defendant to pay restitution to a person who has assumed the victim's rights. In particular, the defendant must pay restitution to reimburse the person's necessary and reasonable costs for (1) lost income, child care, transportation, and other expenses associated with participating in the investigation or prosecution of the offense or attending proceedings relating to the offense; and (2) lost income, transportation, and other expenses associated with transporting a victim to receive medical and nonmedical care and treatment (including physical and occupational therapy and rehabilitation).</summary>
</bill>
