<bill session="108" type="s" number="2891" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Green Mountain National Forest Land Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to sell or exchange certain National Forest System land in the State of Vermont.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Green Mountain National Forest Land Adjustment Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2004-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2948" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Skiing"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-10T16:39:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Green Mountain National Forest Land Adjustment Act of 2004 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to sell or exchange any right, title, and interest of the United States in and to five specified parcels of National Forest System land in Vermont. Directs the Secretary to offer to convey such land to Bromley Mountain Ski Resort, Inc.

Makes sale proceeds available for: (1) the location and relocation of the Appalachian National Scenic Trail and the Long National Recreation Trail in Vermont; (2) the acquisition of land for National Forest System purposes within the boundary of Green Mountain National Forest; (3) the acquisition of wetland within the boundary of the Forest to offset the loss of wetland from the parcels sold or exchanged; and (4) the payment of direct administrative costs incurred in carrying out this Act.

Allows the Secretary, using funds made available as described above or otherwise made available for acquisition, to acquire land or an interest in land for National Forest System purposes within the boundary of the Forest.</summary>
</bill>
