<bill session="117" type="s" number="1071" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA AID Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to provide pension claim enhancement assistance to individuals submitting claims for pension from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA AID Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Application Assistance Inefficiency Decrease Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2021-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-01T15:55:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Application Assistance Inefficiency Decrease Act of 2021 or the VA AID Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing claim enhancement assistance to individuals who are applying for certain VA pensions in order to reduce the backlog and expedite processing of claims. Specifically, the program applies to those applying for service pensions, non-service-connected disability pensions, or pensions to surviving spouses and children.

The Government Accountability Office must complete a review of the pilot program and a study on the feasibility and advisability of permanently extending claim enhancement assistance to individuals and spouses applying for the specified VA pensions.</summary>
</bill>
