<bill session="108" type="sj" number="2" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:04Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to require a balanced budget and protect Social Security surpluses.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States to require a balanced budget and protect Social Security surpluses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000858"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2003-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S85"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Constitutional Amendment - Prohibits outlays for a fiscal year (except those for repayment of debt principal) from exceeding total receipts for that fiscal year (except those derived from borrowing) unless Congress, by a three-fifths rollcall vote of each House, authorizes a specific excess of outlays over receipts.Provides that any surplus of receipts over outlays of the Social Security trust funds shall not be counted, and any deficit of receipts relative to outlays of the Social Security trust funds shall be counted, and must be completely offset by a surplus of all other receipts over all other outlays.Requires a three-fifths rollcall vote of each House to increase the public debt limit.Directs the President to submit a balanced budget to Congress annually.Prohibits any bill to increase revenue from becoming law unless approved by a majority of each House by rollcall vote.Authorizes waivers of these provisions when a declaration of war is in effect or under other specified circumstances involving military conflict.</summary>
</bill>
