<bill session="118" type="s" number="1859" updated="2025-11-19T03:34:54Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Our Gas Stoves Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Gas Stoves Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Secretary of Energy from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing the proposed rule entitled "Energy Conservation Program: Energy Conservation Standards for Consumer Conventional Cooking Products", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2023-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1640" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-02T18:25:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Save Our Gas Stoves Act

This bill places limits on energy conservation standards for kitchen ranges or ovens under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act.

The Department of the Energy (DOE) may not prescribe or amend energy conservation standards for kitchen ranges or ovens if they would result in the unavailability of a product on account of the type of fuel the range or oven uses.

In addition, DOE may not finalize, implement, or enforce the proposed rule titled Energy Conservation Program: Energy Conservation Standards for Consumer Conventional Cooking Products issued on February 1, 2023, or any substantially similar rule. The proposed rule prescribes energy conservation standards for consumer conventional cooking products, including electric cooking tops, gas cooking tops, electric ovens, and gas ovens.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
