<bill session="117" type="h" number="397" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:12-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:12-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear intelligence and information sharing functions of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security and to require dissemination of information analyzed by the Department to entities with responsibilities relating to homeland security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2021-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence and Counterterrorism.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Recovery.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19T14:59:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Torres (NY) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19T14:59:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1904-1905" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1904" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19T14:59:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19T15:04:05-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:12-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 6 of H. Res. 330, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 367; H.R. 370; H.R. 396; H.R. 397, as amended; H.R. 408; H.R. 490; H.R. 965, as amended; H.R. 1251, as amended; H.R. 1395; H.R. 1491; H.R. 1528; H.R. 1532; H.R. 1565; H.R. 1602; and H.R. 2523, as amended; and the following resolution was agreed to under suspension of the rules: H. Res. 124, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1979-1994" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1981" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:12-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 330, proceedings on H.R. 397 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="330" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-17T14:10:41Z" status="Passed House">CBRN Intelligence and Information Sharing Act of 2021

 This bill expands the functions of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security related to homeland-security focused intelligence and information sharing.

 The office shall

 support intelligence analysis and risk assessment of terrorist actors, their claims, and their plans to conduct attacks involving chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear materials against the United States, including critical infrastructure; support intelligence analysis and risk assessment of global infectious disease, public health, food, agricultural, and veterinary issues; leverage existing and emerging homeland security intelligence capabilities and structures to enhance early detection, prevention, protection, response, and recovery efforts with respect to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear attack; and share information and provide tailored analytical support on these threats to state, local, tribal, and territorial authorities and to relevant national biosecurity and biodefense stakeholders and other federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
