<bill session="116" type="h" number="6857" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COHORT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a COVID-19 skilled nursing facility payment incentive program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COHORT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID-19-Only Homes Organized for Resident Treatment Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6800" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-08T17:31:54Z" status="Introduced in House">COVID-19-Only Homes Organized for Resident Treatment Act of 2020 or the COHORT Act of 2020

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to establish a program in which Medicare skilled nursing facilities (SNFs) may elect to be designated as COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) treatment centers.

Participating SNFs must agree to only care for individuals who test positive for COVID-19 and must transfer all other residents to other facilities. The bill increases the applicable Medicare resident per diem for participating SNFs.

In order to qualify for the program, SNFs must meet minimum quality measurements with respect to staff, health inspections, and infection control. Participation may be voluntarily terminated by the SNF or revoked by the CMS.

The CMS must implement the program within two weeks of enactment of this bill. The program terminates at the end of the public health emergency relating to COVID-19.</summary>
</bill>
