<bill session="117" type="s" number="4661" updated="2023-03-09T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8239" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8294" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2617" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-02T15:09:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agriculture, Rural Development, Food and Drug Administration, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023

This bill provides FY2023 appropriations for the Department of Agriculture (USDA), the Food and Drug Administration, and related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to USDA for agricultural programs, including

 the Office of the Secretary, Executive Operations, the Office of Civil Rights, the Economic Research Service, the National Agricultural Statistics Service, the Agricultural Research Service, the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service, the Agricultural Marketing Service, and the Food Safety and Inspection Service. The bill also provides appropriations to USDA for farm production and conservation programs, including

 the Farm Production and Conservation Business Center, the Farm Service Agency, the Risk Management Agency, and the Natural Resources Conservation Service. The bill provides appropriations to the Federal Crop Insurance Corporation Fund and the Commodity Credit Corporation Fund.

For USDA rural development programs, the bill includes appropriations for

 Rural Development Salaries and Expenses, the Rural Housing Service, the Rural Business-Cooperative Service, and the Rural Utilities Service. The bill provides appropriations to the Food and Nutrition Service for

 Child Nutrition Programs; the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC); the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP); the Commodity Assistance Program; and Nutrition Programs Administration. The bill provides appropriations to the Foreign Agricultural Service for (1) Food for Peace Title II Grants, and (2) McGovern-Dole International Food for Education and Child Nutrition Program Grants.

The bill also provides appropriations for (1) the Food and Drug Administration, and (2) the Farm Credit Administration.

Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
</bill>
