<bill session="118" type="h" number="6165" updated="2025-07-22T13:27:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RIFA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting on Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RIFA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act to require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000086"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2023-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5933" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3362" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-28T15:17:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Reporting on Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act or the RIFA Act

This bill requires private institutions of higher education (IHEs) with specified assets or investments to file annual investment disclosure reports. The bill applies to a private IHE with (1) assets in excess of $6 billion, or (2) certain investments in excess of $250 million.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires such a private&#160;IHE to file a disclosure report with the Department of Education (ED) for a year in which the IHE purchases, sells, or holds one or more investments of concern. Investment of concern means any specified interest (e.g., stock or debt) with respect to a foreign country of concern (e.g., North Korea, China, Russia, or Iran) or a foreign entity of concern (e.g., a foreign entity that is designated as a foreign terrorist organization).&#160;

Additionally, the bill requires ED to (1) establish and maintain a publicly available and searchable database with these disclosure reports, and (2) transmit copies of these disclosure&#160;reports to certain federal agencies.

The bill authorizes ED to investigate possible violations of this bill and outlines the various penalties for each violation.</summary>
</bill>
