<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2266</number>
    <updateDate>2025-06-23T14:16:52Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-06-23T14:16:52Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-07-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2023-07-12T17:05:46Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-07-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-07-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000141</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cardin, Benjamin L. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ben</firstName>
        <lastName>Cardin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
        <updateDate>2023-08-10T15:30:24Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-07-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2024-07-08T17:27:05Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengthening American Communities Act of 2023&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bill provides funding and establishes grant programs to expand access to higher education, including by providing free community college to students. The bill also establishes the&amp;nbsp;National Public Service Education Grant program and revises the Public Service Loan Forgiveness (PSLF) program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Specifically, the bill establishes a program to waive resident tuition and fees for community college students. The Department of Education (ED) must award grants to states and Indian tribes to pay the federal share (75% of the average resident community college tuition and fees per student) of the program.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Next, the bill directs ED to award grants to states and Indian tribes for implementing evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve student outcomes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, ED must award grants to participating historically Black colleges and universities, tribal colleges and universities, and minority-serving institutions to waive or significantly reduce the first 60 credits of tuition and fees for low-income students.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill directs ED to establish grant programs to pay the costs of an undergraduate education for students who commit to working for at least three years in public service jobs upon graduation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, the bill revises the PSLF program to provide for partial loan cancellation based on the length of public service employment. Specifically, ED must cancel&amp;nbsp;15%, 15%, 20%, 20%, and 30% of the amount a borrower owes after 2, 4, 6, 8, and 10 years of public service employment, respectively, on Federal Direct Loans made after the bill's enactment.&lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Strengthening American Communities Act of 2023</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Strengthening American Communities Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:21:08Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Strengthening American Communities Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:37:56Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>22</titleTypeCode>
        <title>America's College Promise Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-02-23T14:59:57Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide greater access to higher education for America's students, to eliminate educational barriers for participation in a public service career, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-08-05T01:59:03Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-07-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s2266is/xml/BILLS-118s2266is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-07-12</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
