<bill session="114" type="hr" number="709" updated="2023-01-11T13:31:28Z">
  <state datetime="2016-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Iran, by failing to adhere to international maritime law, ignoring United Nations resolutions, and conducting military operations in a manner that raises tensions within the Arabian Gulf, has undermined stability in the Arabian Gulf, raised the danger of inadvertent escalation, and increased the risk to members of the United States Armed Forces overseas.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that Iran, by failing to adhere to international maritime law, ignoring United Nations resolutions, and conducting military operations in a manner that raises tensions within the Arabian Gulf, has undermined stability in the Arabian Gulf, raised the danger of inadvertent escalation, and increased the risk to members of the United States Armed Forces overseas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000445"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-05-27T14:36:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the actions of Iranian military and paramilitary forces in the Arabian Gulf undermined Gulf stability, raised the danger of escalation, and increased the risk to members of the U.S. Armed Forces.

 Calls on Iranian military and paramilitary forces to act in accordance with international law for conduct at sea.

 Urges the Administration to strongly respond to instances of dangerous behavior by Iranian forces.

 Declares that the House pledges to consider such behavior when considering legislation that pertains to Iran, including sanctions and arms control agreements.</summary>
</bill>
