<bill session="118" type="s" number="1564" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AI Leadership Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">AI Leadership Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Artificial Intelligence Leadership Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AI Leadership Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Artificial Intelligence Leadership Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to establish, or otherwise ensure the provision of, a training program on artificial intelligence for Federal management officials and supervisors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-109.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-11-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="234">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 234.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-19T17:06:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Artificial Intelligence Leadership Training Act or the AI Leadership Training Act

This bill requires the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to develop and implement an annual training program on artificial intelligence (AI) for federal managers, supervisors, and other employees designated to participate in the program.

The program shall, at a minimum, include information relating to

 what AI is and how it works, the benefits offered and risks posed by AI, ways to mitigate the risks of AI, organizational considerations for the development and deployment of AI, and other specified topics. The program must be updated at least every two years. OPM must establish a means by which to (1) understand and measure the participation of employees in the program, and (2) receive and consider feedback from participants.

The bill terminates 10 years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-109</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
