<bill session="118" type="s" number="3088" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CONFUCIUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Concerns Over Nations Funding University Campus Institutes in the United States Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CONFUCIUS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish limitations regarding Confucius Institutes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T20:47:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Concerns Over Nations Funding University Campus Institutes in the United States Act or the CONFUCIUS Act

This bill addresses China's influence on postsecondary educational institutions through Confucius Institutes, which are cultural institutes directly or indirectly funded by the Chinese government.

Specifically, the bill establishes requirements for postsecondary educational institutions that receive federal funding and that have contracts or agreements with Confucius Institutes. The contracts or agreements must include clear provisions that (1) protect the academic freedom of the institutions; (2) prohibit the application of foreign law on the institutions' campuses; and (3) grant full managerial authority of the institutes to the institutions, including full control over teaching plans, activities, research grants, and employment decisions.</summary>
</bill>
