<bill session="116" type="h" number="5314" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:04Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Support for Veterans in Effective Apprenticeships Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enable registered apprenticeship programs to better serve veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support for Veterans in Effective Apprenticeships Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001123" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2019-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="760" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-19T16:19:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Support for Veterans in Effective Apprenticeships Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Labor to revise its registered apprenticeship programs to include additional program requirements for increasing the access of veterans and their survivors or dependents to such programs.

Labor must acquire written assurance that sponsors of apprenticeship programs (1) are aware of the availability of educational assistance for veterans and eligible individuals for use in such programs, (2) will make a good faith effort to obtain approval for such educational assistance for at least each program location that employs or recruits such recipients, and (3) will not deny a qualified applicant to avoid making a good faith effort to obtain approval for educational assistance.

In addition, Labor must (1) require program sponsors to provide standards that contain provisions to grant advanced standing or credit, (2) provide increased wages commensurate to such standing or credit for veterans or individuals eligible for educational assistance, and (3) provide a copy of the approved apprenticeship program's certificate of registration to the state approving agency.</summary>
</bill>
