<bill session="108" type="sj" number="37" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution to acknowledge a long history of official depredations and ill-conceived policies by the United States Government regarding Indian Tribes and offer an apology to all Native Peoples on behalf of the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to acknowledge a long history of official depredations and ill-conceived policies by the United States Government regarding Indian Tribes and offer an apology to all Native Peoples on behalf of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2004-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2004-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5002-5003"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5003" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. With written report No. 108-310.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="638">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 638.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="hj" number="98" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-02T16:17:10Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Declares that the United States acting through Congress: (1) recognizes the special legal and political relationship the Indian tribes have with it, the solemn covenant with the land we share, and that there have been years of official depredations, ill-conceived policies, and the breaking of covenants by the Federal Government regarding Indian tribes; (2) commends and honors the Native Peoples for the thousands of years that they have stewarded and protected this land; (3) apologizes on behalf of the people of the United States to all Native Peoples for the many instances of violence, maltreatment, and neglect inflicted on them by U.S. citizens; (4) expresses its regret for the ramifications of former offenses and its commitment to build on the positive relationships of the past and present to move toward a brighter future where all the people of this land live reconciled as brothers and sisters, and harmoniously steward and protect this land together; (5) urges the President to acknowledge the wrongs of the United States against Indian tribes in U.S. history in order to bring healing to this land by providing a proper foundation for reconciliation between such entities; and (6) commends the State governments that have begun reconciliation efforts with recognized Indian tribes located in their boundaries and encourages all State governments similarly to do the same.

Provides that nothing in this Joint Resolution authorizes any claim against the United States or serves as a settlement of any claim against it.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-310</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
