<bill session="119" type="h" number="854" updated="2025-03-25T13:11:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DERAIL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decreasing Emergency Railroad Accident Instances Locally Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DERAIL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue certain regulations to define high-hazard flammable train, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000530"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001131" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000579" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2025-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2025-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-25T13:10:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Decreasing Emergency Railroad Accident Instances Locally Act or the DERAIL Act

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to expand the definition of a high-hazard flammable train (HHFT), thereby subjecting more trains to additional safety requirements.

Specifically, DOT must expand the definition of HHFT to mean a train transporting one or more loaded tank cars of a Class 3 flammable liquid (e.g., benzene residue) or a Class 2 flammable gas (e.g., vinyl chloride) and other materials DOT determines necessary for safety. Current regulations define HHFT as a train transporting 20 or more loaded tank cars of a Class 3 flammable liquid in a continuous block or 35 or more loaded tank cars of a Class 3 flammable liquid dispersed throughout the train.

The bill also requires railway carriers to report a train derailment that involves a train carrying material toxic by inhalation within 24 hours of the derailment to the National Response Center (NRC), state and local officials, and tribal governments. As background, the NRC is a part of the federally established National Response System. Reports to the NRC activate&#160;the National Oil and Hazardous Substances Pollution Contingency Plan and the federal government's response capabilities.</summary>
</bill>
