<bill session="110" type="h" number="5491" updated="2019-11-15T21:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2008-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emily's Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pharmacy Technician Training and Registration Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Pharmacy Technician Training and Registration Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants to States to establish and implement programs for registering pharmaceutical technicians.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2008-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000589" joined="2008-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Pharmacists"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-21T18:46:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Pharmacy Technician Training and Registration Act of 2008 or Emily's Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to states to establish and implement a pharmaceutical technician registration program that requires a state to: (1) prohibit an individual from performing the duties of a pharmaceutical technician unless the individual is registered by the State Board of Pharmacy; (2) require for registration that the individual meet certain requirements related to education and training; and (3) submit an annual report to the Secretary on pharmaceutical technician errors in the state.

Allows a state receiving a grant to provide a transitional period for individuals who began practicing as pharmaceutical technicians before the date of the enactment of this Act to comply with the requirements of the registration program.

Expresses the sense of Congress that State Boards of Pharmacy should strive to ensure: (1) a ratio of two pharmaceutical technicians to each pharmacist in hospital settings; and (2) a ratio of three pharmaceutical technicians to each pharmacist in other settings, including drug stores.</summary>
</bill>
