<bill session="116" type="s" number="3639" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:44Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to discount FHA single-family mortgage insurance premium payments for first-time homebuyers who complete a financial literacy housing counseling program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2162" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-15T17:49:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housing Financial Literacy Act of 2020

This bill&#160;modifies the&#160;discount&#160;given by&#160;the Federal Housing Administration (FHA) on single-family mortgage-insurance premium payments for first-time homebuyers who complete a financial-management counseling program. Under current law, the maximum premium amount for such homebuyers is 2.75% of the original insured principal obligation of the mortgage (compared to 3% for other homebuyers).

The bill instead&#160;requires that the premium amount for such homebuyers (1) in the case of a mortgage insured within four years of enactment, be 25 basis points (0.25% of the original insured principal obligation of mortgage) lower than the amount otherwise established by the FHA; or (2) in the case of a mortgage insured four years after enactment, at a rate set by the FHA that corresponds to the reduced risk of loss due to the counseling.</summary>
</bill>
