<bill session="117" type="s" number="2677" updated="2023-01-01T20:17:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act to limit overdraft fees and establish fair and transparent practices related to the marketing and provision of overdraft coverage programs at depository institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Overdraft Profiteering Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Overdraft Profiteering Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4277" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-08T14:32:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Overdraft Profiteering Act of 2021

This bill prohibits a depository institution from engaging in certain acts in connection with overdraft coverage.

Each depository institution that offers overdraft coverage for accounts must disclose overdraft coverage fees and certain related information. A depository institution must provide certain other disclosures regarding its overdraft protection program, including prompt notification of the account's overdraft status.

Regarding overdraft fees, the bill

 limits the number of overdraft fees a consumer may be charged each month and year, provides that such fees must be reasonable, and prohibits an overdraft coverage fee if the overdraft results solely from a debit hold amount that exceeds the actual dollar amount of the transaction. The bill also prohibits a depository institution from

 charging a non-sufficient fund fee for any debit card transaction, or reporting negative information regarding consumer use of overdraft coverage to any consumer reporting agency when the overdraft amounts and coverage fees are paid under the terms of an overdraft coverage program.</summary>
</bill>
