<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3515</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:19:46Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:19:46Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-06-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-08-02T20:33:19Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-06-30T20:14:57Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-06-21T23:25:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-242</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Clean Energy Jobs and Oil Company Accountability Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>3663</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-07-29</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 493.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 502.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-242.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-02</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 111-242.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-30</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works. (text of measure as introduced: CR S5205-5206)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S5204-5205)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001181</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Shaheen, Jeanne [D-NH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeanne</firstName>
        <lastName>Shaheen</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000038</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Mark [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-06-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-06-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-07-13T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3515, Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21624</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on June 30, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-07-13T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3515, Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21624</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on June 30, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accidents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy revenues and royalties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government trust funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Worker safety and health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-06-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-07-02T17:06:37Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Department of the Interior Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a program of research, development, technology demonstration, and risk assessment to address issues associated with the detection of, response to, and mitigation and cleanup of oil spills occurring on federal land managed by the Department of the Interior, whether onshore or on the outer Continental Shelf.</p> <p> Requires the Secretary to enter into arrangements with the National Academy of Sciences to establish an independent Science and Technology Advisory Board to provide scientific and technical advice to the program that includes: (1) identification of knowledge gaps that the program should address; (2) establishment of scientific and technical priorities; and (3) an annual review of the results and effectiveness of the program, including successful technology development.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to: (1) develop and publish a research and technology plan for the program; (2) establish at one or more institutions of higher education a research center of excellence for the research, development, and demonstration of technologies necessary to respond to, contain, mitigate, and clean up deepwater, ultra deepwater, and other extreme environment oil spills; (3) provide grants to such a center to conduct and oversee research in the technologies described; (4) conduct deepwater, ultra deepwater, and other extreme environment oil spill response demonstration projects for the purpose of developing and demonstrating new integrated deepwater oil spill mitigation and response systems that use the information and implement the improved practices and technologies developed from the program; and (5) in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), conduct a pilot program of field tests in U.S. waters of newly developed oil spill response, mitigation, and cleanup technologies.</p> Authorizes the award of competitive research grants in coordination with research centers of excellence to institutions of higher education or other research institutions. <p> Establishes in the Treasury an Oil Spill Technology and Research Fund into which shall be transferred, for each of FY2010-FY2020, $25 million from amounts of federal royalties, rents, and bonuses derived from federal onshore and offshore oil and gas leases issued under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act or the Mineral Leasing Act that are deposited in the Treasury.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-08-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-07T22:40:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to direct the Chairman of the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research (Interagency Committee) to arrange with the National Academy of Sciences to establish an independent Science and Technology Advisory Board to provide the Committee with scientific and technical advice relating to the oil pollution research and development program, including: (1) identification of knowledge gaps to be addressed; (2) establishment of scientific and technical priorities; and (3) an annual review of program results and effectiveness, including successful technology development.</p> <p>Requires Board recommendations and reports to be made available promptly to Congress and the public.</p> <p>Directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to advise and guide the Interagency Committee regarding quality assurance and standards measurements relating to its activities.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Requires the oil pollution research and development program to provide for: (1) the use of containment vessels, booms, and skimmers, particularly under worst-case release scenarios, in research, development, and demonstration of new or improved systems for the recovery, removal, and disposal of oil; (2) research, development, and demonstration of new or improved technologies and systems to contain, respond to, and clean up a discharge of oil in extreme or harsh conditions on the outer Continental Shelf (OCS); and (3) research to evaluate the relative effectiveness and environmental impacts (including human and environmental toxicity) of dispersants.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to implement a program of research, development, technology demonstration, and risk assessment to address issues associated with the detection of, response to, and mitigation and cleanup of oil spills occurring on federal land managed by the Department of the Interior, whether onshore or on the OCS.</p> <p>Sets forth specified areas of focus for prevention and mitigation technologies that protect the environment, including the control of hydrocarbons released from a loss of well control.</p> <p>Requires the Committee's oil pollution effects research, in developing improved models and capabilities for predicting the environmental fate, transport, and effects of oil discharges, to concentrate on: (1) fundamental scientific characterization of oil and natural gas behavior in and on soil and water, including miscibility, plume behavior, emulsification, physical separation, and chemical and biological degradation; (2) the behavior and effects of emulsified, dispersed, and submerged oil in water; and (3) modeling, simulation, and prediction of oil flows from releases and the trajectories of releases on the surface, the subsurface, and in water.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct deepwater, ultra deepwater, and other extreme environment oil discharge response demonstration projects for the purpose of developing and demonstrating new integrated deepwater oil discharge mitigation and response systems that use the information and implement the improved practices and technologies developed under the oil pollution research and development program; and (2) establish at institutions of higher education, and make research grants to, a research center of excellence for research, development, and demonstration of technologies necessary to respond to, contain, mitigate, and clean up deepwater, ultra deepwater, and other extreme-environment discharges of oil.</p> <p>Directs the Undersecretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to establish and make research grants to a research center of excellence for research and innovation in the fate of, behavior and effects of, and damage assessment and restoration relating to discharges of oil.</p> <p>Authorizes any agency that is a member of the Interagency Committee to establish other similar research centers of excellence.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to conduct a pilot program to conduct field tests, in U.S. waters, of new oil discharge response, mitigation, and cleanup technologies developed under the oil pollution research and development program.</p> <p>Requires the Interagency Committee Chairman to develop and publish a research and technology plan for the program. Requires an impartial peer review of the scientific and technical merit of the research proposals before any funding is granted.</p> <p>Establishes in the Treasury an Oil Spill Technology and Research Fund for the transfer, in each of FY2010-FY2020, of $25 million from federal royalties, rents, and bonuses derived from federal onshore and offshore oil and gas leases issued under the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act or the Mineral Leasing Act.</p> ]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize and enhance the programs of the Department of the Interior relating to the detection of, response to, and mitigation and cleanup of oil spills on Federal land managed by the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Department of the Interior Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Federal Research and Technologies for Oil Spill Prevention and Response Act of 2010</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-08-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3515rs/xml/BILLS-111s3515rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-06-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3515is/xml/BILLS-111s3515is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-08-02</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 502.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
