<bill session="111" type="h" number="6006" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:49Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To affirm that waters of the Great Lakes Basin are impressed with a public trust and managed consistent with public trust principles and other standards to protect the navigational, conservation, and public interests in such waters, to provide for enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To affirm that waters of the Great Lakes Basin are impressed with a public trust and managed consistent with public trust principles and other standards to protect the navigational, conservation, and public interests in such waters, to provide for enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000336"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001045" joined="2010-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-01T20:22:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 to authorize enforcement through a civil suit of the prohibition against the diversion or export of Great Lakes water by a state, federal agency, or private entity for use outside the Great Lakes basin unless such diversion or export is approved by the governor of each of the Great Lakes states.

Allows such a civil suit to be filed by the federal government, a state or local government, or by any person or organization whose property or other legally recognized interest will be adversely affected. Makes the proper venue for such a civil suit the federal judicial district with jurisdiction over any portion of the Great Lakes Basin and from which the diversion or export of water will occur or has occurred.</summary>
</bill>
