<bill session="118" type="s" number="508" updated="2025-11-19T04:15:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Work Opportunities in Correctional Facilities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Work Opportunities in Correctional Facilities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for occupational education and training programs of the Bureau of Prisons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2669" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T14:36:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ensuring Work Opportunities in Correctional Facilities Act of 2023

This bill expands job training and education programs in correctional facilities.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the Bureau of Prisons to provide additional support for occupational education and training programs. The bill requires an annual report that (1) includes a list of programs receiving funding; and (2) analyzes the efficacy of these programs in providing incarcerated workers with valuable job skills, improving their quality of life, and increasing their job prospects upon release.

Additionally, the bill reauthorizes through FY2029 grant programs for (1) evaluating and improving educational methods at prisons, jails, and juvenile facilities; (2) offender reentry demonstration projects; and (3) career training demonstration projects.

The bill also increases the number of prison work pilot projects that may be designated by the Bureau of Justice Assistance.</summary>
</bill>
