<bill session="117" type="h" number="2751" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PFAS Accountability Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to codify a Federal cause of action and a type of remedy available for individuals significantly exposed to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, to encourage research and accountability for irresponsible discharge of those substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PFAS Accountability Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000631"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001296" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001185" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2021-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1334" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-21T15:38:34Z" status="Introduced in House">PFAS Accountability Act of 2021

This bill provides a cause of action under the Toxic Substances Control Act for individuals or classes of individuals who were significantly exposed to perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS. These substances are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds, such as nonstick cookware or weatherproof clothing.

Specifically, the bill provides a cause of action those who were significantly exposed to PFAS (or have reasonable grounds to believe they were exposed) against persons who engaged in any portion of a manufacturing process that created the PFAS and foresaw (or reasonably should have foreseen) the creation or use of PFAS would result in human exposure.

The bill authorizes a court to award medical monitoring to claimants if (1) they have been significantly exposed to PFAS, (2) they have an increased risk of developing a disease associated with such exposure, (3) the increased risk provides a reasonable basis to conclude that periodic diagnostic medical examinations is necessary, and (4) the medical examinations are effective in detecting a disease associated with PFAS exposure.

The bill establishes a presumption of significant exposure to PFAS if the claimant (1) provides medical results proving the presence of PFAS in the body, or (2) demonstrates the defendant's manufacturing process created the PFAS to which the claimant was exposed and the PFAS were released into one or more areas where the claimant would have been exposed for at least one year.</summary>
</bill>
