<bill session="117" type="h" number="206" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paperwork Reduction for Farmers and H&#226;&#8364;&#8220;2A Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline the application process for H-2A employers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paperwork Reduction for Farmers and H&#226;&#8364;&#8220;2A Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2021-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4813" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-18T18:09:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Paperwork Reduction for Farmers and H-2A Modernization Act

This bill expands the H-2A (temporary agricultural worker) visa program to cover additional types of labor, makes various changes to the program, and provides a safe harbor for errors in nonimmigrant worker visa applications in certain instances.

The bill makes H-2A visas available to an alien providing temporary labor that falls within the federal government classification categories for (1) grounds maintenance workers; (2) farming, fishing, and forestry occupations; or (3) forest, conservation, and logging workers.

The bill authorizes joint employers to file a joint petition for an H-2A alien.

The bill allows (1) employers seeking to rehire an H-2A worker to submit a simplified petition, and (2) employers seeking to hire H-2A workers for different time periods during a fiscal year to submit a single petition for such workers.

The Department of Labor shall establish an electronic filing and appeals system for H-2A petitions. U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) shall communicate electronically with an H-2A employer when USCIS requests evidence from the employer, if the employer asks to do so.

An employer who uses a third-party service to apply for a nonimmigrant worker visa shall not be civilly or criminally liable for errors in the application if the employer reasonably believed that the application was accurate and complied with statutory requirements.</summary>
</bill>
