<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="4041" updated="2022-02-03T06:04:00Z">
  <amends type="sr" number="445" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-10-09">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000102"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <description>To vest sole jurisdiction over the Federal budget process in the Committee on the Budget, and to give the Committee on the Budget joint jurisdiction with the Governmental Affairs Committee over the process of reviewing, holding hearings, and voting on persons nominated by the President to fill the positions of Director and Deputy Director for Budget within the Office of Management and Budget.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-10-09" how="roll" result="pass" roll="206">
      <text>Amendment SA 4041 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 35. Record Vote Number: 206.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10900-10901, S10909" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10901" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Amendment SA 4041 proposed by Senator Nickles to Amendment SA 4027. (consideration: CR S10900-10901; text: CR S10900-10901) To vest sole jurisdiction over the Federal budget process in the Committee on the Budget, and to give the Committee on the Budget joint jurisdiction with the Governmental Affairs Committee over the process of reviewing, holding hearings, and voting on persons nominated by the President to fill the positions of Director and Deputy Director for Budget within the Office of Management and Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 4041 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 35. Record Vote Number: 206.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 4041 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 35. Record Vote Number: 206.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4041 proposed by Senator Nickles to Amendment SA 4027.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10900-10901" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10900-10901" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
