<bill session="116" type="h" number="5079" updated="2022-11-01T05:17:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Historic Vehicle Register Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to accurately document vehicles that were significant in the history of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Historic Vehicle Register Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2019-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2019-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2455" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-23T22:13:47Z" status="Introduced in House">National Historic Vehicle Register Act of 2019

This bill directs the National Park Service (NPS) to establish and maintain a National Historic Vehicle Register that shall include (1) a narrative describing each historic vehicle and its historical significance, (2) a photographic record of the vehicle, and (3) a line drawing or engineering drawing of the vehicle. Such register shall be archived in the Library of Congress.

 The NPS shall (1) coordinate with the Historic Vehicle Association, American Motorcycle Heritage Foundation, and other appropriate organizations in order to invite owners of historic vehicles to participate in the register; and (2) develop criteria for the inclusion of historic vehicles on the register.

 When developing such criteria, the NPS shall consider whether a vehicle is (1) associated with an important event or a significant individual in automotive or U.S. history; (2) distinctive based on design, engineering, craftsmanship, or aesthetic value; or (3) of a particular type that was the first or last produced or among the most well-preserved or authentically restored examples of that type.</summary>
</bill>
