<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="622" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:47Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2499" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2010-04-29T17:51:44-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001149"/>
  <offered datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <description>Amendment retains the requirement that all ballots used for authorized plebiscites include the full content of the ballot printed in English. Amendment also requires the Puerto Rico State Elections Commission to inform voters in all authorized plebiscites that if Puerto Rico retains its current status or is admitted as a State: (1) any official language requirements of the Federal Government shall apply to Puerto Rico to the same extent as throughout the United States; and (2) it is the Sense of Congress that the teaching of English be promoted in Puerto Rico in order for English-language proficiency to be achieved.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in House Report 111-468 to retain the requirement that all ballots used for authorized plebiscites include the full content of the ballot printed in English. It would also require the Puerto Rico State Elections Commission to inform voters in all authorized plebiscites that if Puerto Rico retains its current status or is admitted as a State: (1) any official language requirements of the Federal Government shall apply to Puerto Rico to the same extent as throughout the United States; and (2) it is the Sense of Congress that the teaching of English be promoted in Puerto Rico in order for English-language proficiency to be achieved.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2010-04-29T17:51:44-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="237">
      <text>On agreeing to the Burton (IN) amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 301 - 100 (Roll no. 237).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29T16:02:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Burton (IN).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3045-3047, H3054-3055" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3045-3046" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29T16:02:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Burton (IN).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3045-3047, H3054-3055" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3045-3046" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29T17:51:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Burton (IN) amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 301 - 100 (Roll no. 237).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29T17:51:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29T17:51:44-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
