<bill session="117" type="s" number="3160" updated="2022-12-30T08:33:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Border Accountability, Oversight, and Community Engagement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Accountability, Oversight, and Community Engagement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase transparency, accountability, and community engagement within the Department of Homeland Security, to provide independent oversight of border security activities, to improve training for agents and officers of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3557" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-06T19:24:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Border Accountability, Oversight, and Community Engagement Act 

This bill establishes various bodies and policies related to border security operations.

The bill establishes the independent Department of Homeland Security (DHS) Border Oversight Commission. The commission's duties shall include recommending policies to protect civil rights and improve the safety of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) officers.

The bill establishes the Office of the Ombudsman for Border and Immigration-Related Concerns. The office shall independently receive and resolve complaints and requests for assistance regarding border security and immigration activities. The office shall have the power to provide redress, including immigration relief and monetary damages.

The bill establishes the Border Community Liaison Office. The office's duties include consulting with communities in sectors on the northern and southern borders&#160;when developing policies and programs.

DHS must ensure CBP officers receive continual education and training each year on topics including interaction with vulnerable populations and professional conduct standards.

The bill imposes data collection requirements on law enforcement officials conducting border and immigration-related stops and searches.

The bill requires various reports, including a Government Accountability Office report on the use of force by the CBP.</summary>
</bill>
