<bill session="111" type="h" number="3582" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Census Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make organizations which have been indicted for violations of Federal or State law relating to elections for public office ineligible to participate in the Planning Partnership Program for the 2010 census of population, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Census Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000361" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000365" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000453" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000550" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2010-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000528" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000566" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001138" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2010-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2009-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Information Policy, Census, and National Archives.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO23" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Policy, Census, and National Archives" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-05T19:37:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Census Improvement Act - Prohibits any organization that has been indicted for a violation of law relating to an election for federal or state office or that employs or otherwise uses the services of an individual who has been indicted for such a violation from participating in the Planning Partnership Program for the 2010 census of population.

Provides that no bill, joint resolution, amendment, or conference report containing a provision which would have the effect of limiting the application of provisions regarding the confidentiality of census information shall be considered as passed or agreed to by either chamber of Congress except by a vote of at least two-thirds of the Members voting.

Requires: (1) the Secretary of Commerce to submit to the Government Accountability Office (GAO) a copy of each question proposed to be included in the 2010 census and the American Community Survey; (2) GAO&#160; to review and report to Congress on such questions; and (3) the Secretary to include his or her views on, and GAO to specifically address, the reasons for each question, the purposes for which the information obtained is likely to be used, alternative means by which the same information could be obtained, and the relative advantages and disadvantages of obtaining the information through a census or survey.

Prohibits any person conducting the Survey or 2010 census from seeking answers to any questions relating to a household or any member of such household from any person who is not a member of that household.</summary>
</bill>
