<bill session="109" type="h" number="2511" updated="2022-02-03T05:33:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To postpone the 2005 round of defense base closure and realignment until the completion of certain specified activities by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To postpone the 2005 round of defense base closure and realignment until the completion of certain specified activities by the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001037" joined="2005-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2005-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2005-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2005-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000789" joined="2005-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1051"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="2427" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1075" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and military policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Naval operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-04T18:26:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Act of 1990 to postpone the 2005 round of defense base closures and realignments, as currently required under such Act, until the last of the following occurs: (1) the complete analysis, consideration, and implementation by the Secretary of Defense (Secretary) of the recommendations of the Commission on Review of Overseas Military Facility Structure of the United States; (2) the return from deployment in Iraq of substantially all major U.S. combat units and assets; (3) the receipt by the congressional defense committees of the report on the quadrennial defense review to be submitted by the Secretary in 2006; (4) the complete development and implementation by the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security of the National Maritime Security Strategy; (5) the complete development and implementation by the Secretary of the Homeland Defense and Civil Support directive; and (6) the receipt by the defense committees of a report from the Secretary assessing military installation needs.

States that, upon the enactment of this Act, the list of recommendations for 2005 base closures and realignments submitted by the Secretary pursuant to such Act, as well as all other actions carried out under such Act by the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission or the President before the date of enactment of this Act, shall have no further force and effect.</summary>
</bill>
