<bill session="111" type="h" number="2271" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:17Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Online Freedom Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent United States businesses from cooperating with repressive governments in transforming the Internet into a tool of censorship and surveillance, to fulfill the responsibility of the United States Government to promote freedom of expression on the Internet, to restore public confidence in the integrity of United States businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Online Freedom Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000023" joined="2010-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2010-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2010-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000793" joined="2009-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-06">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-03T20:49:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Global Online Freedom Act of 2009 - Makes it U.S. policy to: (1) promote the freedom to seek, receive, and impart information and ideas through any media; (2) use all appropriate instruments of U.S. influence to support the free flow of information without interference or discrimination; and (3) deter U.S. businesses from cooperating with Internet-restricting countries in effecting online censorship.

Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should seek international agreements to protect Internet freedom; and (2) some U.S. businesses, in assisting foreign governments to restrict online access to U.S.-supported websites and government reports and to identify individual Internet users, are working contrary to U.S. foreign policy interests.

Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require assessments of electronic information freedom in each foreign country.

Establishes in the Department of State the Office of Global Internet Freedom (OGIF).

Directs the Secretary of State to annually designate Internet-restricting countries. Prohibits, subject to waiver, U.S. businesses that provide to the public a commercial Internet search engine, communications services, or hosting services from locating, in such countries, any personally identifiable information used to establish or maintain an Internet services account.

Requires U.S. businesses that collect or obtain personally identifiable information through the Internet to notify the OGIF and the Attorney General before responding to a disclosure request from an Internet-restricting country. Authorizes the Attorney General to prohibit a business from complying with the request, except for legitimate foreign law enforcement purposes.

Requires U.S. businesses to report to the OGIF certain Internet censorship information involving Internet-restricting countries.

Prohibits U.S. businesses that maintain Internet content hosting services from jamming U.S.-supported websites or U.S.-supported content in Internet-restricting countries.

Authorizes the President to waive provisions of this Act: (1) to further the purposes of this Act; (2) if a country ceases restrictive activity; or (3) if it is the national interest of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
