<bill session="118" type="h" number="1164" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">OFAC Outreach and Engagement Capabilities Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OFAC Outreach and Engagement Capabilities Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study with respect to outreach activities performed by the Office of Foreign Assets Control, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T17:02:13Z" status="Introduced in House">OFAC Outreach and Engagement Capabilities Enhancement Act

This bill addresses the outreach activities of the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC), including by requiring the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to assess such outreach activities. (OFAC, within the Department of the Treasury, is one of the agencies that administers and enforces economic and trade sanctions.)

Specifically, GAO must conduct a study examining various aspects of OFAC&#8217;s outreach activities, including (1) the goal and strategy of such activities; and (2) how, if at all, the activities help with sanctions enforcement.

After reviewing the GAO study, OFAC must assess the feasibility of a voluntary public-private information sharing program to support efforts to administer and enforce economic sanctions.

After reviewing the GAO study and OFAC feasibility assessment, Treasury may direct OFAC to establish a pilot program to facilitate such voluntary public-private information sharing.</summary>
</bill>
