<bill session="108" type="s" number="1314" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Collaborative Forest Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expedite procedures for hazardous fuels reduction activities on National Forest System lands established from the public domain and other public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, to improve the health of National Forest System lands established from the public domain and other public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Forest Health Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2003-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2003-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8362-8363"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8363-8365" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-140.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Integrated pest management"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-29T20:27:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Collaborative Forest Health Act - Permits the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior (the Secretaries) to find that a proposed hazardous fuels reduction project that meets certain criteria shall not require an environmental assessment or an environmental impact statement.

Directs the Secretaries to identify projects implemented under this section through a collaborative framework to reduce hazardous fuels. Sets a limit of 20 million acres for projects implemented under this section (not including the existing hazardous fuels reduction program).

Prohibits, except in extraordinary circumstances, timber sales and log skidding machines in at-risk communities and the nearby vicinities and in certain municipal watersheds.

Excludes the provisions of this Act relating to expedited planning and implementation from applying to certain Federal lands.

Directs the Secretaries to take certain actions to ensure that the agencies are implementing projects pursuant to this Act that reduce the risk of unnaturally intense wildfires and improve forest health.

Directs the Secretaries to expend at least 70 percent of the hazardous fuels operations funds provided annually only on projects in at-risk communities and nearby vicinities or within municipal watersheds.

Directs the Secretaries to jointly: (1) establish a commission to complete an assessment of the positive or negative impacts and effectiveness of projects implemented under this section; (2) earmark funds for the conduct of a systematic information gathering program on certain insect types that have caused large-scale damage to forest ecosystems; and (3) disburse funds to reduce the risk of wildfire to structures and restore burned areas on tribal lands.

Allows the Secretaries to make cost-share grants to various entities for the removal, transport, and disposal of hazardous fuels around homes and properties.</summary>
</bill>
