<bill session="110" type="s" number="134" updated="2023-01-11T20:06:39Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the construction of the Arkansas Valley Conduit in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Arkansas Valley Conduit Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arkansas Valley Conduit Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000109"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001163" joined="2007-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S133"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2974" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="186" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="317" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-02-15T15:54:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Arkansas Valley Conduit Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to plan, design, and construct a water delivery pipeline, to be known as the Arkansas Valley Conduit, from a location in the vicinity of Pueblo Reservoir, Pueblo, to Lamar, Colorado.

Designates the Southeastern Colorado Water Conservancy District, or its designee that is recognized under state law as an entity that has taxing authority, as the lead non-federal entity for the Conduit. Directs such entity to: (1) act as the official agent of the Conduit; (2) pay the non-federal share of any increased costs, including construction costs, under this Act; and (3) pay costs for and perform the operations, maintenance, and replacement of the Conduit. Sets the federal share of: (1) total planning, design, and construction costs at 80%; and (2) any increased costs that are a result of fundamental design changes conducted at the request of anyone other than such entity at 100%. Directs the Secretary, upon completion, to transfer ownership of the Conduit to such entity.</summary>
</bill>
