<bill session="117" type="h" number="5385" updated="2022-12-31T05:36:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make housing affordable, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Affordable HOME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable HOME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Housing Opportunities Made Equitable Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3200" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1632" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2234" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-07T21:00:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable Housing Opportunities Made Equitable Act or the Affordable HOME Act

This bill addresses the availability and affordability of housing.

Among other provisions for low-income and homeless individuals, the bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to construct and preserve multifamily rental housing projects in rural areas, specifies the number of low-income housing choice vouchers HUD must provide in FY2022-2031, and provides FY2022-2031 appropriations for HUD to assist permanent supportive housing. The bill also repeals the limitation on construction of new public housing units, commonly known as the Faircloth limit or the Faircloth amendment; prohibits discrimination in housing based on source of income; and provides additional FY2021 appropriations for the Housing Trust Fund, which provides assistance to states to produce and preserve affordable housing.

For individuals experiencing unemployment or income shortfalls during periods of increased state unemployment or during certain disasters, the bill establishes an emergency assistance fund to provide housing assistance.

 For qualifying homeowners, the bill requires HUD to provide grants for down payment assistance and establishes a 15% annual mortgage interest tax credit.

 Among other provisions for residential renters, the bill requires notice and specific cause for eviction, provides funding to state and local governments that have established a right to counsel in certain housing cases, and requires certain landlords to provide renters an opportunity to purchase before selling or transferring the rental property.

The bill also provides grants for acquisition and preservation of manufactured home communities.</summary>
</bill>
