<bill session="112" type="h" number="3810" updated="2020-02-14T19:13:56Z">
  <state datetime="2012-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 23, United States Code, to modify a provision relating to minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to modify a provision relating to minimum penalties for repeat offenders for driving while intoxicated or driving under the influence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000265"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2012-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1813" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1816" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-03T18:01:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the federal-aid highway program to modify the minimum penalties states are required to impose on motorists convicted multiple times for driving while intoxicated or under the influence of alcohol.

Requires repeat offenders to have: (1) all their driving privileges suspended (currently, a driver's license suspension) for at least one year; or (2) their unlimited driving privileges suspended for one year, with limited driving privileges permitted, subject to restrictions and limited exemptions established under state law, if an ignition interlock device is installed for at least one year on each of the motor vehicles they own or operate.

Eliminates the current alternative of a combination of suspension of all driving privileges for the first 45 days of the suspension period followed by a reinstatement of limited driving privileges for the purpose of getting to and from work, school, or an alcohol treatment program if an ignition interlock device is installed on each of the motor vehicles owned or operated, or both, by the individual.</summary>
</bill>
