<bill session="108" type="s" number="1188" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans' Survivor Benefits Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the two-year limitation on the payment of accrued benefits that are due and unpaid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs upon the death of a veteran or other beneficiary under laws administered by the Secretary, to allow for substitution of parties in the case of a claim for benefits provided by the Secretary when the applicant for such benefits dies while the claim in pending, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Survivor Benefits Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-10T14:08:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans' Survivor Benefits Act of 2003 - Repeals the limitation (benefits due and unpaid for not to exceed two years) on the accrued benefits required to be paid by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs upon the death of a veteran or other beneficiary. Provides that, upon the death of a child claiming benefits as a child of a Vietnam veteran, such benefits shall be paid to the surviving parents.

Authorizes the substitution of any of the following parties in the case of a veteran's claim for benefits provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs when the original claimant dies while the claim is pending: (1) the surviving spouse; (2) the custodian of a surviving minor or incapable child; (3) a child between 18 and 21 years of age pursuing a program of education; (4) a dependent parent; or (5) in the case of the death of a child claiming benefits as a child of a Vietnam veteran, a surviving parent.

Authorizes the substitution of the above eligible parties in cases pending before a U.S. Circuit Court or the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims.</summary>
</bill>
