<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="152" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:29Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1817" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-05-18T14:42:42-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  <description>Amendment makes modifications to the Federal flight deck officer training program.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in part B of House Report 109-84 to make improvements to the Federal Flight Deck Officers (FFDO) Program including increasing access to initial and recurrent training for FFDO's by establishing qualification standards, exploring the possibility of alternate sites for training, and ensuring that the training be provided at no cost to the pilot. Also requires the Secretary to establish a secure means for TSA personnel to communicate with FFDO's in support of their mission, issue badges to FFDO's within 180 days, set up a process by which pilots can appeal a TSA decision to revoke a FFDO's status, establish a pilot program to allow FFDO's to carry their weapon, and encourage the President to pursue international agreements that will allow the use of FFDO's on international flights.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-05-18T14:42:42-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the DeFazio amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18T14:36:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. DeFazio.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3483-3484" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3483" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18T14:36:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. DeFazio.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3483-3484" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3483" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18T14:42:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18T14:42:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the DeFazio amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
