<bill session="118" type="h" number="4474" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:02Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to confirm the requirement that States allow access to designated congressional election observers to observe the election administration procedures in elections for Federal office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001126"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6513" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-21T12:52:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Confirmation Of Congressional Observer Access Act of 2023 or the COCOA Act of 2023

This bill requires states to provide designated congressional election observers with full access to observe the administration procedures of federal elections. The bill prohibits such an observer from handling ballots or elections equipment, advocating for a position or candidate, taking any action to reduce ballot secrecy, or otherwise interfering with the elections administration process.

Designated congressional election observer refers to an individual who is designated in writing by specified congressional committees to gather information with respect to an election, including in the event that the election is contested in the House of Representatives or the Senate and for other purposes permitted by Article I, Section 5 of the U.S. Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
