<bill session="116" type="h" number="7964" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Peer Support for Veteran Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Peer Support for Veteran Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out education programs and peer support programs for family members and caregivers of veterans with mental health disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2020-08-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001124" joined="2020-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2020-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2020-08-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-09T18:59:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Peer Support for Veteran Families Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish an education program and a peer support program for the education and training of family members and caregivers of eligible veterans with mental health disorders. Under this bill, eligible veterans are those who are enrolled in the VA health care system. Such veterans must give permission for their caregiver or family caregiver to participate in either program established under this bill.

The VA must establish a four-year education program to provide a course to family members and caregivers of eligible veterans on matters relating to coping with mental health disorders in veterans. In implementing the program, the VA must enter into contracts with certain nonprofit entities with experience in mental health education.

Under the peer support program, the VA must provide peer support to family members and caregivers of eligible veterans on matters relating to coping with mental health disorders in veterans. The VA must provide peer support at each location where the education program is provided, and such support must include regular meetings in group settings between peer support coordinators, family members, and caregivers.

The VA must conduct a survey of the satisfaction of individuals who have participated in the education program and the peer support program.

VA mental health care providers must monitor the progress of the programs.</summary>
</bill>
