<bill session="117" type="h" number="487" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESET for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to expand the operation of the State employment and training programs under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESET for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Future Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revitalize and Expand SNAP Education and Training for America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Future Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2021-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-10T18:23:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Revitalize and Expand SNAP Education and Training for America's Future Act or the RESET for America's Future Act

This bill increases federal reimbursement for certain state employment and training programs under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program).

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must issue certain guidelines that permit a state to submit for full and expedited federal reimbursement of any costs incurred through SNAP employment and training programs that meet certain criteria (e.g., programs with proven positive outcomes), with no match requirement.

USDA must temporarily reimburse each state 100% of costs incurred in connection with transportation costs and other expenses related to participation in such programs through the end of the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) public health emergency or two years, whichever is later. It must also reimburse each state 100% of costs incurred to build, modernize, or improve state and local data systems related to SNAP employment and training programs.

Further, USDA must commission a thorough national assessment of its SNAP employment and training programs to develop a strategy for continuous improvement to the programs.</summary>
</bill>
