<bill session="117" type="s" number="1432" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">POWER ON Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish an electric grid resilience grant program and an electric grid resilience research and development program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POWER ON Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Outages With Enhanced Resilience and Operations Nationwide Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2885" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-28T18:05:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Outages With Enhanced Resilience and Operations Nationwide Act of 2021 or the POWER ON Act of 2021

This bill provides incentives for enhancing the resilience of the electric power grid to natural disasters and strengthening the emergency response and management of the grid.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish an electric grid resilience program. Under the program, DOE must provide grants to states and Indian tribes for projects that enhance the physical resilience of the electric grid to natural disasters.

In addition, DOE must establish a research, development, demonstration, and commercial application program to enhance resilience and strengthen emergency response and management of the electric grid. Under the program, DOE must award grants to improve the resilience of the electric grid by developing technologies and capabilities to withstand and address the current and projected impact on electric grid infrastructure of natural disasters, such as wildfires.</summary>
</bill>
