<bill session="117" type="h" number="814" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Union Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To nullify the effect of Executive Order 14003 relating to the Federal workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Union Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-04T20:46:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Union Accountability Act This bill nullifies the executive order titled Protecting the Federal Workforce, which was issued on January 22, 2021.

The order revoked previous executive orders&#160;concerning federal-employee collective bargaining and classifications. Specifically, it revoked orders that

 limited the use of unrestricted grants for union activity, specified objectives for agencies to negotiate collective-bargaining agreements and established the Interagency Labor Relations Working Group, established principles for the removal and discipline of federal employees and other personnel issues, and placed certain executive agency positions under a new schedule in the excepted service instead of the competitive service. The order also instructs agencies to engage in collective bargaining negotiations over certain non-mandatory subjects, and requires the Office of Personnel Management to provide the President with recommendations to promote a minimum wage of $15 an hour for federal employees.</summary>
</bill>
