<bill session="109" type="h" number="6016" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:32Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To prohibit the sales of certain defense articles and defense services to Pakistan unless the President adheres to long-standing practice and procedures relating to congressional review of proposed sales of defense articles and defense services.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the sales of certain defense articles and defense services to Pakistan unless the President adheres to long-standing practice and procedures relating to congressional review of proposed sales of defense articles and defense services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hj" number="93" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-28T22:18:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibits specified certifications transmitted by the President to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the Chairman of the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate on June 28, 2006, relating to the proposed sales of defense articles and defense services to Pakistan from being effective for purposes of complying with the congressional notification requirements of the Arms Export Control Act.

Declares that: (1) any letter of offer with respect to such proposed sales of defense articles and defense services to Pakistan issued before the date of the enactment of this Act null and void; and (2) any subsequent letter of offer with respect to such proposed sales of defense articles and defense services to Pakistan issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be issued only in accordance with the congressional notification requirements of the Arms Export Control Act.

Expresses the sense of Congress that, if the President desires to proceed with such proposed sales of defense articles and defense services to Pakistan, the President should only proceed with such sales in accordance with long-standing practice and procedures relating to congressional review of proposed sales of defense articles and defense services, including by providing specified advance notification to and consultation with Congress.</summary>
</bill>
