<bill session="117" type="s" number="5011" updated="2023-11-13T13:45:39Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">KIDS Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kickstarting Innovative Demonstrations Supporting Kids Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">KIDS Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to establish a demonstration project testing Whole Child Health Models, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9037" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T18:23:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Kickstarting Innovative Demonstrations Supporting Kids Health Act of 2022 or the KIDS Health Act of 2022

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to implement a demonstration program that supports a whole child health model for children under Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).

Specifically, the CMS must award grants to up to 15 states to plan and implement a health care model that supports the physical, behavioral, social, and other needs of children who qualify for Medicaid or CHIP through care coordination and integrated supportive services. States must implement models for 4-6 years. The CMS must provide technical assistance and guidance to states for the demonstration program. The bill also provides for an 80% federal matching rate for program costs.

The Government Accountability Office must report on program outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
