<bill session="118" type="h" number="2907" updated="2025-11-19T03:34:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Let Doctors Provide Reproductive Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Let Doctors Provide Reproductive Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the right to provide reproductive health care services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2024-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2024-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1297" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-16T23:31:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Let Doctors Provide Reproductive Health Care Act

This bill sets out protections for and establishes programs to support health care providers (and those who assist such providers) who offer reproductive health care services that are lawful in the state where the services are provided. Reproductive health care services refer to abortion services; contraceptive services; in vitro fertilization; or other reproductive care, education, and counseling that is provided (1) at a health care site or via telehealth, and (2) in a medically accurate manner.

The bill prohibits individuals, entities, and states from preventing, restricting, or otherwise interfering with the provision of lawful reproductive health care services by health care providers. The Department of Justice, individuals, or providers may bring a lawsuit to enforce this bill, and states are not immune from suits for violations.

Furthermore, states may not use federal funds to pursue legal cases or similar proceedings (e.g., adverse licensing proceedings) against health care providers, individuals, or entities that offer or assist with lawful reproductive health care services. Additionally, medical malpractice insurers may not deny coverage to or sue a health care provider because the provider offers or assists with lawful reproductive health care services.

The bill also funds grants to assist health care providers who offer or refer for abortion services and face legal issues relating to their provision of reproductive health care services with legal matters and improving security.</summary>
</bill>
