<bill session="117" type="h" number="2536" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:47Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prevention of Anti-Immigrant Violence Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide relief for victims of hate crimes, advance the safety and well-being of immigrants and refugees, and fund improved law enforcement and prosecution official training.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention of Anti-Immigrant Violence Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-25T16:36:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevention of Anti-Immigrant Violence Act of 2021 

This bill provides protections for noncitizens who are victims of certain crimes.

The bill expands eligibility for U visas, which are for victims of certain serious crimes or individuals who are likely helpful to law enforcement in persecuting such a crime, to include victims of hate crimes.

The bill raises the annual cap on U visas to 12,000 (from 10,000) and designates the additional visas for victims of hate crimes. (Such caps apply only to the primary visa recipient, not to certain family members who may accompany the primary recipient.)

A noncitizen with a pending application for certain immigration benefits, such as for a U visa or a T visa (human trafficking victim), may not be removed from the United States. A noncitizen with such a pending application may only be detained if there is clear and convincing evidence that (1) alternatives to detention would not reasonably ensure the noncitizen's appearance at removal proceedings, or (2) the noncitizen is a threat to the community.

The Department of Justice may award grants to entities to assist noncitizen victims of hate crimes or to train law enforcement to identify and protect victims of anti-immigrant violence.</summary>
</bill>
