<bill session="118" type="h" number="3791" updated="2025-11-19T03:46:34Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving DATA in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Data Accessibility Through Advancements in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving DATA in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to public health data accessibility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4697" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3545" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-26T16:04:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Data Accessibility Through Advancements in Public Health Act or the Improving DATA in Public Health Act

This bill authorizes the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to require entities such as health care providers and local health departments to report public health data to the CDC. The bill also establishes grants to support collecting and reporting public health data&#160;and establishes the Public Health Information Sharing and Availability Advisory Committee.

The Department of Health and Human Services must award grants and other assistance to state, tribal, and local governments; health care providers; and other eligible entities to develop and disseminate best practices for collecting electronic health information and using data and technology standards for public health data systems.

The bill also expands requirements related to those standards, including by requiring them to capture demographic characteristics and other information (e.g., veteran status and housing status).

Additionally, the CDC must collaborate with state, local, and tribal health authorities to ensure that collected data is accessible to such authorities in a timely manner. Further, if data or information is reportable under state or local law, the state or local jurisdiction must receive the data or information before or at the same time as the CDC.

Further, the CDC may modify reporting requirements during declared emergencies without going through typical rulemaking procedures.

The bill expressly restricts, subject to exceptions, certain disclosures of data and information reported to the CDC, including for purposes of litigation.</summary>
</bill>
