<bill session="109" type="s" number="1365" updated="2022-02-03T05:25:58Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 35 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve the health coverage tax credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8379"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-11T14:29:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">TAA Health Coverage Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to revise the tax credit for the health insurance costs of trade adjustment assistance (TAA) workers to, among other things: (1) increase the amount of such credit from 65 to 95 percent; (2) allow for the full amount of such credit and for full payment of TAA worker health insurance premiums for months prior to the issuance of a qualified health insurance costs credit eligibility certificate; and (3) set forth new tax credit eligibility rules for TAA workers and their family members.

 Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to establish a program to offer TAA workers enrollment in the Federal Employees Health Benefit Program (FEHBP).

Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to: (1) prevent a lapse of health care coverage for TAA workers; and (2) align coverage periods under such Act with eligibility periods for TAA workers.

Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require a state or entity to use national emergency grant funds to provide TAA workers and their family members with health insurance coverage for periods prior to their first eligibility month.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to extend: (1) through FY2007 funding for the creation and initial operation of state high risk health insurance pools; and (2) through FY2010 funding for allotments for the operation of existing state pools.</summary>
</bill>
