<bill session="118" type="h" number="664" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense Access Roads Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Access Roads Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain reports relating to defense access roads, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E79"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-01T21:07:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Defense Access Roads Improvement Act

This bill updates provisions and requirements related to the Defense Access Roads Program, which authorizes the Department of Defense (DOD) to pay for construction and maintenance of defense access roads.

 DOD must establish a formal mechanism under which a state, county, or municipality may petition to certify roads as defense access roads, and DOD must respond in writing.

Additionally, DOD must maintain and regularly update on a federal website a list of all defense access roads that includes certain unclassified information about each road (e.g., the military installation that is closest to the road).

The bill also includes military installations and commercial shipyards as sites that utilize defense access roads, thereby authorizing the use of program funds for the maintenance or construction of such roads. Further, the bill requires that defense access road projects abide by certain wage and materials requirements.</summary>
</bill>
