<bill session="117" type="h" number="627" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Custody Protection Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit taking minors across State lines in circumvention of laws requiring the involvement of parents in abortion decisions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Custody Protection Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000827"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="16" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="109" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2223" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-27T12:54:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Child Custody Protection Act of 2021

This bill establishes new criminal offenses related to the transportation of a minor across state lines for an abortion.

Specifically, the bill makes it a crime to knowingly transport a minor across a state line to obtain an abortion without satisfying a parental involvement law in the minor's resident state. A parental involvement law requires parental consent or notification, or judicial authorization, for a minor to obtain an abortion.

A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, up to one year in prison, or both. The bill provides an exception for an abortion that is necessary to save the life of a minor whose life is endangered by a physical disorder, illness, or condition.

Additionally, the bill imposes criminal penalties on an individual who commits incest with a minor and knowingly transports the minor across a state line to receive an abortion.</summary>
</bill>
