<bill session="119" type="h" number="2124" updated="2025-08-16T08:05:37Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that a foreign purchaser of agricultural land be subject to the same restrictions as are applicable to United States citizens and nationals in the home country of such foreign purchaser.</title>
    <title type="display">LAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land And National Defense Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001317" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000596" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001102" joined="2025-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001235" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001188" joined="2025-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-12T18:29:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Land And National Defense Act or the LAND Act

This bill requires that a foreign purchaser of agricultural land be subject to (1) the same restrictions and limitations as a U.S. citizen or national would be subject to when purchasing agricultural land in the foreign purchaser's home country, and (2) any restrictions and limitations that apply under state law with respect to the purchase.

The bill applies to all foreign purchasers, including U.S. citizens who are also a citizen of one or more other countries (e.g., a dual citizen).

For a foreign company purchasing agricultural land, a country is treated as the company's home country if (1) it has the most restrictive laws with respect to the purchasing of agricultural land, and (2) the citizens of the country hold at least 5% of the company.

The seller of the agricultural land to a foreign purchaser must report the sale to the Department of Agriculture (USDA). Further, USDA must&#160;notify certain&#160;Members of Congress of the sale, including&#160;(1) the Senators from the state in which the agricultural land is located, and (2) the Representative from the congressional district where the land is located.

In addition, the bill establishes the U.S. Land Protection Task Force, chaired by the Secretary of Agriculture, to identify violations of these restrictions on foreign agricultural land purchasers.

The task force must submit a report to Congress every six months, which must include specific information on the sale of agricultural land to foreign purchasers.</summary>
</bill>
