<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3530</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:19:46Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:19:46Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-06-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-06-24T18:45:49Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S5462)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000590</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Pryor, Mark L. [D-AR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Pryor</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <middleName>Lunsford</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-06-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advanced technology and technological innovations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-06-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-11-22T21:46:11Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Reward Innovation in America Act of 2010 - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to authorize each head of a federal agency (other than a legislative agency) to carry out a program to award prizes competitively to stimulate innovation that has the potential to advance the agency's mission, including: (1) point solution prizes that reward and spur the development of solutions for a particular, well-defined problem; (2) exposition prizes that help identify and promote a broad range of ideas and practices that may not otherwise attract attention, facilitating further development of the idea or practice by third parties; and (3) participation prizes that create value by encouraging contestants to change their behavior or develop new skills that may have beneficial effects during and after the competition. Requires the agency head to: (1) widely advertise each competition to encourage broad participation; and (2) publish notices of competitions in the Federal Register. </p> <p>Prohibits the government from gaining an interest in intellectual property developed by a participant in a competition without the written consent of the participant, but authorizes the government to negotiate a license for the use of intellectual property developed by a participant. </p> <p>Authorizes: (1) an agency head to enter into an agreement with a private, nonprofit entity to administer competitions; and (2) support for a competition to consist of federal appropriated funds and funds provided by the private sector for cash prizes. Prohibits a prize from being announced until all funds needed to pay out the announced amount of the prize have been appropriated or committed in writing by a private source. Limits prize amounts. </p> <p>Requires: (1) the General Services Administration (GSA) to provide government-wide services to share best practices and assist agencies in developing guidelines for issuing competitions; and (2) the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy to submit annual reports on program activities.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Reward Innovation in America Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Reward Innovation in America Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to provide for prize competitions to stimulate innovations that advance the missions of Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Reward Innovation in America Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-06-24T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3530is/xml/BILLS-111s3530is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-06-24</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S5462)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
