<bill session="111" type="h" number="596" updated="2019-11-15T20:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Recovery Through Increased Feeding Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Economic Recovery Through Increased Feeding Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to reduce hunger, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000792"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="6539" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-22T20:06:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Economic Recovery Through Increased Feeding Act of 2009 - Amends the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (the Food Stamp Act of 1977 as renamed by the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008) to increase to 12 months the amount of time certain work capable adults can receive Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) benefits (formerly, food stamp benefits).

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to require appropriate states to: (1) submit to the Secretary reports identifying SNAP participation in the 25 largest U.S. cities; and (2) implement practices to increase program participation in cities where eligible household participation is less than 85%.

Increases funding for grants to increase program participation.

Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to support the use of electronic benefits transfers for federal nutrition programs at farmers' markets.</summary>
</bill>
