<bill session="118" type="s" number="1537" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Raising Tariffs on Imports from China Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Raising Tariffs on Imports from China Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the imposition of additional duties with respect to articles imported from the People's Republic of China until trade between the United States and the People's Republic of China comes into balance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-01T15:08:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Raising Tariffs on Imports from China Act of 2023

This bill directs the President to annually calculate and publish in the Federal Register (1) the total value of articles imported into the United States from China, and (2) the total value of articles exported from the United States to China.

If the total value of articles imported into the United States from China exceeds the total value of articles exported from the United States to China for the preceding year, then the President must impose a 25% ad valorem duty on each article imported from China. These additional duties must continue until the total value of articles imported from China is equal to or less than the total value of articles exported to China for the preceding calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
