<bill session="118" type="h" number="290" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:19Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-30T16:38:27-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-30T16:38:27-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commercial Remote Sensing Amendment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Commercial Remote Sensing Amendment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Remote Sensing Amendment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Commercial Remote Sensing Amendment Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for transparent licensing of commercial remote sensing systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2023-01-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H495"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30T16:31:05-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30T16:31:07-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H495-496" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30T16:31:09-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 290.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2023-01-30T16:38:27-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H495" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30T16:38:29-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-09T16:51:03Z" status="Passed House">Commercial Remote Sensing Amendment Act of 2023

This bill modifies provisions relating to the licensing of private remote sensing space systems. (Remote sensing refers to the collection of unenhanced data by an instrument in Earth's orbit that can be processed into imagery of surface features of the Earth; private remote sensing space systems refer to remote sensing instruments not owned by the U.S. government.)

The bill decreases from 120 to 60 days the amount of time in which the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration must review and make a determination on an application for a license to operate a private remote sensing space system.

Further, the bill expands annual reporting on the licensing of private remote sensing systems to include a list of all applications, listed by tier, as well as the rationale for each tier categorization (currently, each license is categorized into one of three tiers based on whether the system produces or is capable of producing unenhanced data that is already available from other entities). Additionally, the report must include all terms, conditions, or restrictions placed on licensees.

The bill also extends the requirement for annual reports from September 30, 2020, to September 30, 2030.</summary>
</bill>
