<bill session="117" type="h" number="8743" updated="2022-12-29T19:03:39Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to provide enhanced enforcement authority for occupational safety and health protections applicable to the legislative branch, to provide whistleblower protections and other antidiscrimination protections for employees of the legislative branch, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2022-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2022-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E873"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-13T19:21:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Congress Leads by Example Act of 2022

This bill authorizes the Office of Congressional Workplace Rights (OCWR) to investigate alleged violations of occupational safety and health protections in legislative branch entities. The bill also provides certain employment-related protections to employees of such entities.

The OCWR shall have subpoena authority to inspect and investigate occupational safety and health complaints in congressional offices and committees, the Congressional Budget Office, the Capitol Police, and other specified entities. The bill also imposes record-keeping requirements on such entities with respect to the enforcement of occupational safety and health protections.

Additionally, these entities may not (1) retaliate against an employee for requesting OCWR action or for participating in an OCWR investigation, (2) fire an employee because the employee's wages have been garnished due to a debt, (3) retaliate against an employee for whistleblowing activities, (4) discriminate against an employee for being a debtor or bankrupt, or (5) retaliate against an employee for attending jury service.

Other matters addressed in the bill include:

 authorizing the OCWR to seek, in appropriate cases when an unfair labor practice complaint is filed, court-ordered temporary relief from the practice, such as a temporary restraining order; excluding additional types of proceedings (e.g., proceedings involving discrimination claims) from confidentiality provisions that currently apply; and requiring employing offices in the legislative branch to enter mediation if requested by a claimant (currently, both parties must agree to enter mediation).</summary>
</bill>
