<bill session="118" type="s" number="1689" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combatting Fentanyl Trafficking from China and Mexico Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combatting Fentanyl Trafficking from China and Mexico Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prioritize efforts of the Department of State to combat international trafficking in precursor chemicals and covered synthetic drugs with the Government of Mexico, to provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to persons of the People's Republic of China contributing to international proliferation of illicit drugs or their means of production, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-30T16:06:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combatting Fentanyl Trafficking from China and Mexico Act

This bill requires the Department of State to carry out programs and activities to prioritize efforts to combat the international trafficking of certain synthetic drugs and precursor chemicals from Mexico and China.

Specifically, the State Department shall strengthen law enforcement and rule of law efforts outlined in certain agreements between the United States and Mexico, strengthen bilateral efforts, and provide Mexico with technical assistance and equipment for anti-drug law enforcement.

The President may impose certain sanctions on persons of China determined to have engaged in or benefited from the international proliferation of illicit drugs or their means of production. The President may terminate sanctions on Chinese persons upon determination that China has made substantial efforts in counternarcotics.

The bill also authorizes through FY2027 State Department International Narcotics and Law Enforcement&#160;for Mexico, Customs and Border Protection interdiction programs, and a Department of Homeland Security transnational criminal investigative unit with Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
