<bill session="108" type="h" number="4932" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northwest Rural Employment and Forest Restoration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish management priorities for Federal forest lands in Oregon and Washington located west of the Cascade Crest that will protect old growth timber while improving the health of young managed stands, increasing the volume of commercial timber available from these lands, and providing economic opportunities in local communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest Rural Employment and Forest Restoration Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Logging"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-01T18:06:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Northwest Rural Employment and Forest Restoration Act of 2004 - Requires each Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management administrative unit containing Westside Forest land to identify: (1) different forest land management allocations, as amended by the Northwest Forest Plan; and (2) the location, acreage, and age of old growth stands, young managed stands, and other naturally occurring stands.

Requires such administrative units to: (1) plan and implement projects to enhance the forest health of Westside Forest land managed by the administrative unit; and (2) prioritize projects so that significant acreage identified in the inventory are planned for treatment, and treatment has begun, before planning other projects. Sets forth priorities for such projects.

Prohibits such administrative units from planning, advertising, contracting or implementing any harvest of timber for matrix land containing old growth stands, except for noncommercial use or noncommercial purposes in an emergency situation.

Allows such administrative units to prepare programmatic environmental documentation pursuant to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 to study the significant environmental effects of the major Federal actions contemplated in projects authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
