<bill session="118" type="h" number="6398" updated="2025-06-23T14:16:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Institution Regulatory Tailoring Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Institution Regulatory Tailoring Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the asset thresholds at which financial institutions become subject to certain requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2024-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8337" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T19:29:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Institution Regulatory Tailoring Enhancement Act

This bill increases several different asset levels which determine the applicability of specific regulations to financial institutions.

The bill raises the asset level above which insured depository institutions and credit unions become subject to supervision by the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau for purposes of compliance with consumer financial laws and for risk assessments of products and services.

The bill also raises the asset level below which debit card issuers are exempt from interchange transaction fee regulations.

The bill raises the asset level above which banks must comply with the Volcker Rule, which prohibits banks from proprietary trading and having an ownership interest in private funds.

The bill raises the asset level below which financial institutions must comply with less prescriptive ability-to-repay determinations for residential mortgages.

Finally, the bill raises the asset level below which certain depository institutions and depository institution holding companies qualify as community banks and are therefore subject to a simplified leverage ratio.</summary>
</bill>
