<bill session="108" type="h" number="2470" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:30Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MEDDS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain actions with respect to the availability of medicines for HIV/AIDS and other diseases in developing countries.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEDDS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicines to Eliminate Diseases in Developing States Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000250" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2003-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2003-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2003-11-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2003-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2003-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International organization"/>
    <term name="Patent infringement"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-04T19:11:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicines to Eliminate Diseases in Developing States Act or MEDDS Act - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, the Administrator of the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), and the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to encourage developing countries and pharmaceutical companies to make medicines for HIV/AIDS and other diseases available without charge or at affordable prices in developing countries.

Prohibits agencies from obligating or expending Federal funds to seek the revocation or revision of any intellectual property or competition law or policy of a developing country that regulates medicines for HIV/AIDS and other diseases, if the law or policy promotes access to such medicines for the population of the country. Prohibits the USTR from initiating a proceeding in the World Trade Organization (WTO) challenging any law or policy of a developing country that promotes such access.

Requires the President to direct the U.S. respresentative to the WTO to urge the WTO to exempt developing countries from the application of any provision of the Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights (TRIPS Agreement) or other trade agreements that would prohibit or restrict those countries from establishing law or policy promoting access to medicines for HIV/AIDS and other diseases for their populations, and to support full implementation of the Declaration on the TRIPS Agreement and Public Health. Requires the USTR to oppose the inclusion in future trade agreements of any provision that would prohibit or otherwise restrict developing countries from establishing or implementing the laws or policies encouraged by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
