<bill session="111" type="s" number="4026" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Minority Business Development Improvements Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish in the Department of Commerce the Minority Business Development Program to provide qualified minority businesses with technical assistance and contracting opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Business Development Improvements Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4343" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-20T15:13:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Minority Business Development Improvements Act of 2010 - Requires the Director of the Minority Business Development Agency to establish the Minority Business Development Program to provide qualified minority businesses with technical assistance and contract procurement assistance. Outlines minority business qualification requirements for the Program, including that: (1) not less than 51% of the entity be directly and unconditionally owned or controlled by historically disadvantaged individuals; and (2) each officer or other individual exercising control over regular operations is a historically disadvantaged individual. Outlines specific types of technical assistance authorized under the Program.

Authorizes the Director to enter into agreements for the fulfillment of federal procurement contracts by, and contracting opportunities for, qualified minority businesses. Provides contract limits.

Allows the Director to terminate a qualified minority business from the Program under specified circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
