<bill session="117" type="h" number="8041" updated="2023-08-15T14:00:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">China Social Media Reciprocity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">China Social Media Reciprocity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide authorities to prohibit the provision of services by social media platforms to individuals and entities on the Specially Designated Nationals List and certain officials and other individuals and entities of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2022-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T13:53:18Z" status="Introduced in House">China Social Media Reciprocity Act

This bill authorizes the President to impose sanctions by requiring social media companies to block certain individuals and entities from using the company's social media services.

The bill also requires the President to impose such sanctions on certain individuals and entities, including those that a social media company knows or should have known are (1) on the Office of Foreign Asset Control's list of specially designated nationals and blocked persons, (2) senior officials in China's government, or (3) agents or instrumentalities of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) or China's government. The President may waive such sanctions if the President certifies to Congress that the CCP and China's government have removed all prohibitions on U.S. government officials participating in social media platforms in China.</summary>
</bill>
