<bill session="117" type="s" number="760" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require recipients of Federal funds to disclose information relating to programs, projects, or activities carried out using the Federal funds.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cost Openness and Spending Transparency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-19T14:21:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cost Openness and Spending Transparency Act of 2021 or the COST Act

This bill requires recipients of federal funds to disclose financing information relating to programs, projects, or activities carried out using such funds.

Specifically, such a recipient (including a state or local government or a recipient of a federal research grant) must clearly state in any press release, request for proposals, bid solicitation, or other document describing the activity the amount and percentage of federal funding and the amount and percentage of nongovernmental funding.

 If the Office of Management and Budget determines that a recipient is failing to comply, it may direct each agency providing federal funds to withhold up to 25% of the funds until the recipient complies.</summary>
</bill>
