<bill session="118" type="h" number="7073" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-24T14:20:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-24T14:20:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="display">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve public-private partnerships and increase Federal research, development, and demonstration related to the evolution of next generation pipeline systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000814"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2024-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2024-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2024-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2024-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 36 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 118-699.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-20" calendar="Union" number="593">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 593.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lucas moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5631-5635" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:39:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7073.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T19:53:38-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T14:14:36-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5572-5673" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="447" datetime="2024-09-24T14:20:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 373 - 41 (Roll no. 447).</text>
      <reference ref="9/23/2024 CR H5631-5633" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T14:20:06-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-25T18:53:07Z" status="Reported to House">Next Generation Pipelines Research and Development Act

This bill establishes programs for researching, developing, and demonstrating advanced materials and technologies applicable to pipelines and associated infrastructure, such as liquefied natural gas facilities and liquid fuel storage facilities.

The Department of Energy (DOE) must establish a five-year initiative under which DOE awards financial assistance for carrying out demonstration projects&#226;&#8364;&#8221;on low- to mid-technology readiness level subjects&#226;&#8364;&#8221;to achieve deployment of technologies that (1) are applicable to pipelines and associated infrastructure; and (2) involve the development of next generation pipeline systems, components, and related technologies. DOE must select projects that (1) best advance research undertaken by DOE and the Department of Transportation (DOT), and (2) incorporate a range of technology focus areas.

In consultation with DOT and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST), DOE must establish a joint research and development program concerning advanced and innovative materials and technologies for pipeline transportation systems. DOE must enter into or update an existing memorandum of understanding with DOT and NIST to administer the joint program.

DOE must also establish a National Pipeline Modernization Center, which must focus on collaborating with industry and stakeholders to coordinate and carry out research, development, and demonstration projects related to commercializing cost-effective products and procedures aligned with the goals and priorities set forth by DOE.&#160;

Additionally, NIST must carry out a program of measurement research, development, demonstration, and standardization to (1) ensure the integrity of pipeline facilities; and (2) support pipeline safety, security, efficiency, sustainability, and resilience.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-699</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
