<bill session="117" type="h" number="672" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rejecting and Eliminating the Foul Use of Symbols Exulting Confederate Principles Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to provide funds for the removal of Confederate symbols, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REFUSE Confederate Principles Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rejecting and Eliminating the Foul Use of Symbols Exulting Confederate Principles Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-25T02:00:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Rejecting and Eliminating the Foul Use of Symbols Exulting Confederate Principles Act or the REFUSE Confederate Principles Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to establish, within the National Park Service (NPS), a program to be known as the Emancipation Historic Preservation Program to award grants to states and other eligible entities to

 remove a Confederate symbol; remove and replace a Confederate symbol with an alternative monument, memorial, statue, commemorative structure, symbol, or signage; remove and replace a Confederate symbol with an alternative monument, memorial, statue, commemorative structure, symbol, or signage to commemorate or depict the freedom of enslaved African Americans; and remove and transfer a Confederate symbol to a state historic preservation program. Interior shall also provide technical assistance to eligible entities related to these activities.

None of the funds made available by this bill may be used by Interior, the NPS, or an eligible entity for the preservation, rehabilitation, restoration, reconstruction, or new construction of a Confederate symbol.</summary>
</bill>
