<bill session="111" type="h" number="5991" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:49Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Metalworking Manufacturers Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish small metalworking business financial assistance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Metalworking Manufacturers Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-18T18:13:49Z" status="Introduced in House">American Metalworking Manufacturers Support Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to: (1) carry out a program to provide business stabilization loans to viable small metalworking businesses that have a qualifying SBA small business loan and are experiencing immediate financial hardship; and (2) establish a technical assistance program to assist a bank or other financial institution to provide such loans to such businesses. Prohibits the Administrator from charging any loan fees.

Makes specified funds available to the Secretary of the Treasury for the loan program. Limits each loan to a maximum of $3 million and 18 months, without interest.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a small metalworking business tax credit of 30% of the amount paid or incurred for metal parts, components, or assemblies produced for the taxpayer under a contract between the taxpayer and a small metalworking business.</summary>
</bill>
