<bill session="118" type="s" number="2582" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AANAPISI Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AANAPISI Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an integrated research, education, and extension competitive grant program and scholarship grant program for certain Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving agricultural institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2783" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-20T20:00:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">AANAPISI Opportunity Act

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a scholarship grant program for covered Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions (AANAPISIs) to provide scholarships in agriculture-related fields.

Covered institutions include institutions of higher education that (1) have a student body consisting of at least 10% Asian American or Native American Pacific Islander students; and (2) offer associate, bachelors, or other accredited degree programs in agriculture-related fields.

USDA may only award the grants to AANAPISIs that have established a competitive scholarship awards process for individuals who intend to pursue a career in agriculture, including in the agricultural disciplines of business, engineering, technology, food science, forestry, home economics, nutrition, soil conservation, non-medical biological sciences, and computer science.

 This bill also allows USDA to provide competitive grants for up to five years for integrated agricultural research, education, and extension projects at covered AANAPISIs to address U.S. agriculture priorities. The project grants include a 50% matching funds requirement that USDA may waive if certain requirements are met.</summary>
</bill>
