<bill session="112" type="h" number="3119" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:10Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Families and Businesses Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to remove the per-country limitation on employment-based immigrant visas, to adjust the per-country limitation on family-sponsored immigrant visas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Families and Businesses Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2011-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1857" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-06T17:02:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting American Families and Businesses Act of 2011 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) eliminate the per country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, and (2) increase the per country numerical limitation for family based immigrants.

Amends the Chinese Student Protection Act of 1992 to eliminate the provision requiring the reduction of annual Chinese (PRC) immigrant visas to offset status adjustments under such Act.

Allows extensions of stay based upon a lengthy labor certification or priority adjudication for: (1) foreign students, (2) speciality occupation aliens, and (3) intracompany transfers.

Eliminates the foreign residency requirement for certain foreign students.

Provides for the recapture of unused employment-based and family-based immigrant visas.</summary>
</bill>
