<bill session="111" type="h" number="2351" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:15Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Credit Union Share Insurance Stabilization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act to increase the borrowing authority of the National Credit Union Administration, establish a National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund restoration plan period, assess insured credit unions for the costs associated with the corporate credit union stabilization effort on an anti-cyclical basis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Share Insurance Stabilization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000553" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2010-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2009-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-09T21:56:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Credit Union Share Insurance Stabilization Act - Amends the Federal Credit Union Act (FCUA) to grant the National Credit Union Administration (NCUA) increased borrowing authority until December 31, 2010.

Requires the NCUA Board to: (1) establish a National Credit Union Share Insurance Fund (NCUSIF) Restoration Plan whenever it projects that the equity ratio of the NCUSIF will fall below a designated minimum equity ratio; and (2) establish the Temporary Corporate Credit Union Stabilization Fund (TCCUSF) to make payments connected to the actual or threatened conservatorship or liquidation of a corporate credit union. Authorizes the TCCUSF to borrow from the Secretary of the Treasury, subject to specified conditions.</summary>
</bill>
