<bill session="116" type="h" number="904" updated="2022-11-01T15:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Illegal Deduction Elimination Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New IDEA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Illegal Deduction Elimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify that wages paid to unauthorized aliens may not be deducted from gross income, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000362"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2019-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2019-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2019-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8838" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="9064" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-27T18:43:47Z" status="Introduced in House">New IDEA Act or the New Illegal Deduction Elimination Act

This bill denies a tax deduction for wages and benefits paid to or on behalf of an unauthorized alien. The bill also extends to six years&#160;the period for assessing and collecting underpayments of tax due to deductions claimed for wages paid to unauthorized aliens.

The Social Security Administration (SSA), the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), and the Department of the Treasury must jointly establish a program to share information that may lead to the identification of unauthorized aliens. Treasury must provide information to DHS and the SSA regarding employers who paid nondeductible wages to unauthorized aliens and the aliens to whom such wages were paid.

The bill amends the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 to (1) make permanent the E-Verify Program for verifying the employment eligibility of alien workers, (2) apply such program to current employees in addition to new hires, (3) establish a rebuttable presumption that employers who participate in the E-Verify Program and obtain confirmation of identity and employment eligibility have not violated hiring requirements under such Act, and (4) allow employers participating in the E-Verify Program&#160;to make a conditional offer of employment pending final verification of the identity and employment eligibility of the job applicant.</summary>
</bill>
