<bill session="116" type="s" number="3341" updated="2022-02-08T23:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CEO and Worker Pension Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CEO and Worker Pension Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to restrict the tax benefits of executive deferred compensation and increase disclosure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-27T17:30:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CEO and Worker Pension Fairness Act

This bill limits tax benefits for deferred compensation of highly compensated employees (e.g., corporate chief executive officers) and increases disclosure requirements for such compensation.

The bill includes such deferred compensation in taxable income when there is no substantial risk of forfeiture (i.e., when vested) of the rights of the person entitled to such compensation rather than at distribution.

The bill transfers revenue from this revised tax treatment of deferred compensation from the Treasury to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation to increase insurance coverage of multiemployer pension plans.

The bill requires the Department of Labor to report on nonqualified deferred compensation plans of highly compensated employees known as top hat plans. The Department of the Treasury must disclose amounts deferred under such plans on W-2 forms</summary>
</bill>
