<bill session="108" type="s" number="906" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the certification of programs to provide uninsured employees of small business access to health coverage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Access for Small Businesses Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5120-5121"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5361-5363" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2544" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Health Care Access for Small Business Act of 2003 - Amends the Social Security Act to add a new title XXII (Providing for the Uninsured) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate regulations for the certification of three-share programs for purposes of offering a refundable tax credit to small businesses who participate in such programs where: (1) not more than 30 percent of the cost of the monthly premium for health coverage (including prescription drug benefits) is paid by the qualified employee who lacks access to health coverage and desires coverage; and (2) at least 70 percent of such cost is paid by the qualified employer of such a qualified employee.Authorizes the Administrator to award startup grants to eligible entities to establish three-share programs for certification.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for a refundable tax credit in the case of an eligible employer in an amount equal to 40 percent of the costs of a three-share program resulting from the participation of the taxpayer in such program during the taxable year.</summary>
</bill>
