<bill session="119" type="h" number="1613" updated="2025-05-01T08:06:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Mushroom Farmers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Mushroom Farmers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require the research and development of a policy to insure the production of mushrooms.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2025-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-27T15:12:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Mushroom Farmers Act

This bill requires the federal crop insurance program (FCIP) to provide for the research and development of a policy to insure&#160;the production of mushrooms and mushroom-growing media. (The term policy means an insurance policy, plan of insurance, provision of a policy or plan of insurance, and related materials.) The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the agency that finances FCIP operations, must make any resulting policy available that meets specified&#160;FCIP requirements.

As part of the research and development, the bill requires an evaluation of the effectiveness of insurance for the production of mushrooms, including policies that (1) are based on the risk of specific pests and pathogens, (2) consider appropriate best practices to minimize the risk of loss, and (3) consider whether to provide coverage for mushrooms under one policy or to provide coverage for various phases of production.</summary>
</bill>
