<bill session="117" type="s" number="5160" updated="2023-10-18T15:00:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NBACC Authorization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Biodefense Analysis and Countermeasures Center Authorization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NBACC Authorization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate a laboratory as the National Biodefense Analysis and Countermeasures Center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9401" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-14T20:07:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Biodefense Analysis and Countermeasures Center Authorization Act of 2022 or the NBACC Authorization Act of 2022

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security to designate a specified laboratory as the National Biodefense Analysis and Countermeasures Center (NBACC). It shall be the lead federal facility dedicated to defending the United States against biological threats.

The NBACC may include the National Bioforensic Analysis Center and the National Biological Threat Characterization Center.

The NBACC shall engage in specified activities, including

 conducting studies and experiments to better understand current and future biological threats and hazards and pandemics; providing the scientific data required to assess vulnerabilities, conduct risk assessments, and determine potential impacts to guide the development of countermeasures; conducting and facilitating the technical forensic analysis and interpretation of materials recovered following a biological attack, or in other law enforcement investigations requiring evaluation of biological materials, in support of the appropriate lead federal agency; and coordinating with other national laboratories to enhance research capabilities, share lessons learned, and provide training more efficiently. The NBACC must

 engage in a continuously operating Work for Others program to make the unique biocontainment and bioforensic capabilities of the NBACC available to other federal agencies; and perform regularly scheduled and required maintenance of laboratory infrastructure, and procure mission-critical equipment and capability upgrades. The Office of the Under Secretary for Science and Technology shall conduct a mission needs assessment of the NBACC.</summary>
</bill>
