<bill session="108" type="s" number="725" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Transportation Program Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to provide from the Highway Trust Fund additional funding for Indian reservation roads, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Transportation Program Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4514-4516"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4516-4518" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-122.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2331" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bikeways"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Highway maintenance"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic engineering"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Transportation Program Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends the Transportation Equity Act for the 21st Century to authorize appropriations for Indian reservation roads under the Federal Lands Highways Program through FY 2009.Prohibits the Secretary of Transportation from distributing, for years after FY 2003, any amount of obligation authority made available for Indian reservation road bridges and roads.Authorizes appropriations to carry out the planning, design, engineering, construction, and inspection of certain projects concerning deficient Indian reservation road bridges.Raises from two percent to four percent the ceiling for the amount of funds made available for Indian reservation roads for each fiscal year that may be allocated to Indian tribal governments applying for transportation planning pursuant to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act.Requires the Secretary to establish a Federal lands highway program demonstration project for Indian reservation roads and highway bridges located on Indian reservations.Requires the Secretary to carry out a program to provide to eligible Indian tribes competitive grants for use in establishing tribal transportation safety programs.Directs the Secretary of Transportation to issue grants to Indian tribes to establish rural transit programs on reservations or other land under tribal jurisdiction.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the maintenance of roads on Indian reservations is a responsibility of the Bureau of Indian Affairs; and (2) Congress should provide annually to the Bureau funding necessary to carry out all maintenance of roads on Indian reservations.</summary>
</bill>
