<bill session="118" type="h" number="3968" updated="2024-06-11T15:57:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Child Trafficking Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Child Trafficking Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to require a DNA test to determine the familial relationship between an alien and an accompanying minor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001086" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2024-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1843" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-19T13:25:47Z" status="Introduced in House">End Child Trafficking Now Act

This bill imposes restrictions related to adult non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) being admitted into the United States with a minor.

Such an adult may not be admitted with a minor unless the adult (1) presents documents or witness testimony proving that the adult is a relative or guardian of the minor, or (2) submits to a DNA test that proves such a relationship. The Department of Homeland Security may request a DNA test only if the required relationship cannot be established by the presented documents or witness testimony. An adult who does not consent to a requested DNA test shall be inadmissible. If the required relationship cannot be established and the immigration officer believes the adult is guilty of a felony offense, the officer may arrest the adult.

The bill makes it a crime for an adult to knowingly use a minor to whom the adult is not a relative or guardian to enter the United States.</summary>
</bill>
