<bill session="117" type="s" number="1442" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Workforce PATHWAYS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Corporation for Career Pathways to promote pathways to unfilled and emerging job markets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce PATHWAYS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Promotion to Access Training to Help Workers, Adults, and Youths Succeed Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-22T17:09:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workforce Promotion to Access Training to Help Workers, Adults, and Youths Succeed Act or the Workforce PATHWAYS Act

This bill establishes the nonprofit Corporation for Career Pathways to increase awareness of career pathways for U.S. workers, educators, and employers by promoting workforce development initiatives, educational programs, and other opportunities that develop skills relevant to high-demand industries.

The corporation must (1) develop and submit to the Department of Labor an annual workforce strategy for engaging all labor market stakeholders about opportunities or changes to useful degrees, registered apprenticeship programs, and certifications or skill sets; and (2) publish an annual United States Career Forecast and Resource Guide that provides job market and other information regarding in-demand industries, workforce needs, and training.

The corporation must also establish (1) an awards program to annually recognize workers and students who achieve excellence in registered apprenticeships, adult education programs, career and technical education programs, or other nontraditional workforce development pathways; and (2) a website to provide information to the public, conduct public outreach activities, and distribute marketing campaign materials (including the resource guide).

The bill establishes the United States Career Pathways Fund for grants to the corporation or to state and local workforce boards to assist in implementing the annual workforce strategy.

The Government Accountability Office must review and report on the corporation's programmatic activities.</summary>
</bill>
