<bill session="111" type="s" number="720" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:41Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Land REPAIR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a source of funds to carry out restoration activities on Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land REPAIR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Land Restoration, Enhancement, Public Education, and Information Resources Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3918-3919"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3919-3920" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-28T18:51:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Land Restoration, Enhancement, Public Education, and Information Resources Act or Federal Land REPAIR Act - Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and federal law relating to National Forest System lands to make available for certain restoration and public informational activities on federal land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture any amounts received from fines or any amounts received from collateral payments in lieu of appearance for violations of rules and regulations applicable to such land. Transfers any excess funds to the Crime Victims Fund established under the Victims of Crime Act of 1984.</summary>
</bill>
