<bill session="119" type="h" number="688" updated="2025-04-07T21:18:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Standing with Moms Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standing with Moms Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to furnish tailored information to expecting mothers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-07T21:12:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Standing with Moms Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to disseminate information about pregnancy-related resources, including information about abortion risks and alternatives.

Specifically, HHS must create a public website called life.gov that lists such resources that are available through federal, state, and local governments and private entities.

Additionally, HHS must create&#160;on its existing&#160;website a portal that provides a user, based on the user's responses to a series of questions, tailored information about pregnancy resources available in the user's zip code and risks related to abortion. HHS must develop a plan to conduct follow-up outreach to users of the portal (if the user consents to the outreach). States must recommend resources that meet criteria set by HHS for&#160;inclusion in the portal. HHS may award grants to states to establish or support a system that aggregates resources to include in the portal.

Further, the Health Resources and Services Administration must share information about the new website&#160;and portal through the National&#160;Maternal Mental Health Hotline.

HHS must also ensure that the new&#160;website and hotline are available to families who speak languages other than English.

The new website, portal, and hotline may not include resources provided by entities that (1) perform, induce, refer for, or counsel in favor of abortions; or (2) financially support such entities.

The bill also requires HHS to report on traffic to the new website&#160;and portal, gaps in services available to pregnant and postpartum individuals, and related matters.</summary>
</bill>
