<bill session="108" type="s" number="591" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Moment of Quiet Reflection in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a period of quiet reflection at the opening of certain schools on every school day.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Moment of Quiet Reflection in Schools Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1202" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Meditation"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religion in the public schools"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Moment of Quiet Reflection in Schools Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA) to require each local educational agency (LEA), if it receives ESEA funds, to ensure that the teacher in charge of each classroom in each school served by the LEA conducts a brief period of quiet reflection for not more than 60 seconds with the participation of all the students assembled in the classroom, at the opening of school on every school day.Prohibits such period from being conducted as a religious service or exercise. Requires such period to be considered as an opportunity for a moment of silent reflection on the anticipated activities of the day.Declares that this Act shall not be construed as prohibiting or restricting constitutionally protected prayer.Requires LEAs, as a condition of receiving ESEA funds, to certify in writing to their State that they are in compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
