<bill session="116" type="h" number="4355" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-09T15:45:03-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-09T15:45:03-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IOGAN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the National Science Foundation to support research on the outputs that may be generated by generative adversarial networks, otherwise known as deepfakes, and other comparable techniques that may be developed in the future, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">IOGAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IOGAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">IOGAN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">IOGAN Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2019-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001087" joined="2019-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2019-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2019-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2019-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2019-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2019-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-05">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 116-268.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-11-05" calendar="Union" number="213">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 213.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:39:02-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Johnson (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:39:19-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9363-9364" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:39:21-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4355.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-12-09T15:45:03-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9363-9364" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:45:05-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2904" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-26T22:35:55Z" status="Passed House">Identifying Outputs of Generative Adversarial Networks Act or the IOGAN Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to support research on manipulated or synthesized media, including the output of generative adversarial networks. A generative adversarial network is a software system designed to be trained with authentic inputs (e.g., photographs) to generate similar, but artificial, outputs (e.g., deepfakes).

Specifically, the NSF must support research on manipulated or synthesized content and information authenticity.

 (Sec. 4) NIST must support research for the development of measurements and standards necessary to accelerate the development of the technological tools to examine the function and outputs of generative adversarial networks or other technologies that synthesize or manipulate content.

NIST shall conduct outreach to (1) receive input from private, public, and academic stakeholders on fundamental measurements and standards research necessary to examine the function and outputs of generative adversarial networks; and (2) consider the feasibility of an ongoing public and private sector engagement to develop voluntary standards for the function and outputs of such networks or other technologies that synthesize or manipulate content.

(Sec. 5) The NSF and NIST must jointly submit to Congress a report containing (1) such agencies' findings with respect to the feasibility for research opportunities with the private sector, including digital media companies to detect the function and outputs of generative adversarial networks or other technologies that synthesize or manipulate content; and (2) any policy recommendations of those agencies that could facilitate and improve communication and coordination between the private sector, the NSF, and relevant federal agencies through the implementation of innovative approaches to detect digital content produced by such networks or such technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-268</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
