<bill session="117" type="s" number="3913" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving DATA in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Data Accessibility Through Advancements in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving DATA in Public Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to public health data accessibility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2022-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1775-1776" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8481" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-13T21:05:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Data Accessibility Through Advancements in Public Health Act or the Improving DATA in Public Health Act

This bill addresses the collection and reporting of public health data with a particular focus on electronic health information.

Specifically, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must designate data and technology standards for public health data systems no later than two years after enactment of this act. These standards must, among other requirements, align with standards designated by the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC). In addition, the ONC must study matters concerning the use of standards for certain laboratory information.

Further, the CDC may require, subject to some limits, additional reporting of public health and health care data by health care providers, health departments, and other entities for public health surveillance.

Additionally, the bill addresses agreements regarding access to, exchange of, and use of public health data, including for public health preparedness and response activities. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must develop or update interagency agreements while the CDC and the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response may develop and update agreements with health departments and other nonfederal entities.

The bill also requires HHS to award grants and other support for developing and disseminating best practices to collect electronic health information. Entities eligible for the awards include state, tribal, and local governments; health care providers; and nonprofits.</summary>
</bill>
