<bill session="116" type="h" number="8214" updated="2023-07-06T19:48:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to direct the Institute to establish a robust program focusing on driving improvements in America's cybersecurity posture by creating more robust digital identity management standards and guidelines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2020-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-28T17:43:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2020

This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to continue a cybersecurity program to support the development of voluntary and cost-effective management standards, metrology, testbeds, and conformance criteria, taking into account appropriate user concerns.

NIST shall develop and implement a comprehensive forward-looking investment strategy for identity management research and development and standards focused on enabling the use and adoption of modern digital identity solutions that align with criteria set forth by this bill.

NIST shall develop, and periodically update, a framework of standards, methodologies, procedures, and processes as a guide for federal, state, and local governments to follow when providing services related to digital identity verification.</summary>
</bill>
