<bill session="118" type="h" number="4460" updated="2025-06-23T14:16:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NO VOTE for Non-Citizens Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">NO VOTE for Non-Citizens Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Non-citizens: Outlawed from Voting in Our Trusted Elections Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NO VOTE for Non-Citizens Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Non-citizens: Outlawed from Voting in Our Trusted Elections Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 and the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to ensure that only eligible American citizens may participate in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2024-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 8 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 118-462, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-04-15" calendar="Union" number="383">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 383.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-03T16:17:09Z" status="Reported to House">Non-citizens: Outlawed from Voting in Our Trusted Elections Act of 2023 or the NO VOTE for Non-Citizens Act of 2023

This bill establishes additional requirements related to noncitizens and voting and addresses related issues.

Currently, each state must conduct a general program that makes a reasonable effort to remove the names of ineligible voters from the official eligible voter lists by reason of the death of the voter or a change in the residence of the voter. In addition to these requirements, states must also make reasonable efforts to remove noncitizens from the official eligible voter lists.

The bill requires states that allow noncitizens to vote in state or local elections to maintain separate state voter registration lists for noncitizens.

Additionally, the bill requires states and local jurisdictions that allow noncitizens to vote in their elections to ensure that the ballot used for casting votes by noncitizens may only include the candidates for state or local elections for which noncitizens are permitted to vote.

Further, the bill reduces election assistance payments to states and local jurisdictions that allow noncitizens to vote.

If a U.S. district court recuses an individual from jury duty on the grounds that the individual is a noncitizen, then the court shall transmit a notice of such recusal to the chief state election official and the Department of Justice.

The bill also references current federal law prohibiting noncitizens from voting in federal elections and related criminal penalties for violations. &#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-462</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
