<bill session="116" type="s" number="2301" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide disaster assistance to States, insular areas, units of general local government, and Indian tribes under a community development block grant disaster recovery program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T19:32:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act

This bill addresses housing assistance in disaster recovery areas.

The Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) must establish the Office of Disaster Recovery and Resilient Communities. The office's duties shall include (1) developing policy to build community resiliency and restore housing, (2) leading certain HUD disaster recovery activities, and (3) providing periodic disaster mitigation and recovery training to HUD staff.

In addition, HUD must award grants under the Community Development Block Grant program for government entities to provide disaster relief, increase long-term resilience to natural hazards, and provide housing assistance to distressed areas after a declared major disaster.

HUD and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must collect certain information during the course of a disaster recovery and make such information public. Additionally, the Government Accountability Office must analyze and report on the allocation of disaster-related housing benefits administered by FEMA, HUD, and the Department of Agriculture.</summary>
</bill>
