<bill session="118" type="h" number="2542" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Infrastructure Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To preclude absolute liability in any action against a property owner or contractor for projects receiving Federal financial assistance for infrastructure and transportation development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000828"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2023-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2023-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-29T16:26:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Infrastructure Expansion Act of 2023 

This bill precludes absolute liability in any action against a property owner or contractor for certain federal infrastructure and transportation development projects for any injury associated with an elevation- or gravity-related risk occurring on those projects. This applies to federally owned or operated projects and to projects receiving federal financial assistance for infrastructure and transportation development.

In any such claim, a state must apply a liability standard that considers the comparative negligence of the injured person when such negligence is a proximate cause of an injury, and state law would otherwise apply absolute liability as the basis for such claim.

The bill applies to claims arising from projects in which a state or local government accepts federal financial assistance beginning on or after January 1, 2025.</summary>
</bill>
