<bill session="119" type="h" number="811" updated="2025-11-18T18:53:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mentoring to Succeed Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mentoring to Succeed Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a competitive grant program to support the establishment, expansion, or enhancement of youth mentoring programs for eligible youth, and to provide for social and emotional learning, employability skill development, career exploration, work-based learning, and other youth workforce opportunities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2025-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2025-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000309" joined="2025-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2025-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000617" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="299" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-17T16:56:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Mentoring to Succeed Act of 2025

This bill establishes grants to support mentoring programs for eligible youth (e.g., in-school youth, out-of-school youth, or youth who are failing academically or who meet specified criteria).&#160;

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Labor to award competitive grants for certain community-based organizations or partnerships involving community-based organizations to (1) establish, expand, or support mentoring programs; (2) assist eligible youth enrolled in secondary schools in developing cognitive and social-emotional skills; and (3) prepare eligible youth for success in high school, postsecondary education, and the workforce.

Additionally, Labor must work with the Department of Justice's Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention and the Department of Education to (1) refer grant recipients to the National Mentoring Resource Center to obtain mentoring resources, and (2) provide grant recipients with information regarding transitional services for eligible youth returning from correctional facilities and transition services for students with disabilities.

The bill also requires Labor's Chief Evaluation Office to study and report on mentoring programs.</summary>
</bill>
