<bill session="116" type="s" number="3666" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 DISASTER in Indian Country Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Designation of Immediate Special Authority of Spectrum for Tribes&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Emergency Response in Indian Country Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 DISASTER in Indian Country Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to fund grants for the immediate deployment of temporary wireless broadband service on Tribal lands and Hawaiian Home Lands, to provide emergency special temporary authority to use electromagnetic spectrum for the provision of wireless broadband service on Tribal lands and Hawaiian Home Lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6819" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8200" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-22T20:07:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">COVID-19 Designation of Immediate Special Authority of Spectrum for Tribes' Emergency Response in Indian Country Act or the COVID-19 DISASTER in Indian Country Act

This bill grants emergency special temporary authority and provides funds to deploy wireless broadband service on tribal lands and Hawaiian home lands.

Specifically, the bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to grant emergency special temporary authority to Indian tribes, certain tribal entities, and the Department of Hawaiian Home Lands if they request such authority to use electromagnetic spectrum to provide wireless broadband service over tribal lands or Hawaiian home lands. The FCC must grant such emergency authority within 10 days of receiving a request.

In addition, the bill provides funds to specified Department of Agriculture grant programs for (1) immediate deployment of wireless broadband service on tribal lands and Hawaiian home lands, including repairs to damaged infrastructure and backhaul costs; and (2) technical assistance and training.</summary>
</bill>
