<bill session="118" type="s" number="747" updated="2025-11-19T03:25:30Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Relief for Farmers Hit with PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Relief for Farmers Hit with PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide grants to States, territories, and Indian Tribes to address contamination by perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances on farms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2024-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S747" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1517" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-16T13:25:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Relief for Farmers Hit with PFAS Act 

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a grant program to help states and other entities address contamination by perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS, on agricultural land and commercial farms.

Specifically, the USDA program must provide an eligible government (e.g., a state, territory, or Indian tribe) a grant for purposes that include

 providing financial assistance to a person whose commercial farm is affected by PFAS contamination; assisting the producers on agricultural land and commercial farms contaminated by PFAS in developing an enterprise budget for alternative production, remediation strategies, transitioning to an alternative revenue stream, or relocating farming operations; expanding the capacity of PFAS testing and data management; and conducting research on soil and water remediation systems and food safety relating to PFAS contamination. At least 30% of the program's total annual funding is set aside for one or more eligible governments with a population of less than 3 million people.

The bill also requires USDA to establish a task force to provide (1) advice regarding whether addressing PFAS contamination should be added as an eligible activity for each USDA program, (2) evaluations of necessary actions for farms already enrolled in a USDA program where PFAS is detected, and (3) technical assistance to eligible governments in addressing PFAS contamination.</summary>
</bill>
