<bill session="118" type="h" number="5656" updated="2025-01-14T15:42:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Michael F. Donoughe Tax Credit for Off Road Electric Vehicles Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Michael F. Donoughe Tax Credit for Off Road Electric Vehicles Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit for new off-road plug-in electric vehicles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000616"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-14T15:41:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Michael F. Donoughe Tax Credit for Off Road Electric Vehicles Act 

This bill expands the clean vehicle tax credit to include new qualified off-road plug-in electric vehicles. The amount of the tax credit allowed for a new qualified off-road plug-in electric vehicle is 10% of the cost of the vehicle or $2,500,&#160;whichever is lower.

The bill defines a new qualified off-road plug-in electric vehicle as any vehicle that

is acquired new and for use by the taxpayer;is made by a qualified manufacturer;is powered by an electric motor that draws electricity from a battery with a capacity of at least six&#160; kilowatt hours;has final assembly occurring in North America;has a dry weight of less than 3,500 pounds;has three or more wheels;has one or more seats;is manufactured primarily for off-road use;is designed for use on rough terrain&#160;and, except in the case of a vehicle designed to operate on land and water, is not designed to operate on rails, in the air, or in or on the water; andis capable of reaching a speed of 40 miles per hour.Under current law, a qualified manufacturer is any manufacturer that has a written agreement with the Internal Revenue Service and submits reports containing information about each eligible clean vehicle.

Finally, the bill allows the tax credit for a new qualified off-road plug-in electric vehicle to be transferred from the taxpayer to an eligible entity (e.g., vehicle dealer) in exchange for a financial benefit (e.g., rebate).</summary>
</bill>
