<bill session="112" type="h" number="2647" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:42Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Attorney General to make competitive grants to eligible State, tribal, and local governments to establish and maintain certain protection and witness assistance programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2011-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2011-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-11-03T20:12:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2011 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) make competitive grants to state, tribal, and local governments to establish or maintain programs to protect or assist witnesses in court proceedings involving homicide, a serious felony or drug offense, or gangs or organized crime; (2) evaluate grant applicants based on specified criteria, including the extent of witness intimidation and the number of serious crimes per capita with respect to such applicant; (3) provide technical assistance to grant applicants for establishing or maintaining a witness protection plan; and (4) develop and disseminate best practice models to assist states and other relevant entities in addressing witness safety, short-term and permanent witness relocation, financial and housing assistance, and other necessary services.

Expresses the sense of Congress that states and relevant entities should use the best practice models developed by the Attorney General to evaluate, improve, and develop witness protection or witness assistance programs.</summary>
</bill>
