<bill session="116" type="h" number="8517" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Speech Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Speech Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure that the immunity under such section incentivizes online platforms to responsibly address illegal content while not immunizing the disparate treatment of ideological viewpoints and continuing to encourage a vibrant, open, and competitive internet, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000289"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2020-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001088" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001082" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000299" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2020-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2020-11-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000244" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2020-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2020-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-16T15:21:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Speech Act

This bill modifies the immunity from liability of a provider or user of an interactive computer service (e.g., a social media company) for screening and blocking offensive content on its platform.

Specifically, the bill provides that this immunity shall not apply to any action taken to restrict access to or availability of material provided by another information content provider unless the action is taken in good faith based on an objectively reasonable belief that the material is (1) obscene, lewd, lascivious, filthy, excessively violent, promoting terrorism or violent extremism, harassing, promoting self-harm, or unlawful; or (2) violates the applicable terms of service or use.

In order to avoid liability for taking action based on either belief, certain good faith requirements must be met, such as (1) making publicly available terms of service or use that plainly state the criteria for content moderation practices, and (2) not restricting access to or availability of material on deceptive grounds.

Further, the bill specifies that being responsible in whole or in part for the creation or development of information includes instances in which a person or entity solicits, comments upon, funds, or affirmatively and substantively contributes to, modifies, or alters information provided by another person or entity.</summary>
</bill>
