<bill session="108" type="h" number="3283" updated="2023-01-15T07:32:53Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve recreational facilities and visitor opportunities on Federal recreational lands by reinvesting receipts from fair and consistent recreational fees and passes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000666" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000263" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001146" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000119" joined="2003-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-790, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Nov. 22, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-22">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than Dec. 10, 2004.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Revolution"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Boats and boating"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Civil War"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Historians"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Recreational vehicles"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-19T20:07:03Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Federal Lands Recreation Enhancement Act - (Sec. 3) Authorizes the appropriate Secretary (the Secretary of the Interior with respect to a Federal land management agency other than the Forest Service or the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to the Forest Service), beginning on January 1, 2005, to establish, modify, charge, and collect recreation fees at Federal recreational lands and waters as provided for in this section.

Specifies requirements for recreation fees, entrance fees, standard amenity recreation fees, expanded amenity recreation fees, and special recreation permit fees.

(Sec. 4) Sets forth provisions for public participation in the development or changing of recreation fees established under this Act. Requires the appropriate Secretary to provide: (1) notice of the establishment of a new recreation fee area for each agency six months before establishment; and (2) advance notice of a new recreation fee or change to an existing recreation fee established under this Act.

Directs the appropriate Secretary to establish a Recreation Resource Advisory Committee in each State or region for the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management to advise the Secretary regarding the establishment of a standard amenity recreation fee or expanded amenity recreation fee.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretaries to: (1) establish, and authorize charging a fee for, America the Beautiful-the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Passes which shall cover the entrance fee and standard amenity recreation fee for all Federal recreational lands and waters for which an entrance fee or a standard amenity recreation fee is charged; (2) hold annual competitions to select the image on the Pass; (3) establish the price of the Pass; and (4) market the Pass. Allows such Secretaries to enter into cooperative agreements with governmental and nongovernmental entities for the development and implementation of the National Parks and Federal Recreational Lands Pass Program. Prohibits establishing any national pass, except as provided in this section.

Authorizes the appropriate Secretary to establish and charge fees for site-specific and regional multientity passes.

(Sec. 6) Sets forth requirements regarding specified cooperative agreements.

(Sec. 7) Provides for the establishment of special accounts for Federal land management agencies and the distribution and expenditure of recreation fees and pass revenues from such accounts.

(Sec. 8) Sets forth requirements for use of fees at specific sites and areas.

(Sec. 9) Requires reports to Congress every three years on the status of the recreation fee program for Federal recreational lands and waters.

(Sec. 10) Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this Act ten years after the enactment of this Act.

(Sec. 11) Authorizes the appropriate Secretary to: (1) use volunteers to collect recreation fees and sell recreation passes; and (2) issue passes to volunteers in exchange for significant volunteer services.

(Sec. 12) Provides for the enforcement of the payment of recreation fees.

(Sec. 13) Repeals specified superseded admission and use fee authorities.

(Sec. 14) Sets forth provisions concerning the relationship of this Act to other laws and fee collection authorities.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-790</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
