<bill session="115" type="h" number="3133" updated="2023-01-11T13:37:42Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to reduce unnecessary permitting delays by clarifying associated procedures to increase economic development and support coastal restoration programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">SEA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEA Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000374" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2017-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2017-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2017-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2017-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-16">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1030.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-16" calendar="Union" number="804">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 804.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4239" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-08T19:31:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Streamlining Environmental Approvals Act of 2017 or the SEA Act of 2017

This bill amends the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 to: (1) limit the scope of the moratorium on taking and importing marine mammals and marine mammal products, and (2) revise the requirements for obtaining an authorization for incidentally taking by harassment marine mammals (incidental harassment authorizations or IHAs). Harassment is an act of pursuit, torment or annoyance which has the potential to either: (1) injure a marine mammal in the wild; or (2) disturb a marine mammal by causing disruption of behavioral patterns, such as migration or breeding.

The bill: (1) allows persons who are not U.S. citizens to make requests to obtain IHAs, (2) eliminates the requirement that the taking occur within a specific geographic region, and (3) permits more than a small number of marine mammals to be taken.

Monitoring requirements under an IHA must be efficient and practical. Additionally, the bill eliminates a requirement that IHAs prescribe reporting requirements. Any condition imposed by an IHA for minimizing adverse impacts on marine mammals may not result in more than a minor change to the activity and may not alter the activity's basic design, location, scope, duration, or timing.

The bill establishes a process and deadlines for approving or denying IHAs, including a process for extending IHAs.

Any taking of a marine mammal in compliance with an IHA is exempt from the prohibitions on takings under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1030</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
