<bill session="116" type="h" number="4623" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keep STEM Talent Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide lawful permanent resident status for certain advanced STEM degree holders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep STEM Talent Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2020-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2019-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2019-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2019-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1744" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-16T18:43:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep STEM Talent Act of 2019

This bill exempts certain aliens with advanced degrees in a science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) field from direct limitations on the number of immigrant visas granted per year. Specifically, the alien must (1) have earned a master's level or higher degree in certain STEM fields while in the United States attending an accredited higher education institution, (2) be employed (or have a job offer) in a field related to the degree and earn at least the median wage for that occupation, and (3) meet certain labor certification requirements.

The bill also allows an alien seeking a nonimmigrant F-1 (student) visa to obtain an advanced STEM degree to have dual intent. Specifically, such an alien may obtain the nonimmigrant visa or change nonimmigrant status even if the alien intends to seek lawful permanent resident status. (Generally, an alien may be denied a nonimmigrant visa if the alien actually intends to seek immigrant status, unless dual intent is allowed for that type of visa.)</summary>
</bill>
