<bill session="116" type="s" number="3969" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aircraft Safety and Certification Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aircraft Safety and Certification Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to reform the Federal Aviation Administration's aircraft certification process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2020-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3866" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-27T19:01:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Aircraft Safety and Certification Reform Act of 2020

This bill revises the aircraft certification process of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA).

Among other requirements, the FAA must

 require certain aircraft manufacturers to have in place a safety management system that is consistent with the standards established by the International Civil Aviation Organization; initiate a review of its existing regulations and policies to integrate and emphasize human factors and human system integration, particularly those related to pilot and aircraft interfaces; address the integration of human factors in the design and certification of transport category aircraft; develop a Center of Excellence focused on flight automation and human factors in aircraft that are intended for use in air transportation; revise existing policies for manufacturers of large transport category airplanes that are expected to be operated for passenger air transportation to ensure that pilot operational evaluations use pilots from foreign and domestic air carriers; establish an Office of Continuing Education to provide continuing education and training to FAA personnel who hold positions involving aircraft and flight standards certification, including engineers and inspectors; and maintain a safety reporting program for FAA employees to anonymously and voluntarily report instances where they have identified safety concerns during the certification process.</summary>
</bill>
