<bill session="111" type="h" number="84" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:28Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Timely Access to Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="display">Veterans Timely Access to Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish standards of access to care for veterans seeking health care from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001247"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-15T17:47:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Timely Access to Health Care Act - Makes the standard for access to care for a veteran seeking primary care from the Department of Veterans Affairs 30 days from the date the veteran contacts the Department. Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to prescribe an appropriate standard for waiting times at Department health-care facilities as measured from the time a visit is scheduled until the time the veteran is seen.

Directs the Secretary to periodically review the performance of Department health-care facilities in meeting such standards. Authorizes the Secretary to contract for health care services in non-Department facilities in a case in which the Secretary is unable to meet access standards. Prohibits such contracting-out with respect to a Department geographic service area that has a compliance rate in meeting such standards of 90 percent or more.

Requires quarterly reports from the Secretary to the congressional veterans' committees on the Department's experience with respect to waiting times.</summary>
</bill>
