<bill session="117" type="s" number="459" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 and the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to promote integrity in voter registration, the casting of ballots, and the tabulation of ballots in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Democracy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="873" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="322" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1130" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-28T18:40:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Save Democracy Act

This bill addresses issues involving voter registration, casting of ballots, and tabulation of ballots in federal elections.

Specifically, regarding voter registration for federal elections, the bill

 prohibits the use of automatic voter registration systems, requires individuals to provide documentary proof of U.S. citizenship to register to vote, requires individuals to provide their full Social Security number on their voter registration application, and requires courts to notify state election officials when an individual is recused from jury duty because the individual is not a U.S. citizen. Next, regarding the casting of ballots in federal elections, the bill

 requires individuals to provide proof of identification for absentee and in-person voting, prohibits states from mailing unrequested absentee ballots, prohibits the use of a drop box for collecting voted absentee ballots unless it is located inside of a building that serves as an office for the election official, restricts the delivery of ballots by third parties (i.e., prohibits ballot harvesting), requires that absentee ballots be received before the polls close on election day, and requires states to use Social Security numbers to verify the identification of each individual who casts a ballot. Finally, regarding the tabulation of ballots in federal elections, the bill

 requires states to permit poll watching by at least two campaign representatives per campaign, requires continuous counting of ballots after the closure of polling places on election day, and requires an audit of voting systems.</summary>
</bill>
