<bill session="117" type="h" number="5093" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28T16:40:44-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-28T16:40:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain National Forest System land in the State of Washington to Skamania County, Washington.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 117-434.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-07-26" calendar="Union" number="338">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 338.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28T16:31:50-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Lowenthal moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28T16:32:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7399-7400" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28T16:32:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5093.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-07-28T16:40:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7399" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28T16:40:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-10T15:47:27Z" status="Passed House">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act

This bill directs the Forest Service to convey to Skamania County in Washington, upon request of the county, all right, title, and interest of the United States in approximately 23.4 acres of National Forest System land, related infrastructure, and all improvements on the map titled Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Proposal and dated July 7, 2020.

The conveyance shall be

 made by quitclaim deed; subject to a right-of-way and restrictive easement reservation for the protection of the Pacific Crest National Scenic Trail; and completed in accordance with certain Forest Service conveyance requirements, except that certain market value requirements shall not apply. The Forest Service must meet specified disclosure requirements for hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants and shall not otherwise be required to remediate or abate the hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants disclosed.

The lands and related infrastructure conveyed must be maintained by the county pursuant to standards established by the Department of the Interior regarding the preservation of historic property.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-434</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
