<bill session="116" type="s" number="193" updated="2022-11-01T14:32:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ethan's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ethan's Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to require the safe storage of firearms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2019-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2867" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-08T14:47:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ethan's Law

This bill prohibits the improper storage of firearms. It also establishes grants to assist states and Indian tribes with implementing secure gun storage laws.

Specifically, the bill makes it unlawful to store or keep any firearm on the premises of a residence if (1) an individual who is under the age of 18 is likely to gain access to the firearm without the permission of the individual's parent or guardian, or (2) an individual residing at such residence is ineligible to possess a firearm.

The bill establishes penalties for violations. Further, any firearm that is improperly stored is subject to seizure and forfeiture.

The bill provides an exception for an individual who (1) keeps the firearm secure using a secure gun storage or safety device or in a location that a reasonable person would believe to be secure, or (2) carries the firearm on or in close proximity to the individual's person.

Additionally, the Department of Justice must award grants to states and Indian tribes to implement secure gun storage laws that are functionally identical to the requirements established by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
