<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3548</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:52:34Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:52:34Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2008-09-23</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported original measure</name>
            <date>2008-09-23T23:37:12Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2008-09-23T22:17:38Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
        <congress>110</congress>
        <number>7039</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2008-09-24</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
        <congress>110</congress>
        <number>7061</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2008-09-25</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
        <congress>110</congress>
        <number>7081</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2008-10-08</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 110-369.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1048.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Dodd. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000388</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Dodd, Christopher J. [D-CT]</fullName>
        <firstName>CHRISTOPHER</firstName>
        <lastName>DODD</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CT</state>
        <middleName>JOHN</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R.7081, which became Public Law 110-369 on 10/8/2008.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R.7081</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/110th-congress/house-bill/7081</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress and foreign policy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>India</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International control of nuclear power</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative resolutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licenses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Negotiations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear exports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear fuels</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear nonproliferation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear power plants</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>President and foreign policy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Reactor fuel reprocessing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>South Asia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology transfer</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Treaties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Uranium enrichment</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2008-10-10T14:55:45Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act - Approves the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy (Agreement), subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006, and other applicable U.S. law. </p> <p>Urges the government of India to sign and adhere to an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA).</p> <p>States that licenses may be issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) for transfers pursuant to the Agreement only after the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the Agreement Between the Government of India and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards to Civilian Nuclear Facilities has entered into force; and (2) the government of India has filed a declaration of facilities that is not materially inconsistent with the facilities and schedule of the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India.</p> <p>Amends the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 to revise related congressional reporting requirements.</p> <p>States that no subsequent arrangement concerning reprocessing arrangements and procedures shall take effect until: (1) the President reports to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Committees) respecting the reasons for such arrangement and a certification that third-party reprocessing arrangements with India will be conducted under similar arrangements; and (2) a period of 30 days of continuous session has elapsed after such report's transmittal.</p> <p>Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the President to inform the Committees of any negotiations relating to a new or amended agreement for peaceful nuclear cooperation.</p> <p>Directs the President to: (1) certify to the Committees that it is U.S. policy to work with members of the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) to restrict transfers of equipment and technology related to the enrichment of uranium and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel; and (2) seek to achieve within NSG or with NSG participating governments the adoption of principles and exchanges of information to assure peaceful use and accounting of by-product material. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>80</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-01-28T18:09:53Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act - (Sec. 2) Defines specified terms.</p> <p><b>Title I: </b> <b>Approval of United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy</b> - (Sec. 101) Approves the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy (Agreement), subject to the provisions of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006, and other applicable U.S. law.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) Declares that it is the understanding of the United States that the provisions of the Agreement have the meanings conveyed in the authoritative representations provided by the President and his representatives to the Congress and its committees prior to September 20, 2008.</p> <p>Declares it to be congressional policy that: (1) in the event that nuclear transfers to India are suspended or terminated it is U.S. policy to prevent the transfer to India of nuclear equipment, materials, or technology from other participating governments in the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) or from any other source; and (2) any nuclear power reactor fuel reserve provided to India for use in safeguarded civilian nuclear facilities should be commensurate with reasonable reactor operating requirements.</p> <p>States that before exchanging specified diplomatic notes the President shall certify to Congress that entry into force and implementation of the Agreement pursuant to its terms is consistent with the obligation of the United States under the Treaty on the Nonproliferation of Nuclear Weapons (Nuclear Nonproliferation Treaty) not to assist, encourage, or induce India to manufacture or otherwise acquire nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Urges the government of India to sign and adhere to an Additional Protocol with the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA).</p> <p>(Sec. 104) States that licenses may be issued by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) for transfers pursuant to the Agreement only after the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the Agreement Between the Government of India and the International Atomic Energy Agency for the Application of Safeguards to Civilian Nuclear Facilities has entered into force; and (2) the government of India has filed a declaration of facilities that is not materially inconsistent with the facilities and schedule of the separation plan presented in the national parliament of India.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) Amends the Henry J. Hyde United States-India Peaceful Atomic Energy Cooperation Act of 2006 to revise related congressional reporting requirements.</p> <p><b>Title II: Strengthening United States Nonproliferation</b> <b>Law Relating to Peaceful Nuclear Cooperation</b> - (Sec. 201) States that no subsequent arrangement concerning reprocessing arrangements and procedures shall take effect until: (1) the President reports to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations (Committees) respecting the reasons for such arrangement and a certification that third-party reprocessing arrangements with India will be conducted under similar arrangements; and (2) a period of 30 days of continuous session has elapsed after such report's transmittal.</p> <p>States that a subsequent agreement shall not become effective if during such 30-day period Congress enacts a joint resolution of disapproval.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the President to inform the Committees of any negotiations relating to a new or amended agreement for peaceful nuclear cooperation.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) Requires that Congress enact a joint resolution to override a presidential determination permitting the export of nuclear materials, equipment, or technology to a country to which such export is otherwise prohibited. (Current law provides for a concurrent resolution of disapproval.)</p> <p>(Sec. 204) Directs the President to: (1) certify to the Committees that it is U.S. policy to work with members of the Nuclear Suppliers Group (NSG) to restrict transfers of equipment and technology related to the enrichment of uranium and reprocessing of spent nuclear fuel; (2) seek to achieve within NSG or with NSG participating governments the adoption of principles and exchanges of information to assure peaceful use and accounting of byproduct material; and (3) report every six months to the Committees until achievement of such purposes. </p> <p>(Sec. 205) Makes conforming amendments with respect to related congressional actions under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>An original bill to approve the United States-India Agreement for Cooperation on Peaceful Uses of Nuclear Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States-India Nuclear Cooperation Approval and Nonproliferation Enhancement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2008-09-23T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s3548pcs/xml/BILLS-110s3548pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2008-09-23</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1048.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
