<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="667" updated="2022-02-08T23:01:03Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4863" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-11-15T11:19:12-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000461"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-11-14"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 3 printed in House Report 116-289 to strike Section 13 and create the office of energy efficiency and clean energy exports which advises the EXIM board on ways to improve the export of goods and services that increase energy efficiency and clean energy abroad. Also, the amendment requires the EXIM bank to consider energy affordability as well as environmental impacts before approving transactions, and requires the EXIM bank to include in its annual report the impacts of any transaction backed by the Bank on the cost of energy in the importing country and the estimated emissions reductions caused by exports financed by the Bank.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to strike section 13, and create the office of energy efficiency and clean energy exports which would have sought to advise the Export-Import Bank board on ways to improve the export of goods and services that increase energy efficiency and clean energy abroad.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-11-15T11:19:12-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="618">
      <text>On agreeing to the Flores amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 232 (Roll no. 618).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8895-8896" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14T15:49:15-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Flores.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8861-8862" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8861" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:19:12-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:19:12-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14T15:49:15-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Flores.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8861-8862" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8861" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:19:12-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Flores amendment (A003) Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 232 (Roll no. 618).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
