<bill session="111" type="s" number="3477" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blue Star/Gold Star Flag Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the right of an individual to display the Service Flag on residential property not be abridged.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blue Star/Gold Star Flag Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000803"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001268" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2010-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001266" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2010-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2546" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Cooperative and condominium housing"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National symbols"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-02-23T17:07:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Blue Star/Gold Star Flag Act of 2010 - Prohibits a condominium association, cooperative association, or residential real estate management association from adopting or enforcing any policy, or entering into any agreement, that would restrict or prevent an association member from displaying a Service Flag on residential property within the association with respect to which such member has a separate ownership interest or a right to exclusive possession or use. (A Service Flag, also known as a "blue star banner," is an official banner authorized by the Department of Defense [DOD] for display by families who have members serving in the Armed Forces during any period of war or hostilities the United States may be engaged in for the duration of such hostilities.)

Prohibits anything in this Act from being considered to permit any display or use inconsistent with: (1) any DOD regulations regarding rules or customs pertaining to the proper display or use of the Service Flag; or (2) any reasonable restriction pertaining to the time, place, or manner of displaying the flag necessary to protect a substantial interest of the condominium, cooperative, or residential real estate management association.</summary>
</bill>
