<bill session="119" type="s" number="1911" updated="2025-11-11T23:27:58Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALTH Panel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALTH Panel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Equipping And Lending Technical Help Panel Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to codify the Panel of Health Advisors within the Congressional Budget Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2025-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="751" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-24T10:11:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthy Equipping And Lending Technical Help Panel Act or the HEALTH Panel Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Panel of Health Advisors within the Congressional Budget Office (CBO). The panel provides expertise and recommendations to CBO to support&#160;its analysis and cost estimates relating to health and healthcare.

The bill requires the panel to report to the House and Senate Budget Committees on the recommendations the panel provided to CBO and how CBO utilized such recommendations. CBO must publish this report on its website.

The bill also requires the panel to consist of 15 members serving three-year terms. The respective chairs and ranking minority members of the House and Senate Budget Committees, and the director of CBO, must&#160;each appoint three members to the panel.</summary>
</bill>
