<bill session="109" type="s" number="656" updated="2019-11-15T21:56:00Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Liberian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Liberian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the adjustment of status of certain nationals of Liberia to that of lawful permanent residence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2005-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Africans"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-05T18:56:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Liberian Refugee Immigration Fairness Act of 2005 - Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to adjust the status of Liberian nationals who have been continuously present in the United States from January 1, 2005, through the date of application for adjustment (or the spouse, child, or unmarried son or daughter of such aliens) if: (1) application is made before April 1, 2007; and (2) the alien is otherwise eligible for an immigrant visa and admissible as a permanent resident, except that certain specified grounds of inadmissibility do not apply.

Authorizes otherwise qualified aliens who have been ordered excluded, deported, removed, or to depart voluntarily to apply for adjustment under this Act without filing a separate motion to reopen, reconsider, or vacate such order. Prohibits the removal of such aliens pending a final determination on the application for adjustment.

Authorizes the Secretary to grant work authorization to aliens who have applied for adjustment of status under this Act.

Provides for administrative review of such adjustment decisions but precludes judicial review.

States that the Secretary of State shall not be required to offset immigrant visa numbers as the result of adjustments of status made pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
