<bill session="109" type="s" number="476" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Boy Scouts of America to exchange certain land in the State of Utah acquired under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000382" joined="2005-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 04/07/2006 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-231.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-04-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="393">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 393.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2006-09-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10528" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10528" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T18:33:49-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29T22:03:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boy Scouts"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-01T16:34:27Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on April 20, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Boy Scouts of America Land Transfer Act of 2006 - Authorizes the Utah National Parks Council of the Boy Scouts of America (the Boy Scouts) to convey to Brian Head Resort certain public land in Utah acquired under the Recreation and Public Purposes Act (the Act) for the purpose of operating a camp in exchange for conveyance by Brian Head Resort of certain of its private land to the Boy Scouts.

Requires that, upon conveyance to the Boy Scouts, the private land shall be subject to the terms and conditions imposed on the entire tract of land acquired by the Boy Scouts for a camp under a specified Bureau of Land Management (BLM) patent.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior, upon completion of the land exchanges under this Act, to amend the original BLM patent providing for the conveyance of the public land to the Boy Scouts under the Act to take into account such exchanges.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-231</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
