<bill session="108" type="s" number="2569" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:23Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Junk Fax Prevention Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 227 of the Communications Act of 1934 to clarify the prohibition on junk fax transmissions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Junk Fax Prevention Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/24/2004 S7324"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/24/2004 S7324-7325" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4600" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="Facsimile transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-17T14:03:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Junk Fax Prevention Act of 2004 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a person from using any telephone facsimile (fax) machine, computer, or other device to send, to another fax machine, an unsolicited advertisement to a person who has requested that such sender not send such advertisements, or to any other person unless: (1) the sender has an established business relationship with the person; and (2) the advertisement contains a conspicuous notice on its first page that the recipient may request not to be sent any further unsolicited advertisements, and includes a domestic telephone and fax number (neither of which can be a pay-per-call number) for sending such a request.

Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to provide by rule that a request not to send unsolicited advertisements complies with legal requirements if: (1) the request identifies the recipient fax number to which the request relates; (2) the request is made to the telephone or fax number of the sender; and (3) the person making the request has not subsequently provided express invitation or permission to have such advertisements sent. Authorizes the FCC to allow professional tax-exempt trade associations to send unsolicited advertisements to their members in furtherance of association purposes.

Requires the: (1) FCC to report annually to Congress on the enforcement of the above requirements; and (2) Comptroller General to study, and report to specified congressional committees on, complaints received by the FCC concerning unsolicited advertisements sent to fax machines.</summary>
</bill>
