<bill session="117" type="s" number="4929" updated="2023-10-10T15:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consensual Donation and Research Integrity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consensual Donation and Research Integrity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to ensure the consensual donation and respectful disposition of human bodies and human body parts donated or transferred for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science and not for use in human transplantation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4062" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Organ and tissue donation and transplantation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-09T20:28:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consensual Donation and Research Integrity Act of 2022

This bill requires entities that acquire or transfer human bodies or body parts for education, research, or the advancement of medical, dental, or mortuary science to register with the Department of Health and Human Services.

Registered entities must comply with record-keeping, labeling, packaging, and disposition requirements. The registration and related requirements do not apply to (1) the acquisition or transfer of human bodies or body parts for use in human transplantation, or (2) the preparation, transportation, and final disposition of human bodies or body parts by funeral service professionals.</summary>
</bill>
