<bill session="112" type="h" number="2374" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:53Z">
  <state datetime="2011-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require automobile dealers to disclose to consumers the presence of event data recorders, or "black boxes", on new automobiles, and to require manufacturers to provide the consumer with the option to enable and disable such devices on future automobiles.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require automobile dealers to disclose to consumers the presence of event data recorders, or "black boxes", on new automobiles, and to require manufacturers to provide the consumer with the option to enable and disable such devices on future automobiles.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-09-15T13:31:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Requires the event data recorder in a motor vehicle and any data recorded on such a recorder to be considered the property of the vehicle owner. Makes retrieval of such data by anyone other than the vehicle owner unlawful, except: (1) with the owner's consent; (2) in response to a court order; (3) by a vehicle dealer or an automotive technician for servicing the vehicle; or (4) for improving vehicle safety, provided the identity of the registered owner or driver is not disclosed. Gives the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) the authority to enforce this Act.

Makes it unlawful to manufacture, sell, or import new motor vehicles manufactured after 2011 (bearing a model year of 2013 or later) that are equipped with event data recorders, unless those recorders can be disabled by the vehicle owner.</summary>
</bill>
