<bill session="109" type="h" number="1099" updated="2019-11-15T21:33:17Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-phishing Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Anti-phishing Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To criminalize Internet scams involving fraudulently obtaining personal information, commonly known as phishing.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000762"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2005-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="472" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-05-02T18:52:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Anti-phishing Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal criminal code to criminalize Internet scams involving fraudulently obtaining personal information (phishing).

Imposes a fine or imprisonment for up to five years, or both, for a person who knowingly and with the intent to engage in an activity constituting fraud or identity theft under Federal or State law: (1) creates or procures the creation of a website or domain name that represents itself as a legitimate online business without the authority or approval of the registered owner of such business; and (2) uses that website or domain name to solicit means of identification from any person.

Imposes a fine or imprisonment for up to five years, or both, for a person who knowingly and with the intent to engage in activity constituting fraud or identity theft under Federal or State law sends an electronic mail message that: (1) falsely represents itself as being sent by a legitimate online business; (2) includes an Internet location tool referring or linking users to an online location on the World Wide Web that falsely purports to belong to or be associated with a legitimate online business; and (3) solicits means of identification from the recipient.</summary>
</bill>
