<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3410</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T06:05:41Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-10T00:14:52Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-05-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Acceptance of Offer on Liability and Expedited Claims at Mississippi Canyon 252 Act</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>3461</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-06-09</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-1241.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 410.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-25</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>V000127</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Vitter, David [R-LA]</fullName>
        <firstName>David</firstName>
        <lastName>Vitter</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000572</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. LeMieux, George S. [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>LeMieux</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000055</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Isakson, Johnny [R-GA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Johnny</firstName>
        <lastName>Isakson</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Energy</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accidents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gulf of Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judicial review and appeals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pollution liability</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Energy</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-05-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-06-10T18:37:46Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Acceptance of Liability and Expedited Claims at Mississippi Canyon 252 Act - Establishes within the Department of the Interior the Office of Deepwater Horizon Claims Compensation (Office) to compensate, on a no-fault basis and in a nonadversarial manner, persons and governmental entities that have incurred damages as a result of the Deepwater Horizon incident.</p> <p>Makes the Office Administrator responsible for processing claims for compensation for damages.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to: (1) establish comprehensive claimant assistance and resource centers in areas with large concentrations of potential claimants; and (2) designate categories of claims to be handled on an expedited basis as a result of extreme financial hardship.</p> <p>Imposes a stay upon any claim for monetary damages pending in federal or state court related to the Deepwater Horizon incident. Makes any such claim eligible for disposition only if the claimant elects to pursue it under this Act.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to establish an Advisory Committee on Deepwater Horizon Compensation.</p> <p>Sets forth the essential elements of an eligible claim for damages, including proof, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the claimant suffered damages as a result of the Deepwater Horizon incident. Declares that a claimant shall not be required to demonstrate that such damages resulted from the negligence or other fault of any other person. </p> <p>Sets forth claims procedures. Covers damages for losses to real or personal property, subsistence use, revenues, profits and earning capacity, and the costs of public services.</p> <p>Confers on the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive jurisdiction over any action for declaratory or injunctive relief challenging any provision of this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to renegotiate the terms of the &quot;Mississippi Canyon 252&quot; lease to reflect statements made in a certain letter from the Group Chief Executive of British Petroleum Exploration &amp; Production, Incorporated (BP) to the Secretaries of Homeland Security and of the Interior that BP is &quot;prepared to pay above $75 million&quot; on &quot;all legitimate claims&quot; relating to that explosion and oil spill. Requires BP, as a condition of such renegotiated lease, to pay all damages awarded pursuant to this Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Acceptance of Liability and Expedited Claims at Mississippi Canyon 252 Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Acceptance of Liability and Expedited Claims at Mississippi Canyon 252 Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Acceptance of Liability and Expedited Claims at Mississippi Canyon 252 Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to create a fair and efficient system to resolve claims of victims for economic injury caused by the Deepwater Horizon incident, and to direct the Secretary of the Interior to renegotiate the terms of the lease known as "Mississippi Canyon 252" with respect to claims relating to the Deepwater Horizon explosion and oil spill that exceed existing applicable economic liability limitations.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2010-05-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3410pcs/xml/BILLS-111s3410pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-05-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 410.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
