<bill session="111" type="h" number="2540" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:10Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Investment in Oil shale the Next generation of Environmental, Energy and Resource Security (PIONEERS) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To set clear rules for the development of United States oil shale resources, to promote shale technology research and development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Investment in Oil shale the Next generation of Environmental, Energy and Resource Security (PIONEERS) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000564"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000329" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-01T21:49:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Investment in Oil shale the Next generation of Environmental, Energy and Resource Security (PIONEERS) Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to hold a lease sale offering an additional 10 parcels for lease for research, development, and demonstration of oil shale resources under the terms offered in the solicitation of bids for such leases published on January 15, 2009.

Applies the oil shale management final rules published by the Department of the Interior on November 18, 2008, to all commercial leasing for the management of federally owned oil shale, and any associated minerals, located on federal lands.

Authorizes the Secretary to reduce temporarily any royalties, fees, rentals, bonus, or other payments for leases of federal lands for oil shale resources development and production as necessary to incentivize and encourage development of such resources, if the Secretary determines that such payments, otherwise authorized by law, are hindering production of such resources.</summary>
</bill>
