<bill session="117" type="h" number="4705" updated="2023-06-15T12:30:51Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to modify the treatment of revenue from timber sale contracts and certain payments made by counties to the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior under good neighbor agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Treating Tribes and Counties as Good Neighbors Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Treating Tribes and Counties as Good Neighbors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2022-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2492" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-26T16:46:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Treating Tribes and Counties as Good Neighbors Act 

This bill revises the Good Neighbor Authority program to modify the treatment of revenue from timber sale contracts under good neighbor agreements with the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior. (The Good Neighbor Authority permits USDA and Interior to enter into cooperative agreements or contracts with states, counties, and Indian tribes to perform forest, rangeland, and watershed restoration services on federal land managed by the Forest Service or the Bureau of Land Management.)

Specifically, the bill (1) requires Indian tribes and counties to retain revenue generated from timber sales under a good neighbor agreement; and (2) allows states, counties, and Indian tribes to use such revenue for authorized restoration projects on nonfederal lands under a good neighbor agreement. (Under current law, only a state is permitted to retain the revenues, and the revenues must be used for restoration projects on federal land.)</summary>
</bill>
