<bill session="116" type="s" number="1201" updated="2022-11-01T19:47:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EFFECT Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">EFFECT Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Enhancing Fossil Fuel Energy Carbon Technology Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Fossil Fuel Energy Carbon Technology Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the fossil energy research and development provisions of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to enhance fossil fuel technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2019-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 116-296.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-115.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="218">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-02T15:15:28Z" status="Reported to Senate">Enhancing Fossil Fuel Energy Carbon Technology Act of 2019 or the EFFECT Act of 2019

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to replace its existing fossil energy research and development technology programs with new programs. Under the new programs, DOE must research and develop fossil fuel technology for carbon capture, utilization, storage, or removal.

DOE must establish a coal and natural gas technology program to ensure the continued use of domestic coal and natural gas resources through the development of technologies. The technologies must significantly improve the efficiency, effectiveness, costs, and environmental performance of coal and natural gas use.

In addition, DOE must establish a research, development, and demonstration carbon storage program and a large-scale carbon sequestration demonstration program. DOE may establish an integrated storage program.

DOE must also establish a carbon utilization program to identify and assess novel uses for carbon, carbon capture technologies for industrial systems, and alternative uses for coal.

Finally, DOE must establish a program to develop technologies and strategies for removing carbon dioxide from the atmosphere on a large scale. The program must include air capture technology prizes provided under a competition as well as grants for centers that test direct air capture and storage technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-115</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
