<bill session="117" type="h" number="7631" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans for Mustangs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans for Mustangs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wild Free-Roaming Horses and Burros Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to implement fertility controls to manage populations of wild free-roaming horses and burros, and to encourage training opportunities for military veterans to assist in range management activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2022-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2022-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2022-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-30T21:10:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans for Mustangs Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to prioritize use of nonsurgical, medically safe on-range fertility controls to manage populations of wild, free-roaming horses and burros. In implementing such fertility controls, the Bureau of Land Management shall prioritize the recruitment of military veterans to train and become certified in the application of fertility controls, including the certified PZP applicator certification offered by the Science and Conservation Center's Certification Program.

Interior shall provide appropriate compensation to military veterans participating in such a certification program.

The bill authorizes Interior to contract with military veterans who have completed the training program to carry out fertility control activities.</summary>
</bill>
