<bill session="111" type="h" number="2549" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:09Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Municipal Bond Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure uniform and accurate credit rating of municipal bonds and provide for a review of the municipal bond insurance industry.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Municipal Bond Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001037"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001234" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000008" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001171" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2009-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-02T14:53:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Municipal Bond Fairness Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to require each registered nationally recognized statistical rating organization (NSRO) (credit rating agency) to establish, maintain, and enforce written policies and procedures reasonably designed to: (1) establish and maintain credit ratings with respect to securities and money market instruments designed to assess the risk that investors in such instruments may not receive payment in accordance with their terms of issuance; and (2) define clearly any rating symbol and apply it consistently.

Permits an NSRO to use or consider the following when assessing the risk that an investor in a security or money market instrument will not receive repayment in accordance with the terms of issuance: (1) additional credit factors that it has documented and disclosed; (2) credit factors that are unique to municipal securities that are not backed by the issuer's full faith and credit; or (3) an additional credit rating symbol to distinguish ratings of a certain type of security or money market instrument from ratings of any other types.

Prohibits the SEC from imposing any requirement that prevents an NSRO from establishing ratings that are complementary to such mandatory ratings and that are created to measure a discrete aspect of risk.

Directs the SEC to establish performance measures to consider when deciding whether to initiate a review concerning whether an NSRO has failed to adhere to its procedures and methodologies for issuing ratings.</summary>
</bill>
