<bill session="111" type="h" number="6268" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:32Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wage Theft Prevention and Community Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a wage theft prevention grant program in the Department of Labor to prevent wage and hour violations and expand and improve cooperative efforts between enforcement agencies and members of the community.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wage Theft Prevention and Community Partnership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2010-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2010-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-18T14:50:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Wage Theft Prevention and Community Partnership Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award one- to three-year renewable grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partners to prevent wage and hour violations of the Fair Labor Standards Act, the Migrant and Seasonal Agricultural Worker Protection Act, or any related regulations, or violations of any other law enforced by the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor by: (1) informing workers of their rights and the remedies available to them; and (2) expanding and improving cooperative efforts between agencies charged with enforcing wage and hour requirements and employers and their employees.

Makes eligible for such grants such partners as: (1) not-for-profit community organizations dedicated to combating poverty and preventing abuse of wage and hour laws; (2) labor organizations; and (3) Joint Labor Management Cooperative Committees established under the Labor Management Relations Act, 1947.

Directs the Secretary to establish a Wage Theft Prevention Fund to fund such grants.

Prohibits the award of such a grant to: (1) any entity that infringes upon the organizational and collective bargaining rights guaranteed by the National Labor Relations Act; or (2) the Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) or any of its subsidiaries.</summary>
</bill>
