<bill session="117" type="h" number="4772" updated="2023-08-01T21:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-01T17:10:18-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-01T17:10:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the application and review process of the Department of Veterans Affairs for clothing allowance claims submitted by veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mark O&#226;&#8364;&#8482;Brien VA Clothing Allowance Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mark O&#226;&#8364;&#8482;Brien VA Clothing Allowance Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Mark O&#226;&#8364;&#8482;Brien VA Clothing Allowance Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2022-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000592" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2022-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2021-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29T14:29:53-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29T14:30:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8604-8605" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8604-8605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29T14:30:18-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4772.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-29T14:35:36-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01T17:10:16-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1499, proceedings on H.R. 4772 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-01T17:10:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 5 of H. Res. 1499, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 4601, as amended; H.R. 4772, as amended; H.R. 4899; H.R. 5943, as amended; H.R. 7158, as amended; H.R. 8203; H.R. 9308; and S. 3825; and the following resolutions were agreed to under suspension of the rules: H. Res. 744, as amended; and H. Res. 922, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8696-8700" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8697" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2513" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1499" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-01T21:01:15Z" status="Passed House">Mark O'Brien VA Clothing Allowance Improvement Act

This bill modifies the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) clothing allowance policy for veterans who, due to a service-connected disability, wear a prosthetic, use an orthopedic appliance (e.g., a wheelchair), or use a prescription skin medication that the VA determines causes irreparable damage to clothing.

The bill requires the VA to continue the clothing allowance for such a veteran on an annual basis until the veteran elects to no longer receive the allowance, or the VA determines the veteran is no longer eligible for the allowance, whichever occurs first.

The bill sets forth a procedure by which the VA must conduct reviews of clothing allowance claims to determine the continued eligibility of veterans. Specifically, the VA must conduct a review (1) five years after the date on which a veteran initially receives a clothing allowance and periodically thereafter, and (2) whenever the VA receives notice that the veteran no longer meets eligibility requirements. If a veteran is eligible for a clothing allowance based on a circumstance that is not subject to change, the VA does not need to review whether the veteran has continued eligibility.

If the VA determines, as the result of a review of a claim, that a veteran no longer meets the eligibility requirements for a clothing allowance, the VA must provide notice of the determination and discontinue the clothing allowance. The notice must include a description of applicable actions that may be taken following the determination (e.g., filing a notice of disagreement).

The bill also extends certain loan fee rates through January 15, 2031, under the VA's home loan program.</summary>
</bill>
