<bill session="116" type="h" number="2608" updated="2022-02-08T23:19:31Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PFAS Testing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the testing of perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances under the Toxic Substances Control Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PFAS Testing Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-25T15:04:05Z" status="Introduced in House">PFAS Testing Act of 2019

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to order comprehensive toxicity testing on all perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS. These substances are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds, such as nonstick cookware or weatherproof clothing.

An order from the EPA for comprehensive toxicity testing for PFAS shall require the development of information by any person who manufactures, processes, or intends to manufacture or process PFAS. The bill also provides guidelines for the development of these orders, including the methodologies and protocols to be used. Additionally, the bill specifies when a PFAS may be exempt from testing or information submission.

Each person who manufactures or processes PFAS must submit to the EPA (1) all records of significant adverse reactions to health or the environment alleged to have been caused by PFAS, and (2) all health and safety studies related to PFAS of which the person is aware. The EPA must make all such health and safety studies available to the public within four months of the enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
