<bill session="118" type="hr" number="1486" updated="2025-08-21T21:11:18Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-24T14:05:15-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-24T14:05:15-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3334) to provide for the imposition of sanctions on members of the National Communist Party Congress of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8205) to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide that Byrne grant funds may be used for public safety report systems, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8790) to expedite under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and improve forest management activities on National Forest System lands, on public lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, and on Tribal lands to return resilience to overgrown, fire-prone forested lands, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 1469) ensuring accountability for key officials in the Biden-Harris administration responsible for decisionmaking and execution failures throughout the withdrawal from Afghanistan; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 3334) to provide for the imposition of sanctions on members of the National Communist Party Congress of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8205) to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide that Byrne grant funds may be used for public safety report systems, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 8790) to expedite under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and improve forest management activities on National Forest System lands, on public lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, and on Tribal lands to return resilience to overgrown, fire-prone forested lands, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 1469) ensuring accountability for key officials in the Biden-Harris administration responsible for decisionmaking and execution failures throughout the withdrawal from Afghanistan; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>Reported in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-705, by Mr. Burgess.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-23T20:56:38-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 3334 and H.R. 8790 under a structured rule and H.R. 8205 and H. Res. 1469 under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on each measure with one motion to recommit on H.R. 3334, H.R. 8790, and H.R. 8205.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-23" calendar="House" number="91">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 91.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T12:24:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5662-5669" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T12:30:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1486.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T12:33:03-04:00">
      <text>UNANIMOUS CONSENT REQUEST - Mr. Burgess asked unanimous consent that amendment No. 3 printed in part D of House Report 118-705, to be offered by Representative Valadao of California or a designee, be modified by an amendment placed at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T12:33:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on H. Res. 1486.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T13:22:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1486, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T13:31:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5669-5671" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T13:59:01-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 204 (Roll no. 443).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="444" datetime="2024-09-24T14:05:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 212 - 207 (Roll no. 444).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5662-5663" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24T14:05:17-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3334" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8205" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8790" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1469" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="5" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-21T21:11:14Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of multiple measures:

the bill (H.R. 3334) to provide for the imposition of sanctions on members of the Central Committee of the Chinese Communist Party;the bill (H.R. 8205) to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide that funds for the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program may be used for public safety report systems;the bill (H.R. 8790) to expedite the review of certain forest management projects under the National Environmental Policy Act (NEPA) of 1969 and improve forest management activities on National Forest System lands, public lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management, and tribal lands;the resolution (H.Res. 1469) to ensure accountability for key officials in the Biden-Harris administration responsible for decision-making and execution failures throughout the withdrawal from Afghanistan; andan amendment to&#160;H.Res.&#160;5, which established the rules of the House of Representatives for the 118th Congress, to modify the rule for the remote appearance of witnesses.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-705</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
