<bill session="116" type="h" number="4357" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Forest Products Program Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a program to charge and collect not less than the fair market value for forest botanical products harvested on National Forest System lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Forest Products Program Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2019-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-21T16:46:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Special Forest Products Program Reauthorization Act of 2019

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a program of charging and collecting fees for forest botanical products harvested on National Forest System (NFS) lands. Under the program, USDA may not permit forest botanical products to be harvested in excess of sustainable harvest levels.

Collected fees must be in an amount to recover a portion of the fair market value of the harvested forest botanical products and a portion of all of the costs incurred by USDA that are associated with the granting, modifying, or monitoring of the authorization for harvest of the products, including the costs of any environmental or other analysis.

USDA must establish a personal use harvest level for each forest botanical product. The harvesting of a forest botanical product below that level by a person for personal use shall not be subject to the charges and fees under this bill.

USDA shall (1) conduct analyses to determine whether and how the harvest of forest botanical products on NFS lands can be conducted on a sustainable basis, and (2) establish procedures and timeframes for monitoring and revising the harvest levels established for such products.

Funds collected under the program shall be expended at NFS units to pay for the costs of conducting inventories of forest botanical products, determining sustainable levels of harvest, monitoring and assessing the impacts of harvest levels and methods, restoration activities, and authorizing harvest.</summary>
</bill>
