<bill session="118" type="s" number="324" updated="2025-04-21T12:24:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP Neglected Diseases of Poverty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Neglected Diseases of Poverty Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Study, Treat, Observe, and Prevent Neglected Diseases of Poverty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out activities relating to neglected diseases of poverty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-12T21:32:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Study, Treat, Observe, and Prevent Neglected Diseases of Poverty Act or the STOP Neglected Diseases of Poverty Act

This bill establishes a task force, a grant program, and other efforts to address neglected diseases of poverty in the United States. (Neglected diseases of poverty are chronic and disabling diseases that are caused by parasites, bacteria, and other pathogens and that primarily impact those living in extreme poverty, such as Chagas disease or hookworm infection.)

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services must (1) establish an interagency task force to provide recommendations for addressing the diseases, (2) increase awareness among health care providers and the public about the diseases, and (3) support research into affordable vaccines and other therapeutics for the diseases.

Additionally, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention must provide grants to (1) states to implement surveillance systems for the diseases; and (2) federally qualified health centers to implement guidelines for the diagnosis, control, and treatment of the diseases.

The bill also authorizes one or more centers of excellence for researching and developing methods to diagnose, prevent, control, and treat the diseases.</summary>
</bill>
