<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="880" updated="2022-02-08T23:02:14Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2639" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2020-09-15T16:51:13-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <offered datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 9 printed in Part B of House Report 116-502 to expand the allowable uses of implementation grants to include creating or improving a one-stop enrollment process for students with multiple public school options, including making school information and data more accessible and easier to understand.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment to expand the allowable uses of implementation grants to include creating or improving a one-stop enrollment process for students with multiple public school options, including making school information and data more accessible and easier to understand.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2020-09-15T16:51:13-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="188">
      <text>On agreeing to the Moulton amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 379 - 34 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T14:57:20-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A006) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T14:46:56-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Moulton.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4412-4413, H4414-4415" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4412" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T14:46:56-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Moulton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T16:51:13-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Moulton amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 379 - 34 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T16:51:13-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Moulton amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 379 - 34 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15T16:51:13-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
