<bill session="116" type="h" number="8025" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:27Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Rural Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Rural Access to Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to clarify the application of the 15-mile secondary road distance requirement with respect to previously designated critical access hospitals under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001308" joined="2020-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2020-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000020" joined="2020-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-13T14:43:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Rural Access to Care Act

This bill limits the scope of guidance issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) regarding the secondary road criteria for Medicare critical access hospitals (CAHs).

Currently, in order to qualify as a CAH under Medicare, a hospital must either (1) be located more than 35 miles (15 miles in mountainous regions or areas with only secondary roads) from another hospital, or (2) have been certified prior to January 1, 2006, by the state as a necessary provider of services in the area.

The CMS issued guidance on July 31, 2015, that provided more detail as to the differences between primary and secondary roads for purposes of CAH certification. The bill specifies that this guidance does not apply to CAHs that were certified prior to July 31, 2015, and that these CAHs are instead subject to the standards that were in place before the guidance was issued. Ongoing CAH certifications are also subject to pre-guidance standards until the CMS issues new guidance after a specified public comment period.</summary>
</bill>
