<bill session="117" type="s" number="3631" updated="2022-12-29T21:18:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bipartisan Ban on Congressional Stock Ownership Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan Ban on Congressional Stock Ownership Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit stock trading and ownership by Members of Congress and spouses of Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2022-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2022-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2022-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2022-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6678" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Ethics"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Senate Select Committee on Ethics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-05T16:35:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bipartisan Ban on Congressional Stock Ownership Act of 2022

This bill prohibits Members of Congress and their spouses from owning or trading stocks, bonds, commodities, futures, or any other form of security. Each current Member must divest within 180 days after the bill is enacted and each new Member must divest within 180 days after becoming a Member. However, Members and their spouses have 5 years to divest from specified complex investment vehicles. The bill does not apply to certain investments, such as investments in widely held investment funds that are diversified and do not present a conflict of interest and investments held in government employee retirement plans.

A Member or spouse who violates the bill may be subject to a fine of up to $50,000 for each violation. The bill permits a Member or spouse who is required to divest property under the bill to avoid recognizing gain for income tax purposes from the sale of that property to the extent that the Member or spouse purchases permitted bonds or diversified investment funds within 60 days of the divestiture.</summary>
</bill>
