<bill session="116" type="s" number="4742" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CLINICAL TREATMENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLINICAL TREATMENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Covering Life-saving Investigations Needed In Cancer And other Life-threatening conditions through Timely use of Resources for Easy and Affordable Treatment from Medicaid for Enrollees in Need Today Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to promote access to life-saving therapies for Medicaid enrollees by ensuring coverage of routine patient costs for items and services furnished in connection with participation in qualifying clinical trials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2020-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="913" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-03T22:23:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Covering Life-saving Investigations Needed in Cancer and Other Life-threatening Conditions through Timely use of Resources for Easy and Affordable Treatment from Medicaid for Enrollees in Need Today Act or the CLINICAL TREATMENT Act

This bill requires state Medicaid programs to cover routine patient costs for items and services that are provided in connection with a qualifying clinical trial regarding serious or other life-threatening conditions.

The bill defines routine patient costs to include items and services that would otherwise be covered under Medicaid absent the patient's participation in the clinical trial; the term includes items and services relating to trial complications, but excludes those items and services that are the subject of the trial or that are provided solely in relation to data analysis and are not otherwise covered.

Additionally, a qualifying clinical trial means, among other things, a clinical trial that is approved or funded by specified entities (e.g., the National Institutes of Health) or is an authorized new drug trial.</summary>
</bill>
