<bill session="117" type="h" number="1250" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20T16:44:39-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-20T16:44:39-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Emergency Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Emergency Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Communications Commission to issue reports after activation of the Disaster Information Reporting System and to make improvements to network outage reporting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000479" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19T14:37:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pallone moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19T14:37:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3642-3644" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3642-3643" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19T14:37:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1250.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19T14:43:39-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20T16:44:38-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 535, proceedings on H.R. 1250 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2021-07-20T16:44:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 7 of H. Res. 535, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 678; H.R. 1036; H.R. 1079, as amended; H.R. 1158; H.R. 1250; H.R. 1754; H.R. 1833, as amended; H.R. 1850; H.R. 1871; H.R. 1877, as amended; H.R. 1893; H.R. 1895; H.R. 2118; H.R. 2795, as amended; H.R. 2928; H.R. 2980, as amended; H.R. 3003; H.R. 3138, as amended; H.R. 3223; H.R. 3263; and H.R. 3264; and the following resolutions were agreed to under suspension of the rules: H. Res. 277; and H. Res. 294.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3715-3730" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3717-3718" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-07-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="390" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="535" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-12T10:32:00Z" status="Passed House">Emergency Reporting Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to report on certain activations of the Disaster Information Reporting System (the system through which communications providers report their operational status during times of crisis) and to adopt specified rules related to network outage reporting.

If the system was activated for at least seven days, the FCC must issue a preliminary a report that includes (1) the number and duration of any service outages, (2) the approximate number of users or the amount of infrastructure potentially affected by a service outage, and (3) the number and duration of any outages at public safety answering points (PSAPs) that prevent the PSAPs from receiving and routing emergency calls to emergency service personnel. The FCC must also hold at least one public field hearing in the area affected by the event, and it must issue a final report that includes recommendations on how to improve the resiliency of affected communications or networks recovery efforts.

The FCC must also determine the circumstances under which it shall require certain service providers to notify a PSAP of a communications service disruption that prevents the origination of 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 calls or the delivery of information that allows the PSAP to identify the number of or locate a 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 caller. Further, the FCC must require this notification to be made and specify the appropriate timing of the notification.</summary>
</bill>
