<bill session="110" type="h" number="6189" updated="2019-11-15T21:29:25Z">
  <state datetime="2008-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Charter Forest Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Colorado Charter Forest Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a "Charter Forest" demonstration project on all National Forest System lands in the State of Colorado in order to combat insect infestation, improve forest health, reduce the threat of wildfire, protect biological diversity, and enhance the social sustainability and economic productivity of the lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000458"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2008-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Sustainable forestry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-08-25T20:31:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Colorado Charter Forest Act of 2008 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct a demonstration project for National Forest System lands in Colorado ("covered lands") for the purposes of increasing community involvement in decision making regarding management and evaluating methods to improve the health and management of the lands.

Requires establishment of: (1) an independent scientific panel to assess the ecological, social, and economic sustainability of the covered lands and prepare a monitoring plan; and (2) a community management council to advise on environmental, economic, and social issues related to the management, occupancy, and use of the lands.

Requires the Secretary, not later than 60 days after appointment of the community management council, to begin to develop a land and resource management charter for the covered lands, notwithstanding the requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.

Requires the Secretary to promulgate rules to establish a pre-decision review process for use in connection with site-specific projects.

Expresses the sense of Congress that in order to offset funds appropriated to implement this Act for a fiscal year, the Forest Service land acquisition budget for that year should be reduced by an equal amount.</summary>
</bill>
