<bill session="109" type="h" number="3608" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:30Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet Drug Sales Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit third-party Internet sales sites from posting offers to sell controlled substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Drug Sales Accountability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000165" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-19T18:17:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Internet Drug Sales Accountability Act - Amends the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit a person who controls a third-party Internet sales site from: (1) accepting for posting on the site an offer to sell an item that the person knows is a controlled substance; or (2) failing to promptly remove from the site an offer to sell an item which a federal or state official notifies the person is a controlled substance. Requires such person to create a system for receipt of such notice in writing and specifying information including the offer and substance involved and the name, title, address, and contact information of the officials who sent the notice. (Makes this provision inapplicable with respect to the sale of controlled substances by a licensed pharmacy.)

Sets criminal and civil penalties for violations. Requires a third-party Internet sales site to monitor and remove in good faith any posting of an offer to sell an item that the site believes to violate federal or state law or that is the subject of notice under this Act. Shields from liability any such site that in good faith monitors and removes a posting pursuant to this provision.</summary>
</bill>
