<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1092</number>
    <updateDate>2020-02-12T18:58:29Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2020-02-12T18:58:29Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-26T16:14:40Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Carper</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001268</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Scott P. [R-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Scott</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>P.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-05-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aviation and airports</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal officials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Firearms and explosives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law enforcement officers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Railroads</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Travel and tourism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-06-21T22:28:39Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Aviation Security Innovation &amp; Reform Act of 2011 or AIR Act of 2011 - Places the Transportation Security Administration (TSA), headed by the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (TSA), under the administration of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). (Effectively updates federal law to reflect the transfer of the TSA from the Department of Transportation [DOT] to DHS in March 2003.)</p> <p>Establishes in the TSA the Office of Behavior Analysis, which shall provide behavior detection training to TSA and other federal, state, and local government law enforcement personnel.</p> <p>Transfers from the Under Secretary of Transportation for Security to the Assistant Secretary the duty to prescribe employment standards for air carrier personnel and airport security personnel.</p> <p>Revises security screening personnel training plan requirements to require the Assistant Secretary to establish a training plan for TSA Transportation Security Officers (TSOs) that: (1) ensures that TSO training is standardized; and (2) meets certain other requirements, including that each TSO receives training in basic security screening skills and criminal and antiterrorism awareness.</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to develop partnerships with state and local law enforcement agencies to improve coordination of behavior detection activities.</p> <p>Directs the DHS Secretary to: (1) study the feasibility of creating an Aviation Sharing Analysis Center to provide real-time information sharing among public and private sector entities with respect to threats to aviation infrastructure, and (2) continue to advocate for international cooperation with foreign governments and organizations in the development of international aviation security standards to strengthen security while promoting travel and protecting travelers' rights.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to: (1) require the TSA Transportation Security Operations Center to use all of the law enforcement and intelligence databases available when checking passengers whose behavior warrants intervention by a law enforcement official, and (2) standardize and streamline threat-reporting guidelines to allow behavior detection officers or other designated TSA officials to receive Center information in a timely manner.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to continue the standardization of TSA security and personnel procedures at U.S. airports.</p> <p>Requires the Assistant Secretary to deploy: (1) behavior detection officers to National Special Security Events designated by the DHS Secretary; and (2) Visible Intermodal Prevention and Response teams at passenger rail facilities to enhance security and cross-training opportunities for behavior detection officers. </p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish an electronic medium through which TSOs and behavior detection officers may anonymously submit feedback regarding TSA transportation security programs or management issues.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to develop: (1) a system to verify the accuracy of air carrier screening data to determine the level of compliance with the congressionally mandated 100% air cargo screening requirements specified under the SAFE Port Act; and (2) a technology implementation plan that establishes how screening technologies will be integrated into overall aviation security systems at airports, such as screening technology to detect explosive compounds like pentaerythritol tetranitrate (PETN) and acetone peroxide (TATP).</p> <p>Directs the DHS Secretary to explore expanding access to international trusted traveler programs for international passengers entering the United States by looking at other domestic and foreign government trusted traveler programs and identifying the best practices.</p> <p>Directs the Assistant Secretary to establish an independent aviation advisory panel to review TSA aviation security programs, including passenger screening programs, checked baggage screening programs, and air cargo screening programs.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>AIR Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>AIR Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Aviation Security Innovation &amp; Reform Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>AIR Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to address aviation security in the United States by bolstering passenger and air cargo screening procedures, to ensure that purchases of screening technologies are thoroughly evaluated for the best return on investment of the taxpayer's money, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1092is/xml/BILLS-112s1092is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
