<bill session="116" type="h" number="6713" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FORWARD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand and modify the credit for increasing research activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FORWARD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Furthering Our Recovery With American Research &amp; Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2020-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2020-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3593" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-19T21:22:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Furthering Our Recovery With American Research &amp; Development Act or the FORWARD Act

This bill makes several changes to the income tax credit for business expenses for increasing research activities.

Specifically, the bill

 expands eligibility for the credit by increasing the maximum amount of gross receipts of an entity for the taxable year and using an eight-year (rather than five-year) period in the calculation of those amounts; removes the business credit carryforward from calculation of the payroll tax credit portion of the credit; includes among qualified research expenses wages paid in connection with research activity training expenses; and increases the credit rate for expenses incurred in certain collaborative research activities (i.e., conducted with higher education institutions, tax-exempt scientific research organizations, or charitable grant organizations) and qualified domestic manufacturers. The bill appropriates to the Social Security trust funds amounts equal to the reduction in revenues from payroll taxes by reason of this bill.

The Internal Revenue Service (IRS) shall develop partnership agreements to provide for development of basic training relating to federal tax credits benefitting small business concerns and startups, especially credits for research and experimentation, and informational materials relating to such credits, including IRS guidance documents.

Small business development centers shall provide informational materials, education, and basic training to small business concerns relating to federal tax credits, including those available to (1) businesses generally; and (2) small business concerns and startups specifically, especially credits for research and experimentation.</summary>
</bill>
