<bill session="117" type="h" number="1398" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:02Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Filtering and Retrofitting the Environment for Safe and Healthy Activities Indoors and Revenue (FRESH AIR) for Businesses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a credit against payroll taxes to businesses and nonprofit organizations that purchase or upgrade ventilation and air filtration systems to help prevent the spread of COVID-19 and other airborne communicable diseases.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Filtering and Retrofitting the Environment for Safe and Healthy Activities Indoors and Revenue (FRESH AIR) for Businesses Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001312"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001135" joined="2021-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="122" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-09T12:20:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Filtering and Retrofitting the Environment for Safe and Healthy Activities Indoors and Revenue (FRESH AIR) for Businesses Act

This bill allows employers a payroll tax credit in each calendar quarter through 2021 equal to 50% of the cost of qualified ventilation, zoning, and air filtration and purification expenses. This includes the purchase and installation of a heating, ventilation, and air conditioning system, updates to such systems, and the purchase of any air filter, air cleaner, or air purifier. The maximum amount of this credit for any employer may not exceed $15,000 for all calendar quarters.

The bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a framework and guidelines for a voluntary label to certify that air pressure, ventilation, zoning, fresh air intake, purification, or filtration systems meet the standards established by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
