<bill session="109" type="h" number="1544" updated="2022-02-03T05:35:44Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-12T14:13:19-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-05-12T14:13:19-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="popular">Homeland Security Grant bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide faster and smarter funding for first responders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000830"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000136" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000372" joined="2005-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000152" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001035" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000287" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000321" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000517" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001148" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2005-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001152" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000268" joined="2005-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2005-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2005-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Science, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-12">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-19">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-28">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 109-65.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-04-28" calendar="Union" number="32">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 32.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-05-10T20:49:50-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 269 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1544 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:22:43-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 269 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:24:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 269.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3211-3237" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:24:12-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1544 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:24:19-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 269 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:24:21-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Ken Calvert to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T11:24:30-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1544.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T12:31:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Berry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T12:38:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Berry amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T12:46:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Bass amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T12:57:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Weiner amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:13:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Weiner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Weiner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:20:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 269 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Castle amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:29:24-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of the Weiner amendment which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:54:54-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1544.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:54:55-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3236" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T13:55:40-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3223-3228" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="170" datetime="2005-05-12T14:13:19-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 409 - 10 (Roll no. 170).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12T14:13:21-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1013" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="269" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Capital budgets"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-territorial relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Rescue work"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h126"/>
    <amendment number="h125"/>
    <amendment number="h124"/>
    <amendment number="h123"/>
    <amendment number="h122"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2005-05-17T14:17:30Z" status="Passed House amended">Faster and Smarter Funding for First Responders Act of 2005 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to set forth provisions governing Department of Homeland Security (DHS) grant funding for first responders pursuant to the State Homeland Security Grant Program, the Urban Area Security Initiative, and the Law Enforcement Terrorism Prevention Program. Excludes non-DHS programs, fire grant programs, and the Emergency Management Performance Grant program and Urban Search and Rescue Grants program authorized by specified Federal laws.

Makes eligible for a covered grant any State, region, or directly eligible tribe. Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to require any State applying for a covered grant to submit a three-year State homeland security plan, to be developed in consultation with local governments and first responders. Precludes a grant award to a State absent approval of such plan. Sets forth minimum contents for grant applications, including the designation of regional and tribal liaisons (if the applicant is a region or directly eligible tribe). Requires regional and tribal applications to be coordinated with State applications.

Requires the Secretary to establish a First Responder Grants Board. Directs the Board to evaluate and annually prioritize pending applications for covered grants based upon the degree to which they would lessen the threat to, vulnerability of, and consequences for persons (including transient commuters and tourists) and critical infrastructure. Requires such evaluation and prioritization to be based upon the Directorate for Information Analysis and Infrastructure Protection's most current risk assessment of terrorist threats against the United States. Requires the Board to coordinate with State, local, regional, and tribal officials in establishing grant criteria and to specifically consider: (1) terrorist threats against specified critical infrastructure sectors; and (2) specified types of threats to such critical infrastructure sectors and to populations in all areas of the United States, urban and rural. Sets forth minimum funding amounts for grants, providing for larger grant awards to applicants that have a significant international land border and/or adjoin a body of water within North America through which an international boundary line extends.

Directs the Secretary to establish a Task Force on Terrorism Preparedness for First Responders to assist the Secretary in updating, revising, or replacing essential capabilities for terrorism preparedness. Requires the Task Force to submit reports on its recommendations to the Secretary within 12 months of establishment and every two years thereafter. Requires the Task Force to ensure that its recommendations are consistent with the preparedness goals or recommendations of the Federal working group established under the Public Health Service Act and to take into account terrorism-related capabilities that State or local officials have determined to be essential and have undertaken since September 11, 2001.

Lists authorized uses of covered grants. Prohibits the use of grant funds to supplant State or local funds, to construct physical facilities, to acquire land, or for any State or local government cost sharing contribution. Authorizes covered grant applicants to petition the Secretary for reimbursement of the costs of any activity relating to prevention of, preparedness for, response to, or recovery from acts of terrorism that is a Federal duty and normally performed by a Federal agency, and that is being performed by a State and/or local government under agreement with a Federal agency. Sets the Federal share of the costs of activities carried out under covered grants at 100 percent of the total for the two-year period following enactment of this Act and at 75 percent thereafter. Requires each covered grant recipient to submit annual reports on homeland security spending. Establishes penalties for States that fail to pass through to local governments, first responders, and other local groups funds or resources, as required by this Act, within 45 days of receipt.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on grant program activities annually.

Directs the Secretary, in consultation with specified officials and standards organizations, to promulgate national voluntary consensus standards for grant-funded first responder equipment and training. Requires the coordination of such activities that relate to health professionals with the Secretary of Health and Human Services.

(Sec. 4) States that this Act supersedes a provision of the USA PATRIOT Act that sets forth minimum allocation amounts for domestic preparedness grants.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to establish within the Office for Domestic Preparedness (ODP) an Office of the Comptroller to oversee the grant distribution process and the financial management of ODP.

(Sec. 6) Requires the Comptroller General to report to Congress on the overall inventory and status of first responder training programs of DHS and other Federal agencies and the extent to which such programs are coordinated.

(Sec. 7) States that a person (including a governmental or other entity) who donates fire control or fire rescue equipment to a volunteer fire company shall not be liable for State or Federal civil damages for personal injuries, property damage or loss, or death caused by the equipment after the donation.

Waives such liability protection if: (1) the person's act or omission causing the injury, damage, loss, or death constitutes gross negligence or intentional misconduct; or (2) the person is the manufacturer of such equipment.

Preempts State law unless such law provides additional protection from liability.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-65</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
