<bill session="111" type="h" number="6018" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:48Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to a country that denies or unreasonably delays accepting the country's nationals upon the request of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to a country that denies or unreasonably delays accepting the country's nationals upon the request of the Secretary of Homeland Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-19T14:13:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretary of State, upon notice by the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) that a foreign government denies or unreasonably delays accepting the return of an alien who is a citizen, subject, national, or resident of that country, to order consular officers in that foreign country to stop granting immigrant visas or nonimmigrant visas to citizens, subjects, nationals, and residents of that country until the country has accepted the alien. (Under current law the Attorney General provides such notice to the Secretary of State.)

Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security, upon a determination that a foreign government denies or unreasonably delays accepting an alien who is a citizen, subject, national, or resident of that country after the alien has been ordered removed, to deny admission to any citizen, subject, national, or resident of such country who is seeking or has received a diplomatic nonimmigrant visa.</summary>
</bill>
