<bill session="116" type="s" number="2799" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NEWS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEWS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">NEWS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of the Interior to establish a joint Nexus of Energy and Water Sustainability Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Murkowski with an amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="362">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 362.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-01-07">
      <text>By Senator Murkowski from Committee on Energy and Natural Resources filed written report. Report No. 116-198.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2019" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2665" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-01T18:48:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability Act of 2019 or the NEWS Act of 2019

This bill establishes requirements concerning the energy-water nexus, which means the links between (1) the water needed to produce fuels, electricity, and other forms of energy; and (2) the energy needed to transport, reclaim, and treat water and wastewater.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of the Energy (DOE) and the Department of the Interior to establish a joint Nexus of Energy and Water for Sustainability (NEWS) Office and Interagency Coordination Committee on NEWS to plan for and coordinate energy-water nexus research, development, and demonstration activities.

In addition, DOE must establish and carry out a smart energy and water efficiency management pilot program. Under the program, DOE must award grants to water authorities (i.e., authorities that provide water, wastewater, or water reuse services) for demonstrating unique, advanced, or innovative technology-based solutions that will

 improve the net energy balance of water, wastewater, and water reuse systems; support the implementation of innovative and unique processes and the installation of established, advanced automated systems that provide real-time data on energy and water; and improve energy-water conservation and quality and predictive maintenance through technologies that utilize internet-connected technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-198</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
