<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="536" updated="2022-02-03T05:35:18Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3132" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-09-14T13:50:17-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-09-14"/>
  <description>At the end of the Title V, add the following new section: \   SEC. __. SENSE OF CONGRESS. \   It is the sense of Congress that background checks conducted as a precondition to approval of any foster or adoptive placement of children affected by a natural disaster or terrorist attack should be expedited in order to ensure that such children do not become subjected to the offenses enumerated in this act.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 31 printed in the Congressional Record to express the sense of Congress that background checks conducted as a precondition to approval of any foster or adoptive placement of children affected by a natural disaster or terrorist attack should be expedited in order to ensure that such children do not become subjected to the offenses enumerated in the Children's Safety Act.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-09-14T13:50:17-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A017) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T13:47:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A017) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7911-7912" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7911" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T13:47:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A017) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7911-7912" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7911" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T13:50:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A017) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14T13:50:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
