<bill session="112" type="h" number="2670" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:42Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jobs for Americans Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that States and local governments may pass laws that identify illegal aliens, deter illegal aliens from entering the United States, apprehend illegal aliens, or encourage or otherwise cause illegal aliens to leave the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs for Americans Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2011-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2011-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2011-08-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2011-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-10-05T17:08:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Jobs for Americans Act of 2011 - Authorizes states and their political subdivisions to enact and enforce laws that help identify illegal aliens, deter illegal aliens from entering the United States, apprehend illegal aliens, or encourage or cause illegal aliens to leave the United States.

Prohibits states and their political subdivisions from enacting or enforcing laws that are inconsistent with federal statutes that define the lawful status of persons who are in the United States.

Prohibits any law from preempting any state or local law imposing civil or criminal sanctions upon persons who knowingly aid or abet, in any way, the presence of an illegal alien within the borders of the United States.

Exempts from civil and criminal liability any person or entity for taking an action or failing to take an action that was undertaken in good faith to comply with the law.

 Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act regarding the unlawful employment of aliens to prohibit any law from preempting any state or local law imposing civil or criminal sanctions upon persons who knowingly employ, recruit, or refer for a fee an unauthorized alien.</summary>
</bill>
