<bill session="109" type="s" number="3664" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:29Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Improvements Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to improve assistance after a major disaster, to authorize emergency bridge loans, bridge loan guarantees, and recovery grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Improvements Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2006-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7556-7557"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7557-7560" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-12T21:16:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Disaster Recovery Assistance Improvements Act of 2006 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make both emergency bridge loans and business recovery grants to a qualified small business concern after major disasters, and to provide assistance until the concern is able to obtain funding through insurance claims, other federal assistance programs, or other sources.







Authorizes the Administrator to: (1) guarantee loans made under an approved State Bridge Loan Program; and (2) make loans under expedited procedures that include loss verification and loan processing.

Sets forth maximum disaster loan amounts.

Doubles the minimum size of loans for which collateral must be required.

Directs the Administrator to hire a full-time disaster planning specialist in the Office of Disaster Assistance.

Provides for economic injury disaster loans to private non-profit organizations.

Authorizes the Administrator, in the event of a major disaster, to waive the maximum $100,000 amount for small business development center portability grants. Makes such grants available for small business development centers assisting small business concerns adversely affected by the disaster.

Directs the Administrator to authorize a small business development center, regardless of location, to provide advice, information, and assistance to a small business concern located in a major disaster area.</summary>
</bill>
