<bill session="117" type="h" number="6097" updated="2022-12-30T08:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indigenous Peoples Exchange and Economic Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indigenous Peoples Exchange and Economic Cooperation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate contacts and cooperation, including commercial relationships, between Native American Tribes and Indigenous peoples in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2022-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2021-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere, Civilian Security, Migration and International Economic Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-26T15:58:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Indigenous Peoples Exchange and Economic Cooperation Act

This bill requires certain agencies to facilitate contacts and cooperation between federally recognized tribes and Indigenous peoples of other countries in the Western Hemisphere.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Commerce, in coordination with the Department of the Interior, to submit a strategy to Congress. The strategy must promote and facilitate (1) cross-investments and export opportunities between tribes and Indigenous peoples in tribal businesses and commercial enterprises that involve Indigenous peoples, and (2) the development of supply chains for U.S. entities that include certified products produced by tribes and Indigenous peoples.

Additionally, the Inter-American Foundation, the Department of State, the U.S. Agency for International Development, and the Millennium Challenge Corporation must (1) consult with representatives of civil society organizations, especially organizations comprised of or representing the interests of Indigenous peoples; and (2) provide assistance to Western Hemisphere countries that promotes and facilitates entrepreneurship among Indigenous peoples.</summary>
</bill>
