<bill session="108" type="s" number="192" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">John's Law of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for criminal and civil liability for permitting an intoxicated arrestee to operate a motor vehicle.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John's Law of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1082-1083"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S1083" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Driver licenses"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">John's Law of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to withhold specified Federal highway funds from a State that fails to enact and enforce a law that requires: (1) an agency to provide an individual summoned to transport or accompany a person who has been arrested for public intoxication with a written statement advising that individual of his or her potential criminal and civil liability for permitting or facilitating the arrestee's operation of a motor vehicle while the arrestee remains intoxicated; and (2) a law enforcement agency to impound the vehicle of a person arrested for public intoxication for a period of 12 hours or until such later time as the person is able to operate the vehicle in a safe manner and not in violation of driving while intoxicated laws.Allows withheld funds to: (1) remain available for apportionment to the State (once it meets Act requirements) for four years; (2) remain available for expenditure for three fiscal years after apportionment; and (3) be redistributed to other States if the originally targeted State is not in compliance, or the funds are not obligated for expenditure, within such periods.</summary>
</bill>
