<bill session="116" type="s" number="2266" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Group Flood Insurance Policy Extension Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Group Flood Insurance Policy Extension Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend group flood insurance policy assistance for victims of the 2016 West Virginia floods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-24T20:03:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Group Flood Insurance Policy Extension Act of 2019 

This bill extends the term of certain existing Group Flood Insurance Policies. Specifically, the term is extended for active policies awaiting funds from the Department of Housing and Urban Development's Community Development Block Grant-Disaster Recovery fund. (Group Flood Insurance Policies are offered through the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to certain individuals who do not have flood insurance and have received FEMA assistance after a presidentially declared disaster.)

FEMA must provide financial assistance to individuals with extended-term policies in the amount of the additional required premium.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the costs and benefits of Group Flood Insurance Policies and the rate at which individuals purchase private policies after the term of these policies expire.</summary>
</bill>
