<bill session="116" type="h" number="3909" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Adopted Children and Families Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend subpart 2 of part B of title IV of the Social Security Act to authorize grants to eligible entities to develop and implement statewide or tribal post-adoption and post-legal guardianship mental health service programs for all children who are adopted or placed in legal guardianship, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Adopted Children and Families Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2019-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2019-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2019-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Worker and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1450" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-18T15:31:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Adopted Children and Families Act of 2019 This bill requires the Administration for Children and Families (ACF) to award grants to states for post-adoption and post-legal guardianship mental health services. Specifically, grants may be used to implement statewide direct service programs such as educational support or counseling to aid adoptive parents and families in addressing common behavioral health issues among adopted children. Grants also may be used for activities such as peer-to-peer mentoring, crisis intervention, program evaluation, policy development, and research, among others uses. The ACF must grant only one awards per state, or state-designated entity, and preference must be given to eligible entities that partner with a state's mental health agency and have demonstrated success at increasing adoption and legal guardianship competency.</summary>
</bill>
