<bill session="116" type="h" number="7406" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Licensing Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline nuclear technology regulatory permitting and licensing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Licensing Efficiency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2020-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-23T17:59:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Nuclear Licensing Efficiency Act

This bill revises the permitting and licensing process for nuclear production or utilization facilities.

The Nuclear Regulatory Commission must follow specified procedures when reviewing an application for an early site permit, construction permit, operating license, or combined construction permit and operating license for a nuclear production or utilization facility.

The Government Accountability Office must study and report on the effects of eliminating mandatory hearings for uncontested licensing and construction permit applications under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.

The bill revises the composition of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards, and provides specific timelines for the committee to complete its review for a construction permit or an operating license for a nuclear facility.

The bill also places a limit on the amount of annual fees that may be charged to a nuclear fuel facility, with specified exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
