<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="472" updated="2022-02-25T17:32:27Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2112" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-06-16T10:08:07-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before any short title), insert the following new section:    SEC. __. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to provide (or to pay the salaries and expenses of personnel to provide) to upland cotton producers counter-cyclical payments for upland cotton under section 1104 of the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 (7 U.S.C. 8714), repayment rates for marketing assistance loans under section 1204(b) of such Act (7 U.S.C. 8734(b)) at the prevailing world market price for upland cotton, cotton storage benefits under section 1204(g) of such Act (7 U.S.C. 8734(g)), or loan deficiency payments for upland cotton under section 1205 of such Act (7 U.S.C. 8735).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to provide to upland cotton producers counter-cyclical payments for upland cotton, repayment rates for marketing assistance loans at the prevailing world market price for upland cotton, or loan deficiency payments for upland cotton.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-06-16T10:08:07-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A054) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T09:42:52-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A054) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4286-4288" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4286" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T10:08:07-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T09:42:52-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A054) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4286-4288" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4286" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16T10:08:07-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A054) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
