<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>882</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:54:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T05:54:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-04T18:47:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sherrod</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Drug trafficking and controlled substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug, alcohol, tobacco use</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prescription drugs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-06-17T19:26:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Stop Trafficking of Pills Act or STOP Act - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require state Medicaid plans to: (1) identify prescription drugs that present a high-risk of misuse or overutilization, (2) establish a dosage level for each such drug that would be deemed excessive in the absence of evidence of medical necessity, (3) identify Medicaid-eligible individuals who are either receiving a prescription drug at excessive dosage levels or who have been convicted of a drug-related offense, and (4) ensure that they are assigned to a state-established restricted recipient program.</p> <p>Requires a state to establish a Medicaid Lock-in Program to ensure that a high-risk prescription drug user is assigned to: (1) a single and exclusive physician for purposes of receiving any medical assistance related to a prescription drug, and (2) a single and exclusive pharmacy to receive any physician-prescribed drug.</p> <p>Requires a state to establish a Medicaid prescription drug restriction program to ensure that the state claims processing system does not permit a prescription drug to be dispensed to a high-risk prescription drug user more than once every 20 days.</p> <p>Amends part D (Miscellaneous) of SSA title XXVIII (Medicare) to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a similar restricted recipient program for high-risk prescription drug users under the Medicare program. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>STOP Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>STOP Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Stop Trafficking of Pills Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>STOP Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to prevent misuse, overutilization, and trafficking of prescription drugs by limiting access to such drugs for Medicare and Medicaid beneficiaries who have been identified as high-risk prescription drug users.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-04T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s882is/xml/BILLS-112s882is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-05-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
