<bill session="118" type="s" number="962" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Voices of Freedom Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Voices of Freedom Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect individuals who face reprisals for defending human rights and democracy by enhancing the capacity of the United States Government to prevent, mitigate, and respond in such cases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-31T20:48:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Global Voices of Freedom Act of 2023

This bill requires certain actions to support and protect human rights defenders, defined in the bill as individuals who use nonviolent means to promote or protect human rights and fundamental freedoms.

The bill requires the President to develop a comprehensive interagency strategy to support and protect human rights defenders abroad.

The Department of State and the U.S. Permanent Representative to the United Nations must use their voice, vote, and influence to protect human rights defenders at the United Nations and other multilateral bodies (for example, by opposing efforts to block the accreditation of bona fide human right organizations at these institutions).

Additionally, the State Department must provide training to certain Foreign Service Officers and presidential appointees on support for human rights defenders.</summary>
</bill>
