<bill session="117" type="s" number="3713" updated="2022-12-29T21:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reproductive Choice Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reproductive Choice Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to codify the essential holdings of Roe v. Wade (410 U.S. 113 (1973)) and Planned Parenthood of Southeastern Pennsylvania v. Casey (505 U.S. 833 (1992)).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2022-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S838" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-31T19:49:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reproductive Choice Act

This bill provides statutory authority for certain Supreme Court holdings on abortion rights and restrictions in the cases of Roe v. Wade and Planned Parenthood of Southeastern Pennsylvania v. Casey.

In Roe, the Court held that the Constitution protects a woman's decision to terminate her pregnancy. In Casey, the Court reaffirmed this holding and additionally held that state abortion regulations may not place a substantial obstacle in the path of a woman seeking an abortion before fetal viability (i.e., an undue burden). However, a state may (1) restrict abortions after viability, except when a pregnancy endangers the life or health of the woman; and (2) enact regulations to further the health or safety of a woman seeking an abortion, except for unnecessary health regulations that present a substantial obstacle to a woman seeking an abortion.

The bill provides statutory authority for these holdings. It also specifies that the bill does not affect laws regarding conscience protection.</summary>
</bill>
