<bill session="118" type="s" number="3625" updated="2025-11-19T03:38:51Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Small Business and Prevent Illicit Financial Activity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Small Business and Prevent Illicit Financial Activity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to provide small businesses with additional time to file beneficial ownership information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2024-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2024-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2024-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5119" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-21T23:03:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Small Business and Prevent Illicit Financial Activity Act

This bill revises the requirements for small U.S. companies to report certain beneficial ownership information that take effect on January 1, 2024. Beneficial ownership information includes the identity of an individual behind a corporate entity.

The bill extends the deadline for companies to report ownership information to the Department of the Treasury's Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN). Specifically, existing companies must file their initial ownership report within two years (current regulations require the report within one year). New companies must file their initial ownership report within 90 days (current regulations require the report within 30 days). Companies must report updates or changes in ownership within 90 days (current regulations require companies to report such changes within 30 days).</summary>
</bill>
