<bill session="118" type="h" number="3586" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Transportation Funding Equality Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Transportation Funding Equality Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to treat the District of Columbia as a State for purposes of certain grant programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E472-473"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-30T17:35:21Z" status="Introduced in House">District of Columbia Transportation Funding Equality Act

This bill treats the District of Columbia as a state with respect to certain Department of Transportation (DOT) grant programs.

Specifically, the bill applies to the Bus and Bus Facilities Grant Program, which provides funding for capital expenses to purchase and rehabilitate buses and to construct bus-related facilities. Currently, the District is treated as a territory under the program.

The bill also treats the District as a state under two additional DOT programs. The National Culvert Removal, Replacement, and Restoration Grant Program provides competitive grants to eligible entities for projects that meaningfully improve or restore fish passage for certain types of fish. The Safe Streets and Roads for All grant program supports initiatives to prevent roadway deaths and serious injuries. Currently, the District is not included under either of these programs.

Further, the bill treats the District as a state for purposes of the Growing States and High Density States Formula, which provides additional money to some places (e.g., states with a population density greater than 370 persons per square mile) and is distributed through the Urbanized and Rural Area Formula Programs. Currently, the District is not included under the formula.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
