<bill session="117" type="s" number="1663" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Postal Service Shipping Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, and title 39, United States Code, to provide the United States Postal Service the authority to mail alcoholic beverages, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Postal Service Shipping Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2021-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2022-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2021-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3287" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-13T18:10:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Postal Service Shipping Equity Act

This bill authorizes the mailing of alcoholic beverages by certain entities in accordance with the delivery requirements otherwise applicable to a privately carried shipment. The authorization applies to an entity (including a winery, brewery, beverage distilled spirits plant, or other wholesaler, distributer, importer, or retailer of alcoholic beverages) that has registered with, obtained a permit from, or obtained approval of an application from the Department of the Treasury.

The bill directs the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to prescribe regulations (1) requiring direct delivery to a duly authorized agent at a postal facility or to the addressee, who must be at least 21 years of age and present a valid, government-issued photo identification at the time of delivery; (2) prohibiting such alcoholic beverages from being for resale or any other commercial purpose; and (3) requiring such entity to certify that the mailing is not in violation of applicable laws or regulations and to provide other information as directed by the USPS.

A state, local, or tribal government may bring a civil action against the USPS in U.S. district court for a violation of a law of the state, locality, or tribe regarding the sale, mailing, transportation, or importation of alcoholic beverages. The USPS shall be liable to the same extent as a private individual under like circumstances but shall not be liable for interest prior to judgment or for punitive damages.</summary>
</bill>
