<bill session="108" type="s" number="2481" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Increasing Notice of Foreign Outsourcing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that notices to consumers of health and financial services include information on the outsourcing of sensitive personal information abroad, to require relevant Federal agencies to prescribe regulations to ensure the privacy and security of sensitive personal information outsourced abroad, to establish requirements for foreign call centers, and for purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Notice of Foreign Outsourcing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2004-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6275-6276"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6276-6278" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2472" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contractors"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care industry"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-04T18:30:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increasing Notice of Foreign Outsourcing Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to issue regulations requiring covered entities under the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 that outsource protected health information to foreign-based business associates to include in their notice of privacy protections: (1) notification of outsourcing; (2) any risks and consequences to the privacy and security of such information resulting from outsourcing; (3) additional measures the covered entity is taking to protect outsourced protected health information; and (4) certification that the covered entity has taken reasonable steps to ensure that the handling of such information will comport with applicable laws.

Amends the Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act to impose similar requirements on financial institutions that outsource nonpublic personal information to foreign-based businesses.

Directs the Secretary of HHS, with regard to protected health information outsourced by covered entities, and the Federal banking agencies, National Credit Union Administration, Secretary of the Treasury, Securities and Exchange Commission, and Federal Trade Commission, with regard to nonpublic personal information outsourced by financial institutions, to issue regulations requiring: (1) outsourcing contracts with foreign-based businesses to contain audit provisions; and (2) such businesses and subcontractors to be contractually bound by Federal privacy standards and security safeguards.

Establishes notification procedures in the event of a breach of database security involving protected health or nonpublic personal information.

Requires contracts with foreign call centers to include a provision requiring call center employees to disclose their physical location upon request. Imposes civil penalties for violators.</summary>
</bill>
