<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="826" updated="2022-02-03T06:02:00Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2250" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-10-11T19:22:44-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-10-11"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill, add the following section:    SEC. 6. PROTECTION FROM RESPIRATORY AND CARDIOVASCULAR ILLNESS AND DEATH.    Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Administrator shall not delay actions pursuant to the rules identified in section 2(b) of this Act to reduce emissions from waste incinerators or industrial boilers at chemical facilities, oil refineries, or large manufacturing facilities if such emissions are causing respiratory and cardiovascular illnesses and deaths, including cases of heart attacks, asthma attacks, and bronchitis.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment umbered 18 printed in the Congressional Record to add a section which directs the EPA Administrator to implement the rules included in this Act to reduce emissions from waste incinerators or industrial boilers at chemical facilities, oil refineries, or large manufacturing facilities if such emissions are causing respiratory and cardiovascular illness and deaths, including cases of heart attacks, asthma attacks, and bronchitis.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-10-11T19:22:44-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="773">
      <text>On agreeing to the Connolly (VA) amendment (A007) Failed by recorded vote: 168 - 250 (Roll no. 773).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:46:24-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Connolly (VA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6699-6700, H6722-6723" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6699" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:22:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Connolly (VA) amendment (A007) Failed by recorded vote: 168 - 250 (Roll no. 773).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:46:24-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Connolly (VA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6699-6700, H6722-6723" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6699" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
