<bill session="118" type="h" number="8023" updated="2025-01-16T11:48:07Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Seniors from Emergency Scams Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Seniors from Emergency Scams Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Trade Commission to include in the report of the Commission under the Elder Abuse Prevention and Prosecution Act certain information relating to scams disproportionately impacting seniors during emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2024-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2024-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2024-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001223" joined="2024-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-24T18:53:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Seniors from Emergency Scams ActThis bill requires the Federal Trade Commission to report on, and increase awareness regarding, scams disproportionately impacting older adults. Specifically, the commission must

report on the number and types of scams that disproportionately impact&#160;older adults during emergencies, report on the enforcement actions taken with respect to such scams, and provide policy recommendations to prevent such scams;revise the commission's web portal to include current information about scams that disproportionately impact older adults, including information about how consumers can report such scams; andcoordinate with media outlets and law enforcement to disseminate such information.</summary>
</bill>
