<bill session="116" type="h" number="5615" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TREES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to assist retail power providers with the establishment and operation of energy conservation programs using targeted residential tree-planting programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Residential Energy and Economic Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TREES Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2020-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2020-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2020-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-29T18:10:27Z" status="Introduced in House">The Residential Energy and Economic Savings Act or the TREES Act

This bill provides incentives for retail power providers or cities to plant trees to reduce energy costs.

Specifically, the Department of Energy (DOE) must establish a program to award grants to retail power providers that partner with nonprofit tree-planting organizations to establish or continue operating tree-planting programs. Under the program, retail power providers must give residential consumers free or discounted trees that provide maximum amounts of shade during the summer or wind protection during the fall and winter. Retail power providers include entities that generate, distribute, or provide retail electricity, natural gas, or fuel oil service.

In addition, DOE must annually give an award that designates communities or other areas as the Arbor City of America. The award must recognize communities for superior efforts in increasing tree canopy coverage and assisting residents in reducing energy costs. DOE must give award recipients funding for green infrastructure or green spaces.</summary>
</bill>
