<bill session="108" type="h" number="1768" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:04Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-24T12:48:46-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-24T12:48:46-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Multidistrict Litigation Restoration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to allow a judge to whom a case is transferred to retain jurisdiction over certain multidistrict litigation cases for trial, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Multidistrict Litigation Restoration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Multidistrict Litigation Restoration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Multidistrict Litigation Restoration Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2003-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2003-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 108-416.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-02-10" calendar="Union" number="239">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 239.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T10:29:46-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T10:30:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1377-1379" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T10:30:09-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1768.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T10:38:16-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T12:41:21-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1395" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="79" datetime="2004-03-24T12:48:46-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 418 - 0 (Roll no. 79).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1377" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T12:48:47-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Change of venue"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial districts"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Multidistrict Litigation Restoration Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal judicial code to allow a civil action transferred for coordinated or consolidated pretrial proceedings (multidistrict litigation) to be transferred to the transferee or other district for trial purposes in the interest of justice and for the convenience of the parties and witnesses. Directs that any such action transferred for trial purposes be remanded to the district court from which it was transferred for the determination of compensatory damages unless the court determines the same justification applies to retaining the action for damages determination.Provides that, in actions transferred when jurisdiction is or could have been based on the Multiparty, Multiforum Trial Jurisdiction Act of 2002 (granting district courts original jurisdiction of any civil action involving minimal diversity between adverse parties that arises from a single accident, where at least 75 natural persons have died in the accident at a discrete location), the transferee court may retain actions so transferred for the determination of liability and punitive damages. Directs that an action retained for the determination of liability be remanded to the district court from which the action was transferred, or to the State court from which the action was removed, for the determination of damages other than punitive damages, unless the court finds, for the convenience of parties and witnesses and in the interest of justice, that the action should be retained for the determination of damages. Modifies the definition of "accident" under that Act to mean specified events resulting in death incurred at a discrete location by at least 25 (currently, 75) natural persons.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-416</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
