<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>361</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:20:27Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:20:27Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-02-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-02-16T16:05:19Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to authorize the application of State law with respect to vehicle weight limitations on the Interstate Highway System in the States of Maine and Vermont.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>112</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-16</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S793-796)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-02-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Collins, Susan M. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Susan</firstName>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Commerce</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Agricultural conservation and pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Budget process</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Business investment and capital</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment and training programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment taxes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy efficiency and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax credits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax deductions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maine</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Manufacturing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military facilities and property</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor carriers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor fuels</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sales and excise taxes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tariffs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax administration and collection, taxpayers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Vermont</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Commerce</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-02-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-04-26T12:32:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Seven Point Plan for Growing Jobs Act - Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish a Manufacturing Job Training National Program and make grants to state governors and agencies with responsibility for labor programs to plan and develop a new program of employment and training activities that targets the specific needs of manufacturers. </p> <p>Amends the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary to provide workplace development and economic assistance to eligible recipients affected by the base realignment and closure (BRAC) activities established by the Secretary of Defense (DOD) in 2005.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to review job training programs to identify ways to increase efficiency and reduce duplicative and unnecessary processes and activities in such programs.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) carry out an offshore wind energy research and deployment program, and (2) award grants to institutions of higher education to establish one or more national offshore wind centers.</p> <p>Amends the Tax Relief, Unemployment Insurance Reauthorization, and Job Creation Act of 2010 to extend reductions in the employment tax to employers and certain self-employed individuals. </p> <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) make permanent accelerated depreciation for qualified leasehold and restaurant buildings and improvements, nonresidential real property and residential rental property, and increased depreciation and expensing allowances for business and investment property; (2) extend through 2016 the tax credit for increasing research activities; (3) increase the rate of the alternative simplified research tax credit; (4) repeal provisions added by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that require reporting of payments made to corporations of $600 or more; and (5) eliminate the tax credit for ethanol used as fuel.</p> <p>Imposes new requirements on federal agencies relating to regulatory actions. Allows a reduction or waiver of civil penalties on small entities for failures to comply with regulatory requirements.</p> <p>Extends to all portions of the Interstate Highway System in Maine and Vermont the application of vehicle weight limit laws and regulations of those states in lieu of federal vehicle weight limits.</p> <p> Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to eliminate the additional tariff on ethanol and ethanol fuel mixtures.</p> <p>Prohibits the consideration by Congress of any legislation that would cause discretionary spending limits to exceed levels specified for FY2012-FY2014.</p> <p>Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to impose limits on farm subsidies based upon the adjusted gross income of the recipient.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Seven Point Plan for Growing Jobs Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Seven Point Plan for Growing Jobs Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Seven Point Plan for Growing Jobs Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-02-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s361is/xml/BILLS-112s361is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-02-16</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
