<bill session="116" type="h" number="5968" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to increase participation in community solar and the receipt of associated benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2020-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-04T13:32:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Solar Consumer Choice Act of 2020

This bill supports the expansion of community solar energy and doubles the allowable time period for a long-term contract between the General Services Administration (GSA) and a public utility.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program for expanding community solar energy options, including options for low-income and moderate-income individuals. In addition, DOE must expand existing grant, loan, and financing programs to include community solar projects as specified by the bill.

Further, the bill revises requirements for electric utilities, including by requiring each electric utility to offer a community solar program.

Finally, the bill allows the GSA to make a public utility contract for a period of up to 20 years. Currently, the GSA may make a public utility contract for up to 10 years.</summary>
</bill>
