<bill session="108" type="s" number="1993" updated="2023-01-15T09:17:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Highway Safety Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to provide a highway safety improvement program that includes incentives to States to enact primary safety belt laws.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Highway Safety Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2004-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2004-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16128-16130"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16130-16132" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Bicycles"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Seat belts"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-02T20:05:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Highway Safety Act of 2003 - Requires the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a highway safety improvement program to reduce traffic fatalities and serious injuries on public roads.

 Requires a State, to receive funds under this Act, to have in effect a highway safety improvement program under which the State: (1) develops and implements a strategic highway safety plan that identifies and analyzes highway safety problems and opportunities; (2) produces a program of projects or strategies to reduce identified safety problems; and (3) evaluates the plan regularly to ensure the accuracy of the data and the priority of proposed improvements.

Sets forth provisions regarding State plan requirements, eligible projects, and the Federal share. Provides for a reduction of funds to a State that fails to have in effect a primary safety belt law or that fails to demonstrate that the safety belt use rate in the State is at least 90 percent. Provides for a restoration of funds if, within three years, the State meets those requirements. Provides for reallocation of apportioned funds.

Sets formulas for apportionment of highway safety improvement program funds.

Requires at least $200 million of funds authorized and expended under this Act be available each fiscal year for the elimination of hazards and the installation of protective devices at railway-highway crossings.</summary>
</bill>
