<bill session="116" type="s" number="4662" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Law Enforcement Officers Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Penalizing Radicals and Others who Thwart Emergency Care and Transportation for Law Enforcement Officers Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Law Enforcement Officers Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to criminalize blocking law enforcement officers who have been injured by a criminal act or in the line of duty from accessing emergency medical services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-09T15:50:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Penalizing Radicals and Others who Thwart Emergency Care and Transportation for Law Enforcement Officers Act of 2020 or the PROTECT Law Enforcement Officers Act of 2020

This bill establishes a new criminal offense for preventing or attempting to prevent a law enforcement officer from accessing emergency medical services for an injury caused by a criminal act or incurred in the line of duty.

An individual who engages in this conduct is subject to criminal penalties--a fine, a prison term of up to 20 years, or both. If death results, the prison term may be for a term of any years or for life.

In a prosecution of this offense, the government is not required to prove that the defendant knew the law enforcement officer suffered an injury caused by a criminal act or incurred in the line of duty.</summary>
</bill>
