<bill session="119" type="s" number="363" updated="2025-06-11T16:46:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP MADNESS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stifling Transnational Operations and Proliferators by Mitigating Activities that Drive Narcotics, Exploitation, and Smuggling Sanctions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP MADNESS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to foreign governments that resist efforts to repatriate their citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States and foreign governments and foreign persons that knowingly facilitate unlawful immigration into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001242" joined="2025-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-11T16:44:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stifling Transnational Operations and Proliferators by Mitigating Activities that Drive Narcotics, Exploitation, and Smuggling Sanctions Act or the STOP MADNESS Act

This bill allows the President to impose sanctions on (1) foreign governments the President determines knowingly refuse or obstruct U.S. efforts to repatriate its citizens who have unlawfully entered the United States, and (2) foreign governments or foreign persons the President determines knowingly facilitate unlawful immigration into the United States.

The President may waive sanctions if the President determines that it is in the national security interest of the United States.

If a person violates this bill, criminal and civil penalties applicable to violations of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (IEEPA) apply.

To carry out the bill, the President may exercise authorities under the&#160;IEEPA.</summary>
</bill>
