<bill session="117" type="h" number="3091" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:52Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cherokee Nation and Chickasaw Nation Criminal Jurisdiction Compacting Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support clarity and consistency with regard to the exercise of criminal jurisdiction and authority in Indian country, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cherokee Nation and Chickasaw Nation Criminal Jurisdiction Compacting Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-10T17:01:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Cherokee Nation and Chickasaw Nation Criminal Jurisdiction Compacting Act of 2021

This bill authorizes the Cherokee Nation and the Chickasaw Nation to each enter into intergovernmental compacts with Oklahoma for the state to exercise its criminal jurisdiction within Indian country.

The bill outlines the requirements for such compacts, including that they must define the categories of criminal offenders or offenses within the reservation over which Oklahoma may exercise its jurisdiction.

The Department of Justice must, upon the request of a nation, consult with and provide technical assistance for developing or implementing a compact.

A nation may require an offender who is sentenced to a term of imprisonment of more than six months to serve such a sentence in the nearest appropriate federal facility.

The Department of the Interior must publish a compact that it receives from a nation. Interior must also report on the development and implementation of compacts and make recommendations to support and enhance the criminal justice system of each nation.</summary>
</bill>
