<bill session="117" type="h" number="8838" updated="2023-02-06T17:30:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguard Healthcare Industry Employees from Litigation and Distress Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect health care providers and people seeking reproductive health care services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000396" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2022-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7869"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8105-8106"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-04T18:37:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguard Healthcare Industry Employees from Litigation and Distress Act or the SHIELD Act

This bill establishes a framework to limit interference with persons seeking to provide or access reproductive health services at the state level.

For the purposes of this summary, interference with persons seeking to provide or access reproductive health services includes acts to prevent, restrict, impede, or retaliate against

 a health care provider who provides reproductive health care services, any person or entity who helps health care providers to provide such services, any person who seeks to access such services, or any person or entity who helps another person to access such services. First, the bill reduces the allocation of funds under certain law enforcement grant programs for a state that has in effect a law authorizing state or local officers or employees to interfere with persons seeking to provide or access reproductive health services.

Second, the bill prohibits interference with persons seeking to provide or access reproductive health care services

 by state or local officers or employees acting under color of law in any manner that would have a discriminatory effect on a woman, and by persons who are not state or local officers or employees and are attempting to implement or enforce a state law in circumstances affecting interstate commerce. The bill authorizes civil remedies for a violation, including damages and injunctive relief. Additionally, it authorizes criminal penalties for a violation involving the use of a deadly or dangerous weapon or the infliction of bodily injury.</summary>
</bill>
