<bill session="116" type="s" number="166" updated="2022-11-01T14:17:31Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide provisional protected presence status for certain aliens and to provide mandatory appropriations relating to border security.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide provisional protected presence status for certain aliens and to provide mandatory appropriations relating to border security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-05T14:57:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides for protected presence status for certain types of aliens and mandatory appropriations for immigration enforcement.

The Department of Homeland Security shall grant provisional protected presence status to a qualified alien who applies for such status, which prevents removal from the United States and provides employment authorization. Such status shall be effective for three years from the bill's enactment.

To qualify for such status, the alien shall be a Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals (DACA) recipient who was born after June 15, 1981, and entered the United States before age 16. The bill imposes other requirements, including enrolling in or having completed various types of schooling or military service.

The bill also provides for renewable provisional protected presence status for aliens who had temporary protected status or deferred enforced departure status on or before October 1, 2017. Renewable provisional protected presence status shall be granted for three years upon a successful application and is renewable indefinitely.

Both types of protected presence status are limited to aliens who have not been convicted of various crimes, do not pose a threat to national security, and have been physically present in the country for a certain amount of time.</summary>
</bill>
