<bill session="117" type="h" number="5636" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for naturalization processes for the immediate relatives of public safety officers who die as a result of their employment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Kerrie Orozco First Responders Family Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kerrie Orozco First Responders Family Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-29T21:21:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Kerrie Orozco First Responders Family Support Act

This bill establishes that a surviving spouse, child, or parent of a U.S. citizen public safety officer may be naturalized at the time of the officer's death if the death was caused by an injury incurred or aggravated by the officer's employment. The individual may be naturalized upon meeting the relevant immigration law requirements, except that no prior residence or specified U.S. physical presence shall be required. A surviving spouse seeking naturalization must have been living in marital union with the officer at the time of death.

Public safety officers include law enforcement officers, firefighters, or chaplains, and certain Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) employees engaged in hazardous duties.</summary>
</bill>
