<bill session="118" type="s" number="1869" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SITE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SITE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Site-based Invoicing and Transparency Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act and title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to ensure fair billing practice for items and services furnished by off-campus hospital locations, to amend such title XVIII to provide for payments for graduate nursing education costs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-01T21:01:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Site-based Invoicing and Transparency Enhancement Act or the SITE Act&#160;

This bill modifies the payment methodology for services that are furnished at off-campus outpatient departments of hospitals under Medicare. It also establishes a nurse training program through hospitals.

Under current law, off-campus outpatient departments of hospitals that began billing prior to November 2, 2015, or that were under construction as of that date, are exempt from certain site-neutral payment requirements under Medicare. The bill ends this exemption. It&#160;also (1) reduces payments for services furnished at off-campus outpatient emergency departments that are six or fewer miles from a hospital, and (2) requires off-campus outpatient departments of hospitals to have unique health identifiers.

Additionally, the bill provides for funding of regional nurse education hubs. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services may select one hospital in each referral region to operate as a hub for training, in coordination with nursing schools, Medicare and Medicaid providers, and other training partners. The bill provides for up to 20,000 nursing student positions in the program by 2030.</summary>
</bill>
