<bill session="111" type="h" number="2901" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Coast Guard Servicemember Benefits Improvements Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 14, United States Code, to improve benefits for members of the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Coast Guard Servicemember Benefits Improvements Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000554"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001045" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000074" joined="2009-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-29T20:25:48Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Coast Guard Servicemember Benefits Improvements Act - Establishes or modifies the housing-related authorities of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating regarding: (1) reconstruction and maintenance of military family housing or unaccompanied housing; (2) conveyance or lease of real property; and (3) the Coast Guard Housing Fund.

Repeals the $40 million cap on the total value in budget authority of all contracts and investments undertaken using Coast Guard housing authorities. Repeals the expiration date for such authorities, thus making them permanent.

Eliminates specified new housing demonstration projects.

Authorizes the Coast Guard Commandant to: (1) use appropriated funds to provide child development services; and (2) collect and expend, for such services, fees based on family income.

Raises from 62 to 64 the mandatory retirement age for flag officers. Allows deferral of the mandatory retirement age of any regular commissioned officer serving in a flag officer grade position (currently 62): (1) by the Secretary until age 66; and (2) by the President until age 68.

Authorizes the Secretary of the Navy to: (1) detail Chaplain Corps personnel to the Coast Guard; and (2) provide support services (including transportation, food, lodging, child care, supplies, fees, and training materials) to chaplain-led programs to assist members of the Coast Guard on active duty and their dependents, and members of the reserve component in an active status and their dependents, in building and maintaining a strong family structure.

Authorizes the President to award a Coast Guard cross and silver star medals to persons serving in any capacity with the Coast Guard for extraordinary heroism or gallantry in action while engaged in action against a U.S. enemy, or in other specified actions.

Removes provisions excluding the Coast Guard from provisions relating to Armed Forces Retirement homes. (Authorizes Coast Guard participation in the Armed Forces Retirement Home system.)

Authorizes the Secretary of Homeland Security, subject to the availability of legal staff resources, to provide to members of Coast Guard reserve components legal assistance in connection with their personal civil legal affairs.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to require that, during a public health emergency, Coast Guard members and assets remain under the command and control of the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</summary>
</bill>
