<bill session="116" type="s" number="3959" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:15Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Civil Aviation Authority Assistance Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Civil Aviation Authority Assistance Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to provide assistance for foreign civil aviation authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2020-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-04T15:33:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Foreign Civil Aviation Authority Assistance Act of 2020

This bill provides Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) support for foreign civil aviation authorities.

In addition to the current requirement that the FAA promote and achieve global improvements in the safety, efficiency, and environmental effect of air travel, the bill requires the FAA to engage both bilaterally and multilaterally, including with the International Civil Aviation Organization, to bolster international collaboration, data sharing, and harmonization of international aviation safety requirements.

The FAA must seek to expand technical assistance in support of enhancing international aviation safety, and it is authorized to provide technical assistance related to all aviation safety-related training and operational services in connection with bilateral and multilateral agreements.

The bill also authorizes support for the implementation of certain recommendations to address pilots' dependency on automation.</summary>
</bill>
