<bill session="117" type="h" number="8764" updated="2023-08-11T17:00:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LIHEAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LIHEAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lowering Inflated Heating, Energy, and Air Conditioning Prices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To change certain household income eligibility requirements for low-income home energy assistance in fiscal years 2023 and 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000614"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-11T16:54:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Lowering Inflated Heating, Energy, and Air Conditioning Prices Act or the LIHEAP Act

This bill increases for FY2023-FY2024 the federal income eligibility threshold for the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Program, which provides federal grants to states, tribes, and territories to assist low-income households pay for heating and cooling costs.

Currently, households are eligible with incomes at or below 150% of the poverty rate or 60% of the median income of their applicable state, tribe, or territory. This bill permits payments to households with incomes that are 75% of the applicable median income.</summary>
</bill>
