<bill session="116" type="h" number="5332" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:04Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-29T18:39:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-06-29T18:39:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to ensure that consumer reporting agencies are providing fair and accurate information reporting in consumer reports, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2019-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 116-416.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-03-12" calendar="Union" number="335">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 335.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-06-24T19:02:39-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1017 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1425, H.R. 5332, H.R. 7120, H.R. 7301 and H.J. Res. 90. The resolution provides that the provisions of section 125(c) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall not apply during the remainder of the 116th Congress and the resolution amends H.Res. 967, agreed to on May 15, 2020.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26T15:19:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1017.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2559-2571" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26T15:19:32-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1425, H.R. 5332, H.R. 7120, H.R. 7301 and H.J. Res. 90. The resolution provides that the provisions of section 125(c) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall not apply during the remainder of the 116th Congress and the resolution amends H.Res. 967, agreed to on May 15, 2020.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26T15:22:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 5332.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26T16:14:02-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26T16:14:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of Rule XIX, further proceedings on H.R. 5332 were postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:47:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2663-2664" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:48:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Riggleman moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Financial Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2663" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:49:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Riggleman motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to strike section 3 from the bill and insert a new section prohibiting the use of social security numbers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:53:49-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:53:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Riggleman demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further consideration on the motion to recommit until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T17:19:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2665-2667" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T18:01:22-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 184 - 228 (Roll no. 125).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="126" datetime="2020-06-29T18:39:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 179 (Roll no. 126).</text>
      <reference ref="06/26/2020 CR H2559-2561" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T18:39:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="1017" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h818"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-07-07T21:09:18Z" status="Passed House">Protecting Your Credit Score Act of 2020

This bill revises provisions related to consumer credit reports and credit reporting agencies.

(Sec. 2) Credit reporting agencies are directed to create a central online portal that allows consumers to (1) access free credit reports and credit scores, (2) dispute errors, and (3) place or lift security freezes.

(Sec. 3) Credit reporting agencies must verify specified identifying information when adding credit information to a consumer's file. Credit reporting agencies must also perform periodic audits of credit reports to ensure accuracy.

(Sec. 4) A credit reporting ombudsperson, whose responsibilities include resolving persistent errors by credit reporting agencies, is established at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB).

Credit reporting agencies must provide a consumer with additional information after an agency's reinvestigation of disputed credit information.

(Sec. 5) A court may award injunctive relief to compel a credit reporting agency to comply with credit report protections.

(Sec. 6) Consumers will receive a free credit score upon request and upon certain adverse credit decisions.

Credit reporting agencies must provide available information to consumers regarding the purpose behind the procurement of a credit report.

(Sec. 7) The bill establishes a public registry for credit reporting agencies.

(Sec. 8) The bill also provides the CFPB with statutory authority for supervising credit reporting agencies.

(Sec. 9) The bill gives the CFPB the authority to establish data security requirements for credit reporting agencies.

(Sec. 10) The CFPB must report on the effectiveness of specified audits in addressing data security risks at credit reporting agencies.

(Sec. 11) The Government Accountability Office must report on the feasibility of credit reporting agencies replacing Social Security numbers as identifiers with another type of federal identification.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-416</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
