<bill session="118" type="s" number="1036" updated="2025-11-19T03:08:30Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Senior Hunger Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senior Hunger Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to streamline nutrition access for older adults and adults with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3474" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-20T19:43:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Senior Hunger Prevention Act of 2023

This bill modifies and expands nutrition programs for older adults and adults with disabilities, including the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) and the Commodity Supplemental Food Program (CSFP).

Under the bill, a household's eligibility for SNAP benefits may be certified for 36 months if all adult household members are elderly or disabled, an increase from 24 months. The bill also expands the SNAP medical expense deduction.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must establish an elderly simplified application program (ESAP). Under ESAP, a state may implement a streamlined SNAP application and certification process for households where all adult household members are elderly or disabled and have no earned income.

The bill also directs USDA to authorize public-private partnerships between USDA, retail food stores participating in SNAP, and community-based organizations to provide free or low-cost food delivery under SNAP, including through the use of private funds.

Further, the bill reauthorizes CSFP, provides additional funding for the program, and expands eligibility to include low-income adults with disabilities. CSFP benefits may also be certified for 36 months. Currently, benefits may be certified for not less than one year, but not more than three years.

The bill also expands eligibility for the Seniors Farmers Market Nutrition Program (SFMNP) to include adults with disabilities, provide a 36-month certification period, and include minimum and maximum benefit amounts.

Under the bill, USDA must also establish various grant programs; for example, USDA must establish grant programs to modernize SFMNP operations and establish new farmers' markets.</summary>
</bill>
