<bill session="111" type="h" number="5289" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:11Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Get the Lead Out Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to reduce lead in drinking water, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get the Lead Out Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3874" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-15T21:04:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Get the Lead Out Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to exempt from prohibitions on the use or sale of lead pipes, solder, and flux: (1) pipes or pipe or plumbing fittings or fixtures, including backflow preventers, that are used exclusively for nonpotable services such as manufacturing, industrial processing, irrigation, outdoor watering or any other uses where the water is not anticipated to be used for human consumption; or (2) toilets, bidets, urinals, fill valves, flushometer valves, tub fillers, shower valves, service saddles, or water distribution main gate valves that are two inches in diameter or larger.

 Redefines "lead free" under such Act to mean: (1) not containing more than 0.2% lead when used with respect to solder and flux (current law); and (2) not more than a weighted average of 0.25% when used with respect to the wetted surfaces of pipes and pipe and plumbing fittings and fixtures. Establishes a formula to calculate the weighted average lead content of a pipe or pipe or plumbing fitting or fixture.</summary>
</bill>
