<bill session="117" type="h" number="2390" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Donument Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Southern Border Wall National Monument, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Donument Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001104"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-19T17:16:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Donument Act

This bill establishes the Southern Border Wall National Monument in the states of California, Arizona, New Mexico, and Texas to protect the southern border wall from alteration.

The Bureau of Land Management (BLM) shall administer the monument.

The BLM shall establish administrative jurisdiction over portions of the southern border wall within the monument as necessary to carry out this bill by entering into memoranda of understanding with

 each federal department or agency with administrative jurisdiction over land within the monument on which portions of the wall are located, and the governing body of each Indian tribe with administrative jurisdiction over land within the monument on which portions of the wall are located. The BLM shall prepare a general management plan for the monument.</summary>
</bill>
