<bill session="118" type="h" number="5766" updated="2024-12-19T09:05:47Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Increasing American Ferrosilicon Production Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing American Ferrosilicon Production Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the rate of duty applicable to certain ferrosilicon produced in the Russian Federation or the Republic of Belarus and to require a domestic production assessment before increasing rates of duty applicable to products of the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus under the Suspending Normal Trade Relations with Russia and Belarus Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2023-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2024-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2937" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-09T19:23:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing American Ferrosilicon Production Act

This bill requires certain actions related to trade with Russia and Belarus, including by requiring an increase in the rate of duty for certain types of ferrosilicon. (Ferrosilicon is an alloy of iron and silicon.)

Specifically, the bill directs the President to proclaim an increase in the rate of duty applicable to ferrosilicon that is (1) classified under subheading 7202.21.50 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States, and (2) produced in Russia or Belarus. This rate of duty shall be 35% ad valorem.

Additionally, the bill extends through January 1, 2025, the authority of the President to proclaim increased rates of duty for all products of Russia or Belarus. (Currently, this authority terminates on January 1, 2024.)

The bill requires the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR) to carry out a public comment period regarding which products of Russia or Belarus are also produced in the United States and, for each product, the ability of U.S. producers to increase production in order to meet U.S. demand. If the USTR determines that U.S. producers have the ability to increase production to meet U.S. demand for a product, then the USTR must notify Congress and indicate whether the President will proclaim an increase in the rate of duty applicable to products of Russia or Belarus. If the President will not proclaim such an increase, then the USTR must explain the reasoning for the decision.</summary>
</bill>
