<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="542" updated="2021-02-08T15:31:26Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-02-05">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to protecting American taxpayers and the border, which may include prohibiting the cancellation of contracts for physical barriers and other border security measures for which funds already have been obligated and for which penalties will be incurred in the case of such cancellation and prohibiting the use of funds for payment of such penalties.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-02-05" how="roll" result="fail" roll="33">
      <text>Amendment SA 542 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 33.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Amendment SA 542 proposed by Senator Johnson. (consideration: CR S446-447; text: CR S446) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to protecting American taxpayers and the border, which may include prohibiting the cancellation of contracts for physical barriers and other border security measures for which funds already have been obligated and for which penalties will be incurred in the case of such cancellation and prohibiting the use of funds for payment of such penalties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03"/>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 542 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 542 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 50 - 50. Record Vote Number: 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 542 proposed by Senator Johnson.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
