<bill session="117" type="s" number="4083" updated="2022-12-29T23:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Energy Minerals Reform Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Energy Minerals Reform Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the requirements applicable to locatable minerals on public domain land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-09T12:49:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Energy Minerals Reform Act of 2022

This bill modifies requirements related to the mining of hardrock minerals on federal land. For example, the bill

 prohibits the United States from issuing a patent for any mining claim, millsite, or tunnel site unless a patent application was filed with the Department of the Interior by September 30, 1994; subjects production of all locatable minerals from any mining claim to a reasonable royalty established by Interior; requires an exploration permit and mining operations permit for non-casual mining operations; establishes the Hardrock Minerals Reclamation Fund for responding to hazardous substance releases on abandoned hardrock mine land; requires consultation with Indian tribes prior to the undertaking or issuing of a permit for mineral activity that has tribal implications; and establishes civil penalties for violation of surface management or operation requirements and related regulations.</summary>
</bill>
