<bill session="110" type="h" number="4719" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:32Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Additional Safeguards For Lease and Development of Non-Excess Property of Military Departments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Additional Safeguards For Lease and Development of Non-Excess Property of Military Departments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to take reasonable steps to prevent avoidable disasters related to seismic activity in connection with the lease and development of non-excess property of military departments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2594-2595"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-14T17:10:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Additional Safeguards For Lease and Development of Non-Excess Property of Military Departments Act - Prohibits the lease of non-excess land that is under the control of a military department if the land is located in an area designated UBC Seismic Zone 4.

Provides for an exception if the Secretary concerned determines that seismic activity would not have any significant impact on any portion of the proposed development under the lease. Prohibits such Secretary from omitting a revocation provision from a lease allowed under this exception.

Requires revocation of previously-approved leases in such zones unless a lease is under substantial construction or the Secretary determines a lease should not be revoked.</summary>
</bill>
