<bill session="116" type="s" number="1339" updated="2022-02-09T02:55:57Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prove It Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prove It Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require greater transparency for Federal regulatory decisions that impact small businesses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Subcommittee on Regulatory Affairs and Federal Management. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA19" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Regulatory Affairs and Federal Management" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-21T15:30:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prove It Act of 2019

This bill authorizes the Small Business Administration (SBA) to request a review of any federal agency certification that a proposed rule will not have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities. The request must explain why the SBA disagreed with the certification and provide a factual basis for the statement. If it is determined, after agency review and reconsideration, that the proposed rule will have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small entities, the agency shall then perform an initial regulatory flexibility analysis for the rule.

An initial regulatory flexibility analysis is prepared to ensure the agency has considered all reasonable regulatory alternatives that would minimize the rule's economic burdens or increase its benefits for the affected small entities, while achieving the objectives of the rule or statute.</summary>
</bill>
