<bill session="117" type="s" number="5178" updated="2022-12-29T09:03:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DITCH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DITCH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dump Investments in Troublesome Communist Holdings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose restrictions on the investment in Chinese companies by tax-exempt entities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9385" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-08T22:09:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dump Investments in Troublesome Communist Holdings Act or the DITCH Act 

This bill denies an organization a tax exemption if it holds any interest in a disqualified Chinese company or fails to timely transmit required annual reports. A disqualified Chinese company is any corporation incorporated in China, or that invests more than 10% of its stock in certain Chinese entities, including entities controlled by the Chinese Communist Party.

The Department of the Treasury may grant organizations a waiver of the denial of the tax exemption under specified circumstances.

Organizations that hold any interest in a disqualified Chinese company must file annual reports describing each interest held in the company, the period during which such interest was held, and whether the organization has been granted a waiver.</summary>
</bill>
