<bill session="108" type="s" number="2892" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Children and Family HIV/AIDS Research and Care Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize and extend certain programs to provide coordinated services and research with respect to children and families with HIV/AIDS.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children and Family HIV/AIDS Research and Care Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2004-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10440-10442"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-07T16:35:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Children and Family HIV/AIDS Research and Care Act of 2004 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require that recipients of certain grants related to human immunodeficiency virus (HIV) research and services for women, infants, and children agree to provide coordinated, family-centered care. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to award grants to provide health care and other supportive services to youth with HIV designed to recruit and retain youth in care.

Requires that chief elected officials in eligible areas and States allocate certain grant funds using HIV case data rather than acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) case data as soon as such data is adopted for other allocation purposes. Requires the Secretary to report on the status of using such HIV case data and the impact of this transition on the resources directed to women, infants, children and youth.

Requires the Secretary to award demonstration grants to public and nonprofit private entities to conduct assessments of the effectiveness of certain strategies in reducing the mother-to-child transmission of HIV.

Requires the Director of NIH, acting through the Director of the Office of AIDS Research, to report on activities related to the testing of potential HIV vaccine candidates in relevant pediatric populations.

Requires the Commission of Food and Drugs to issue guidance on the minimum requirements for obtaining Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval to test an HIV vaccine in pediatric populations and for a pediatric indication of an HIV vaccine.

Requires the Director of NIH to invest in domestic and international research on specified topics related to HIV and pediatric populations.</summary>
</bill>
