<bill session="118" type="s" number="185" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Direct Loan Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Direct Loan Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the program for direct housing loans made to Native American veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8371" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-31T16:37:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native American Direct Loan Improvement Act of 2023

This bill revises the Native American Direct Loan (NADL) program, which is administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Under the NADL program, the VA makes loans directly to Native American veterans to purchase, construct, improve, or refinance their homes located on federal trust land.

Specifically, the bill expands the NADL program by allowing Native American veterans to refinance other existing mortgage loans on the same property if certain conditions are met.

Additionally, the bill requires the VA to conduct additional program outreach by partnering with local service providers (e.g., tribal organizations and nonprofit organizations) to conduct outreach, homebuyer education, housing counseling, and post-purchase education.

The bill directs the VA to assign a sufficient number of personnel to carry out the NADL program, including construction and valuation specialists to assist with issues unique to new construction and renovations on trust land.

The bill also authorizes the VA to make a loan with a 1% interest rate to a Native community development financial institution to allow the institution to relend loan amounts to qualified Native American veterans residing on federal trust land.</summary>
</bill>
