<bill session="116" type="h" number="3813" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Brian Tally VA Medical Care and Liability Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that certain health care contractors of the Department of Veterans Affairs are subject to Federal tort claims laws, to improve the accountability of physicians of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brian Tally VA Medical Care and Liability Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2019-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2019-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2019-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2019-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-22T18:04:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Brian Tally VA Medical Care and Liability Improvement Act

This bill imposes civil liability under the federal tort claim law upon certain contractors hired by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for their negligence or malpractice in providing medical care to veterans. Such liability is waived if the VA provides a notice to affected individuals or their estates identifying the full names of the contractors involved and the nature of the health care they furnished, among other information. The VA must provide such notice within 30 days after the veteran or the veteran's estate files a claim.

The bill also requires the VA to revoke a contractor's authorization to provide health care at a VA facility if the contractor is a defendant in at least three separate negligence claims during a five-year period. This revocation requirement also applies to VA physicians and other health practitioners if claims against the physicians or providers resulted in a judgment against the United States or were compromised or settled.</summary>
</bill>
