<bill session="109" type="h" number="2685" updated="2021-09-29T20:32:17Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation Act</title>
    <title type="display">Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for prescription drugs at reduced prices to Medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000557"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2006-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2005-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2005-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Price discrimination"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-09T21:11:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Prescription Drug Price Negotiation Act - Requires each participating manufacturer of a covered outpatient drug to make such drugs available for purchase by any qualified Federal health care provider, by each pharmacy, and by each provider of services, physician, practitioner, and supplier under the Medicare program at a price that the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in conjunction with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, negotiates with the manufacturer. Provides that the amount of such a drug made available for purchase is equal to the sum of the aggregate amounts of the drug dispensed by pharmacies to Medicare beneficiaries plus the aggregate amounts dispensed through qualified Federal health care providers.

Requires the Secretary, in conducting negotiations with participating manufacturers, to take into account the goal of promoting the development of breakthrough drugs.

Requires the United States to exclude from Government contracting and subcontracting, for a period of time, a manufacturer of drugs or biologicals that does not comply with this Act.

Directs the Secretary to establish a mechanism (such as an ombudsman) for the resolution of disputes between Medicare beneficiaries and prescription drug resellers and drug manufacturers in order to protect such beneficiaries and to ensure that: (1) prescription drug resellers are not artifically increasing prices charged to Medicare beneficiaries (above those negotiated under this Act) in places (such as rural areas) where there is less competition; and (2) such resellers are not colluding on prices in areas with more potential significant competition.</summary>
</bill>
