<bill session="116" type="s" number="3467" updated="2022-02-09T00:10:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TRACER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRACER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to share with State, local, and regional fusion centers release information from a Federal correctional facility, including name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of certain individuals who may pose a terrorist threat, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8309" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-04T18:06:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terrorist Release Announcements to Counter Extremist Recidivism Act or the TRACER Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the Department of Justice,&#160;to share with state, local, and regional fusion centers release information from a federal correctional facility, including the name, charging date, and expected place and date of release, of individuals who may pose a terrorist threat. Such information shall be for homeland security purposes, and regarding individuals convicted of a federal crime of terrorism.

A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.

DHS shall coordinate with federal officials to provide fusion centers with periodic assessments regarding the threat from known or suspected terrorists currently incarcerated.</summary>
</bill>
