<bill session="116" type="s" number="1161" updated="2022-02-08T23:14:49Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Educator Support and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the education of Indian children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2019-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1157" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-31T16:25:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native Educator Support and Training Act or the NEST Act 

This bill establishes scholarships, loan forgiveness plans, and training programs for students and educators who commit to teaching in Bureau of Indian Education (BIE) schools or other specified schools serving Indian students.

The bill establishes three scholarship programs: (1) the Indian Student Educator Scholarship Program for students seeking degrees, (2) the Indian Educator Scholarship Program for Indian students seeking degrees, and (3) the Indian Educator Graduate Fellowship Program for Indian students seeking graduate degrees. Recipients of the scholarships must commit to working for a BIE school, a tribal early childhood education program, or other specified schools or agencies for the greater of three years or the number of school years that the scholarship funded.

The bill also establishes loan forgiveness programs for educators and Indians who have taught for at least five consecutive years at BIE schools or local educational agencies with high percentages of Indian students.

The bill extends the federal Perkins Loan Cancellation Program to educators teaching in BIE schools or in Native American language immersion programs.

The bill authorizes professional development grants for Native-serving elementary and secondary schools. It also establishes the Native American Language Teacher Training Program to provide grants for institutions of higher education to develop training programs for Native American immersion and language teachers.</summary>
</bill>
