<bill session="118" type="h" number="6650" updated="2025-11-19T03:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Development Investment Tax Credit Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Development Investment Tax Credit Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for investment in Community Development Financial Institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000488"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2963" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-10T14:46:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Development Investment Tax Credit Act of 2023 

This bill allows investors a business-related tax credit for investment in a Community Development Financial Institution (CDFI). The applicable percentage of such credit is 3% for the first 10 years of investment in a CDFI with a 1% increase after the initial credit allowance date and for investments without a fixed term or duration.

The tax credit is available to investors who invest in various CDFIs to provide financial support for increasing wealth in low- and moderate-income communities. The national limitation on the credit is $1 billion for 2022, $1.5 billion for 2023, and $2 billion for 2024 and each year thereafter, with adjustments for inflation.</summary>
</bill>
