<bill session="116" type="s" number="4937" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Screening Partnership Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Screening Partnership Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the program providing for private screening companies to conduct security screening at airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-17T19:43:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Screening Partnership Reform Act of 2020

This bill revises the Screening Partnership Program of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to

 authorize the operator of an airport to select a qualified private screening company with which the operator prefers the TSA enter into a contract for screening services at that airport; direct the TSA to enter into a contract with a private screening company only if the cost of providing screening services at the airport is equal to or less than the cost to the federal government of providing the same screening services, and entering into the contract would not compromise aviation security or the effectiveness of the screening of passengers or property at the airport; allow a private screening company to use screening supervisors who have been trained and certified at a Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to administer comparable on-site training and certification to private security screeners at an airport that is participating in the screening partnership program; and require a private screening company in the program to annually submit recommendations to the TSA on new approaches to screening processes and procedures that would enhance the screening of passengers and property at the airport.</summary>
</bill>
