<bill session="117" type="s" number="3485" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SERVIS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Enfranchisement and the Rights of Voters regardless of Inoculation Status Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVIS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that the right to vote shall not be impaired due to vaccination status.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6558" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-10T17:55:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing Enfranchisement and the Rights of Voters regardless of Inoculation Status Act or the SERVIS Act

This bill prohibits requiring voters to present vaccine passports or other information regarding their COVID-19 vaccination status, and also restricts masking requirements, for voting in federal elections.

Specifically, the bill makes it unlawful for any state or political subdivision to require a voter to present a vaccine passport or other information regarding the voter's COVID-19 vaccination status.

Further, a state or political subdivision may require a voter to wear a mask in order to enter a polling location only under certain circumstances. In particular, the state or political subdivision must (1) make masks readily available and at no cost to the voter and to an individual who accompanies the voter, and (2) provide reasonable accommodation from such masking requirement to an individual with a disability.</summary>
</bill>
