<bill session="111" type="s" number="1241" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:38Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend Public Law 106-206 to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to require annual permits and assess annual fees for commercial filming activities on Federal land for film crews of 5 persons or fewer.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend Public Law 106-206 to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to require annual permits and assess annual fees for commercial filming activities on Federal land for film crews of 5 persons or fewer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2010-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2009-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6548-6549"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6549" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2031" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="General public lands matters"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-21T22:16:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture (the Secretary), for any film crew of five persons or fewer, to require a permit and assess an annual fee of $200 for commercial filming activities or similar projects on federal lands and waterways administered by the Secretary. Makes such a permit valid for such activities or projects that occur in areas designated for public use during public hours on all federal lands and waterways administered by the Secretary for a 12-month period.

Prohibits the Secretary, for persons holding such a permit, from assessing any additional fee for commercial filming activities and similar projects that occur in those areas during those hours.

Bars the Secretary from prohibiting, as a mechanized apparatus or under any other purposes, the use of cameras or related equipment used for commercial filming activities or similar projects in accordance with this Act on federal lands and waterways administered by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
