<bill session="117" type="h" number="3895" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">College Athlete Right to Organize Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish collective bargaining rights for college athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Athlete Right to Organize Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001223"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000592" joined="2021-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2021-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1929" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="National Labor Relations Board (NLRB)"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-21T20:23:57Z" status="Introduced in House">College Athlete Right to Organize Act

This bill establishes collective bargaining rights for college athletes.

Specifically, the bill amends the National Labor Relations Act to (1) define college athlete employee as an employee of an institution of higher education if the individual receives direct compensation from the institution and such compensation requires participation in intercollegiate sports, and (2) include public institutions as employers within the context of intercollegiate sports.

The National Labor Relations Board (NLRB) must consider the colleges within an athletic conference as part of a bargaining unit with which college athletes can negotiate.

The NLRB shall have jurisdiction over all institutions of higher education within the context of intercollegiate athletics regarding collective bargaining and representation matters and labor disputes.

The bill prohibits any agreements, such as scholarship agreements, that waive the right of athletes to collectively bargain.</summary>
</bill>
