<bill session="119" type="h" number="5305" updated="2025-09-24T14:41:35Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional MRA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Money Returned to America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional MRA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require any amounts remaining in the Members' Representational Allowance at the end of a fiscal year to be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit reduction or to reduce the Federal debt, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2025-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2025-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-24T14:40:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Money Returned to America Act or the Congressional&#160;MRA Act

This bill requires funds that were provided to House offices for the Members' Representational Allowance (MRA) and remain in the MRA account after all payments for the year are made to be deposited in the Treasury and used for deficit or debt reduction.&#160;

The&#160;MRA is an allowance that Members of the House of Representatives receive each year to operate their offices. It must be used to support official and representational duties and may not be used for personal or campaign purposes.&#160;

Annual appropriations acts that fund the legislative branch have generally included a provision that requires unused amounts remaining in the&#160;MRA to be used for deficit reduction or to reduce the federal debt. This bill makes this requirement permanent.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
