<bill session="116" type="h" number="7817" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernize Nuclear Reactor Environmental Reviews Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernize Nuclear Reactor Environmental Reviews Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to submit a report on facilitating efficient, timely environmental reviews of nuclear reactors through expanded use of categorical exclusions, environmental assessments, and generic environmental impact statements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2020-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-16T16:26:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Modernize Nuclear Reactor Environmental Reviews Act

This bill directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to submit to Congress a report on facilitating efficient, timely environmental reviews of nuclear reactors through expanded use of categorical exclusions, environmental assessments, and generic environmental impact statements.

The commission must promulgate a final rule to (1) establish an optical generic environmental impact statement for actions relating to nuclear reactors that may be used in the process for issuing a construction permit, early site permit, or combined license; and (2) amend criteria for and identification of licensing and regulatory actions to eliminate the list of actions that require environmental impact statements to allow for the use of environmental assessments and categorical exclusions for such actions.</summary>
</bill>
