<bill session="117" type="hr" number="38" updated="2023-03-09T17:48:12Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-12T21:14:58-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-01-12T21:14:58-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 21) calling on Vice President Michael R. Pence to convene and mobilize the principal officers of the executive departments of the Cabinet to activate section 4 of the 25th Amendment to declare President Donald J. Trump incapable of executing the duties of his office and to immediately exercise powers as acting President; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 21) calling on Vice President Michael R. Pence to convene and mobilize the principal officers of the executive departments of the Cabinet to activate section 4 of the 25th Amendment to declare President Donald J. Trump incapable of executing the duties of his office and to immediately exercise powers as acting President; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T18:19:43-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H126-131" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T18:19:55-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 117-1, by Ms. Scanlon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T18:26:08-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 21 with 1 hour of general debate. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-01-12" calendar="House" number="1">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 1.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T19:05:27-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 38, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cole demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T19:32:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H131-133" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T20:28:59-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 206 (Roll no. 12).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H131-132" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="13" datetime="2021-01-12T21:14:58-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 204 (Roll no. 13).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H126" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T21:15:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="21" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="85" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-04T17:49:20Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for the consideration of H.Res. 21 (calling on Vice President Michael R. Pence to take appropriate actions to declare President Donald J. Trump incapable of executing the duties of his office and to immediately exercise powers as Acting President).

The prohibition against personality in debate shall not apply during such consideration or any special order of business providing for consideration of H.Res. 24 (impeaching President Donald John Trump for high crimes and misdemeanors) with respect to references to the President.

During the 45-day period designated by the Speaker of the House of Representatives in H.Res. 965, 116th Congress (allowing remote voting by proxy in the House and remote official committee procedures during a public health emergency due to a novel coronavirus [e.g., the virus that causes COVID-19])

 the Sergeant-at-Arms is directed to impose a $500 fine for a first offense and a $2,500 fine for any subsequent offense against a Member, Delegate, or the Resident Commissioner for failure to wear a mask in contravention of the Speaker's announced policies of January 4, 2021; and the fine shall be treated as though imposed and administered under Rule II (Other Officers and Officials) of the Rules of the House. After the Committee on Ethics receives an appeal of the fine, the 30 calendar days or 5 legislative days, whichever is later, by which the committee must either dismiss the fine or allow it to proceed may not commence until the committee has adopted written rules.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-1</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
