<bill session="119" type="s" number="1616" updated="2025-09-29T16:10:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRECISE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECISE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Producing Responsible Energy and Conservation Incentives and Solutions for the Environment Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act and the Food Security Act of 1985 to leverage incentives for the adoption of precision agriculture practices and technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-29T16:07:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Producing Responsible Energy and Conservation Incentives and Solutions for the Environment Act of 2025 or the PRECISE Act of 2025

This bill incorporates support for precision agriculture into various programs of the Department of Agriculture (USDA). Precision agriculture refers to managing, tracking, or reducing crop or livestock production inputs, including seed, feed, fertilizer, chemicals, water, and time, at a heightened level of spatial and temporal granularity to improve efficiencies, reduce waste, and maintain environmental quality. Precision agriculture technology includes any technology and equipment that directly contributes to a reduction in, or improved efficiency of, inputs used in crop or livestock production.

Specifically, the bill makes changes to eligibility criteria, payments, and other aspects of the Environmental Quality Incentives Program and the Conservation Stewardship Program. These changes include allowing the programs to support the adoption of precision agriculture practices and acquisition of precision agriculture technologies.

In addition, the bill expands a program through which USDA makes and insures loans to for-profit and nonprofit organizations that invest in rural areas by allowing the loans to be used for precision agriculture practices.

Also, USDA must emphasize the use of third-party providers when providing technical assistance on matters related to soil health for participants in certain USDA conservation programs. This includes planning related to the use of cover crops, precision agriculture practices, and comprehensive nutrient management.</summary>
</bill>
