<bill session="117" type="h" number="6946" updated="2023-08-15T13:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Americans from the Fentanyl Emergency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to fentanyl-related substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000594" joined="2022-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2022-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1910" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6713" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T12:46:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Americans from the Fentanyl Emergency Act of 2022 or the SAFE Act of 2022 

This bill&#160;permanently&#160;places fentanyl-related substances as a class into schedule I of the Controlled Substances Act. A schedule I controlled substance is a drug, substance, or chemical that has a high potential for abuse; has no currently accepted medical value; and is subject to regulatory controls and administrative, civil, and criminal penalties under the Controlled Substances Act.

It limits the application of mandatory minimum penalties for certain offenses involving fentanyl-related substances, establishes a process to deschedule or remove certain fentanyl-related substances that have a low potential for abuse, and allows a federal court to vacate or reduce the sentence for convictions of offenses involving a fentanyl-related substance that is descheduled or moved to a schedule other than schedule I or II.

The bill establishes a new, alternative registration process for schedule I research. It also makes other changes to registration requirements for conducting research with controlled substances, including

 permitting a single registration for related research sites in certain circumstances, waiving the requirement for a new inspection in certain situations, and allowing a registered researcher to perform certain manufacturing activities with small quantities of a substance without obtaining a manufacturing registration. Finally, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to analyze the implementation and impact of permanently placing fentanyl-related substances into schedule I of the Controlled Substances Act.</summary>
</bill>
