<bill session="119" type="h" number="4658" updated="2025-11-20T09:06:18Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STUDENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STUDENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 1511 of title 36, United States Code, to impose certain requirements on the National Education Association, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000471"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001322" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000478" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2025-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000597" joined="2025-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2025-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2428" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-18T21:00:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping Teachers Unions from Damaging Education Needs Today Act or the STUDENT Act

This bill revises the federal charter for the National Education Association.

The bill specifies that&#160;the corporation and its state and local affiliates may only accept payment of membership dues or fees from a state or local government employee if the employee (1) has been notified of the employee's right under the First Amendment to refrain from membership and payment of associated dues or fees, (2) has clearly and affirmatively consented to membership and payment of associated dues or fees, and (3) has authorized the transmittal of membership dues or fees without the use of payroll deduction.

Further, the corporation and its state or local affiliates must process and honor cancellation requests for membership or payment of dues as soon as practicable following receipt of the request.

The bill also outlines requirements for the corporation, such as&#160;

prohibiting the corporation or its directors or officers from contributing to, supporting, or participating in political activities;requiring each officer of the corporation to be a U.S. citizen;&#160;requiring the corporation to submit annual reports to Congress;prohibiting the corporation and its affiliates from requiring staff, officers, affiliates, or members to affirm, adopt, or adhere to certain principles related to race or sex; andprohibiting the corporation and its affiliates from calling or participating in a strike, work stoppage, or slowdown affecting a state or local government.The bill repeals the corporation's exemption from District of Columbia property taxes.</summary>
</bill>
