<bill session="119" type="h" number="414" updated="2025-03-19T14:39:09Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Visa Security Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Visa Security Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to strengthen student visa background checks and improve the monitoring of foreign students in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-19T14:38:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Visa Security Improvement Act

This bill establishes new requirements for foreign student visas and participating educational institutions.&#160;

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must review the applications of student visa applicants and conduct in-person interviews when appropriate to determine whether they are inadmissible due to terrorist-related activities. DHS must also conduct on-site reviews of applications and supporting documents deemed appropriate prior to final adjudication.

Institutions and exchange student visitor programs must ensure that student visa-holders are active participants in the program. Students must be regularly observed and must be reported on if they transfer or change majors. The bill also provides for enhanced access to the Student and Exchange Visitor Information System for institutions and programs that meet staffing and training requirements.

The Government Accountability Office must review the fees for the Student and Exchange Visitor program.</summary>
</bill>
