<bill session="110" type="s" number="2454" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:25Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wireless 411 Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless 411 Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to protect the privacy rights of subscribers to wireless communications services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2007-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2007-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-10T16:52:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wireless 411 Privacy Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a provider of commercial mobile services, or any affiliate or agent of such provider (provider), from including the wireless telephone number (wireless number) of any subscriber in any wireless directory assistance service (WDAS) database unless the provider: (1) provides a conspicuous, separate notice to the subscriber of the right not be listed in any WDAS; and (2) obtains express prior listing authorization from such subscriber, and that authorization has not been withdrawn.

Requires a provider to remove the wireless number of any subscriber from a WDAS upon request of that subscriber and without subscriber cost. Provides limited circumstances under which a provider may connect a calling party from a WDAS to a commercial mobile service subscriber.

Prohibits a telecommunications carrier from disclosing in billing information provided to customers wireless numbers of subscribers who have indicated a preference to their provider for not having their wireless number disclosed.

Prohibits a provider from publishing (listing) in any form, selling, or otherwise distributing the contents of any WDAS database unless the provider: (1) notifies the subscriber of the right not to be listed; and (2) obtains express prior authorization for listing from such subscriber, and that authorization has not been withdrawn.

Prohibits a provider from charging a subscriber for the exercise of any rights under this Act.

 Prohibits selling, marketing for sale, or otherwise disseminating the wireless telephone information of any individual, or any directory or other list of such information of individuals, unless each such individual provides written express prior authorization. Preempts inconsistent state or local laws.</summary>
</bill>
