<bill session="118" type="s" number="1214" updated="2025-11-19T03:11:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">RARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Retaining Access and Restoring Exclusivity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RARE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retaining Access and Restoring Exclusivity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to set forth limitations on exclusive approval or licensure of drugs designated for rare diseases or conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Sanders without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="109">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 109.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3433" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7383" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-29T21:17:20Z" status="Reported to Senate">Retaining Access and Restoring Exclusivity Act or the RARE Act

This bill specifies that the seven-year market exclusivity period for drugs for rare diseases or conditions (i.e., orphan drug exclusivity period) prohibits the approval of the same drug for the same approved use or indication with respect to the disease or condition.

Current law grants a seven-year period of market exclusivity for an approved orphan drug, during which the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) may not approve an application from another manufacturer for the same drug for the same disease or condition. The FDA's regulations provide that this exclusivity is specific to the same approved use or indication of the drug, rather than all uses or indications, for the disease or condition. However, in Catalyst Pharmaceuticals, Inc. v. Becerra, a court held that exclusivity did extend to all uses or indications for the disease or condition.

The bill provides statutory authority for the FDA's regulations.</summary>
</bill>
