<bill session="117" type="s" number="120" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Connections Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent and respond to the misuse of communications services that facilitates domestic violence and other crimes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Safe Connections Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Connections Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Safe Connections Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2022-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="193">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 193.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1246-1248" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-03-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1257-1259" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-03-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24T13:01:20-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24T13:02:00-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7132" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5001"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2022-07-26T13:53:30Z" status="Passed Senate">Safe Connections Act of 2022

This bill establishes requirements concerning access to communication services for survivors of domestic violence, human trafficking, and related harms.

At a survivor's request, a mobile service provider must separate from a shared mobile service contract the survivor's line (and the line of any individual in the survivor's care) from the abuser's line unless separation is operationally or technologically infeasible. A survivor requesting this must (1) verify through appropriate documentation that an individual under the contract committed or allegedly committed an act of domestic violence, trafficking, or a related criminal act against the survivor; and (2) assume financial responsibility for services after a line separation.

A provider may not charge fees or impose other requirements on such requests. Additionally, a provider must

 separate the line within two business days of receiving a request; allow requests to be made remotely (if feasible); meet conditions related to confidentiality of, disposal of, and other matters concerning communications about requests; and make information about the process for requests available through consumer-facing communications (e.g., websites). The bill (1) provides liability protection for providers' acts or omissions undertaken to comply with such requests, and (2) requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to adopt rules for these requests.

Additionally, the FCC must (1) expand access to federally subsidized communication services for survivors facing financial hardship, and (2) evaluate this expanded access.

The FCC must also consider rules requiring communication service providers to omit from consumer-facing logs calls and texts to hotlines for domestic violence and similar issues while retaining internal records.</summary>
</bill>
