<bill session="116" type="s" number="2421" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2019-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Contract Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Contract Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve accountability of disaster contracts, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2019-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-30T18:08:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disaster Contract Transparency Act of 2019

This bill modifies the process for contracting following natural disasters.

Specifically, the bill (1) requires state and local governments to have advance contracts in place for debris removal services in order to be eligible for the public assistance grant program; and (2) limits Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) reimbursement of debris removal to the lower of federal, state, or local contract rates.

The bill further requires FEMA to

 penalize vendors for failing to adhere to pre-disaster contracts; develop and implement clear rules regarding the oversight of debris removal contracts; develop a documented risk-based approach for grants that federal coordinating officers can use to determine appropriate cost-effective field presence required for debris removal oversight; and report to Congress annually detailing a comprehensive list of advance contracts and a review of the need for advance contracts that may be lacking for debris removal and other services.</summary>
</bill>
