<bill session="116" type="h" number="2600" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Toxic PFAS Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To regulate per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances under the Toxic Substances Control Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Toxic PFAS Control Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000631"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2019-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001123" joined="2019-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2019-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2019-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-18T19:16:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Toxic PFAS Control Act

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to regulate and phase out the manufacturing, processing, and distribution of perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS. PFAS are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds, such as nonstick cookware or weatherproof clothing.

Beginning six months after the date of enactment of this bill, no person may manufacture any new PFAS nor may they manufacture or process any PFAS for a significant new use as determined by the EPA.

The bill prohibits the manufacture of any PFAS beginning two years after the date of enactment of this bill. Additionally, three years after the date of enactment of the bill, no person may process or distribute in commerce any PFAS.

With regard to PFAS, the EPA must regulate

 the manner or method of disposal of PFAS or any article containing such substances; packaging or labeling of substances or articles containing PFAS to ensure clear and adequate minimum warnings and instructions for its processing, use, distribution, or disposal; reporting requirements for persons manufacturing or processing PFAS; and PFAS manufacturers in relation to the disposal of unprocessed PFAS, replacement or repurchase of PFAS, and notice requirements to certain parties. The EPA is authorized to grant exemptions from requirements related to PFAS, but such exemptions are only permitted to last up to one year.</summary>
</bill>
