<bill session="116" type="h" number="149" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Fairness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Housing Fairness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Women, Families with Children, Race, and Persons with Disabilities Housing Fairness Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2019-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2019-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2019-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 33 - 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 116-664.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-17" calendar="Union" number="548">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 548.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-19T14:48:47Z" status="Reported to House">Housing Fairness Act of 2020

This bill provides for testing and investigations to detect housing discrimination and awards grants to study the causes and effects of such discrimination.

Specifically, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) must conduct regional or national testing programs and investigations to (1) detect and document differences in the treatment of prospective renters, homebuyers, or mortgage borrowers; (2) measure patterns of differential treatment because of the status of a renter, homebuyer, or borrower as a member of the protected classes under the Fair Housing Act (i.e., race, color, religion, sex, familial status, disability status, or national origin); and (3) measure the prevalence, nature, and extent of such discriminatory practices covered under the Act.

Furthermore, the bill (1) eliminates restrictions on the use of fair housing initiative program-earned income received by qualified fair housing enforcement organizations after the grant period for such organizations ends, (2) increases funding for the fair housing initiatives program in FY2021-FY2031, and (3) requires HUD to study and report on the feasibility, efficiency, and effectiveness of converting the program into a specified noncompetitive, entitlement program.

Additionally, HUD shall award grants to public and private entities to study housing discrimination, including the causes and effects of such discrimination.

Finally, the bill prohibits the use of funds made available by this bill for any political activities, political advocacy, lobbying, such travel-related expenses, or for preparation of or provision of advice on tax returns.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-664</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
