<bill session="117" type="s" number="1980" updated="2023-12-05T10:26:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to track the distribution of all farm subsidies by race, gender, and size of the farm operation and to make that information about farm subsidies available to the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Farm Subsidy Transparency Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Subsidy Transparency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3794" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-29T15:23:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farm Subsidy Transparency Act of 2021

This bill requires the collection and disclosure of demographic and other information about recipients of agricultural benefits.

Specifically, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must collect and make publicly available (1) the race and gender of individuals who directly or indirectly received or applied for certain benefits, such as grants or other funding under USDA's commodity, conservation, research, extension, and education programs; and (2) the farm or ranch acreage of the recipients of such benefits.

USDA must also collect and track the race and gender of individuals who register for the USDA service center information management system (a repository of participants in programs offered by USDA's Farm Service Agency, Natural Resource and Conservation Service, and rural development agencies).

Additionally, the Commodity Credit Corporation must collect and disclose (1) the race and gender of individuals who receive or apply for benefits from the corporation, and (2) the farm or ranch acreage of the recipients of such benefits.

The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation must collect and disclose (1) the name, race, gender, and farm or ranch acreage of individuals who receive federally subsidized insurance for crops, livestock, or forage; and (2) the premium subsidy amount for each recipient.

The bill also requires financial institutions to gather demographic information in response to loan applications for farms and ranches that are minority-owned or women-owned. (Currently, institutions must gather that information in response to loan applications from women-owned and minority-owned small businesses.)</summary>
</bill>
