<bill session="117" type="h" number="3652" updated="2022-12-30T21:29:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a food waste research and technical assistance program and grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">National Food Waste Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Food Waste Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2022-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-13T18:07:38Z" status="Introduced in House">National Food Waste Reduction Act

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture's Food Loss and Waste Reduction Liaison to establish a Food Waste Research Program in partnership with five regional institutions of higher education.

The program must focus on food waste reduction and food recovery issues on a national, regional, and local level and support certain areas of study, such as the diversion of surplus food to those in need and the use of food waste for environmental purposes. The program must share best practices for food waste reduction with governmental entities, agriculture organizations, farmers, and other relevant entities, and must post research and resources on its website.

The bill also establishes a grant program for research centers and nonprofits to support other cooperative efforts relating to food loss and waste reduction.</summary>
</bill>
