<bill session="118" type="h" number="4546" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:06Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">B&#226;&#8364;&#8220;VERIFY Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biometric Verification for Entry and Reconfirming Identity with Forensics Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">B&#226;&#8364;&#8220;VERIFY Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand the requirements for the collection of biometric data, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-07T17:12:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Biometric Verification for Entry and Reconfirming Identity with Forensics Act of 2023 or the B-VERIFY Act of 2023

This bill addresses various immigration-related issues, including by imposing penalties on parents of unaccompanied alien children who arrive in the United States.

Under this bill, any applicant for an immigration benefit, including a U.S. national applying for a non-U.S. national (alien under federal law) beneficiary, must provide biometric information, including DNA.

Furthermore, before the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may release an unaccompanied alien child to a sponsor, the potential sponsor must undergo a background check that includes certain searches, including a Federal Bureau of Investigation National Criminal History Check. (HHS currently conducts background checks of potential sponsors, but is not required to conduct all the checks required by this bill.)

HHS must report a potential sponsor to U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) if the potential sponsor (1) fails to prove a claimed familial relationship with the child, or (2) provides a false identity document. HHS may not use government funds to provide legal counsel to detained unaccompanied alien children. The bill also imposes penalties on the non-U.S. national parents of an unaccompanied alien child who arrives in the United States, including by deeming the parent inadmissible into the United States if the parent does not have lawful permanent resident status. Federal employees must promptly notify ICE if they receive an identification document indicating that an individual is unlawfully present. ICE must promptly place the individual in removal proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
