<bill session="108" type="h" number="4208" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Executive Stock Option Profit Recapture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To discourage the abuse of stock options by executives of public companies by preventing unjust enrichment through the recapture of profits when shareholders suffer losses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Stock Option Profit Recapture Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000339"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee stock options"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-09T19:37:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Executive Stock Option Profit Recapture Act - Amends the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to direct the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to prescribe rules declaring that, if, at the end of a period ending one year after one or more of the five most highly compensated executive officers or the directors of an issuer have exercised options on the issuer's securities granted as compensation, the issuer's stock has declined by a material amount, then such executive officer or director shall be required to reimburse the issuer for all gains realized on the sale of securities obtained as a result of the option exercise that are in excess of any gains that would have been realized had the securities been sold at the stock price at the end of such one-year period.</summary>
</bill>
