<bill session="108" type="s" number="1484" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Citizens' Protection in Federal Databases Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a report on Federal Government use of commercial and other databases for national security, intelligence, and law enforcement purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizens' Protection in Federal Databases Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2003-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10149-10150"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10150-10151" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-12T20:19:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Citizens' Protection in Federal Databases Act - Directs the Attorney General, the Secretaries of Defense, Homeland Security, and Treasury, and the Directors of Central Intelligence and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to submit to specified congressional committees and make available to the public a written report detailing any use by the agency, or by any national security, intelligence, or law enforcement element under that agency's jurisdiction, of databases that were obtained from or remain under the control of a nonfederal entity, or that contain information that was acquired initially by another Federal agency for purposes other than national security, intelligence, or law enforcement. Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of funds by those agencies on the procurement of or access to any commercially available database unless that report has been submitted within 60 days.

Sets forth report requirements, including information on contracts entered into for the use of, access to, or analysis of databases that were obtained from a nonfederal entity for specified purposes..

Prohibits any Government entity, officer, or employee from conducting a search or other analysis of a database for national security, intelligence, or law enforcement purposes based solely on a hypothetical scenario or supposition of who may commit a crime or pose a threat to national security.</summary>
</bill>
