<bill session="118" type="s" number="98" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agriculture Innovation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agriculture Innovation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to improve agricultural productivity, profitability, resilience, and ecological outcomes through modernized data infrastructure and analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-10T02:08:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agriculture Innovation Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to identify, collect, link, and analyze certain data on the impact of conservation practices and other production practices on farm, ranch, and other working land profitability, including the effect on enhancing crop yields, soil health, ecosystem services, and other risk-reducing factors.

Additionally, USDA must

 establish a conservation and farm productivity secure data center that ensures the security, privacy, and integrity of data; make the results of the data collection and analysis available through the secure data center to academic institutions and researchers; and provide technical assistance, including through internet-based tools, based on the analysis conducted and other relevant data, to assist producers in improving sustainable production practices that increase yields and enhance environmental outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
