<bill session="116" type="h" number="255" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-20T13:53:18-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-11-20T13:53:18-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Big Bear Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an exchange of lands with San Bernardino County, California, to enhance management of lands within the San Bernardino National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Big Bear Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Big Bear Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Big Bear Land Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Big Bear Land Exchange Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2019-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-134.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-06-27" calendar="Union" number="98">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20T13:43:51-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Huffman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20T13:43:59-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9074-9075" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20T13:44:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 255.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-11-20T13:53:18-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9074" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20T13:53:20-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-380.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-10T14:50:19Z" status="Passed House">Big Bear Land Exchange Act

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to convey 73 acres of identified Forest Service land to the County of San Bernardino, California, in exchange for approximately 71 acres of identified land owned by the county.

Such land exchange must be for equal value. If the value of the federal land and the nonfederal land to be conveyed are not equal, the values may be equalized by a cash payment or by reducing the acreage of the federal land or the nonfederal land to be exchanged. At the option of the county, any excess value of the nonfederal lands may be considered as a gift to the United States.

Any cash equalization payment that USDA receives shall be available for USDA to acquire lands, waters, and interests in land for the San Bernardino National Forest.

Before completing the exchange, USDA must inspect the nonfederal lands to ensure that they meet federal standards, including for hazardous materials and land line surveys.

The nonfederal lands shall be added to and managed as part of San Bernardino National Forest.

Within three years of enactment of this bill, USDA must relocate the portion of the Pacific Crest National Scenic Trail that&#160;is located on the federal land to (1) adjacent National Forest System land; (2) land owned by the county, subject to county approval; (3) land within the federal land, subject to county approval; or (4) a combination of any of these.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-134</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
