<bill session="116" type="s" number="3246" updated="2022-09-04T07:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spectrum Management And Reallocation for Taxpayers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Federal Communications Commission to conduct a public auction of the C-band, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2020-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2020-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2020-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2956" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-25T14:53:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Spectrum Management And Reallocation for Taxpayers Act or the SMART Act

This bill authorizes the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to conduct a public auction of mid-band spectrum and places requirements on how the FCC must use the proceeds from such an auction.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the FCC to identify, clear, and auction mid-band spectrum. The bill also establishes a (1) C-Band Reimbursement and Implementation Fund to reimburse costs and incentivize license holders to reduce their usage of spectrum so that it may be auctioned, (2) Digital Divide Trust Fund for deployment of broadband infrastructure in unserved and underserved areas, and (3) Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Trust Fund for deployment of upgraded 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 services that use a digital or internet protocol-based system.

The FCC must use the proceeds from a spectrum auction authorized under this bill to (1) reimburse amounts borrowed from the general fund of the Treasury that were deposited into the C-Band Reimbursement and Implementation Fund, (2) deposit a specified amount into the general fund of the Treasury for the purpose of deficit reduction, and (3) deposit all remaining amounts in the Digital Divide Trust Fund and the Next Generation 9&#8211;1&#8211;1 Trust Fund.

Additionally, the bill prohibits an entity that poses a national security risk from participating in a spectrum auction.</summary>
</bill>
