<bill session="118" type="s" number="1728" updated="2025-11-19T04:18:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dark Web Interdiction Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dark Web Interdiction Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the delivery of opioids by means of the dark web, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3587" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-20T15:09:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dark Web Interdiction Act of 2023

This bill establishes enhanced criminal penalties for distributing controlled substances via the dark web. It also establishes other programs and requirements to address the use of the dark web for illicit drug activities. (Dark web means the portions of the internet with hidden sites and services that (1) are not generally searchable, and (2) can only be accessed with specialized devices or services that conceal the identities and locations of users.)

Specifically, the bill provides an enhanced criminal penalty for delivering, distributing, or dispensing controlled substances via the dark web.

The bill also provides statutory authority for the Joint Criminal Opioid and Darknet Enforcement Task Force, which supports the investigation and prosecution of drug offenses committed via the dark web domestically and internationally. In addition, the Department of Justice must report on how and to what extent virtual currencies are used for opioid distribution via the dark web.</summary>
</bill>
