<bill session="119" type="h" number="1258" updated="2025-05-06T13:51:06Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Contractor Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Contractor Cybersecurity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 41, United States Code, to require information technology contractors to maintain a vulnerability disclosure policy and program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-06T13:44:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Contractor Cybersecurity Act

This bill prohibits an executive agency from entering into a contract for information technology unless the contractor maintains a vulnerability disclosure policy (VDP) and program.

The contractor must report to the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) of the Department of Homeland Security, within seven days after the VDP is published&#160;and on an ongoing basis as vulnerability reports are received, information regarding

any valid or credible report of a not previously known public vulnerability on a system that uses commercial software or services that affect, or are likely to affect, other parties in government or industry once a patch or viable mitigation is available; andany other situation where the contractor determines it would be helpful or necessary to involve CISA.CISA must submit vulnerabilities to the MITRE Common Vulnerabilities and Exposures database and the National Institute of Standards and Technology National Vulnerability Database.</summary>
</bill>
