<bill session="116" type="h" number="7354" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to transfer certain National Forest System land in the State of Washington to Skamania County, Washington.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-27T22:12:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Act

This bill directs the Forest Service to convey to Skamania County inWashington, upon request of the county, all right, title, and interest of the United States in approximately 23.4 acres of National Forest System land, related infrastructure, and all improvements on the map titled Wind River Administrative Site Conveyance Proposal and dated February 7, 2020.

The conveyance shall be

 made by quitclaim deed; subject to a right-of-way and restrictive easement reservation for the protection of the Pacific Crest National Scenic Trail; and completed in accordance with certain Forest Service conveyance requirements, except that certain market value requirements shall not apply. The Forest Service must meet specified disclosure requirements for hazardous substances, pollutants, and contaminants and shall not otherwise be required to remediate or abate the hazardous substances, pollutants, or contaminants disclosed.

The lands and related infrastructure conveyed must be maintained by the county pursuant to standards established by the Department of the Interior regarding the preservation of historic property.</summary>
</bill>
