<bill session="117" type="s" number="3810" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Countermeasure Injury Compensation Fund Amendment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countermeasure Injury Compensation Fund Amendment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Countermeasure Injury Compensation Program with respect to COVID-19 vaccines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2022-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-16T22:20:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Countermeasure Injury Compensation Fund Amendment Act

This bill modifies a program that compensates individuals for injuries experienced due to medical countermeasures (e.g., vaccines) delivered during certain public health emergencies, including with respect to compensation for COVID-19 vaccine injuries.

The bill aligns award determination procedures and other aspects of the program with requirements under the Vaccine Injury Compensation Program, which provides compensation for injuries or deaths associated with routinely administered vaccines.

Additionally, the bill establishes a temporary commission to identify injuries caused by receipt of a COVID-19 vaccine. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must list all identified injuries in a table of conditions that are presumed to be caused by a COVID-19 vaccine, provided there is sufficient scientific evidence linking the injury to the vaccine. If HHS does not include an identified injury in the table, it must publish an explanation of that decision.

The bill also allows individuals to resubmit their COVID-19 vaccine compensation claims, including the amounts of previously approved claims, for reconsideration under the provisions set out in the bill.</summary>
</bill>
