<bill session="117" type="h" number="9662" updated="2023-03-03T17:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aviation WORKS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Workforce, Opportunity, Recruiting, Knowledge, and Supply Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation WORKS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 to extend the existing aviation workforce development programs and provide grants to develop aviation manufacturing and supplier workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5324" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-03T17:36:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Aviation Workforce, Opportunity, Recruiting, Knowledge, and Supply Act or the Aviation WORKS Act 

This bill extends through FY2028 and expands aviation workforce development programs of the Department of Transportation (DOT).

Specifically, the bill directs DOT to establish an aviation manufacturing development grant program to develop the aviation manufacturing and supplier workforce. It also requires DOT to develop and support the education of workers who design or produce any aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, or appliance, or a component, part, or system thereof, that (1) is produced under a production approval issued by the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), (2) has been issued a design approval by the FAA, or (3) has an active application for a design approval.

Additionally, DOT must establish a program to provide grants for eligible projects to plan, establish, and expand workforce development partnership programs in the aviation and aerospace industry sector.</summary>
</bill>
