<bill session="111" type="sr" number="176" updated="2017-12-13T21:27:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on United States policy during the political transition in Zimbabwe, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate on United States policy during the political transition in Zimbabwe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001266" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001162" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2009-06-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6389-6390" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6389-6390" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6386-6387" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Zimbabwe"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-16T19:40:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expresses the sense of the Senate that the U.S. government, in coordination with other democratic governments and international institutions, should: (1) continue to provide humanitarian assistance to the people of Zimbabwe; (2) make available increased resources for nongovernmental entities to provide assistance in the critical areas of education, health, water, and sanitation; (3) encourage international efforts to support reforms made by ministries within the government of Zimbabwe, especially the Ministry of Finance; (4) provide financial and technical assistance for efforts to enact a new constitution based on democratic values; (5) work with and encourage regional governments and leaders to promote human rights, the restoration of the rule of law, and economic growth in Zimbabwe; (6) maintain the existing ban on the transfer of defense items and services and the suspension of most non-humanitarian government-to-government assistance until there is demonstrable progress toward restoring the rule of law and respect for human rights in Zimbabwe; and (7) support the continuation of financial sanctions and travel bans against those individuals responsible for the deliberate breakdown of the rule of law in Zimbabwe.</summary>
</bill>
