<bill session="117" type="s" number="1875" updated="2023-02-14T14:28:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans' Emergency Care Claims Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide a deadline of 180 days for the filing of claims for payment for emergency treatment furnished to veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Emergency Care Claims Parity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Veterans' Emergency Care Claims Parity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-231.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2079-2080" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-04-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2079" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-04-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-11T10:32:40-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-11T10:41:12-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s5026"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2022-08-18T16:04:44Z" status="Passed Senate">Veterans' Emergency Care Claims Parity Act

This bill modifies certain deadlines for the submittal of claims by a non-Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) individual or entity seeking reimbursement for the provision of emergency treatment to a veteran. Specifically, a non-VA individual or entity seeking such reimbursement must submit a claim not later than 180 days after the treatment was provided. (Under the VA's current policy, such claims for unauthorized emergency care must generally be submitted within 90 days for conditions that are not service-connected and within two years for conditions that are service-connected.)

Veterans may not be held liable for payment if a claim was submitted by an individual or entity after the deadline due to an administrative error made by the individual or entity or by the VA.

The VA must publish information regarding emergency care authorization for non-VA providers on a publicly available VA website.</summary>
</bill>
