<bill session="109" type="s" number="2001" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:34Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Management Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the management of information technology within the Department of Veterans Affairs by providing for the Chief Information Officer of that Department to have authority over resources, budget, and personnel related to the support function of information technology, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Management Improvement Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4061" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Chief information officers"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning-programming-budgeting"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-17T19:39:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Management Improvement Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that the Chief Information Officer (CIO) of the Department of Veterans Affairs has the authority and control necessary for the development, approval, implementation, integration, and oversight of policies, procedures, processes, activities, and systems relating to the management of Department information technology.

Requires the: (1) Secretary to develop, implement, and maintain a process for the selection and oversight of information technology for the Department, including a strategic plan that includes performance measurements and an integrated enterprise architecture; and (2) CIO to review and update on an ongoing basis the plan and architecture.

Directs the CIO to select the CIOs for each of the Veterans Health Administration, Veterans Benefits Administration, and National Cemetery Administration, who will implement the plan and architecture within their departments.</summary>
</bill>
