<bill session="116" type="h" number="6586" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Media Accountability and Account Verification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the creation and use of fake social media accounts or profiles and the sending of fraudulent emails or other electronic messages, and to require certain social media companies to remove fake or harmful accounts and profiles from their platforms.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Media Accountability and Account Verification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000378"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-18T16:46:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Media Accountability and Account Verification Act

This bill requires a social media company to remove a deceptive or fraudulent account or profile from its platform and to verify the creator of an account that is alleged to be deceptive or fraudulent.

Specifically, a social media company must establish a means whereby a user may request the investigation and removal of a deceptive account or profile. The social media company must expeditiously remove or disable access to a deceptive account or profile and any materials or messages published therefrom.

Further, a social media company must notify a user who submits such a request of any reasons underlying a determination that an account or profile is not deceptive, and it must take escalating actions against an individual who makes false or bad faith requests for the investigation and removal of an account or profile.</summary>
</bill>
