<bill session="116" type="h" number="5456" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to permit leave to care for a domestic partner, parent-in-law, or adult child, or another related individual, who has a serious health condition, and to allow employees to take, as additional leave, parental involvement and family wellness leave to participate in or attend their children's and grandchildren's educational and extracurricular activities or meet family care needs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3071" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-03T13:07:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act

This bill amends the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to expand the number of individuals who are permitted to take leave under that Act.

The bill grants leave to private sector and federal employees to care for a domestic partner and any individual related by blood or affinity whose close association with such employees is the equivalent of a family relationship if (1) such individual has a serious health condition, or (2) there is a qualifying exigency due to such employees' active duty in the Armed Forces.

The bill entitles an employee who is a domestic partner, next of kin of a member of the Armed Forces, or any individual related by blood or affinity to a service member whose close association is the equivalent of a family relationship to take leave to care for the service member.

The bill entitles private&#160;sector and&#160;federal employees to take additional leave to participate in or attend their children's and grandchildren's school or community organization activities, meet routine family medical care needs, or care for their elderly relatives.</summary>
</bill>
