<bill session="117" type="s" number="3195" updated="2022-12-30T02:34:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Online Privacy Rights Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Online Privacy Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide consumers with foundational data privacy rights, create strong oversight mechanisms, and establish meaningful enforcement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-14T14:20:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Online Privacy Rights Act

This bill places requirements on entities that process or transfer a consumer's data.

Specifically, the bill requires such entities to

 make their privacy policy publicly available and provide an individual with access to their personal data; delete or correct, upon request, information in an individual's data; export, upon request, an individual's data in a human-readable and machine-readable format; establish data security practices to protect the confidentiality and accessibility of consumer data; and designate a privacy officer and a data security officer to implement and conduct privacy and data security programs and risk assessments. Further, the bill prohibits such entities from

 engaging in deceptive or harmful data practices; transferring an individual's data to a third party if the individual objects; processing or transferring an individual's sensitive data without affirmative express consent; processing or transferring data beyond what is reasonably necessary or for which they have obtained affirmative express consent; processing or transferring data on the basis of specified protected characteristics (e.g., race, religion, or gender); conditioning the provision of a service or product on an individual's agreement to waive their privacy rights; and retaliating against an employee who provides information about a potential violation of the bill's provisions, or who testifies or assists in an investigation or judicial proceeding concerning such a violation. The Federal Trade Commission must establish a new bureau to assist with enforcement of these provisions.</summary>
</bill>
