<bill session="108" type="s" number="2875" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to extend trade benefits to certain tents imported into the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend trade benefits to certain tents imported into the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3496" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4428" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Algeria"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Azerbaijan"/>
    <term name="Bahrain"/>
    <term name="Bangladesh"/>
    <term name="Boycott"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Central Asia"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial blacklisting"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Equality before the law"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Expropriation"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freedom of association"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Kuwait"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Morocco"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Oman"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Political participation"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Qatar"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="South Asia"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Arab Emirates"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-01T21:29:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the President to provide duty-free treatment for certain tents imported from Afghanistan, Algeria, Azerbaijan, Bahrain, Bangladesh, Egypt, Iraq, Kuwait, Lebanon, Morocco, Oman, Pakistan, Qatar, Saudi Arabia, Tunisia, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates, or Yemen (beneficiary countries).

Prohibits a country from being designated, and if designated, requires it to be withdrawn if it is: (1) listed by the U.S. Department of State as a state sponsor of terrorism; or (2) engaged in activities that undermine U.S. national security or foreign policy interests.

Requires the President, after one year and annually thereafter, to review and determine if a basis exists for withdrawal of such duty-free treatment, taking into consideration: (1) whether or not each beneficiary country has established, or is making continual progress toward establishing, a market-based economy, the rule of law and the right to due process, political pluralism, and other specified economic and political goals; (2) the country's record on activities that undermine U.S. national security or foreign policy interests, and support of a peaceful resolution of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict; (3) whether it is a signatory of the United Nations Declaration of Human Rights, does not engage in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights, and is making continuing and verifiable progress on the protection of internationally recognized human rights; (4) the country's participation in the primary, secondary, or tertiary economic boycott of Israel; and (5) whether it otherwise meets specified eligibility criteria of the Trade Act of 1974. Requires the President to terminate the designation of any beneficiary country determined no longer to meet the requirements of this Act.

Authorizes the President to designate the Palestinian Authority or its successor political entity as a beneficiary political entity, which, if so designated, shall be eligible for the duty-free treatment under this Act as if it were a beneficiary country, if the Authority: (1) does not participate in acts of terrorism, takes active measures to combat terrorism, and cooperates fully in international efforts to combat terrorism; (2) does not engage in activities that undermine U.S. national security or foreign policy interests; (3) does not engage in gross violations of internationally recognized human rights, and is making continuing and verifiable progress on the protection of internationally recognized human rights; and (4) accepts Israel's right to exist in peace within secure borders. Requires the President to terminate the designation of the Authority if it is determined that the Authority no longer meets such requirements.

Requires the President to notify Congress concerning the withdrawal of a country's or the Authority's designation.

Prescribes the rule of origin for tents imported directly from beneficiary countries. Requires that the sum of the cost or value of the materials produced in one or more beneficiary countries, plus the direct cost of processing operations performed in such beneficiary country or countries, be at least 35 percent of the appraised value of such article at the time it is entered into the U.S. customs territory.</summary>
</bill>
