<bill session="108" type="s" number="553" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow all businesses to make up to 24 transfers each month from interest-bearing transaction accounts to other transaction accounts , to require the payment of interest on reserves held for depository institutions at Federal reserve banks, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="758" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money supply"/>
    <term name="NOW accounts"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Business Checking Freedom Act of 2003 - Amends Federal law to authorize interest-bearing transaction accounts for all businesses, permitting up to 24 transfers per month (or any greater number the Federal Reserve Board may determine) to another account of the owner in the same institution.Authorizes the payment of interest by a Federal reserve bank at least quarterly on balances maintained there on behalf of a depository institution.Amends the Federal Reserve Act to revise the ratio of reserves a depository institution must maintain against its transaction accounts, permitting a ratio of zero.Directs the Federal Reserve banks in FY 2003 through 2007 to transfer to the Board for transfer to the Secretary of the Treasury, for deposit in the general fund, additional surplus funds equal to the net cost of their interest payments to depository institutions.</summary>
</bill>
