<bill session="116" type="s" number="3230" updated="2022-02-09T03:26:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TA SUPPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TA SUPPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technical Assistance for Small and Underserved Providers to Prevent Oversights and Refocus on Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for an extension of funding for technical assistance to small practices and practices in health professional shortage areas under the Merit-based Incentive Payment System (MIPS).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2020-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-18T21:26:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Technical Assistance for Small and Underserved Providers to Prevent Oversights and Refocus on Treatment Act or the TA SUPPORT Act

This bill reauthorizes funds through FY2025 for the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to contract with specified entities (e.g., quality improvement organizations) to provide technical assistance regarding the Merit-based Incentive Payment System (MIPS) and alternative payment models under Medicare, specifically for health professionals in practices with 15 or fewer professionals. (MIPS is an incentive program under Medicare that allows health professionals to receive payment adjustments based on certain performance measures.)</summary>
</bill>
