<bill session="116" type="h" number="729" updated="2022-11-01T14:32:39Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-10T17:48:21-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-10T17:48:21-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coastal and Great Lakes Communities Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to authorize grants to Indian Tribes to further achievement of Tribal coastal zone objectives, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Tribal Coastal Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Coastal Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coastal and Great Lakes Communities Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Coastal and Great Lakes Communities Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2019-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001094" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2019-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2019-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2019-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25">
      <text>Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-13">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-283.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-11-13" calendar="Union" number="228">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 228.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T18:39:07-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 748 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 729 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 116-40 shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole and shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:19:45-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 748 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:29:58-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 748.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9969-10005" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9978-9989" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:30:03-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 729 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. An amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 116-40 shall be considered as adopted in the House and in the Committee of the Whole and shall be considered as the original bill for the purpose of further amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:30:08-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 748 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:30:09-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Chellie Pingree to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T14:30:19-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 729.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T15:42:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Case amendment en bloc No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T15:53:11-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Case amendment en bloc No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T15:53:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T15:59:04-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T15:59:39-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:06:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Katko amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:09:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Katko amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:14:21-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crist amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:18:29-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crist amendment No. 12, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gosar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:19:52-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Panetta amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:21:48-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Panetta amendment No. 14, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Budd demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:22:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mucarsel-Powell amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:26:19-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mucarsel-Powell amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Budd demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:27:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Luria amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:32:34-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Luria amendment No. 26, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Budd demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:33:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 748, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Johnson (LA) amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T16:44:21-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Johnson (LA) amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Johnson (LA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:40:00-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 729.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:41:05-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:41:29-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="667" datetime="2019-12-10T17:48:21-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 262 - 151 (Roll no. 667).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:48:23-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table. Objection was heard.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:50:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Himes moved to reconsider the vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:50:23-05:00">
      <text>Ms. McCollum moved to table the motion to reconsider</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10T17:50:40-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair put the question on the motion to table the motion to reconsider and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Harris demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the motion to table the motion to reconsider H.R. 729 until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11T14:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10043-10044" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1023" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1314" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2185" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2189" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2405" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2551" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3115" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3541" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3596" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="754" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="910" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1069" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1342" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1730" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5986" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4401" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="729" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="748" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8632" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="5056" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h709"/>
    <amendment number="h708"/>
    <amendment number="h707"/>
    <amendment number="h706"/>
    <amendment number="h705"/>
    <amendment number="h704"/>
    <amendment number="h703"/>
    <amendment number="h702"/>
    <amendment number="h701"/>
    <amendment number="h700"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-08-10T19:37:07Z" status="Passed House">Coastal and Great Lakes Communities Enhancement Act

This bill addresses provisions related to coastal zone management, waterfronts, climate change, fish habitats, the Great Lakes, coastal science and data, and the National Sea Grant College Program.

TITLE I--COASTAL RESILIENCE AND ECONOMIC ENHANCEMENT

(Sec. 101) This section authorizes the Department of Commerce to award grants to Indian tribes to further achievement of any of the following tribal coastal zone objectives:

 protecting, restoring, or preserving areas in the zone that hold important ecological, cultural, or sacred significance for the tribes, or traditional, historic, and esthetic values essential to the tribes; preparing and implementing a special area management plan and technical planning for important coastal areas; and implementing any coastal or shoreline stabilization measure for the purpose of public safety, public access, or cultural or historical preservation. (Sec. 102) The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must award grants to state or local governments, Indian tribes, or nonprofit organizations to (1) implement climate-resilient living shoreline projects; and (2) encourage innovation in the use of natural materials to protect coastal communities, habitats, and natural system functions.

(Sec. 103) This section addresses the preservation and accessibility of waterfronts in coastal states.

NOAA must establish a Working Waterfront Task Force that will be designed to identify and address critical working waterfront needs with respect to cultural and economic importance, environmental threats, and market conditions for water-dependent businesses.

NOAA must also establish a Working Waterfront Grant Program. Under the program, NOAA may award grants to coastal states with approved working waterfront plans in place to preserve and expand access to coastal waters for people engaged in fishing, aquaculture, boat building, and other water-dependent businesses.

In addition, NOAA is authorized to award grants to coastal states for the purpose of developing or revising working waterfront plans.

States are allowed to allocate any grant money received to eligible local governments and other entities. Each state that is awarded a grant must contribute at least 25% of matching funds towards the total cost of the project carried out with the grant, subject to certain exceptions.

(Sec. 104) This section establishes the Working Waterfronts Preservation Loan Fund to provide loans to coastal states for the purpose of implementing working waterfront plans.

(Sec. 105) This section makes the District of Columbia eligible to receive federal coastal zone management funding, including flood mitigation and prevention funds.

(Sec. 106) Commerce must establish a coastal climate change adaptation preparedness and response program to (1) assist coastal states with voluntarily developing coastal climate change adaptation plans, and (2) provide financial and technical assistance and training for coastal states to implement the adaptation plans.

(Sec. 107) NOAA must update at least once every seven years its environmental sensitivity index products for each coastal area of the Great Lakes. An environmental sensitivity index product is a map or similar tool that is utilized to identify sensitive shoreline resources prior to an oil spill event.

(Sec. 108) Commerce may carry out a program to award competitive prizes to advance certain coastal risk reduction and resilience measures, including natural features such as dunes, reefs, and wetlands.

(Sec. 109) NOAA must identify and evaluate federal research activities regarding coastal risk reduction and resilience measures.

TITLE II--FISHERY RESEARCH AND CONSERVATION

Subtitle A--National Fish Habitat Conservation Through Partnerships

This subtitle establishes the National Fish Habitat Board to (1) encourage partnerships among public agencies and other interested parties to promote fish conservation, (2) establish national goals and priorities for fish habitat conservation, (3) recommend to Congress entities for designation as a Fish Habitat Partnership, and (4) review and make recommendations regarding fish habitat conservation projects.

The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, NOAA, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS) may provide technical and scientific assistance to the partnerships, participants in the fish habitat conservation projects, and the board.

Subtitle B--Great Lakes Fishery Research Authorization

 The USGS may conduct monitoring, scientific assessments, and research in support of fisheries within the Great Lakes Basin between the United States and Canada.

The USGS shall (1) execute a comprehensive, multi-lake, freshwater fisheries science program; (2) work cooperatively with regional, state, tribal, and local governments; and (3) consult with interested groups, including academia and Canadian agencies.

The USGS may provide

 deepwater ecosystem research, fish behavior and habitat reports, fish population assessments, invasive species research, use of biological equipment and laboratory capabilities necessary to support fishery management decisions, and studies that assess impacts on Great Lakes fishery resources. Subtitle C--Chesapeake Bay Oyster Research

NOAA must award grants to certain entities for collaborative research projects on the conservation, restoration, or management of oysters in the Chesapeake Bay.

TITLE III--MEETING 21ST CENTURY OCEAN AND COASTAL DATA NEEDS

Subtitle A--Digital Coast

This subtitle provides statutory authority for and revises NOAA's Digital Coast program. (The program currently exists under NOAA to provide data, tools, and training that communities use to manage their coastal resources.)

NOAA must focus on filling data needs and gaps for critical coastal management issues and support continued improvement in existing efforts to coordinate the acquisition and integration of key data sets needed for coastal management.

NOAA may enter into financial agreements and collect fees to carry out the program.

Subtitle B--Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System

This subtitle reauthorizes through FY2024 and revises the Integrated Coastal and Ocean Observation System Act of 2009.

TITLE IV--NATIONAL SEA GRANT COLLEGE PROGRAM AMENDMENTS

This title reauthorizes through FY2025 and revises the National Sea Grant College Program, through which NOAA supports university-based programs that focus on studying, conserving, and effectively using U.S. coastal resources.

Among other things, the title requires NOAA to award Dean John A. Knauss Marine Policy Fellowships. Currently, NOAA has discretion in awarding such fellowships. The fellowships support the placement of graduate students in fields related to ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources in positions with the executive and legislative branches.

The title reauthorizes through FY2025 grants for (1) university research on the biology, prevention, and control of aquatic nonnative species; (2) university research on oyster diseases, oyster restoration, and oyster-related human health risks; (3) university research on the biology, prevention, and forecasting of harmful algal blooms; and (4) fishery extension activities conducted by sea grant colleges or sea grant institutes to enhance existing core program funding.

The title authorizes grants for (1) priority issues identified in the National Sea Grant Program's strategic plan, and (2) university research on sustainable aquaculture techniques and technologies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-283</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
