<bill session="112" type="s" number="2048" updated="2019-11-15T21:52:17Z">
  <state datetime="2012-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the tax treatment of certain life insurance contract transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the tax treatment of certain life insurance contract transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4348" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1813" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-02T18:27:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the tax treatment of certain life insurance contract transactions, to require reporting to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) of: (1) information identifying persons who acquire a life insurance contract, or any interest therein, in a reportable policy sale; (2) information identifying a seller who transfers an interest in a life insurance contract and the seller's investment in the contract; and (3) reportable death benefit payments.

Requires a basis adjustment for mortality, expense, or other reasonable charges incurred under an annuity or life insurance contract.

Exempts from rules limiting the exclusion from gross income of life insurance death benefit&#160;amounts any amounts realized from the&#160;transfer of a life insurance contract, or any interest therein, that is a reportable policy sale.&#160; Defines "reportable policy sale" as the acquisition of an interest in a life insurance contract, directly or indirectly, if the acquirer has no substantial family, business, or financial relationship with the insured apart from the acquirer's interest in such life insurance contract.</summary>
</bill>
