<bill session="118" type="h" number="1550" updated="2025-05-06T18:51:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jobs and Opportunities for SNAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs and Opportunities for SNAP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to restore and standardize work requirements for able-bodied adults enrolled in the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1062" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-06T18:51:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Jobs and Opportunities for SNAP Act

This bill expands applicability of the work requirements for Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) recipients who are able-bodied adults without dependents (ABAWDs). (SNAP recipients who are ABAWDs have work-related requirements in addition to the general SNAP work registration and employment and training requirements.)

Specifically, this bill applies the work requirements for ABAWDs to adults who are not over 65 years old, whereas these requirements currently apply to adults who are not over 50 years old.

Further, the ABAWD exemption for a parent or household member with responsibility for a dependent child is restricted to a dependent child under the age of seven. Currently, the child must be under the age of 18.

The bill repeals COVID-19 public health emergency waivers issued for ABAWD work requirements.

The bill also repeals an ABAWD waiver program that allows state exemptions based on an area (1) having an unemployment rate of over 10%, or (2) not having a sufficient number of jobs.

Under current law, a state agency may exempt up to 12% of SNAP recipients from the ABAWD work requirements for each fiscal year; unused exemptions may be carried over and used in a subsequent fiscal year. The bill reduces the percentage of exemptions a state agency may provide to up to 3% of SNAP recipients and unused exemptions may not be carried over.</summary>
</bill>
