<bill session="108" type="s" number="1497" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Our Democracy, Our Airwaves Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to revise and expand the lowest unit cost provision applicable to political campaign broadcasts, to establish commercial broadcasting station minimum airtime requirements for candidate-centered and issue-centered programming before primary and general elections, to establish a voucher system for the purchase of commercial broadcast airtime for political advertisements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Our Democracy, Our Airwaves Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2003-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2003-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10272"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10272-10275" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Democratic Party"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="License agreements"/>
    <term name="Political parties"/>
    <term name="Politicians"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Press and politics"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Republican Party"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-10T20:34:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Our Democracy, Our Airwaves Act of 2003 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the lowest unit charge for radio or television broadcast time to a national committee of a political party acting on behalf of a candidate for public office. Prohibits a licensee of a broadcasting station, except under circumstances beyond its control, from preempting the use of such station by an eligible candidate or political committee who has paid for such use. Requires audits of stations to ensure the provision of broadcasting advertising time for political candidates. Provides minimum time requirements for candidate- or issue-centered broadcasts by stations.

Directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to establish and administer a voucher program for the purchase of airtime for political advertisements on radio and television broadcast stations by eligible candidates and political party committees as certified by the FCC. Provides maximum voucher amounts for both candidates and political committees. Allows such vouchers to be used exclusively for the purchase of airtime; but allows the transfer of vouchers between a political party and a candidate and vice versa. Requires the FCC to redeem all vouchers accepted by such stations. Provides for voucher expiration. Directs the FCC to establish the Political Advertising Voucher Account and to collect and deposit into it an annual spectrum use fee based on a percentage of a station's gross revenues. Directs the FCC to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to establish a standardized form for use by broadcasting stations to record and report the purchase of advertising time by or on behalf of a candidate for nomination for election, or for election, to Federal elective office.</summary>
</bill>
