<bill session="118" type="h" number="4543" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Timely Reporting of Election Results Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Timely Reporting of Election Results Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish certain requirements for the timely processing and reporting of results with respect to a District of Columbia election, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="text similarities"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4477" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-02T14:56:45Z" status="Introduced in House">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Timely Reporting of Election Results Act

This bill addresses the tabulation and reporting of election results in a District of Columbia election (i.e., any election for public office in the District of Columbia, including an election for federal office, a ballot initiative, or a referendum).

Under the bill, election officials must begin processing mail-in ballots as soon as they are received. The bill specifies that election results (1) may not be tabulated or reported to the public until after the polls close on election day,&#160;and (2) must be reported by 10 a.m. the next day.

Additionally, the bill requires election officials to make certain information available online, including the total number of voted ballots, the number of mail-in ballots, and the number of absentee ballots requested under the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act.

The bill also directs election officials to administer the election in a bipartisan manner, such as by pairing election workers of different political parties when one must enter a room containing election ballots.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
