<bill session="117" type="h" number="9690" updated="2023-03-06T16:00:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blocked Rail Crossings Safety Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blocked Rail Crossings Safety Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide for highway-rail grade crossing separation grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1356"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3698" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-06T15:50:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Blocked Rail Crossings Safety Improvement Act of 2021

This bill addresses safety and congestion along railroad right-of-way and highway-rail grade crossings.

For example, the bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to provide grants to (1) assist state, local, and tribal governments in funding the cost of highway-rail grade crossing separation projects; and (2) help nonprofit organizations carry out public information and education programs to help prevent and reduce rail-related pedestrian, motor vehicle, and other incidents, injuries, and fatalities, and to improve awareness along railroad right-of-way and at highway-rail grade crossings.

Additionally, the bill prohibits railroad carriers from obstructing travel at public highway-rail crossings for more than 10 minutes, except under limited circumstances (e.g., safety issues).

Further, DOT must (1) establish a national blocked crossings database for the public to report blocked crossing incidents; (2) conduct a comprehensive review of the national highway-rail crossing inventory; and (3) revise its regulations, guidance, or other relevant agency documents to include the number of suicides on a railroad crossing or railroad right-of-way in the total number of rail fatalities it reports each year.</summary>
</bill>
