<bill session="118" type="s" number="3355" updated="2025-06-24T22:41:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COLLEGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Changing Our Learning, Loans, Endowments, and Graduation Expectations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COLLEGE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require institutions of higher education participating in Federal financial aid programs to pay a percentage of the cost of attendance for each enrolled full-time student, based on the endowment fund of the institution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4772" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-28T17:31:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Changing Our Learning, Loans, Endowments, and Graduation Expectations Act or the COLLEGE Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to provide cost-match awards to enrolled students based on the size of the IHE's endowment fund, makes IHEs responsible for a percentage of the student loan balance of students who are in default, and establishes related reporting requirements.

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE that has an endowment fund that is greater than $1 billion to&#160;pay the covered percentage of the cost of attendance for each full-time student enrolled at the IHE.

Additionally, the bill requires&#160;an IHE to remit to the Department of Education (ED) an annually increasing percentage of the loan balance of students who are in default.

The bill also establishes certain reporting requirements, including by requiring IHEs and ED to report certain metrics related to student debt and academic programs.</summary>
</bill>
