<bill session="111" type="h" number="5290" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:11Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">More Doctors, More Choices Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To permit physicians and suppliers a new election to become Medicare participating physicians and suppliers if Medicare physician fee schedule rates are extended.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More Doctors, More Choices Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000554"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2010-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-18T14:41:49Z" status="Introduced in House">More Doctors, More Choices Act 0f 2010 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), if a Medicare SGR extension law is enacted during the 111th Congress, to permit a non-participating physician or supplier who furnishes (or may furnish) services for which payment is made under the Medicare physician fee schedule (or would be so made but for a private contract with a Medicare beneficiary) to elect during a certain period to become a Medicare participating physician or supplier.

Defines Medicare SGR extension law as one that extends or revises for at least one year the amount of the conversion factor used in updating payments under the physicians fee schedule so that it is not lower than the conversion factor for May 2010.</summary>
</bill>
