<bill session="110" type="h" number="90" updated="2021-04-20T13:07:45Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Full Disclosure in Lobbying Act</title>
    <title type="display">Full Disclosure in Lobbying Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require the disclosure of the original source of funds made payable to a lobbyist who is subcontracted to engage in lobbying activities on behalf of a third person or entity, and the disclosure of the identity of that third person or entity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2007-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2007-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-01-22T20:30:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Full Disclosure in Lobbying Act - Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to require a registered lobbyist's semiannual disclosure report, in the case of a registrant (subcontractor) retained by another person or entity to engage in lobbying activities on behalf of a third person or entity, to include: (1) the name, address, and principal place of business of the other person or entity that retained the subcontractor; (2) the name, address, and principal place of business of the third person or entity on whose behalf the lobbying activities were performed; and (3) the amount of funds paid, during such reporting period, to the subcontractor as well as to the other person or entity who retained the subcontractor for such lobbying activities.</summary>
</bill>
