<bill session="117" type="h" number="7227" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">INFORMS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Information on Federal Resources for Military Servicemembers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INFORMS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to create fact sheets, for veterans and for survivors of veterans, that compare benefits and compensation, to such individuals under laws administered by the Secretary, to monthly insurance benefits under title II of the Social Security Act, and to supplemental security income under title XVI of the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-24T18:16:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Information on Federal Resources for Military Servicemembers Act or the INFORMS Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to create fact sheets for veterans and survivors of deceased veterans to compare VA benefits and compensation, certain monthly insurance benefits under the Social Security Act, and supplemental security income for the aged, blind, and disabled under the Social Security Act. The fact sheets must be updated at least annually.

The VA must provide copies of such fact sheets whenever (1) an individual makes an initial claim for a benefit or compensation or a claim to increase a benefit or compensation; or (2) the VA notifies the individual it has denied a claim for, or decreased the amount of, a benefit or compensation.</summary>
</bill>
