<bill session="118" type="s" number="1591" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize dedicated domestic terrorism offices within the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, and the Federal Bureau of Investigation to analyze and monitor domestic terrorist activity and require the Federal Government to take steps to prevent domestic terrorism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2024-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1649-1650" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-02T16:04:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Domestic Terrorism Prevention Act of 2023

This bill establishes new requirements to expand the availability of information on domestic terrorism, as well as the relationship between domestic terrorism and hate crimes.

It authorizes domestic terrorism components within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of Justice (DOJ), and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to monitor, analyze, investigate, and prosecute domestic terrorism.

The domestic terrorism components of DHS, DOJ, and the FBI must jointly report on domestic terrorism, including white-supremacist-related incidents or attempted incidents.

DHS, DOJ, and the FBI must review the anti-terrorism training and resource programs of their agencies that are provided to federal, state, local, and tribal law enforcement agencies. Additionally, DOJ must make training on prosecuting domestic terrorism available to its prosecutors and to assistant U.S. attorneys.

It creates an interagency task force to analyze and combat white supremacist and neo-Nazi infiltration of the uniformed services and federal law enforcement agencies.

Finally, it directs the FBI to assign a special agent or hate crimes liaison to each field office to investigate hate crimes incidents with a nexus to domestic terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
