<bill session="117" type="h" number="3585" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REGROW Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Secretary of the Interior to establish a program to plug, remediate, and reclaim orphaned oil and gas wells and surrounding land, to provide funds to State and Tribal governments to plug, remediate, and reclaim orphaned oil and gas wells and surrounding land, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REGROW Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revive Economic Growth and Reclaim Orphaned Wells Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000377" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2021-08-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1076" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2377" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-03T15:59:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Revive Economic Growth and Reclaim Orphaned Wells Act of 2021 or the REGROW Act of 2021

This bill provides funding for grants to plug orphaned (i.e., abandoned) oil and gas wells, clean up pollution leaking from such wells, and conduct research and related activities.

Specifically, the bill provides funding for a grant program within the Department of the Interior to plug and clean up orphaned wells located on federal, state, tribal, and private land.

In addition, the bill provides funding to the Department of Energy and the Oil and Gas Compact Commission for conducting research and development activities to assist federal land management agencies, states, and Indian tribes in (1) identifying and characterizing undocumented orphaned wells, and (2) mitigating the environmental risks of undocumented orphaned wells.</summary>
</bill>
