<bill session="119" type="h" number="1491" updated="2025-11-18T19:47:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-01T14:34:05-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-01T14:34:05-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act</title>
    <title type="short">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make the postponement of certain deadlines by reason of disasters applicable to the limitation on credit or refund, and to take postponements into account for purposes of sending collection notices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001236" joined="2025-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 44 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 119-43.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-03-27" calendar="Union" number="30">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 30.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:22:48-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MO) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:23:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1353: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:23:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1491.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-31T17:35:53-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01T14:16:06-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1399: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="88" datetime="2025-04-01T14:34:05-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 88).</text>
      <reference ref="03/31/2025 CR H1353" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01T14:34:06-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1438" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-31T13:26:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Related Extension of Deadlines Act

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to treat the postponement of the federal tax return deadline due to a federally declared disaster or certain other events as an extension of such deadline for purposes of calculating the limit on a tax refund. The bill also provides that the IRS&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s deadline for sending certain notices includes such postponement.

Under current law, a tax refund claim must be filed within three years of the date that the federal tax return is filed. (Some exceptions apply.) The tax refund amount generally is limited to federal taxes paid within the three years preceding the tax refund claim plus any extension of the federal tax return deadline (lookback period). The postponement of the federal tax return deadline is not an extension for purposes of the&#160;lookback period. (Thus, certain tax payments made before the federal tax return is filed may be excluded from the lookback period.)

Under the bill, a federal tax return deadline postponed due to a federally declared disaster or certain other events must be treated as an extension of such deadline for purposes of the lookback period.

Under current law, the IRS is required to mail a notice and demand for tax payment within 60 days of an assessment but not before the tax payment due date.&#160;

The bill provides that the tax payment due date includes the postponement of the tax payment deadline due to a federally declared disaster or certain other events.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-43</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
