<bill session="116" type="s" number="3980" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Agriculture First Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Agriculture First Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prioritize the purchase of agricultural commodities from domestically owned enterprises, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000594"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-13T15:13:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Agriculture First Act 

This bill requires the Agricultural Marketing Service (AMS) to purchase at least 75% of an agricultural commodity for the Food Purchase and Distribution Program from domestically owned enterprises if it is necessary to respond to trade damage from retaliation by foreign nations with respect to the agricultural commodity.

The requirement does not apply if the Department of Agriculture reports to Congress that meeting the requirement

 is not possible because the quantity of the agricultural commodity available from domestically owned enterprises cannot meet the supply needs of the AMS; or would result in a greater than 150% increase between the amount necessary to purchase the agricultural commodity, and the average cost of the agricultural commodity purchased by the AMS in the prior three years. The authority provided by this bill expires on September 30, 2023.</summary>
</bill>
