<bill session="119" type="h" number="1508" updated="2025-08-30T08:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DHS Special Events Program and Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Special Events Program and Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize a program to assess the threat, vulnerability, and consequences of terrorism or other security threats, as appropriate, to certain events, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000621" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001221" joined="2025-08-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-09T18:51:44Z" status="Introduced in House">DHS Special Events Program and Support Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct security assessments and provide security and situational awareness support for pre-planned special events that are not designated as National Special Security Events. (National Special Security Events are major federal government or public events so designated by the President or&#160;DHS, such as presidential inaugurations, major international summits, and major sporting events.)

Under the bill, DHS must establish a standard process for federal, state, local, tribal, and territorial officials to voluntarily submit requests to DHS for event assessment and possible security and situational awareness support. DHS must assess such requests using a risk-based methodology and include a process for expedited consideration and, where appropriate, for reassessment.

DHS must also carry out research and development of technologies and techniques for enhancing DHS's security and situational awareness support to such officials relating to mass gatherings in a manner consistent with constitutional, privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections.</summary>
</bill>
