<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1407</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T06:02:43Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T06:02:43Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-07-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-07-15T21:41:00Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>E000286</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Edwards, John [D-NC]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>EDWARDS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NC</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Air pollution control</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Animals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Business records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Farm manure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Feedlots</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fines (Penalties)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Livestock</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Soil conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Soil pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Standards</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Waste disposal sites</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water pollution control</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Environmental Protection</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-07-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-09-12T14:49:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Concentrated Livestock Existing Alongside Nature Act - Prohibits the application of animal waste to land where the nitrogen or phosphorus would increase the risk of soil toxicity or surface or ground water pollution. <p>Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish: (1) permitted levels for other substances found in animal waste; and (2) minimal distances from environmentally sensitive locations or high density or sensitive populations for the aerial spraying of animal waste. <p>Requires a containment system for the retention of all animal waste, both wet and dry, including the construction and use of certain structures to store excess waste. Stipulates that these systems and structures have sufficient structural integrity and/or emergency shutoff devices and be sited in such a way as to eliminate or contain discharges and pollution. <p>Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator to promulgate national primary ambient air quality standards for hydrogen sulfide and ammonia as measured at any point on the property line of a concentrated animal feeding operation (CAFO). <p>Directs the Administrator to establish an animal waste management program which requires animal owners to have an approved animal waste management plan designed to prevent the discharge of animal waste into surface or ground water. Requires the Administrator to develop plan requirements in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture. <p>Requires the Administrator to: (1) compel the closure of any CAFO operating without an approved plan; and (2) review and modify plans where it is administratively determined that a CAFO has caused significant water pollution. <p>Waives Federal requirements where State requirements exist that are equally or more stringent. <p>Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to exclude the expansion of a CAFO from cost-share payments under that Act. Includes, however, as part of the environmental quality incentives program, an animal waste management plan developed by a livestock operator too small to be considered a CAFO.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Concentrated Livestock Existing Alongside Nature Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Concentrated Livestock Existing Alongside Nature Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to regulate concentrated animal feeding operations for the protection of the environment and public health, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Concentrated Livestock Existing Alongside Nature Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-07-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-07-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
