<bill session="116" type="s" number="3604" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency and Oversight of COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Small Business Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency and Oversight of COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Small Business Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to report on COVID-19 recovery small business programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-18T13:44:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transparency and Oversight of COVID-19 Small Business Assistance Act

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to report specified data on economic relief programs implemented in response to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the SBA must

 daily report the total number and dollar amount of loans or grants approved and disbursed under programs such as the paycheck protection program and the emergency grants program; daily report the amount of remaining authority and funds appropriated for such programs and an estimate of the date on which such funds will be depleted; weekly report the number and dollar amount of certain program loans and loan payments disaggregated by specified metrics such as geography, demographics, loan sizes, industry, and lender type; report on the number of employees expected to be retained by borrowers of certain loans as a result of economic relief programs; report its plans to carry out specified relief programs and identify and prevent waste, fraud, and abuse in such programs; request certain information such as demographic and job information when a borrower applies for loan forgiveness; and make each required report publicly available and take all necessary steps to protect sensitive personally identifiable information. The Government Accountability Office must report specified information, including (1) the effectiveness of certain programs in reaching underserved businesses, (2) a review of the reports required to be published under this bill, and (3) the impact of certain relief programs on jobs.</summary>
</bill>
