<bill session="109" type="h" number="5417" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:27Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet Freedom and Nondiscrimination Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clayton Act with respect to competitive and nondiscriminatory access to the Internet.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Internet Freedom and Nondiscrimination Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Freedom and Nondiscrimination Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="popular">Network Neutrality bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2006-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2006-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000108" joined="2006-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 20 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-541.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-29" calendar="Union" number="303">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 303.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-26T20:54:30Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Internet Freedom and Nondiscrimination Act of 2006 - Amends the Clayton Act to prohibit any broadband network provider from: (1) failing to provide its services on reasonable and nondiscriminatory terms; (2) refusing to interconnect its facilities with those of another service provider on reasonable and nondiscriminatory terms; (3) blocking, impairing, discriminating against, or interfering with any person's ability to use a broadband network service to access or offer lawful content, applications, or services over the Internet (or imposing an additional charge to avoid such prohibited conduct); (4) prohibiting a user from attaching or using a device on the provider's network that does not physically damage or materially degrade other users' utilization of the network; or (5) failing to clearly and conspicuously disclose to users accurate information concerning service terms.

Requires a provider that prioritizes or offers enhanced quality of service to data of a particular type to prioritize or offer enhanced quality of service to all data of that type without imposing a surcharge or other consideration.

Permits a provider to take reasonable and nondiscriminatory measures to: (1) manage the functioning of its network and services; (2) give priority to emergency communications; (3) prevent a violation of federal or state law; (4) offer consumer protection services; (5) offer special promotional pricing or other marketing initiatives; or (6) prioritize or offer enhanced quality of service to all data of a particular type without imposing a surcharge or other consideration.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-541</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
