<bill session="117" type="s" number="4140" updated="2022-12-29T16:33:52Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAST Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAST Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Accountability and Security in Transitions Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 22 of title 44, United States Code, to ensure Presidential records are preserved, duly created when non-official electronic messaging accounts are used, and made available to the public and the next administration in a timely fashion to advance national security and accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7605" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-19T15:13:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Accountability and Security in Transitions Act of 2022 or the PAST Act of 2022

This bill revises requirements for preservation of presidential records and requires that information be made available to the next administration in a timely fashion.

Specifically, the bill (1) requires the President to receive written guidance from the National Archives and Records Administration (NARA) before destroying any records, (2) prohibits White House staff from using nonofficial electronic messaging accounts that cannot be easily copied or forwarded to official accounts, (3) establishes consequences for former Presidents who destroy presidential records, (4) requires former Presidents to cover the cost of digitizing records for display in a presidential library, and (5) requires NARA to ensure that newly inaugurated Presidents are granted easy access to national security information.</summary>
</bill>
