<bill session="117" type="s" number="1002" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Junk Plan Accountability and Disclosure Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit false or misleading advertising for health insurance coverage, require warnings and reporting with respect to noncomprehensive health plans, encourage enrollment in health plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Junk Plan Accountability and Disclosure Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="908" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1796" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1806" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1872" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1874" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-13T19:00:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Junk Plan Accountability and Disclosure Act of 2021 This bill establishes requirements for certain noncomprehensive health insurance coverage and provides for additional outreach activities to increase enrollment in qualified health plans.

Specifically, the bill prohibits online advertisements for health insurance coverage that reasonably mislead an individual (1) to believe that the advertisement is on behalf of a government entity such as a state or federal health insurance exchange, or (2) about the cost or benefits of noncomprehensive coverage (e.g., short-term, limited-duration insurance) compared to a qualified health plan under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act. The bill provides authority for the Federal Trade Commission to enforce these prohibitions. The bill also requires certain types of coverage (e.g., coverage for nontraditional benefits or student health insurance coverage) to provide consumers with a clear statement indicating the benefits the coverage provides and that the coverage is not a comprehensive health plan. These plans also must meet specified reporting requirements.

In states with a federally administered exchange, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must conduct outreach and educational activities to individuals about the availability of qualified health plans through the exchange. The bill also provides grants for states to conduct open enrollment outreach with respect to qualified health plans and to explore solutions to promote greater enrollment. The bill provides funding for these outreach activities.</summary>
</bill>
