<bill session="119" type="s" number="1540" updated="2025-11-18T17:57:04Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness for Victims of SNAP Skimming Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Victims of SNAP Skimming Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2023, to expand the replacement of stolen EBT benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3117" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-23T15:16:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness for Victims of SNAP Skimming Act of 2025

This bill requires the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) to provide for the replacement of the full amount of a household's stolen benefits.

Specifically, using funds provided by the Department of Agriculture, a state agency must provide a household with replacement SNAP benefits equal to the amount of benefits&#160;stolen through card skimming, card cloning, or similar fraudulent methods. This requirement applies if the state agency determines that the benefits were stolen and meets certain requirements.&#160;

Under current law, a state agency may only replace SNAP benefits that were stolen between the period beginning on October 1, 2022, and ending on December 20, 2024. Further,&#160;the replacement amount is limited to the lesser of the amount of (1) the benefits stolen, or (2) two months of the&#160;household's monthly allotment immediately prior to the date on which the benefits were stolen. Thus, this bill permanently extends the provision and provides for the replacement of the full amount of the benefits stolen.</summary>
</bill>
