<bill session="119" type="s" number="3085" updated="2025-11-18T19:19:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that certain operations, functions, and services of the Federal Government relating to enforcement of firearms laws and firearm export licensing continue during a lapse in appropriations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000312" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5874" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-10T17:20:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Firearm Access During Shutdowns Act of 2025

This bill requires various federal agencies to continue certain operations, functions, and services related to firearms during a government shutdown.

The bill applies to&#160;

the Federal Bureau of Investigation's National Instant Criminal Background Check System, including the processing of background checks in support of the operations of the Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF);the ATF's Directorate of Enforcement Programs and Services;the activities of the Department of Commerce's Bureau of Industry and Security relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses; andthe activities of the Department of State's Directorate of Defense Trade Controls relating to firearms and firearm-related products, including activities related to processing of applications for export licenses.Under the bill, (1) these operations, functions, and services are deemed to relate to an emergency involving the safety of human life or the protection of property; and (2) employees carrying out the operations, functions, and services are deemed to be excepted employees. (Under an exception in&#160;the Antideficiency Act, an employee whose duties involve the safety of human life or the protection of property may be required to work during a government shutdown. Employees who are required to work during a government shutdown because they fall under this or other exceptions are known as excepted employees.)</summary>
</bill>
