<bill session="116" type="s" number="4776" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to reduce the amount provided to agencies that do not comply with reasonable vehicle utilization standards and to establish methods and procedures for evaluating vehicle fleets.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the amount provided to agencies that do not comply with reasonable vehicle utilization standards and to establish methods and procedures for evaluating vehicle fleets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2020-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-14T15:23:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill reduces funding for executive agencies that do not comply with reasonable vehicle utilization standards and establish uniform methods and procedures for evaluating vehicle fleets.

Specifically, the bill directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish vehicle usage standards for the executive branch and uniform methods and procedures (1) for use by agencies in determining the appropriate size of their vehicle fleet, and (2) that require the vehicle fleet management component of the agency to maintain the procedures and documentation for deciding to keep a vehicle in an easily accessible manner.

The GSA must make publicly available the government-wide vehicle usage standards, including documentation requirements and metrics, and the uniform vehicle fleet methods and procedures.

An agency may establish and implement separate vehicle usage standards, subject to annual review by the GSA. The bill provides for a reduction in budget for weaker standards or for failure to implement standards.

The bill requires (1) each agency to document an annual review of the vehicle fleet to identify underutilized vehicles and actions taken to remove such vehicles from the fleet or a justification for their continued use, and (2) the inspector general of each agency to conduct audits at least once every two years of vehicle fleet management practices.</summary>
</bill>
