<bill session="117" type="h" number="7357" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REACT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Response from Executive Agencies to Congress on Time Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require an executive agency to submit information to any committee of the House of Representatives upon the request of 7 of the members of the committee, and to submit information to any committee of the Senate upon the request of 5 of the members of the committee, if the information relates to any matter under the jurisdiction of the committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2022-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-28T18:06:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Response from Executive Agencies to Congress on Time Act or the REACT Act

This bill requires federal agencies to provide certain information at the request of additional congressional committees and specifies that agencies must respond to such requests within 45 days.

Under current law, agencies must supply information requested by the Committee on Government Operations of the House of Representatives (or any seven of its members) or the Committee on Government Affairs of the Senate (or any five of its members), provided that the requested information relates to matters within the committees' respective jurisdictions. This bill also requires agencies to supply information requested by authorizing committees or permanent select committees.</summary>
</bill>
