<bill session="116" type="s" number="314" updated="2022-11-01T15:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing the Trusted Workforce for the 21st Century Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Trusted Workforce for the 21st Century Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the processing and oversight by the Federal Government of security clearances and background investigations and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="245" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1589" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-11T15:11:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Modernizing the Trusted Workforce for the 21st Century Act of 2019

This bill directs various agencies to report on, and devise plans to improve, systems for handling security clearances and background checks.

The Security, Suitability, and Credentialing Performance Accountability Council shall provide Congress with a plan to reduce the background investigation backlog and to consolidate security clearance processes to improve efficiency.

The Director of National Intelligence, or another individual selected by the President, shall serve as the Security Executive Agent for all U.S. departments and agencies. The agent shall establish a policy and implementation plan for improving security clearance procedures.

The agent shall report to Congress on (1) ways to improve or simplify investigation procedures; (2) the feasibility of the clearance in person concept, which permits an individual to maintain access to classified information for up to three years after leaving a cleared position; and (3) protections for the confidentiality of whistleblower-related communications in continuous vetting programs.

Federal departments and agencies shall report annually to the agent certain information related to reciprocal recognition of security clearances when an individual moves between positions within the department or agency, and the agent shall summarize and report such information to Congress.

The bill imposes various targets for reducing the pendency of secret and top secret level clearance determinations. It also requires reports to Congress on various topics, such as the feasibility of having no more than three tiers of trust and security clearance positions.</summary>
</bill>
