<bill session="116" type="h" number="5666" updated="2022-08-10T23:33:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the programs of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2020-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-23T20:26:22Z" status="Introduced in House">National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2020

The bill reauthorizes the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) through FY2020.

The bill authorizes NASA programs, activities, reports, and reviews, including those regarding a Moon to Mars Program, low-earth orbit activities, small satellites, commercial Earth observation, the wide field infrared survey telescope, the stratospheric observatory for infrared astronomy, Mars communications infrastructure, a commercial lunar payload services program, a dedicated space-based infrared survey telescope mission, near-Earth objects, a space weather research to operations program, testing facilities for in-space propulsion, space nuclear systems, and orbital debris mitigation.

NASA shall

 arrange for a review of the Human Research program related to long-term human spaceflight, continue operations of the International Space Station (ISS) through at least 2028, transmit an ISS Deorbit Capability and Plan, arrange for the development of a comprehensive set of requirements to support life and physical sciences research in microgravity following the end of ISS operations, develop a Mars sample return strategy and plan, establish a data science and management initiative, arrange for a review of the University Leadership Initiative, and arrange for a review of the National Space Grant College and Fellowship Program. To advance progress toward federal STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) education goals, NASA shall establish an Office of STEM Engagement.

The Government Accountability Office shall, among other things, review NASA's space communications and navigation programs, activities, and plans.</summary>
</bill>
