<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="1611" updated="2022-02-03T04:58:52Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2660" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-09-10">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-09-10"/>
  <description>To prohibit funds appropriated in this Act from being used by the Department of Education to enforce any requirement under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, or to implement penalties or sanctions under part A of title I of such Act, if the amount appropriated to carry out such part A for fiscal year 2004 is less than $18,500,000,000.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-09-10" how="roll" result="fail" roll="342">
      <text>Amendment SA 1611 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 28 - 67. Record Vote Number: 342.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Amendment SA 1611 proposed by Senator Durbin to Amendment SA 1542. (consideration: CR S11285-11290, S11295-11296; text: CR S11286-11287) To prohibit funds appropriated in this Act from being used by the Department of Education to enforce any requirement under section 1116 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, or to implement penalties or sanctions under part A of title I of such Act, if the amount appropriated to carry out such part A for fiscal year 2004 is less than $18,500,000,000.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1611 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 28 - 67. Record Vote Number: 342.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 1611 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 28 - 67. Record Vote Number: 342.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1611 proposed by Senator Durbin to Amendment SA 1542.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11285-11290, S11295-11296" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11286-11287" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
