<bill session="116" type="s" number="1738" updated="2022-11-01T06:32:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Workforce DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce DATA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Data for Analyzing and Tracking Automation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Labor to take initiatives to measure the impact of automation on the workforce in order to inform workforce development strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-02T14:09:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Workforce Data for Analyzing and Tracking Automation Act of 2019 or the Workforce DATA Act

This bill provides for a study by the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine on measuring the impact of automation on the workforce.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Labor to request the academies to enter into an arrangement to conduct a consensus study on how to measure the impact of automation on the workforce, including job creation, job displacement, job retention, and the shifting of skills in demand due to automation.

In addition, Labor must establish an advisory board, or form a subcommittee of an existing advisory board, to provide recommendations on addressing the impact of automation on the workforce.</summary>
</bill>
