<bill session="118" type="h" number="1138" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prohibit Insider Trading Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prohibit Insider Trading Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit transactions involving certain financial instruments by Members of Congress and their spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000308" joined="2023-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2023-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2023-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-17T20:09:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibiting Insider Trading Act

This bill prohibits Members of Congress (or their spouses) from holding or trading certain investments (e.g., individual stocks and related financial instruments other than diversified investment funds, investments in the federal retirement savings plan, or U.S. Treasury securities).

Generally, the prohibition applies seven days after the first day of a Member's initial term, though for current Members, it applies on the first day of the second session of the 118th Congress. Additionally, the prohibition does not apply to assets held in a qualified blind trust.

Any profit stemming from a prohibited holding or transaction must be disgorged to the Treasury and may subject the Member to a civil fine. Additionally, a loss stemming from a prohibited holding or transaction may not be used as an income tax deduction.

Each Member must submit an annual certification of compliance to the supervising ethics office. The office must publish each certification on a public website and periodically audit Members' compliance with the bill's provisions.</summary>
</bill>
