<bill session="108" type="s" number="2063" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a demonstration project on priorities in the scheduling of appointments of veterans for health care through the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a demonstration project on priorities in the scheduling of appointments of veterans for health care through the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000705"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000352" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2004-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S807-808"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S808" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3812" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-23T19:58:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) carry out a demonstration project to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing for priorities in scheduling appointments for health care through the Department of Veterans Affairs in accordance with the Department's Waiting Time for Appointments goals (30-30-20) of 2000 and the provisions of the Veterans Health Administration directives entitled Priority for Outpatient Medical Services and Inpatient Hospital Care (VHA Directive 2002-059) and Priority Scheduling for Outpatient Medical Services and Inpatient Hospital Care for Service Connected Veterans (VHA Directive 2003-062); (2) select three Veterans Integrated Service Networks for the project and ensure that the project is carried out in urban, rural, and highly rural areas; (3) schedule each appointment under the project at a Department facility unless the cost is unreasonable or medical or other reasons necessitate an appointment at a non-Department facility.

Requires the Secretary to report to the Committees on Veterans' Affairs in the Senate and the House of Representatives annually on waiting times of veterans for Department health care appointments.</summary>
</bill>
