<bill session="118" type="s" number="953" updated="2025-11-12T00:38:24Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Health Innovation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a rural health center innovation awards program and a rural health department enhancement program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Innovation Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1712" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-20T23:19:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Health Innovation Act of 2023

This bill establishes two grant programs to increase access to emergency care in rural areas. The Federal Office of Rural Health Policy within the Health Resources and Services Administration must manage these programs.

First, the office must provide grants to federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics to enhance the provision of walk-in urgent care, triage, and other emergency services in rural areas.

Second, the office must provide grants to health departments in rural areas for emergency services (including triage and transport to emergency departments), primary care services, and similar services provided by emergency departments.

Recipients of these grants may use funds for staffing, equipment, and other necessary expenses to provide emergency services.</summary>
</bill>
