<bill session="108" type="sc" number="149" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:29Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution commending the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and its employees for its dedication and hard work during Hurricanes Charley, Frances, Ivan, and Jeanne.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution commending the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and its employees for its dedication and hard work during Hurricanes Charley, Frances, Ivan, and Jeanne.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11505-11506" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11505-11506" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11504-11505" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T09:45:14-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T16:48:17-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="hc" number="488" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-10T21:16:08Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Declares that Congress commends the employees of the National Weather Service for their extraordinary dedication and hard work during Hurricanes Charley, Frances, Ivan, and Jeanne, especially: (1) the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) Tropical Prediction Center/National Hurricane Center, Hydrometeorological Prediction Center, and National Data Buoy Center; (2) the NOAA Aircraft Operations Center at MacDill Air Force Base, Tampa, Florida; (3) the 53rd Weather Reconnaissance Squadron of the 403rd Wing of the Air Force Reserve Command at Keesler Air Force Base, Biloxi, Mississippi; (4) the Hurricane Liaison Team; (5) the National Ocean Service; and (6) the National Environmental Satellite Data and Information Service.

Declares that Congress commends the Southern, Eastern, and Central Region Weather Forecast Offices of San Juan, Miami, Tampa Bay, Key West, Melbourne, Jacksonville, Tallahassee, Atlanta, Birmingham, Huntsville, Mobile, Morristown, Charleston, Morehead City, Wilmington, Wakefield, Taunton, Lake Charles, New Orleans, Jackson, Nashville, and Houston for their extraordinary dedication and hard work during such Hurricanes.

Declares that Congress: (1) commends the employees of the Office of Oceanic and Atmospheric Research, especially the Hurricane Research Division; (2) thanks the commercial and media meteorologists for their contributions in disseminating the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration forecasts and warnings to the public; and (3) expresses its support for the ongoing hard work and dedication of all who provide accurate and timely hurricane forecasts.</summary>
</bill>
