<bill session="116" type="s" number="2921" updated="2022-10-28T02:00:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">C-BAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">C-BAND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clearing Broad Airwaves for New Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for an auction of C-Band spectrum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4855" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-23T16:55:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clearing Broad Airwaves for New Deployment Act or the C-BAND Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to make between 200 and 300 megahertz of C-Band spectrum available for reallocation and the assignment of licenses through a system of competitive bidding.

C-Band spectrum is electromagnetic spectrum between the frequencies of 3700 and 4200 megahertz. Such spectrum shall be for the provision of broadband internet access service, and the clearing and reallocation shall take place in a manner that ensures C-Band-dependent users (1) receive equal or better service than was previously available, and (2) receive such service continuously throughout the transition process.

In addition, specified proceeds from such spectrum auctions shall be made available to the FCC for the build out and maintenance of rural broadband infrastructure in unserved rural communities.</summary>
</bill>
