<bill session="118" type="h" number="9333" updated="2024-11-19T09:05:28Z">
  <state datetime="2024-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IVF for Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IVF for Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an income tax credit for the costs of certain fertility treatments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000398"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2024-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2024-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-04T23:30:20Z" status="Introduced in House">IVF for Families Act

This bill establishes a nonrefundable tax credit of up to $15,000 for qualified fertility treatment expenses paid or incurred during the tax year.

Expenses that qualify for the tax credit include any amounts paid or incurred for procedures intended to facilitate pregnancy, including those that involve the handling of human egg, sperm, or embryo outside of the body (e.g., in vitro fertilization), and those that do not involve the handling of human egg, sperm, or embryo outside of the body (e.g., ovulation induction).

The tax credit may not be claimed for any fertility treatment expenses that were reimbursed by insurance or that are used to claim another tax credit or deduction.

Taxpayers who are married at the end of the tax year must file a joint return to claim the tax credit. The requirement to file a joint return does not apply to individuals legally separated, divorced, and some married individuals living apart.</summary>
</bill>
