<bill session="117" type="s" number="3317" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Madeleine K. Albright Democracy in the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Democracy in the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Madeleine K. Albright Democracy in the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen United States national security through the defense of democracy abroad and to address contemporary threats to democracy around the world, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2021-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-07-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="456">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8708" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-08T12:05:36Z" status="Reported to Senate">Madeleine K. Albright Democracy in the 21st Century Act 

This bill establishes programs to promote democracy abroad, authorizes Department of State and U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) democracy programs from FY2023 through FY2027, and addresses related issues.

The State Department must establish programs (1) to defend democracy globally, including by enhancing the ability of the State Department and USAID to respond quickly and flexibly to democratic openings and backsliding; (2) to support efforts to enhance government transparency and other activities related to reducing corruption; and (3) for democracy research and development, such as activities to drive innovation in State Department, USAID, and National Endowment for Democracy (NED) responses to complex challenges to democracy.

The bill establishes the Democracy in the 21st Century Fund, to be administered by the State Department, to support the programs established by this bill and other related activities.

U.S. government assistance for democracy programs shall not be subject to the prior approval of any foreign government.

The bill also protects the identities of implementing partners of certain State Department, USAID, and NED assistance programs in countries that are undemocratic or have engaged in gross violations of civil and political rights, including by exempting the names of partners for democracy programs in such countries from Freedom of Information Act requests.

The President must report to Congress a comprehensive strategy to promote democracy abroad.</summary>
</bill>
