<bill session="117" type="h" number="8270" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Advance Refill Notification Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Advance Refill Notification Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage to provide notices relating to prescription drug refills to individuals covered under such plans or coverage who reside in emergency areas during emergency periods.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2022-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-16T20:17:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Advance Refill Notification Act of 2022

This bill requires private health insurance plans that cover prescription drugs to notify plan holders about the plan's policy concerning advance drug refills in response to a national or public health emergency. Specifically, the plan must notify plan holders in emergency areas whether the plan is waiving time limits on authorized prescription refills and, if so, the process for obtaining an early refill. Plans must issue such notification within five days of an emergency being declared. Concerning the public health emergency declared in response to COVID-19, a plan must provide initial notification of its waiver policy not later than five days after this bill is enacted.</summary>
</bill>
