<bill session="108" type="s" number="2518" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Omnibus Low-Level Radioactive Waste Interstate Compact Consent Act to make the consent of Congress to certain compacts contingent on party states sharing the long-term liability for damages caused by radioactive releases from regional facilities.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Low-Level Radioactive Waste Interstate Compact Consent Act to make the consent of Congress to certain compacts contingent on party states sharing the long-term liability for damages caused by radioactive releases from regional facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000180"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-01T13:42:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Omnibus Low-Level Radioactive Waste Interstate Compact Consent Act to state that Congress grants its consent only if the Compact provides that all party States to the Compact are jointly and severally liable for the cost of long-term liability incurred in connection with the radioactive release from a regional facility in a Compact host State (in excess of funds available from the extended care and long-term liability fund of the host State and from property and third-party liability insurance), based on the proportionate share of the total volume of waste placed in the regional facilities by generators located in each party state.

Declares this condition inapplicable to a party State with a total volume of waste recorded on low-level radioactive waste manifests for any year that is less than ten percent of the total volume recorded on those manifests for the region during the same year.</summary>
</bill>
