<bill session="118" type="s" number="3227" updated="2025-11-19T03:55:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paperwork Burden Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paperwork Burden Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an alternative manner of furnishing certain health insurance coverage statements to individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2023-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2023-11-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5361" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3202" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-21T16:38:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Paperwork Burden Reduction Act

This bill modifies provisions under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act so that employers and health insurance providers are no longer required to send tax forms to covered individuals showing proof of minimum essential coverage (1095-B and 1095-C tax forms) unless a form is requested.

Currently, employers and health insurance providers that provide minimum essential coverage must report this information for each covered individual to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and provide a copy of this information to the covered individual (through 1095-B and 1095-C tax forms) by January 31 of each year.

The IRS allows for 1095-B tax forms, which are sent by certain health insurance providers and employers, to be made available to individuals only upon request. The bill provides statutory authority for this flexibility and extends this flexibility to 1095-C tax forms, which are sent by certain large employers. Such requests must be fulfilled by January 31 or 30 days after the date of the request, whichever is later. Employers and health insurance providers must give individuals timely notice of this option, in accordance with any requirements set by the IRS.</summary>
</bill>
