<bill session="108" type="h" number="1944" updated="2023-01-15T15:18:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Essential Air Service Eligibility Fairness Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise eligibility requirements applicable to essential air service subsidies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Essential Air Service Eligibility Fairness Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000373"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000280" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000169" joined="2003-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E845"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="975" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-17T11:34:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Essential Air Service Eligibility Fairness Act of 2003 - Amends Federal transportation law to revise eligibility requirements with respect to the provision of essential air service subsidies to communities in the 48 contiguous States to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from providing such assistance to a community that is less than 70 miles from the nearest hub airport or requires a rate of subsidy per passenger in excess of $200, unless such community is greater than 210 miles from the nearest hub airport. Repeals specified provisions of Federal laws with respect to such eligibility requirements. Authorizes a community in which the Secretary has eliminated subsidies or terminated subsidy eligibility (between September 30, 1993, and the enactment of this Act) under specified Federal laws to request the Secretary to review such action. Requires the Secretary after receiving a request for a review to: (1) determine whether the community would have been subject to such elimination of subsidies or termination of eligibility under the distance requirements provided in this Act; and (2) issue a final order with respect to the eligibility of such community for essential air service subsidies under the amended requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
