<bill session="118" type="s" number="5231" updated="2025-09-18T11:45:54Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farm Ownership Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Ownership Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a pilot program to implement a pre-qualification or pre-approval process for farmers and ranchers with respect to a direct farm ownership loan under the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2024-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2024-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-18T10:28:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farm Ownership Improvement Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a pilot program to implement a pre-qualification or pre-approval process for farmers and ranchers for direct farm ownership loans. As background, the Farm Service Agency Direct Loan Program provides Farm Ownership Loans to farmers and ranchers for the purchase and development of farm property.

Under the five-year pilot program, USDA must prioritize outreach to organizations that have demonstrated engagement with beginning farmers or ranchers.

In addition, USDA may make use of alternative methods, including financial benchmarking, to reliably evaluate the financial viability of a participant in the pilot program and the likelihood of repayment of the applicable loan.

USDA must submit an annual report to Congress on the pilot program, which must include a description of the program's performance outcomes and a recommendation as to the pilot program's value.</summary>
</bill>
