<bill session="116" type="s" number="3571" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Banking for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Banking for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require member banks to maintain pass-through digital dollar wallets for certain persons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-21T13:25:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Banking for All Act 

This bill requires Federal Reserve member banks to provide digital pass-through accounts (i.e., digital dollar wallets) to residents and citizens, and to businesses domiciled in the United States. Among other things, these accounts must provide specified banking services to eligible persons who elect to deposit funds into these accounts, including access to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) aid payments. These accounts may not charge fees or have balance requirements, and must provide a specified interest rate.

In areas with limited access to Federal Reserve member banks, these banks must partner with postal retail facilities to provide services.

Federal Reserve banks must permit state nonmember banks and credit unions to open master accounts for the purpose of offering digital pass-through accounts.

Postal retail facilities and certain small banks must be reimbursed by the appropriate Federal Reserve bank for operational costs incurred by offering the accounts.</summary>
</bill>
