<bill session="108" type="h" number="889" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To eliminate the backlog in performing DNA analyses of DNA samples collected from convicted child sex offenders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="DNA"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Forensic medicine"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sex offenders"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Convicted Child Sex Offender DNA Index System Support Act - Requires the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation to develop a plan to assist States in performing DNA analyses of samples collected from convicted child sex offenders, with the objective of eliminating the backlog of samples awaiting analysis in State or local forensic laboratory storage and providing for entry of those analyses into the combined DNA Indexing System.Provides that the plan shall require that: (1) the Director establish requirements for the performance of DNA analyses by private forensic laboratories; (2) only laboratories determined to satisfy such requirements perform DNA analyses; (3) the Director provide assistance only pursuant to arrangements with those laboratories; (4) each DNA sample collected and analyzed be accessible only under specified circumstances for criminal justice agencies, in judicial proceedings, for a criminal defendant, or for validation studies and protocol development purposes; and (5) once a State has performed DNA analysis of all convicted child sex offender samples, it may use unexpended funds provided under this Act to perform DNA analysis of other forensic samples.Requires the Director to implement the plan developed with States that elect to participate.</summary>
</bill>
