<bill session="118" type="h" number="3279" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WIRELESS Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Winning the International Race for Economic Leadership and Expanding Service to Support Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WIRELESS Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to streamline siting processes for personal wireless service facilities, including small personal wireless service facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000566"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-17T16:29:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Winning the International Race for Economic Leadership and Expanding Service to Support Leadership Act or the WIRELESS Leadership Act

This bill limits the authority of a state or locality to regulate the placement, construction, or modification of personal wireless service facilities.

The bill revises the prohibition on states or localities discriminating among providers of a personal wireless service to state that providing exclusive or preferential use of facilities to a particular class of providers is prohibited.

However, states or localities may establish reasonable and nondiscriminatory requirements for engineering standards, safety, and aesthetics. They may also charge reasonable, cost-based fees for (1) reviewing requests to place, construct, or modify personal wireless service facilities; or (2) using property owned or managed by the state or locality for placing, constructing, or modifying a facility.

Additionally, states and localities must respond to requests to place, construct, or modify facilities by specified deadlines. If a decision is not made by the deadline, the request is deemed to be approved.</summary>
</bill>
