<bill session="118" type="h" number="159" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-24T18:55:56-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-24T18:55:56-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chance to Compete Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chance to Compete Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Chance to Compete Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Chance to Compete Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement merit-based reforms to the civil service hiring system that replace degree-based hiring with skills- and competency-based hiring, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000450"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001108" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2023-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H261"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T17:31:05-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Comer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T17:31:25-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H258-262" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T17:31:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 159.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T17:40:48-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T18:30:45-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H265-266" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="32" datetime="2023-01-24T18:55:56-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 422 - 2 (Roll no. 32).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H259-261" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-01-24T18:55:57-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-27T17:24:53Z" status="Passed House">Chance to Compete Act of 2023

This bill modifies examination requirements and other components of the federal hiring process for positions in the competitive service.

Specifically, the bill provides that a qualifying examination includes a r&#233;sum&#233; review that is conducted by a subject matter expert. Additionally, beginning two years after the bill's enactment, the bill prohibits examinations from consisting solely of a self-assessment from an automated examination, a r&#233;sum&#233; review that is not conducted by a subject matter expert, or any other method of assessing an applicant's experience or education; an agency may waive these requirements when necessary but must report any such waivers and may not use waivers to fill more than 10% of agency positions.

Agencies may use subject matter experts to develop position-specific technical assessments that allow applicants to demonstrate job-related skills, abilities, and knowledge; assessments may include structured interviews, work-related exercises, procedures to measure career-related qualifications and interests, or other similar assessments. The bill also allows agencies to establish talent teams to support and improve hiring practices.

The Office of Personnel Management (OPM) must create online platforms through which agencies may share and customize technical assessments and share the r&#233;sum&#233;s of qualifying applicants. The OPM must also create online platforms with information about (1) the types of assessments used and hiring outcomes, (2) educational requirements for certain positions and related justifications, and (3) authorities and programs that support agency recruitment and retention.</summary>
</bill>
