<bill session="118" type="s" number="2190" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RECOUP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">RECOUP Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Recovering Executive Compensation Obtained from Unaccountable Practices Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to increase bank executive accountability and to improve financial stability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Brown. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="115">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 115.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-11T13:34:56Z" status="Reported to Senate">Recovering Executive Compensation Obtained from Unaccountable Practices Act of 2023 or the RECOUP Act of 2023 

This bill establishes additional authorities for federal banking agencies and sets forth requirements for insured depository institutions with assets over a specified amount to address their safety and soundness.

In the event of institutional failure, the bill establishes the authority to recover from a senior executive bonus compensation and profits from the sale of securities received during the 24-month period preceding the failure. Federal banking authorities also have the authority at an institution of any size to remove from office a senior executive in cases of gross negligence, breach of fiduciary duty, or failure to carry out specified responsibilities.

The bill also requires depository institutions and depository institution holding companies to adopt governance and accountability standards that promote safety and soundness, responsiveness to supervisory matters, and responsible management.

In addition, the bill increases the cap on civil penalties for associated violations. It also expands certain violations to cover senior executives who recklessly (instead of knowingly) violate the law.

Finally, the bill requires various reports. Federal banking agencies must publish a report after the failure of an institution. The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System must report semiannually on the supervisory and regulatory policies and actions of the Board. After an insured depository institution enters receivership, the inspector general of the appropriate federal regulator must report on the regulator's supervisory performance with respect to that institution.</summary>
</bill>
