<bill session="110" type="s" number="2760" updated="2022-02-03T05:10:17Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard Empowerment and State-National Defense Integration Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">National Guard Empowerment and State-National Defense Integration Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance the national defense through empowerment of the National Guard, enhancement of the functions of the National Guard Bureau, and improvement of Federal-State military coordination in domestic emergency response, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2008-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001210" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2008-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2008-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000445" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2008-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2008-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2008-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2008-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2008-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001078" joined="2008-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2008-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/14/2008 S2145-2146"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/14/2008 S2146-2148" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="5603" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Air force"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governors"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military command and control"/>
    <term name="Military promotions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-06-09T15:38:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Guard Empowerment and State-National Defense Integration Act of 2008 - Adds the Chief of the National Guard Bureau (Chief) to the Joint Chiefs of Staff.

Requires the Chief to: (1) identify gaps between federal and state military capabilities to prepare for and respond to emergencies; and (2) make recommendations to the Secretary of Defense for military assistance to civil authorities to address such gaps. Requires annual defense budget documents to specify separate amounts for training and equipment for the National Guard for military assistance to civil authorities and other domestic operations.

Redesignates the: (1) Director and Deputy Director of the Army National Guard as the Vice Chief and Deputy Vice Chief of the Army National Guard; and (2) Director and Deputy Director of the Air National Guard as the Vice Chief and Deputy Vice Chief of the Air National Guard. Treats Vice Chief service as an adjutant general as joint duty experience for assignment or promotion purposes.

States that the United States Northern Command and the United States Pacific Command shall be the combatant commands principally responsible for the military support of civil authorities in the United States. Requires the Commander of each Command and the Chief to enter into a memorandum of understanding setting forth the operational relationships, and individual roles and responsibilities, during responses to domestic emergencies among such Commands and the National Guard Bureau.

Directs the Secretary to assure that tactical control of the Armed Forces on duty within a state or possession is vested in the governor thereof when such forces are engaged in emergency response activities.

Requires the officer serving as: (1) Commander of Army North Command to be an officer in the Army National Guard; and (2) Commander of Air Force North Command to be an officer in the Air National Guard. Expresses the sense of Congress that, in assigning officers to such positions, the President should afford a preference to officers who have served as a state adjutant general.

Requires at least one of each of three specified commander and deputy commander joint task force positions to be an officer in the Army or Air National Guard.</summary>
</bill>
