<bill session="115" type="h" number="3535" updated="2023-01-11T13:37:15Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To restore Federal recognition to the Ruffey Rancheria of California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Indian, Insular and Alaska Native Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1087.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-12-20" calendar="Union" number="843">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 843.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T16:38:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Ruffey Rancheria Restoration Act of 2017

This bill restores federal recognition of the Ruffey Rancheria Tribe of California and federal rights and privileges of the Indian tribe and its members. It also makes the tribe and its members residing in the tribe's service area eligible for the federal services and benefits that are furnished to federally recognized Indian tribes and their members residing on a reservation.

The Department of the Interior may place up to 441 acres of property located in Siskiyou County, California, into a trust for the benefit of the tribe. The land may be used for gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act if certain requirements are met.

Within a year of the bill's enactment, Interior must compile a membership roll of the tribe. The bill establishes criteria for enrolling members prior to the adoption of a tribal constitution.

The bill sets forth a process for establishing an interim governing body until a new tribal constitution and bylaws are adopted, ratifying the constitution, and electing tribal officials.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1087</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
