<bill session="117" type="s" number="1206" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PUA Eligibility Clarification Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the authority of the Secretary of Labor to modify the pandemic unemployment assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PUA Eligibility Clarification Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2036" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-07T13:48:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">PUA Eligibility Clarification Act of 2021

This bill revokes the authority of the Department of Labor to establish additional eligibility criteria for COVID-19 pandemic unemployment assistance with respect to self-certification by individuals who are directly affected by the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Labor must rescind the guidance titled Expanded Eligibility Provisions for the Pandemic Unemployment Assistance (PUA) Program, issued on February 25, 2021. The guidance makes individuals eligible to receive regular unemployment compensation and COVID-19 PUA if they (1) refuse an offer to work or return to work because of certain safety concerns, (2) provide services to educational institutions or educational service agencies, and (3) experience a reduction of hours or a temporary or permanent layoff.

A recipient of such PUA before enactment of this bill is not required to repay it. However, this requirement excludes individuals who, as of such enactment, were approved for PUA but have not received it.</summary>
</bill>
