<bill session="116" type="s" number="1280" updated="2022-02-08T23:21:43Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BENES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Beneficiary Enrollment Notification and Eligibility Simplification Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BENES Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a system to notify individuals approaching Medicare eligibility, to simplify and modernize the eligibility enrollment process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2020-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2019-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2020-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2019-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2477" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-21T13:52:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Beneficiary Enrollment Notification and Eligibility Simplification Act of 2019 or the BENES Act of 2019

This bill makes a series of changes to, and requires additional notifications regarding, the Medicare enrollment process.

Specifically, the bill changes the Medicare general enrollment period to October 15-December 31, and requires coverage to begin on the first day of the month following enrollment. (Currently, the general enrollment period is January 1-March 31, and coverage begins July 1.) The bill also generally requires coverage to begin on the first day of the month following enrollment for individuals who enroll in the latter months of their initial enrollment period. (Currently, the longer an individual waits to enroll, the more delayed the effective date of coverage.)

The bill also requires Social Security account statements for individuals ages 60 to 64 to include information about Medicare eligibility, late enrollment penalties, coordination of benefits, and special enrollment populations (e.g., veterans).</summary>
</bill>
