<bill session="112" type="s" number="1568" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:17Z">
  <state datetime="2011-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State Innovation Pilot Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 9401 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 with regard to waivers of statutory and regulatory requirements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Innovation Pilot Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2011-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2011-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2011-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5641-5646"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-10-13T20:50:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State Innovation Pilot Act of 2011 - Amends part D (Waivers) of title IX (General Provisions) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to revise the process by which states, LEAs, and Indian tribes obtain waivers of the Act's statutory and regulatory requirements.

Requires waiver requests by states, LEAs, or Indian tribes to include a plan that describes how: (1) the waiver will improve instruction and student achievement in accordance with the state's college and career ready academic content and achievement standards; (2) the plan will be evaluated regularly and improved continuously; (3) they will review implementation of the college and career readiness standards; (4) they will identify, support, and intervene in underperforming schools; and (5) they will maintain and improve transparency in reporting to parents and the public on student achievement and school performance.

Requires the Secretary of Education to approve requests that meet such requirements and do not involve certain specified statutory or regulatory requirements.

Directs the Secretary to establish a multidisciplinary peer review team to review a waiver request if the Secretary requests their input or intends to disapprove the request. Requires peer reviewers to review waiver requests in their totality, in deference to state and local judgment, and with the goal of promoting state and local innovation.

Gives the Secretary a limited amount of time to decide on a waiver request. Gives requesters opportunities to revise their requests.

Prohibits the Secretary from imposing conditions on a waiver that require the state, LEA, or Indian tribe to adopt or drop specific standards or assessment systems.</summary>
</bill>
