<bill session="108" type="s" number="872" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:10Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northern Ireland Peace and Reconciliation Support Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 2004 and 2005 for United States contributions to the International Fund for Ireland, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Ireland Peace and Reconciliation Support Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Ireland"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Northern Ireland"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Police-community relations"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-28T22:08:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Northern Ireland Peace and Reconciliation Support Act of 2003 - Declares the sense of Congress that: (1) the United States should continue to contribute to the International Fund for Ireland to support much needed programs in economically depressed areas of Northern Ireland as such programs remain very important to accomplishing the objectives of the Anglo-Irish Agreement Support Act of 1986; (2) the United States should support an expansion of reconciliation projects funded by the International Fund as a way to promote peace and economic stability in Northern Ireland; and (3) the International Fund should support programs such as those mentioned by this Act.

Amends the Anglo-Irish Agreement Support Act of 1986 to authorize certain appropriations for FY 2004 and 2005 for U.S. contributions to the Fund. Authorizes the use of such contributions to fund programs to: (1) enhance relations between communities and between police officers and the communities served by such officers; (2) promote human rights training for police officers; (3) enhance peaceful mediation in neighborhoods of continued conflict; and (4) promote training programs to enhance the new district partnership police boards recommended by the Commission into Policing for Northern Ireland established by the Agreement Reached in the Multi-Party Negotiations in Belfast on April 10, 1998 (Good Friday Agreement).

Declares the sense of Congress that at least 20 percent of such authorized appropriations for each such fiscal year should be used to carry out such programs.</summary>
</bill>
