<bill session="116" type="h" number="5611" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote State requirements for local educational agencies and public elementary and secondary schools relating to the prevention and treatment of concussions suffered by students.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2020-01-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6007" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3347" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-03T19:38:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Student Athletes From Concussions Act of 2020

This bill conditions each state's receipt of federal funds, beginning in FY2021, on the state's enforcement of specified&#160;minimum requirements for the prevention and treatment of concussions in school-sponsored athletics and activities.

Each local educational agency must develop and implement a standard plan for concussion safety and management that includes (1) the education of students, parents, and school personnel about concussions; (2) specified supports for each student recovering from a concussion; and (3) best practices designed to ensure the uniformity of safety standards, treatment, and management.

Each public school must post on school grounds and&#160;publish on the school website specified information&#160;about concussions.

If any public school personnel suspects that a student has sustained a concussion during a school-sponsored activity, the student must be immediately removed from participation in that activity and prohibited from participating in any school-sponsored athletic activities until the student submits a written release from a health care professional. Furthermore, the school personnel must&#160;report all available information regarding the injury to a concussion management team that will confirm and report&#160;details of the injury&#160;to the student's parents.

The school's concussion management team shall consult with and make recommendations to relevant school personnel and the student to ensure that the student is receiving the appropriate academic supports.</summary>
</bill>
