<bill session="110" type="h" number="1099" updated="2023-01-11T20:02:39Z">
  <state datetime="2007-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to protect disaster assistance employee reservists when activated by the Federal Emergency Management Agency for work at a specific disaster site from termination or demotion in their places of employment.</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Assistance Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2007-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2007-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001120" joined="2007-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2007-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-03-12T21:39:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Assistance Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 2007 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to prohibit the termination or demotion of, or other discrimination in the terms and conditions of employment against, an employee who, when activated by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) as a disaster assistance employee reservist, is absent from or late to work for up to 90 days (or longer if the Secretary of Homeland Security publishes a determination that an extension is appropriate due to a national emergency).

Allows an employer to: (1) charge against the employee's regular pay any time that an employee loses from employment because of such activation; and (2) request the employee to provide written verification from FEMA of the time and dates of such activation.

Requires any such employee to make a reasonable effort to notify his or her employer of such absences or lateness.

Authorizes a person who has been terminated, demoted, or otherwise discriminated against in violation of this Act to bring a civil action in U.S. district court if the action is commenced within one year after the violation.</summary>
</bill>
