<bill session="118" type="s" number="1519" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Western Hemisphere Security Strategy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Hemisphere Security Strategy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a United States security strategy for the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1428" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-14T18:21:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Western Hemisphere Security Strategy Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of State and the Department of Defense (DOD) to implement a multiyear Western Hemisphere Security Strategy.

The strategy must include elements such as (1) a proposal for increasing U.S. bilateral and multilateral security assistance and cooperation in Latin America and the Caribbean, (2) activities to counter transnational criminal organizations and malign influence from state actors, (3) efforts to expand bilateral and multinational military training exercises with partner countries, (4) humanitarian assistance and disaster relief initiatives, (5) continued support for State Department programs to ensure the safety and rights of women and girls, and (6) a detailed assessment of the resources to carry out the strategy.

The bill also requires the State Department to provide technical assistance to partner countries to help them address the long-term implications of investments in strategic sectors by entities controlled by adversarial governments, such as China and Russia.

The State Department and DOD must jointly report the strategy to Congress and also provide periodic briefings on the strategy's implementation. The State Department must also report to Congress on efforts by the Maduro regime of Venezuela to detain U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents.</summary>
</bill>
