<bill session="118" type="s" number="1926" updated="2025-11-19T01:53:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States-Uruguay Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Uruguay Economic Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to make Uruguay eligible for designation as a beneficiary country under that Act, to include Uruguay in the list of foreign states whose nationals are eligible for admission into the United States as E1 and E2 nonimmigrants if nationals of the United States are treated similarly by the Government of Uruguay, and to require a report on the eligibility of Uruguay for the visa waiver program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2023-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6875" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-02T16:52:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States-Uruguay Economic Partnership Act

This bill addresses issues related to Uruguay.

Specifically, this bill adds Uruguay to the list of countries eligible for designation as a beneficiary country under the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act. (Such a designation generally provides for duty-free entry of goods into the United States from the designated countries, with some exclusions and limitations.)

The bill also establishes that a national of Uruguay shall be eligible for an E visa (for an investor or trader who is a national of a foreign country with a treaty of commerce and navigation with the United States) if Uruguay provides a similar nonimmigrant status to U.S. nationals.

Furthermore, the Department of Homeland Security must report to Congress an assessment as to whether Uruguay meets the eligibility criteria for the Visa Waiver Program. If Uruguay fails to meet the criteria, the report must also describe what actions Uruguay must take to become eligible. (Citizens of countries in the program may travel to the United States for business or tourism for up to 90 days without a visa.)</summary>
</bill>
