<bill session="117" type="h" number="3067" updated="2023-08-02T14:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Online Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify that a violation of certain terms of service and related materials is an unfair or deceptive act or practice and subject to enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Online Consumer Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-02T14:42:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Online Consumer Protection Act

This bill requires social media platforms and online marketplaces to establish and maintain terms of service that include a consumer protection policy.

The terms must cover issues such as payment methods, content ownership, and policies related to sharing user content with third parties.

Further, the consumer protection policy must address what content or products are permitted on the platform or marketplace and how content or products may be blocked, removed, or modified.

Social media platforms and online marketplaces must develop and implement a consumer protection program to maintain compliance with their consumer protection policies and other consumer protection laws. Platforms and marketplaces above certain revenues or monthly users also must submit to the Federal Trade Commission annual filings with respect to the requirements of this bill.

The bill provides for enforcement by the commission, state attorneys general, and private civil action.</summary>
</bill>
