<bill session="111" type="s" number="3293" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:15Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Special Olympics Sport and Empowerment Act of 2004, to provide assistance to Best Buddies to support the expansion and development of mentoring programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2010-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2010-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2010-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2010-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="S2808-2809"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2809-2811" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5190" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5220" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-19T19:56:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Eunice Kennedy Shriver Act - Reauthorizes the Special Olympics Sport and Empowerment Act of 2004 for FY2011-FY2015.

Directs the Secretary of State to act through the Assistant Secretary of State for Educational and Cultural Affairs in awarding grants or entering agreements with Special Olympics for activities outside the United States. Includes community-based prevention among the activities for which the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) may award grants or enter into agreements with Special Olympics. Requires grant or agreement applications to include a description of specific measurable annual benchmarks, as well as long-term goals and objectives, to be achieved through specified activities, which must include: (1) activities to increase the full participation of people with intellectual disabilities in inclusive school and community activities with nondisabled people; (2) education programs that dispel negative stereotypes about people with intellectual disabilities; and (3) activities to increase the participation of people with intellectual disabilities in Special Olympics outside of the United States. Requires annual reports by Special Olympics to describe demographic data about Special Olympics participants.

Authorizes the Secretary of Education to award grants or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements to promote the expansion of Best Buddies, including activities to increase the participation of people with intellectual disabilities in social relationships and other aspects of community life, including education and employment, within the United States.

Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education to establish Eunice Kennedy Shriver Institutes for Sport and Social Impact. Requires recipients to use grant funds to advance the quality of life and inclusion of people with intellectual disabilities through research and evaluation, technical assistance, training, data collection, evaluation, collaboration, and dissemination of evidence-based best practices.</summary>
</bill>
