<bill session="119" type="h" number="74" updated="2025-11-20T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Freedom for Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom for Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow for tax-advantaged distributions from health savings accounts during family or medical leave, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2025-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5933" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-08T15:33:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Freedom for Families Act

This bill allows individuals to establish and contribute to a health savings account (HSA) without being enrolled in a high-deductible health plan (HDHP), increases HSA contribution limits, and allows tax-free distributions from an HSA during a period of qualified caregiving.

Under current law, individuals may establish and contribute to an HSA if they are covered under an HSA-eligible HDHP. For 2025, HSA contributions are limited to $4,300 for self-only coverage or $8,550 for family coverage (adjusted annually). Individuals who are at least&#160;55 years&#160;old may make an additional HSA contribution of up to $1,000 per year. Further, under current law, HSA distributions are tax-free if used to pay for qualified medical expenses.&#160;

The bill eliminates the HDHP coverage requirement for purposes of an HSA.

The bill also increases the HSA annual contribution limit to $9,000 for individuals or $18,000 for joint filers&#160;(adjusted annually)&#160;and eliminates the additional contribution for individuals&#160;who are at least 55 years old.

Finally, the bill excludes HSA distributions during a period of qualified caregiving from gross income. The bill defines period of qualified caregiving as any period during which an individual is on leave or not employed due to

the birth or adoption of a child;placement of a foster child;caring for a family member with a serious health condition;an inability to work due to a serious health condition; orcertain emergencies related to a spouse, child, or parent on covered active duty with the Armed Forces.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
