<bill session="116" type="h" number="8532" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:34Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Center for the Advancement of Aviation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Center for the Advancement of Aviation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Center for the Advancement of Aviation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2020-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2020-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E931"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3360" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-05T18:31:48Z" status="Introduced in House">National Center for the Advancement of Aviation Act of 2020

This bill establishes the National Center for the Advancement of Aviation as a federally chartered entity to serve as a national independent forum to facilitate collaboration and cooperation between aviation and aerospace stakeholders for the purpose of supporting and promoting civil and military aviation and aerospace in order to address the demands and challenges associated with ensuring a safe and vibrant national aviation system.

In furtherance of that purpose, the center must focus on the

 development and sustainability of a well-qualified, well-trained civil and military aviation and aerospace workforce; conduct of research and development of new aviation and aerospace training materials and products; coordination of the dissemination of grants for the development of aviation and aerospace oriented high school STEM education curriculum; facilitation of collaboration between institutions of higher education or other research institutions engaged in aviation, aerospace or related research or technical development, including those institutions designated as Centers of Excellence or Test Centers of the Federal Aviation Administration and aviation and aerospace stakeholders; and engagement in other workforce development activities consistent with addressing the demands and challenges facing the aviation and aerospace industry.</summary>
</bill>
