<bill session="118" type="h" number="3245" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nonprofit Stakeholders Engaging and Advancing Together Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonprofit Stakeholders Engaging and Advancing Together Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the partnership between the nonprofit organizations and the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-07-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2024-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committees on Education and the Workforce, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-20T19:07:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Nonprofit Stakeholders Engaging and Advancing Together Act of 2023

This bill addresses interactions between the federal government and nonprofit organizations.

Specifically, the bill establishes

 in the Executive Office of the President an Office on Nonprofit Sector Partnership, in the executive branch an Interagency Council on Nonprofit Sector Partnership, and an Advisory Board on the Nonprofit Sector. The Department of the Treasury must engage in activities including analyzing and publicly releasing the impact of relevant actions on charitable giving and the nonprofit sector.

The Bureau of Labor Statistics shall (1) issue a biennial report on trends in the non-stipended volunteer force, and (2) include nonprofit organizations as a distinct category of employer in certain quarterly reports.

The Corporation for National and Community Service must engage in specified activities, including making recommendations to Congress on updating Service Year Fellowships to broaden access to national service to underserved and marginalized communities.

The Bureau of Economic Analysis must create a Satellite Account on Nonprofit and Related Institutions and Volunteer Work within its national accounts program.

The Office of Management and Budget shall engage in specified activities, including soliciting information from relevant federal agencies that collect existing data on the nonprofit sector.

The Government Accountability Office must report on standards for nonpartisan civic engagement applicable to tax-exempt entities.</summary>
</bill>
