<bill session="111" type="h" number="5946" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:50Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">P.E. for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a competitive pilot program that utilizes community, innovation, and technology to improve physical fitness education and curriculum in elementary schools and secondary schools.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">P.E. for the 21st Century Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000652"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="School athletics"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-31T18:51:06Z" status="Introduced in House">P.E. for the 21st Century Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to local educational agencies and charter schools to improve physical fitness education and curricula in elementary and secondary schools.

Requires each grantee to carry out a pilot program for one school year that: (1) makes technology a key component of assessing students' physical fitness and improvement; (2) creates partnerships with local businesses to ensure community support for the program, and their financial and professional assistance; and (3) incorporates physical fitness education (in addition to regular physical fitness education classes) into multiple areas of the curriculum.

Limits such grants to one grantee in each state.</summary>
</bill>
