<bill session="117" type="h" number="2950" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CAMS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a fundamental research program for the application of advanced computing practices to materials science challenges at the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAMS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computing Advancements for Materials Science Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000814"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2021-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-27T20:13:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Computing Advancements for Materials Science Act or the CAMS Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) Office of Science to support a program of fundamental research for the application of advanced computing practices to foundational and emerging research problems in chemistry and materials science.

The DOE Office of Science shall select and establish up to four computational materials and chemistry science centers to develop open-source, robust, and validated computational codes and user-friendly software, coupled with innovative use of experimental and theoretical data, to enable the design, discovery, and development of new materials and chemical systems including chemical catalysis research and development.

The DOE Office of Science shall support the development of a web-based platform to provide access to a database of computed information on known and predicted materials properties and computational tools to accelerate breakthroughs in materials discovery and design.</summary>
</bill>
