<bill session="108" type="s" number="1677" updated="2023-01-15T07:17:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community College Partnership Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage partnerships between community colleges and 4-year institutions of higher education.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community College Partnership Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12142-12143"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College entrance requirements"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community colleges"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student enrollment"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-14T14:01:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community College Partnership Act of 2003 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a community college opportunity program to help students at community or technical colleges (CTCs) to transfer to four-year institutions of higher education (IHEs) and complete baccalaureate degrees. Directs the Secretary of Education to award not less than six and not more than 12 program grants to eligible entities. Makes eligible for such grants: (1) partnerships that include one or more CTCs that award associate's degrees and one or more IHEs that offer a baccalaureate or postbaccalaureate degree not awarded by the partner colleges; or (2) a statewide governance or coordinating board that has jurisdiction over both CTCs and IHEs, or a partnership of such boards that have separate jurisdiction over such entities. Requires funds from such grants to be used for: (1) development of policies to expand opportunities for community or technical college students to earn baccalaureate degrees, including promoting the transfer of academic credits between institutions and expanding articulation and guaranteed transfer agreements; (2) support services to students participating in the program, including tutoring, mentoring, academic and personal counseling, and transition facilitation; (3) academic program enhancements at the community or technical college that increase program quality and the number of student participants in the dual degree program offered in conjunction with a baccalaureate degree granting institution; and (4) programs to identify barriers that inhibit student transfers.</summary>
</bill>
