<bill session="116" type="sr" number="483" updated="2021-12-29T21:57:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-22">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution to provide for related procedures concerning the articles of impeachment against Donald John Trump, President of the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to provide for related procedures concerning the articles of impeachment against Donald John Trump, President of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000355"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-21">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S377-431" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="26" datetime="2020-01-22" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 47. Record Vote Number: 26.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S377-378" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1294"/>
    <amendment number="s1293"/>
    <amendment number="s1292"/>
    <amendment number="s1291"/>
    <amendment number="s1290"/>
    <amendment number="s1289"/>
    <amendment number="s1288"/>
    <amendment number="s1287"/>
    <amendment number="s1286"/>
    <amendment number="s1285"/>
    <amendment number="s1284"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-01-29T23:44:14Z" status="Passed Senate">This resolution sets forth related procedures for consideration of the articles of impeachment against the President that include

 filing of certain records of the articles of impeachment by the House of Representatives; establishing deadlines by which the President and the House must file certain motions related to the articles and any responses to the motions; providing guidelines for arguments on such motions and presentations by the House and the President; authorizing Senators to question parties; making it in order, after deliberation by the Senate, for the Senate to vote on a motion to consider and debate, under the impeachment rules, any motion to subpoena witnesses or documents; making it in order, following the disposition of that question, other motions provided under such rules; requiring the Senate to depose such witnesses and decide which witnesses shall testify, if it agrees to allow the House or the President to subpoena witnesses; making testimony inadmissible unless the parties have had an opportunity to depose such witnesses; and requiring the Senate to vote on each article of impeachment at the conclusion of its deliberations.</summary>
</bill>
