<bill session="110" type="h" number="3733" updated="2023-01-11T20:24:55Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a National Foundation on Physical Fitness and Sports to carry out activities to support and supplement the mission of the President's Council on Physical Fitness and Sports.</title>
    <title type="display">National Foundation on Physical Fitness and Sports Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Foundation on Physical Fitness and Sports Establishment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2007-12-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2007-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11227"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Emblems"/>
    <term name="Federal incorporation"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-10T22:58:33Z" status="Introduced in House">National Foundation on Physical Fitness and Sports Establishment Act - Establishes the National Foundation on Physical Fitness and Sports as a charitable, nonprofit corporation to promote participation by private organizations in the activities of the President's Council on Physical Fitness and Sports. Subjects any person who uses the Council's or Foundation's official seal or any trademark, trade name, sign, symbol, or insignia falsely representing association with, or authorization by, the Council or Foundation for the purpose of trade, to induce the sale of any goods or services, or to promote any theatrical exhibition, athletic performance, or competition without the Foundation's consent to a civil action for remedies provided in the Trademark Act of 1946. Allows the Foundation, in conjunction with the Council, to authorize contributors and suppliers of goods or services to use such trade name, trademark, seal, symbol, insignia, or emblem in advertising under specified conditions. ,</summary>
</bill>
