<bill session="116" type="h" number="4080" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:18Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the safe storage of firearms and ammunition, and to require the investigation of reports of improper storage of firearms or ammunition.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-04T18:17:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Kimberly Vaughan Firearm Safe Storage Act

This bill establishes a federal statutory framework to regulate the storage of firearms and ammunition on residential premises.

Specifically, the bill requires firearms and ammunition on residential premises to be safely stored if a minor is likely to gain access without permission or if an individual who resides at the residence is ineligible to possess a firearm.

The firearms and ammunition must be safely stored in one of two ways: (1) secured, unloaded, and separated in a safe and locked with a trigger lock; or (2) off the premises at a storage facility or gun range. Safes, trigger locks, and storage facilities must be certified by the Department of Justice (DOJ).

Finally, an individual who violates the safe storage requirements is subject to penalties&#8212;criminal penalties if the violation results in the discharge of a firearm, or civil penalties if the violation does not result in the discharge of a firearm. Additionally, DOJ must seize and safely store the individual's firearms and ammunition.</summary>
</bill>
