<bill session="108" type="sc" number="30" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:25Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-27">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress to commend and express the gratitude of the United States to the nations participating with the United States in the Coalition to Disarm Iraq.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress to commend and express the gratitude of the United States to the nations participating with the United States in the Coalition to Disarm Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2003-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2003-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate and held at desk by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4483-4490" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="109" datetime="2003-03-27" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 0. Record Vote Number: 109.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4489-4490" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31T13:55:51-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Albania"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Croatia"/>
    <term name="Czech Republic"/>
    <term name="Denmark"/>
    <term name="Estonia"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Hungary"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Italy"/>
    <term name="Latvia"/>
    <term name="Lithuania"/>
    <term name="Logistics"/>
    <term name="Macedonia"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Portugal"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Slovakia"/>
    <term name="Slovenia"/>
    <term name="Spain"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced in the Senate on March 26, 2003. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)Commends and expresses the gratitude of the United States to the nations participating in and contributing to the Coalition to Disarm Iraq, including: (1) the supporters of the January 30, 2003, declaration issued by the Prime Ministers of Denmark, Hungary, Italy, Poland, Portugal, and the United Kingdom, and the Presidents of the Czech Republic and the Spanish Government; (2) the supporters of the February 5, 2003, declaration issued by the Foreign Ministers of Albania, Bulgaria, Croatia, Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Macedonia, Romania, Slovakia, and Slovenia; and (3) other allies of the United States who are participating in or contributing to the Coalition.Expresses sincere gratitude to Australia, Denmark, Poland, and the United Kingdom, whose military forces have joined United States Armed Forces to disarm and liberate Iraq.Expresses sincere gratitude to the Prime Minister of the United Kingdom, Tony Blair, the Prime Minister of Australia, John Howard, and the President of the Spanish Government, Jose Maria Aznar, for their courageous support and strong commitment to the Coalition to Disarm Iraq.Expresses sincere gratitude to other allied nations, including nations in the Persian Gulf region, for their military support, logistical support, and other assistance in the current campaign against the regime of Saddam Hussein in Iraq.Welcomes and encourages the active involvement and participation of these countries, other nations, and key international organizations in the reconstruction and administration of Iraq after the current conflict in Iraq.Commends and expresses the gratitude of the United States to the military personnel and civilians of the member states of the Coalition to Disarm Iraq who are serving in operations against the regime of Saddam Hussein in Iraq, and to the family members of such personnel and civilians who have borne the burden of sacrifice and separation from their loved ones during the current conflict in Iraq.</summary>
</bill>
