<bill session="116" type="h" number="6071" updated="2022-02-08T23:14:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FEMA Disaster Preparedness Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to modify the Federal share requirement and establish a period of performance requirement for the hazard mitigation grant program, to amend the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 to modify the Federal share requirement of emergency management performance grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Disaster Preparedness Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2020-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2020-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2020-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E257-258"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-25T18:02:43Z" status="Introduced in House">FEMA Disaster Preparedness Improvement Act

This bill increases Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) support for disaster preparedness and emergency response to states and U.S. territories.

Specifically, the bill increases the federal cost share to 85% for (1) hazard mitigation measures with respect to a major disaster (currently, 75%); and (2) emergency management performance grants (currently, 50%).

The bill makes special flood hazard areas that have suffered at least one severe repetitive loss or repetitive loss under the National Flood Insurance Program eligible for FEMA hazard mitigation grants. It also exempts the time it takes to complete environmental reviews from the 36-month deadline to complete FEMA-funded hazard mitigation projects.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the challenges to states and U.S. territories in obtaining assistance under FEMA's public assistance program alternative procedures.</summary>
</bill>
