<bill session="108" type="s" number="2256" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:06Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to exempt preparation for high-skill, high-demand jobs from participation and time limits under the temporary assistance for needy families program.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to exempt preparation for high-skill, high-demand jobs from participation and time limits under the temporary assistance for needy families program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-19T19:19:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Revises the mandatory work requirements of part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act with respect to the limitation on the number of persons in a State who may be treated as engaged in work by reason of participation in educational activities. Removes two-parent families from the formula for such limitation. Creates an exception to the limitation for education in preparation for sector-specific, high-skill occupations to meet employer demand.

Defines sector-specific, high-demand, high-skill occupation to meet employer demand as an occupation that: (1) has been identified by the State workforce investment board or by the State agency administering the State TANF program as within State needs with regard to current and projected employment opportunities in specific industry sectors; (2) requires occupational training; and (3) provides a wage of at least 75 percent of the State median hourly wage.</summary>
</bill>
