<bill session="109" type="h" number="1378" updated="2019-11-15T21:33:20Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ephedrine Alkaloids Regulation Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Ephedrine Alkaloids Regulation Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act with respect to the regulation of ephedrine alkaloids, including ephedrine and pseudoephedrine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000420" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001254" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000948" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000465" joined="2005-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000119" joined="2005-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-15T20:09:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Ephedrine Alkaloids Regulation Act of 2005 - Requires ephedrine alkaloids (including ephedrine and pseudoephedrine) and phenylpropanolamine to be listed in schedule V of the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) (drugs or other substances that have a low potential for abuse and that have a currently accepted medical use in treatment in the United States, abuse of which may lead to limited physical or psychological dependence). Excepts pseudoephedrine and phenylpropanolamine when contained in a drug that is in liquid or gel form marketed or distributed lawfully in the United States under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FDCA), which shall be considered a listed chemical. Makes such requirement and exception subject to the Attorney General's authority to designate substances as controlled or listed chemicals.

 Amends CSA to revise the definition of "regulated transaction" to: (1) provide that the threshold for any distributor sale of products containing pseudoephedrine products in liquid or gel form, or containing phenylpropanolamine products, shall be nine grams of pseudoephedrine or phenylpropanolamine; and (2) specify as a "chemical mixture" a transaction in which is excluded from such definition a mixture that may be marketed or distributed lawfully in the United States under FDCA.</summary>
</bill>
