<bill session="111" type="s" number="1676" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable Housing Preservation and Revitalization Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow for the use of existing section 8 housing funds so as to preserve and revitalize affordable housing options for low-income individuals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Housing Preservation and Revitalization Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2009-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9439"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-20T22:41:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Affordable Housing Preservation and Revitalization Act of 2009 - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to ensure that funds in the residual receipts account of an eligible multifamily housing property are transferred, at the time of a qualified sale or exchange, to preservation entities.

Requires that funds in the residual receipts account be used, subject to housing agency approval, to: (1) pay for rehabilitation costs approved by the housing agency; (2) deposit funds into the property's replacement reserve account; and (3) pay for social and other services, associated acquisition costs, and any other costs that have been approved by the housing agency and will directly benefit such tenants.

Defines "preservation entity" as: (1) a nonprofit tax-exempt corporation; or (2) a limited partnership or limited liability company where the sole general partner or sole managing member of such ownership entity is a nonprofit tax-exempt corporation; and (3) that has the capacity to acquire and preserve an eligible multifamily housing property.

States that, for purposes of the low-income housing credit under the Internal Revenue Code, residual receipts used or transferred under this Act shall not be considered federal funds.</summary>
</bill>
