<bill session="116" type="h" number="5757" updated="2022-02-23T16:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the care furnished to veterans with military sexual trauma.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Sexual Assault Victims Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2020-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2020-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000571" joined="2020-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-23T16:10:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Sexual Assault Victims Empowerment Act or the Military SAVE Act

This bill addresses care for covered veterans who are seeking counseling, care, or services related to sexual trauma determined by a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) health care professional to have occurred while the veteran was on active duty or in active or inactive training. A covered veteran is a veteran who is (1) enrolled in the VA health care system; or (2) not enrolled in the VA health care system but is otherwise entitled to hospital care, medical services, or extended care services due to a specified disability.

The bill requires the VA to provide hospital care, medical services, and extended care services to a covered veteran at a non-VA provider under the Veterans Community Care Program if such veteran is seeking counseling, care, or services related to such sexual trauma. The decision to receive such care from a non-VA provider shall be at the election of the veteran.

The VA must provide information regarding the counseling, care, and services available through the VA to the covered veteran who is seeking counseling, care, or services related to sexual trauma.

The bill also authorizes the VA to provide counseling and treatment for any condition determined to have resulted from a sexual trauma that occurred while the covered veteran was on active duty or in active or inactive training (previously only psychological trauma was eligible).</summary>
</bill>
