<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="234" updated="2022-06-23T07:16:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="7666" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-06-22T17:59:53-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000627"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 4 printed in Part E of House Report 117-381 to require a report on the available mental health and stress related resources or programs that are available to law enforcement officers. The report shall include additional legislative tools and authorities that may be helpful or necessary to assist in assessing, monitoring, and improving the mental health of law enforcement officers.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires a report on the available mental health and stress related resources or programs that are available to law enforcement officers. The report shall include additional legislative tools and authorities that may be helpful or necessary to assist in assessing, monitoring, and improving the mental health of law enforcement officers.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-06-22T17:59:53-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="283">
      <text>On agreeing to the Demings amendment (A004) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 10 (Roll no. 283).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T15:44:29-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A004) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T15:40:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mrs. Demings.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5791-5792" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5791-5792" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T17:59:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Demings amendment (A004) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 10 (Roll no. 283).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T17:59:53-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T17:59:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Demings amendment (A004) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 411 - 10 (Roll no. 283).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22T15:40:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Mrs. Demings.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
