<bill session="117" type="h" number="5691" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 with respect to certain requirements for institutions of higher education whose students receive TEACH grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TEACH for Tomorrow Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEACH for Tomorrow Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-11T20:23:42Z" status="Introduced in House">TEACH for Tomorrow Act of 2021

This bill revises grant programs that support teacher preparation.

Specifically, the bill revises the Teacher Quality Partnership program by requiring institutions of higher education (IHEs) to report additional information on the performance of their teacher preparation programs. Further, the Department of Education (ED) must impose a fine on an IHE that fails to provide the required information related to their programs. (Currently, ED may impose such a fine but is not required to do so.)

Additionally, the bill revises the eligibility requirements for Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education (TEACH) grants by (1) establishing a minimum pass rate for state assessments used for teacher certification or licensure, and (2) directing ED to continue to make TEACH grants to an ineligible IHE for the duration of each teacher candidate's course of study.

ED must issue or revise regulations to carry out this bill.</summary>
</bill>
