<bill session="108" type="s" number="1553" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Organized Retail Theft Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to combat, deter, and punish individuals and enterprises engaged in organized retail theft.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organized Retail Theft Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000858"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10685-19686"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10686-10687" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cosmetics and personal care"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Infant formulas"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-15T18:53:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Organized Retail Theft Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit organized retail theft. Prescribes penalties to be imposed for: (1) obstructing, delaying, or affecting commerce or the movement of any article or commodity in commerce by taking possession of, carrying away, or transferring, with intent to steal, any goods offered for retail sale with a total value of between $1,000 and $5,000, or of over $5,000, during any 180-day period; (2) receiving, possessing, concealing, storing, bartering, selling, disposing of, or traveling in interstate or foreign commerce with intent to distribute, any property which the person knows, or should have known, has been taken or stolen in violation of this Act; and (3) knowingly promoting, managing, or facilitating such an offense. Provides enhanced penalties for assault, jeopardizing a person's life by use of a dangerous weapon, killing, or kidnapping committeed in the course of such an offense. Requires a person to forfeit any interest in goods acquired or maintained in violation of this Act.

Sets forth provisions concerning injunctions to restrain violations, impounding of goods, the forfeiture and disposition of goods, and civil remedies by persons aggrieved by violations of this Act.

Makes commission of organized retail theft a predicate for a claim under the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act.

Prohibits anyone at a flea market from selling, offering for sale, or knowingly permitting the sale of: (1) baby food, infant formula, or similar products uses as a sole or major source of nutrition, manufactured and packaged for sale for consumption primarily by children under age three; or (2) any drug, food for special dietary use, cosmetic, or device, except by an authorized representative of the product manufacturer or distributor.

Requires the Attorney General to report on Department of Justice actions involving organized retail theft.</summary>
</bill>
