<bill session="111" type="h" number="2349" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:15Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lieutenant Colonel Dominic "Rocky" Baragona Justice for American Heroes Harmed by Contractors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide in personam jurisdiction in civil actions against contractors of the United States Government performing contracts abroad with respect to serious bodily injuries of members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees of the United States Government, and United States citizen employees of companies performing work for the United States Government in connection with contractor activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lieutenant Colonel Dominic "Rocky" Baragona Justice for American Heroes Harmed by Contractors Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001263" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000608" joined="2010-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000609" joined="2009-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000372" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2009-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2782" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="526" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-17T12:08:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Lieutenant Colonel Dominic "Rocky" Baragona Justice for American Heroes Harmed by Contractors Act - Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to amend the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) to include, with respect to any contract for work to be performed outside the United States that is approved and financed by the U.S. government, requirements that: (1) the contractor consent to in personam jurisdiction over the contractor by the federal courts with respect to any suit alleging serious bodily injury of a member of the Armed Forces, civilian government employee, or U.S. citizen employee of a company performing work for the government, or any civil or criminal suit brought by the government alleging wrongdoing associated with the performance of the contract; and (2) a contractor awarded a contract with a value of $5 million or more that does not maintain a U.S. office designate an agent in the United States for service of process in such a suit.

Requires a contractor to consent to federal court jurisdiction in any civil or criminal action commenced between September 11, 2001, and the date of enactment of this Act as a condition of entering into any contract with the U.S. government, or receiving payment for performing any activity under such a contract, on or after the date of enactment of this Act.

Requires the Director to amend FAR to provide that a U.S. government contractor may be debarred or suspended from contracting for: (1) evading service of process in such a suit; or (2) refusing or failing to appear before a federal court in a matter brought against the contractor by the U.S. government or a U.S. citizen or national in connection with contract performance.</summary>
</bill>
