<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="1754" updated="2022-02-25T17:34:19Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2691" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-09-23">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000126"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-09-23"/>
  <description>To substitute a requirement for an annual report on competitive sourcing activities on lists required under the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 that are performed for the Department of the Interior by Federal Government sources.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-09-23" how="roll" result="pass" roll="360">
      <text>Amendment SA 1754 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 53 - 43. Record Vote Number: 360.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11807" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Amendment SA 1754 proposed by Senator Voinovich.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Amendment SA 1754 was modified to reflect a first degree amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Amendment SA 1754 proposed by Senator Voinovich to Amendment SA 1731. (consideration: CR S11791-11795, S11807; text: S11791-11792) To substitute a requirement for an annual report on competitive sourcing activities on lists required under the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 that are performed for the Department of the Interior by Federal Government sources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1754 proposed by Senator Voinovich.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1754 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 53 - 43. Record Vote Number: 360.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11807" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1754 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay. 53 - 43. Record Vote Number: 360.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11807" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
