<bill session="111" type="h" number="970" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:02Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIND Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fugitive Information Networked Database Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">FIND Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the entry of felony warrants into the NCIC database by States and to provide additional resources for extradition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000792"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3120" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-14T16:07:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Fugitive Information Networked Database Act of 2009 or the FIND Act of 2009 - Permits a state attorney general to apply for Department of Justice (DOJ) grants to develop and implement or upgrade systems for the preparation, submission, and validation of state felony warrants that are compatible and interoperable with the National Crime Information Center database. Allows grant funds to be used to hire additional personnel to validate warrants entered into the database.

Directs the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to provide state and local government agencies the technology to make state and local warrant databases compatible and interoperative with the National Crime Information Center database.

Authorizes appropriations for the Fugitive Apprehension Task Forces and for the extradition of fugitives through the Justice Prisoner and Alien Transport System.</summary>
</bill>
