<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="362" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:16Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2920" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-07-22T15:48:38-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000570"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-07-22"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to establish caps on discretionary spending from FY2010 through FY2014 and a cap on total spending as a percentage of gross domestic product. It also sought to put in place maximum limits on deficits through 2019, also as a percentage of gross domestic product.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part C of House Report 111-217 to establish caps on discretionary spending from FY2010 through FY2014 and a cap on total spending as a percentage of gross domestic product. It would also put in place maximum limits on deficits through 2019, again as a percentage of gross domestic product.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-07-22T15:48:38-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="610">
      <text>On agreeing to the Ryan (WI) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 169 - 259 (Roll no. 610).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T15:23:15-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A002) without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8538" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T13:54:57-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Ryan (WI).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8527-8538" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8527-8528" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T13:54:57-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Ryan (WI).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8527-8538" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8527-8528" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T15:48:38-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Ryan (WI) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 169 - 259 (Roll no. 610).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T15:48:38-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Ryan (WI) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 169 - 259 (Roll no. 610).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22T15:48:38-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
