<bill session="118" type="s" number="3517" updated="2025-11-19T02:17:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">POLL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">People Over Long Lines Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POLL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to ensure that voters in elections for Federal office do not wait in long lines in order to vote, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2024-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5291" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-18T01:22:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">People Over Long Lines Act or the POLL Act

This bill sets forth provisions related to voting and the administration of federal elections.

Specifically, the bill requires states to ensure that voters wait no more than 30 minutes at any polling place to cast their vote in a federal election, establishes a private right of action for voters who experience longer waiting times, and directs the Election Assistance Commission to make payments to eligible states to prevent unreasonable waiting times.

Next, the bill requires each state to provide for the minimum required number of voting systems, poll workers, and other election resources for each polling location on the day of any federal election and each day of early voting. The Department of Justice's Civil Rights Division must issue uniform standards regarding the minimum number and distribution of such systems, workers, and other resources.

The bill also prohibits a chief state election administration official from taking an active part in political management or in a political campaign with respect to any federal election over which the official has supervisory authority, with certain exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
