<bill session="116" type="s" number="3466" updated="2022-02-09T01:11:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Acting to Cancel Copays and Ensure Substantial Savings for Biosimilars Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acting to Cancel Copays and Ensure Substantial Savings for Biosimilars Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to eliminate cost sharing for biosimilar biological products furnished under part B of the Medicare program during the first 5 years such products are marketed.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4597" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-08T21:57:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Acting to Cancel Copays and Ensure Substantial Savings for Biosimilars Act of 2020 or the ACCESS for Biosimilars Act of 2020

This bill temporarily eliminates cost-sharing for biosimilar biological products for certain qualifying beneficiaries under Medicare medical services. Specifically, the bill eliminates cost-sharing for beneficiaries whose coverage under private health insurance, a federal program (other than Medicare), a Medicare supplemental policy, or Medicare Advantage does not already do so. The Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must establish a process for determining a beneficiary's eligibility and notifying Medicare Advantage organizations of such determinations.

The bill's provisions apply to products that are furnished during the five-year period beginning on January 1, 2021, or the date on which the product is first marketed, whichever is later.</summary>
</bill>
