<bill session="118" type="sj" number="37" updated="2025-11-19T02:47:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution requiring the advice and consent of the Senate or an Act of Congress to suspend, terminate, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty and authorizing related litigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="89" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-17T22:15:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This joint resolution requires either the advice and consent of the Senate or an act of Congress before the President may suspend, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the North Atlantic Treaty. No funds may be used to support any decisions to suspend, denounce, or withdraw the United States from the treaty unless (1) both the House and the Senate pass a joint resolution approving withdrawal by a two-thirds vote, or (2) the funds are used pursuant to an act of Congress.

The President shall notify Congress in writing of any deliberation or decision to suspend, denounce, or withdraw from the treaty at least 180 days before taking such action. The President must also consult with Congress before providing such written notification.

Upon adoption of a resolution by the appropriate chamber, the joint resolution also allows the Senate Legal Counsel and the General Counsel of the House of Representatives to represent Congress in judicial proceedings related to actions that are inconsistent with this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
