<bill session="118" type="s" number="4099" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food Supply Chain Capacity and Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food Supply Chain Capacity and Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the capacity, resiliency, diversity, and security of the United States food supply chain by codifying and expanding the Food Supply Chain Guaranteed Loan Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4873" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-28T13:58:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Food Supply Chain Capacity and Resiliency Act

This bill allows the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to expand the Food Supply Chain Guaranteed Loan Program. The program may guarantee loans to support new investments in the start-up or expansion of projects in the United States that will increase U.S. food supply chain capacity to aggregate, process, manufacture, store, transport, wholesale, or distribute food.

In awarding loan guarantees under this bill, USDA must give preference to loans for projects that create jobs in economically distressed communities or to help create a more resilient, diverse, and secure U.S. food supply chain.

USDA must prescribe such regulations as may be necessary to carry out this program.

The bill specifies that USDA must use the amounts made available to carry out this bill to supplement, and not supplant, funds provided under other federal, state, or local law.</summary>
</bill>
