<bill session="111" type="h" number="2857" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gang Deterrence and Community Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to reduce violent gang crime and protect law-abiding citizens and communities from violent criminals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gang Deterrence and Community Protection Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000445"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001165" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2009-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2009-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2009-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-16T14:56:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Gang Deterrence and Community Protection Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to modify and expand prohibitions against criminal street gang activity, including forfeiture provisions.

Revises penalties for: (1) interstate or foreign travel or transportation in aid of racketeering enterprises; (2) carjacking; (3) using interstate commerce facilities in the commission of murder-for-hire and other felony crimes of violence; (4) violent crimes in aid of racketeering activity; (5) murder and other violent crimes committed during and in relation to a drug trafficking crime; (6) using interstate commerce facilities to commit multiple murder; and (7) the use of firearms in crimes of violence and drug trafficking.

Amends: (1) the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act (RICO) to expand the definition of "racketeering activity" to cover interstate murder; and (2) the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 to authorize the use of community-based justice grants to hire additional prosecutors to reduce backlogs and to fund technology, equipment, and training for specified purposes, including to increase the accurate identification and successful prosecution of young violent offenders

Expands: (1) the rebuttable presumption against release of persons charged with firearms offenses; (2) venue in capital cases; and (3) the authority to prosecute juveniles as adults.

Sets a 15-year statute of limitations for non-capital felony crimes of violence.

Authorizes the Attorney General to designate specific areas that are located within one or more states as high intensity interstate gang activity areas.</summary>
</bill>
