<bill session="116" type="h" number="6770" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mobility Options, Resiliency, and Efficiency (MORE) through TDM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to encourage and promote the safe and efficient management, operation, and development of surface transportation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mobility Options, Resiliency, and Efficiency (MORE) through TDM Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2020-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2020-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2020-08-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2020-08-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-09T14:15:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Mobility Options, Resiliency, and Efficiency (MORE) through TDM Act

This bill addresses supporting transportation demand management (TDM) expectations and goals that will serve the mobility needs of the people and freight, foster economic growth and development within and between states and urbanized areas. (Transportation demand management is the use of strategies to inform and encourage travelers to maximize the efficiency of a transportation system leading to improved mobility, reduced congestion, and lower vehicle emissions.)

Each state and metropolitan planning organization must include TDM targets in the development of their long-range transportation plans.

The bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish a program to encourage and assist the development and funding of TDM related projects.

Additionally, DOT must provide grants to nonprofit institutions of higher education to establish and operate a university transportation center for research and development related to TDM and TDM strategies. (TDM strategies means the use of planning, programs, policy, marketing, communications, incentives, pricing, and technology to shift travel mode, routes used, departure times, number of trips, and location and design work space or public attractions.)

The bill establishes a National Advisory Committee under the Federal Highways Administration to strategically direct federal resources and policies toward implementation of TDM objectives. Additionally, each state must establish advisory committees focused on the development and furthering of the principles of TDM.</summary>
</bill>
