<bill session="108" type="h" number="271" updated="2023-01-15T21:04:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Equitable Care for All Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to modify the formula, known as the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation (VERA) system, for the allocation of funds appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs for medical care to different geographic regions of the Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equitable Care for All Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000372"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000440" joined="2003-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000078" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2003-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2003-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Equitable Care for All Veterans Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to modify the funding allocation formula for the Department of Veterans Affairs medical care system known as the Veterans Resource Allocation (VERA) system to provide for the incorporation of regional differences in the cost of providing health care to veterans as part of the criteria used to determine the national means differential used. Directs the Secretary to evaluate the effects of such modifications on the regional allocation of funds available to the Department of Veterans Affairs for health care and, if the modifications do not result in a substantive shift in such allocations, to terminate VERA.Directs the Secretary, if required to terminate VERA, to develop a new formula for the allocation of funds to the Department's national service regions, known as Veterans Integrated Service Networks (VISNs), that takes into account specified requirements, including additional costs incurred by a VISN because the age of veterans, or the number of veterans requiring complex care, in that VISN exceeds the median for all VISNs.Authorizes additional appropriations to be allocated to VISNs that have experienced funding reductions.</summary>
</bill>
