<bill session="118" type="h" number="8624" updated="2025-04-17T18:30:43Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HOUSE Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Owners with Unaffordable Shoddy Edicts Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOUSE Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture to withdraw a final determination relating to energy efficiency standards for housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001311" joined="2024-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2024-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2024-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001082" joined="2024-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2024-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2024-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-17T18:29:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Owners with&#160;Unaffordable Shoddy Edicts Act of 2024 or the HOUSE Act of 2024

This bill directs the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to withdraw the final determination titled Adoption of Energy Efficiency Standards for New Construction of HUD- and USDA-Financed Housing and published on April 26, 2024.

The determination adopted updated minimum energy efficiency standards for newly built homes (except manufactured housing) financed through certain HUD and USDA programs. Specifically, it adopted the (1) 2021 International Energy Conservation Code (IECC), which&#160;applies to single family homes and multifamily low-rise buildings up to three stories; and (2) 2019&#160;American National Standards Institute/American Society of Heating, Refrigerating, and Air-Conditioning Engineers/Illuminating Electrical Society (ANSI/ASHRAE/IES) Standard 90.1, which&#160;applies to multifamily residential buildings with four or more stories. HUD and USDA must also revert to using the energy efficiency standards required before the determination.

In addition, the bill prohibits HUD, USDA, and the Department of Veterans Affairs from taking actions or using federal funds to implement or enforce the determination or any substantially similar determination. It also prohibits the Federal Housing Finance Agency from finalizing, implementing, or enforcing a determination or rule relating to energy efficiency standards for single and multifamily housing.

Finally, the bill prohibits HUD and USDA from adopting updates to the IECC or ANSI/ASHRAE/IES Standard 90.1 in certain circumstances unless&#160;at least 26 states have adopted codes or standards that meet or exceed the update's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
