<bill session="117" type="s" number="5099" updated="2023-02-10T05:24:43Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Lending Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Lending Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Abuse and Fraud in Electronic Lending Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Truth in Lending Act to address certain issues relating to the extension of consumer credit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9307" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-08T15:19:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Abuse and Fraud in Electronic Lending Act of 2022 or the SAFE Lending Act of 2022

This bill revises requirements related to consumer financial protection and small-dollar lending, including matters concerning remotely created checks, electronic fund transfers, registration of small-dollar lenders, overdraft fees, and the collection of personal information.

 Under the bill, remotely created checks may only be issued by a person specifically designated in writing by a consumer and provided to the consumer's depository institution. (A remotely created check is a check not issued by the bank and not signed by the account owner.)

A voluntary agreement to repay a small-dollar consumer credit transaction by an electronic fund transfer is subject to certain protections, including the right of the consumer to stop payment.

Small-dollar consumer credit providers must register with the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. Any small-dollar consumer credit transaction is subject to the laws of the state in which the consumer resides.

The bill also prohibits overdraft fees on prepaid accounts.</summary>
</bill>
