<bill session="111" type="h" number="3830" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:52Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health and Wellness for Americans Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop an individual chronic disease prevention and wellness achievement matrix.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health and Wellness for Americans Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000449"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-27T15:57:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Health and Wellness for Americans Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop an individual chronic disease prevention and wellness achievement matrix to: (1) assist individuals to lower their risks of chronic disease; (2) achieve overall reductions in the incidence of chronic disease on a national scale; and (3) lay the foundation for future policies that incentivize achievements.

Requires the matrix to consist of easily measurable, demonstrable, clinical factors for: (1) achieving the recommended body mass index (or alternatively, an individual's recommended waist circumference); (2) achieving recommended lipid profile levels that make up a full lipid panel (or alternatively, the recommended ratio of high density lipoprotein [HDL] to low density lipoprotein [LDL]); (3) achieving the recommended blood pressure level; (4) completing all cancer screenings for age and gender, based on guidelines of the U.S. Preventive Services Task Force; (5) achieving nonsmoking status; and (6) achieving the recommended fasting blood sugar level (or if diabetic, the recommended hemoglobin A1c level).</summary>
</bill>
