<bill session="117" type="s" number="2439" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for the responsibility of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to maintain capabilities to identify threats to industrial control systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment. With written report No. 117-247.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="631">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 631.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1833" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-19T12:37:40Z" status="Reported to Senate">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2021

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to maintain certain capabilities to identify and address threats to industrial control systems.

Specifically, the bill requires CISA's National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center to ensure that its activities address the security of both information and operational technology, including industrial control systems.

Additionally, CISA must maintain capabilities to identify and address threats and vulnerabilities to products and technologies intended for use in the automated control of critical infrastructure processes by (1) leading efforts to identify and mitigate cybersecurity threats to industrial control systems; (2) maintaining threat hunting and incident response capabilities to respond to cybersecurity risks and incidents; (3) providing cybersecurity technical assistance to stakeholders; and (4) collecting, coordinating, and providing vulnerability information to the industrial control systems community.

CISA shall provide to the homeland security committees a briefing on its industrial control systems capabilities at specified intervals.

The Government Accountability Office must review and report on implementation of the bill's requirements.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-247</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
