<bill session="109" type="h" number="3602" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:30Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to award credit toward the service of a sentence to prisoners who participate in designated educational, vocational, treatment, assigned work, or other developmental programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2005-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2005-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-07T20:08:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act - Amends the federal criminal code to allow a prisoner serving a term of imprisonment of more than one year (other than life imprisonment) to receive credit beyond time already served of up to 60 days each year, in addition to any credit received for satisfactory behavior, for earning a certificate of completion in, or for participating in or teaching, a designated program which benefits prisoners or the Bureau of Prisons. Includes specified educational and vocational, treatment, or work and developmental programs.

Requires the Director of the Bureau to establish the number of days of credit a prisoner may be awarded considering the difficulty, time required, responsibility expected, and rehabilitative benefits of the program.

 Makes any person sentenced to a term of imprisonment under the Attorney General's custody eligible for the credits, including prisoners transferred from foreign countries.

Directs the Bureau to assure that a prisoner spends a reasonable part of the last portion (currently, the last ten percent) of the term of imprisonment to be served under conditions that will afford the prisoner a reasonable opportunity to prepare for reentry into the community.</summary>
</bill>
