<bill session="117" type="s" number="2593" updated="2023-01-01T20:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve Federal oversight of foreign funding in education.</title>
    <title type="display">GIFTs in Higher Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GIFTs in Higher Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Greater Insight into Foreign Transactions in Higher Education Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2021-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-10T15:25:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Greater Insight into Foreign Transactions in Higher Education Act of 2021 or the GIFTs in Higher Education Act

This bill revises certain disclosure requirements for institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Under current law, an IHE must disclose to the Department of Education (ED) a gift or contract from a foreign source that is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that foreign source. This bill extends the disclosure requirement to include faculty, professional staff, and all staff engaged in research and development at the IHE.

Further, an IHE (including faculty and staff) must disclose to ED a gift or contract from a designated foreign adversary source that is valued at $50,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that foreign adversary source within a calendar year. The IHE must, within 30 days of receipt of the gift or contract, file a disclosure report with ED.

ED must, within 30 days of submission, publish online these disclosure reports.

Next, the bill requires each federal agency to ensure that no federal funds are distributed to an IHE that knowingly or willfully violates these disclosure requirements.

The bill also prohibits an IHE that knowingly or willfully violates these disclosure requirements from receiving federal education funds, with an exception for federal student-aid program funding.</summary>
</bill>
