<bill session="112" type="h" number="6073" updated="2022-02-03T05:56:53Z">
  <state datetime="2012-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dignified Burial of Veterans Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Dignified Burial of Veterans Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that deceased veterans with no known next of kin can receive a dignified burial, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001155" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000185" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000593" joined="2012-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000031" joined="2012-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3202" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-10-15T18:38:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Dignified Burial of Veterans Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to furnish a casket or urn of sufficient quality for a dignified burial for the burial in a national cemetery of a deceased veteran with no next of kin, or other person claiming the body of the deceased veteran, and who is without sufficient resources to cover burial and funeral expense. Prohibits the furnishing of such casket or urn in the case of a veteran convicted of a federal or state capital crime.

Requires the Secretary, in the case of a deceased veteran with no next of kin and without sufficient resources to cover funeral and burial expenses, to ensure that the entity responsible for transporting the body to a national cemetery for burial notifies the VA as to whether such veteran was cremated and steps taken to ensure that such veteran has no next of kin.

Directs the Secretary to report to the congressional veterans committees on VA compliance with industry standards for caskets and urns.</summary>
</bill>
