<bill session="118" type="s" number="792" updated="2025-11-19T03:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Compact Impact Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compact Impact Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Act of 1996 to provide certain Federal public benefits to citizens of the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau who are lawfully residing in the United States if they are otherwise qualified, consistent with section 141 of the Compacts of Free Association.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="96" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="sj" number="48" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1061" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1571" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-20T16:16:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Compact Impact Fairness Act of 2023 

This bill expands the eligibility of citizens of the Freely Associated States lawfully residing in the United States for certain federal public benefits.

Currently, citizens of the Freely Associated States (Micronesia, the Marshall Islands, and Palau) may live, study, and work in the United States as nonimmigrants. However, such individuals are generally ineligible for most federal public benefits, with Medicaid being one exception. Under this bill, such individuals may be eligible for certain federal public benefits, such as benefits under the Temporary Assistance for Needy Families program.

Furthermore, current law generally bars individuals from receiving federal means-tested public benefits for the five-year period starting from the individual's entry into the United States. Under this bill, citizens of the Freely Associated States living in the United States shall not be subject to this bar.</summary>
</bill>
