<bill session="116" type="s" number="1346" updated="2022-02-09T01:25:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Simplifying Financial Aid for Students Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simplifying Financial Aid for Students Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary to provide for the use of data from the second preceding tax year to carry out the simplification of applications for the estimation and determination of financial aid eligibility, to increase the income threshold to qualify for a student aid index equal to or less than zero, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2019-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="640" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1075" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="416" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1364" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T22:08:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Simplifying Financial Aid for Students Act of 2019

This bill revises the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) process and modifies federal student aid eligibility for certain students.

Among other things, the bill revises FAFSA to

 remove certain questions such as those regarding a student's criminal history, Selective Service registration, and combat pay information; make it available to complete on a mobile device; consolidate questions regarding a student's homeless status; allow a student to automatically populate such form using data available from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS); provide forms in the most common languages spoken at home in the United States; and allow a student to complete FAFSA as an independent student under special circumstances. The bill also modifies the student eligibility criteria for federal student financial aid to

 deem a student eligible for a determination of a zero expected family contribution under certain circumstances, such as when a dependent student's parent participated in a means-tested benefits program (e.g., the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program or Medicaid); revise the simplified needs-analysis formula; remove drug conviction and Selective Service registration provisions; and make Dreamer students (i.e., students who have been granted Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals status) eligible for federal financial aid. Additionally, the IRS must disclose certain tax return information to the Department of Education (ED) for the purpose of administering financial aid and loan programs.

The bill also authorizes ED to carry out an early federal Pell Grant commitment program.</summary>
</bill>
