<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6535</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:12Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:12Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-12-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-12-16T15:03:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsfa00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000515</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rush, Bobby L. [D-IL-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>BOBBY</firstName>
        <lastName>RUSH</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Africa</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of State</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal officials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International exchange and broadcasting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public-private cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>U.S. and foreign investments</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-30T17:32:36Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Relations Promotion Act - Directs the President to appoint a Special Representative for United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Affairs within the Department of State. States that the Special Representative should be a person of distinction, culturally sensitive to the underserved African Diaspora in the United States, with substantial experience in matters of trade or economic development and in matters relating to African Diaspora relations with Africa.<br> </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of State to establish, within the Department of State, the Office of United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Affairs, with the Special Representative as its head.</p> <p>Directs the Special Representative to establish five regional United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Affairs public outreach, education, and liaison centers.</p> <p>Requires the Special Representative and the Office to: (1) promote U.S.-African trade and investment relations and foster socioeconomic development and economic growth; (2) design and implement public outreach, education, and liaison programs and activities intended to foster U.S.-African economic, technical, social, and cultural ties; (3) facilitate and increase the number of international learning exchange, professional, training, and educational programs between Africa and the United States; (4) establish a publicly accessible database through which U.S. and African businesses, academics, and organizations can communicate and establish ties; and (5) consult with African governments, the African Union, African intergovernmental subregional organizations, public-private partnership entities, private businesses and foundations, nongovernmental organizations, and United Nations (U.N.) agencies with respect to matters of Africa-related trade, economic development, and African-African Diaspora relations.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Relations Promotion Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Relations Promotion Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To advance the mutual interests of the United States and Africa with respect to the promotion of trade and investment and the advancement of socioeconomic development and opportunity, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States-Africa Trade, Development, and Diaspora Relations Promotion Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-12-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr6535ih/xml/BILLS-111hr6535ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-12-16</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
