<bill session="115" type="s" number="5" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:38Z">
  <state datetime="2018-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fix IOUs for Student Veterans Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to pay individuals who are owed educational assistance under the Post-9/11 Educational Assistance program the amounts of educational assistance that they are entitled to by law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix Immediately Outstanding Underpayments for Student Veterans Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix IOUs for Student Veterans Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2018-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-26T12:49:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fix Immediately Outstanding Underpayments for Student Veterans Act of 2018 or the Fix IOUs for Student Veterans Act of 2018

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to pay the difference to individuals who received a deficient monthly educational assistance stipend during a specific time span due to difficulties encountered in implementing amendments made to the Harry W. Colmery Veterans Educational Assistance Act, commonly known as the Forever GI Bill. Among other things, changes made to the act affected the calculation of the housing stipend amount based on campus location.</summary>
</bill>
