<bill session="117" type="h" number="7483" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cost of Mental Illness Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cost of Mental Illness Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a study on the direct and indirect costs of serious mental illness for nongovernmental entities, the Federal Government, and State, local, and Tribal governments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2022-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2022-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2022-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-01T20:02:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Cost of Mental Illness Act of 2022

This bill requires a study on the direct and indirect costs associated with serious mental illness (i.e., a mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder resulting in a serious, functional impairment that substantially interferes with major life activities). It also requires periodic surveillance surveys of individuals with schizophrenia.

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must study health care, housing, public safety, and other costs incurred by federal, state, tribal, and local governments and nongovernmental entities to address serious mental illness. HHS must consult with the Department of Justice, the Department of Labor, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development on the study.

Additionally, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) must periodically conduct a surveillance survey to collect information about individuals with schizophrenia, such as their demographic characteristics and health status. SAMHSA must coordinate with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institute of Mental Health, and other federal agencies on the survey. SAMHSA may also award grants or other assistance to nonprofits for convening stakeholder meetings and other activities to support the survey.</summary>
</bill>
