<bill session="116" type="h" number="4993" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REVAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require members of the Armed Forces to receive physical examinations and mental health assessments during the 90-day period before separation from the Armed Forces, to include health care planning in the Transition Assistance Program for members of the Armed Forces, to require the Secretary of Defense to issue an annual report to Congress regarding health care for separating members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Refer and Equip Veterans And Military Personnel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REVAMP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-26T20:37:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Refer and Equip Veterans and Military Personnel Act or the REVAMP Act

This bill revises the Transition Assistance Program, which prepares service members for civilian life.

The bill extends to certain reservists specified program requirements that currently apply to service members separating from active duty. Specifically, the bill requires certain members of a reserve component who have previously served on active duty to be provided with both a physical examination and a mental health assessment prior to separation. Under current law, only a physical examination must be offered to such reservists, and the examination is optional.

The bill also specifies the time period during which the pre-separation physical examination and mental health assessment must occur. Specifically, a service member must undergo a physical examination and mental health assessment during the 90-day period before the service member's separation from the Armed Forces.

In addition, the bill requires pre-separation counseling to include a plan for a service member's achievement of health care objectives.</summary>
</bill>
