<bill session="111" type="h" number="1645" updated="2020-02-10T16:51:55Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial and Economic Literacy Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Financial and Economic Literacy Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide grants to promote financial and economic literacy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2009-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2009-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2010-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000170" joined="2010-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="638" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-09T21:37:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial and Economic Literacy Improvement Act of 2009 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award formula matching grants to states or partnerships between states, experienced nonprofit providers of financial and economic literacy education, and experienced nonprofit providers of teacher training in such fields.

Requires grantees to use 25% of the grant funds to: (1) develop financial and economic literacy standards and assessments for at least three grade levels; (2) create teacher training programs to embed financial and economic literacy education into core academic subjects; and (3) evaluate the impact such education has on students' financial and economic literacy.

Requires the remaining grant funds to be used for subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) or partnerships between LEAs and community organizations, local businesses, or other educational entities to implement such financial literacy activities, including student assessments and teacher training.

Directs the Secretary to maintain a Financial and Economic Literacy and Economic Education Clearinghouse of best practices, tools, and instructional materials that are aligned with voluntary nationally recognized curriculum standards in such areas.

Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) or partnerships between IHEs, experienced nonprofit providers of financial and economic literacy education, and experienced nonprofit providers of teacher training in such fields for activities that increase student knowledge in consumer, economic, and personal financial concepts.</summary>
</bill>
