<bill session="110" type="h" number="5758" updated="2019-11-15T20:55:39Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reverse Mortgage Proceeds Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Reverse Mortgage Proceeds Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit authorized lenders of home equity conversion mortgages from requiring seniors to purchase an annuity with the proceeds of a reverse mortgage, and to provide other consumer protections to reverse mortgage borrowers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2490" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-19T18:58:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Reverse Mortgage Proceeds Protection Act - Amends the National Housing Act of 1937 to modify the eligibility criteria for insurance of home equity conversion mortgages (reverse mortgages) of elderly home owners.

Excludes from the third party adequate counseling requirement counseling by a reverse mortgage lender, servicer or investor, or an entity engaged in the sale of annuities, investments, long-term care insurance, or any other type of financial or insurance product.

Repeals the waiver of upfront insurance premiums for mortgages to fund long-term care insurance.

Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to use a portion of reverse mortgage insurance premiums to fund mandatory counseling and disclosure activities, including counseling for homeowners who elect not to take out a home equity conversion mortgage.

Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to protect elderly homeowners from the marketing of financial and insurance products not in their interest, including the marketing or sale of an annuity as a precondition to obtaining a home equity conversion mortgage.</summary>
</bill>
