<bill session="116" type="h" number="5585" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Listing Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require review of the economic cost of adding a species to the list of endangered species or threatened species, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Listing Reform Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000377" joined="2020-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001109" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000584" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2020-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2020-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-01T16:19:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Listing Reform Act

This bill modifies requirements concerning the review of petitions to add a&#160;species&#160;to the list of endangered or threatened species or to remove a species from the list.

Specifically, the bill allows the Department of the Interior and the Department of Commerce to prioritize the consideration of petitions to list a species as endangered or threatened other than in the order in which the petitions are received. The appropriate department may not give general priority to petitions to add species to the list of endangered or threatened species over petitions to remove a species from the list.

The deadline for the appropriate department to decide on whether or not a petition to list or remove a species should be granted is changed from within 12 months to as expeditiously as possible.

The appropriate department is given the authority to preclude the listing of a species as threatened due to the likelihood of significant, cumulative economic effects that would result from such listing or from the likely resulting designation of critical habitat of the species. Once a petition is precluded due to those economic effects, the appropriate department may not reconsider that finding unless the department (1) determines there is endangerment of extinction of the species; or (2) receives a new petition to add the species to the list that includes an analyses concluding that alternative actions are possible other than those resulting in significant, cumulative economic effects.</summary>
</bill>
