<bill session="119" type="h" number="2351" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-09T17:22:25-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-09T17:22:25-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to update the policy of the Coast Guard regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdose, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to update the policy of the Coast Guard regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdose, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001240"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000601" joined="2025-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 119-149.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-06-06" calendar="Union" number="118">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 118.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09T17:15:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Ezell moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09T17:15:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2547-2548" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09T17:15:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2351.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-06-09T17:22:25-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2547-2548" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-06-09T17:22:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-30T14:46:35Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill&#160;requires the Coast Guard to provide access to naloxone (a medication to reverse opioid overdoses) at its facilities, track distribution of the medication,&#160;and monitor the illegal use of of controlled substances.&#160;

The bill directs the Coast Guard to update its policy regarding the use of medication to treat drug overdoses to require naloxone or a similar medication to be made available to members on all Coast Guard installations and in each operational environment.&#160;

Further, the Coast Guard must participate in the Department of Defense (DOD) tracking system for naloxone distribution and the illegal use of fentanyl and other controlled substances. (The National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2024 directed DOD to&#160;establish the tracking system.) The bill requires the&#160;Coast Guard to finalize a memorandum of understanding with DOD to facilitate Coast Guard access to the tracking system.

The bill also specifies that laws that prohibit manufacturing or distributing controlled substances on vessels apply when controlled substances are intentionally or knowingly placed or caused to be placed on board a vessel (e.g., without the crew's knowledge or on board an unmanned vessel).&#160;

Further, the bill requires the Coast Guard to brief Congress within two years after the bill's enactment about the use of opioids and overdose medication at Coast Guard facilities by members and personnel. The briefing must describe the Coast Guard's progress in implementing its updated policy, the prevalence and incidence of the illegal use of controlled&#160; substances, and its processes to mitigate substance abuse.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-149</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
