<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="3814" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:13Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2845" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-10-04">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-09-30"/>
  <description>To provide the sense of Congress that United States foreign assistance should be provided to South Asia, Southeast Asia, West Africa, the Horn of Africa, North and North Central Africa, the Arabian peninsula, Central and Eastern Europe, and South America to prevent the establishment of terrorist sanctuaries.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-05">
      <text>Amendment SA 3814, as previously agreed to, was modified by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10417" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2004-10-04" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 3814 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04">
      <text>Amendment SA 3814 proposed by Senator Lieberman for Senator Bingaman. (consideration: CR S10351-10358; text: CR S10352) To provide the sense of Congress that United States foreign assistance should be provided to South Asia, Southeast Asia, West Africa, the Horn of Africa, North and North Central Africa, the Arabian peninsula, Central and Eastern Europe, and South America to prevent the establishment of terrorist sanctuaries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3814 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3814 proposed by Senator Lieberman for Senator Bingaman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10351-10358" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S10352" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-30">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
