<bill session="118" type="s" number="1006" updated="2025-11-19T02:46:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to direct the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on implementation of the advanced capabilities pillar of the trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on implementation of the advanced capabilities pillar of the trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1471" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1093" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-25T16:59:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of State to report to Congress on State Department efforts to implement the advanced capabilities pillar of the trilateral security partnership between Australia, the United Kingdom (UK), and the United States. (One of the goals of the partnership is to develop and provide joint advanced military capabilities, such as artificial intelligence, hypersonics, and electronic warfare.)

The report must include (1) the average and median times for the U.S. government to review applications for export licenses for defense articles or services to the governments and persons (entities and individuals) of Australia or the UK, (2) information about certain violations of the International Traffic in Arms Regulations by the governments or persons of Australia or the UK, and (3) recommended changes to the export control laws and regulations of the three partnership countries to implement the partnership.</summary>
</bill>
