<bill session="119" type="h" number="5924" updated="2025-11-18T17:56:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pay Our Capitol Police Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Capitol Police Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for the United States Capitol Police with respect to a Government shutdown.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001213"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3073" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-06T22:24:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Pay Our Capitol Police Act

This bill provides FY2026 continuing appropriations for the U.S. Capitol Police (USCP) to pay and provide benefits for employees who are working during a government shutdown.

The bill provides the appropriations for any period during which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2026 are not in effect (i.e., a government shutdown). Specifically, the bill provides the appropriations to the USCP for salaries, overtime pay, hazardous duty pay, recruitment and retention bonuses, and employee benefits for (1) members of the&#160;USCP who are excepted employees (i.e., required to work) or are performing emergency work during the shutdown, and (2) civilian employees who are providing support to the members.

The bill also provides appropriations for payments to USCP contractors who are providing support to the members of the&#160;USCP who are working during the shutdown.&#160;

The appropriations provided by this bill may not be used during any period in which continuing appropriations are in effect for these purposes.&#160;

The appropriations are available until the earlier of (1) the enactment into law of legislation to provide FY2026 appropriations for the USCP or the legislative branch (including continuing appropriations), or (2) September 30, 2026.

The bill must take effect as if it had been enacted on October 1, 2025.</summary>
</bill>
