<bill session="111" type="h" number="3275" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:27Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the definition of commercial motor vehicle in section 31101 of title 49, United States Code, to exclude certain farm vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the definition of commercial motor vehicle in section 31101 of title 49, United States Code, to exclude certain farm vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2009-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1862"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="639" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-10-14T23:08:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Revises the definition of "commercial motor vehicle" with respect to federal commercial motor vehicle safety laws to include a vehicle with farm-designated license plates engaged in the transportation of agricultural commodities or farm supplies, or a vehicle controlled by a farmer and used to transport such items to or from a farm, having a gross vehicle weight rating or gross vehicle weight the greater of which exceeds the minimum weight of a commercial motor vehicle as established by the state. (Current law applies to vehicles having a gross vehicle weight rating or gross vehicle weight of at least 10,001 pounds, whichever is greater.)

Prohibits the Secretary of Transportation from withholding commercial motor vehicle safety improvement grants from a state solely because it authorizes drivers of farm vehicles having a gross vehicle weight of between 10,000 and 26,001 pounds to operate without complying with federal commercial motor vehicle safety laws.</summary>
</bill>
