<bill session="119" type="h" number="720" updated="2025-11-18T18:45:40Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Life in Health Savings Accounts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Life in Health Savings Accounts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to prohibit treatment of certain distributions and reimbursements for certain abortions as qualified medical expenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001102" joined="2025-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001086" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001188" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="251" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-24T12:54:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Life in Health Savings Accounts Act

This bill excludes expenses paid for an abortion from qualified medical expenses eligible for reimbursement from certain tax-exempt savings accounts. (Some exceptions apply.)

Under the bill, amounts paid for an abortion, other than an excluded abortion, are not qualified medical expenses eligible for reimbursement from a health savings account, Archer medical savings account, health flexible spending arrangement, health reimbursement arrangement, or retiree health account.

The bill defines excluded abortion as any abortion (1) related to a pregnancy that is the result of rape or incest; or (2)&#160;performed because a woman is suffering from a physical disorder, injury, or illness (including a life-endangering physical condition caused by or arising from the pregnancy itself) that would, as certified by a physician, place the woman in danger of death if an abortion were not performed.</summary>
</bill>
