<bill session="118" type="s" number="3601" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Stability Oversight Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Stability Oversight Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to require the Financial Stability Oversight Council to consider alternative approaches before determining that a U.S. nonbank financial company shall be supervised by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2024-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3812" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-22T21:19:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Financial Stability Oversight Council Improvement Act of 2024

This bill requires the Financial Stability Oversight Council, prior to determining that a U.S.&#160;nonbank financial company shall be supervised by the Federal Reserve Board and therefore subject to certain prudential standards, to first determine that certain alternative actions would not mitigate the threat the company may pose to U.S. financial stability.

The bill also requires the council to annually submit a report to Congress identifying planning materials and activities relating to threats to U.S. financial stability, as well as steps taken by the council to plan for a financial crisis.

Finally, the council must publicly release detailed minutes after a closed meeting of the council.</summary>
</bill>
