<bill session="118" type="s" number="807" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RETURN Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RETURN Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Return Employees to Understaffed Work Sites to Reopen Now Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the head of each agency to establish a plan to resume in-person operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-01T18:30:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Return Employees to Understaffed Work Sites to Reopen Now Act of 2023 or the RETURN Act of 2023

This bill requires each federal agency to submit to Congress and publish on the agency's website a plan for the agency to resume in-person operations.

The plan shall, among other things, include

 the agency's policy with respect to permitting permanent remote work for employees who can successfully achieve their duties away from their official work sites, metrics to measure the productivity of employees performing remote work to identify employees that fail to fulfill their duties, a plan to provide essential government services in person for individuals in the United States, and measures to prepare for future public health emergencies that can be quickly implemented if remote work becomes necessary. Each agency must submit a report to the General Services Administration recommending termination of the agency's leases of physical work spaces that are underused.</summary>
</bill>
