<bill session="117" type="h" number="4302" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address the bark beetle epidemic, to reduce catastrophic wildfires in the highest risk areas, to restore and improve the ecological integrity of forest, grassland, rangeland, and watershed ecosystems across the United States through public and private partnerships with Federal, State, local, and Tribal governments and private partners, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Active Forest Management, Wildfire Prevention and Community Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Active Forest Management, Wildfire Prevention and Community Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000825"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2022-08-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2021-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4569" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4573" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2698" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="940" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4516" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-25T22:42:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Active Forest Management, Wildfire Prevention and Community Protection Act

This bill establishes forest management, forest conservation, and wildfire prevention programs and activities.

The bill establishes

 a collaborative prescribed fire program, an incentive program for large, cross-boundary prescribed fires, a program to remove or treat bark beetle-killed or infested trees, the Restoration and Resilience Partnership Program, and Forest Reserve Revenue Areas to generate revenue for counties. The bill also provides for, among other things

 the removal of certain trees or parts of those trees that come within 500 feet of an electric power line as hazard trees, the selection and implementation of landscape-scale forest restoration projects, removing the maximum term limits on stewardship end result contracting projects, study of only two alternatives (action vs. nonaction) in proposed collaborative forest management activities, the balancing of the long- and short-term effects of forest management activities on the affected ecosystem while considering injunctive relief, categorical exclusions from certain environmental requirements for specified forest management activities, and the expansion of the fire regime areas outside the wildland-urban interface for which a collaborative restoration project may be conducted.</summary>
</bill>
