<bill session="119" type="h" number="626" updated="2025-11-19T03:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northwest Energy Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northwest Energy Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for operations of the Federal Columbia River Power System pursuant to a certain operation plan for a specified period of time, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000189"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001322" joined="2025-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000668" joined="2025-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2025-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="182" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-07T16:35:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Northwest Energy Security Act

This bill requires Federal Columbia River Power System (FCRPS) operations to be consistent with the preferred alternative in a&#160;2020 environmental impact statement (EIS)&#160;decision that focuses on the operations, maintenance, and configuration of dams in the system rather than wild fish restoration. The system includes dams in the Columbia and Snake rivers in Oregon, Washington, Montana, and Idaho.

Specifically, the Bureau of Reclamation, the Bonneville Power Administration, and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers must operate the FCRPS consistent with the Columbia River System Operations Environmental Impact Statement Record of Decision dated September 2020. Thus, Reclamation,&#160;the Bonneville Power Administration, and the Army Corps must follow the EIS rather than the 2023 Resilient Columbia Basin Initiative&#226;&#8364;&#8221;and a&#160;supplemental EIS proposed in 2024&#226;&#8364;&#8221;that focus on wild fish restoration in the Columbia Basin.

The EIS decision may be amended if each agency determines that (1) changes are necessary for public safety or electrical grid reliability, or (2) certain requirements in the decision are no longer necessary.

Further, the bill requires statutory authorization for any structural modification, action, study, or engineering plan that (1) restricts FCRPS hydroelectric dam generation; or (2) limits navigation on the Snake River in Washington, Oregon, or Idaho.</summary>
</bill>
