<bill session="116" type="h" number="5462" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BUSREGS21 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to take actions to address issues affecting motorcoach and school bus operators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Buses United for Safety, Regulatory Reform, and Enhanced Growth for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BUSREGS21 Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-22T18:03:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Buses United for Safety, Regulatory Reform, and Enhanced Growth for the 21st Century Act or the BUSREGS21 Act

This bill addresses provisions related to passenger motor carriers, including school buses.

Among other matters, the bill

 prescribes requirements for, and limitations on, the use of Department of Transportation (DOT) motor coach carrier safety fitness determinations; exempts commercial motor coach drivers, motor coach carriers, and private school bus carriers from certain proposed regulations and requirements, including requirements related to obstructive sleep apnea, and the installation of speed limiting devices; requires DOT to establish a committee to modernize Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) regulations applicable to the operations of passenger motor carriers; requires the Government Accountability Office to conduct a study assessing the effects of FMCSA and National Highway Traffic Safety Administration regulations affecting certain small fleet motor carriers that were finalized in the preceding ten years; directs DOT to carry out a pilot program to compare the effectiveness of prescheduled inspections with random destination inspections on passenger motor carriers; prohibits DOT from promulgating any new regulatory mandates for motor coaches or school buses that are not based solely on sound data and science that will directly reduce crashes; and creates an incentive program for public transit agencies that contract with the private sector for fixed route bus transportation services.</summary>
</bill>
