<bill session="116" type="s" number="4625" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Prescribed Fire Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Prescribed Fire Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to encourage and expand the use of prescribed fire on land managed by the Department of the Interior or the Forest Service, with an emphasis on units of the National Forest System in the western United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2020-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2020-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-382.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-05T19:34:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Prescribed Fire Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) and the Department of the Interior to significantly increase the number and size of prescribed fires conducted on federal lands.

Before the end of FY2022, Interior and USDA shall each have carried out a minimum of one prescribed fire on each unit of the National Forest System (with exceptions), unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System, unit of the National Park System, and Bureau of Land Management district (1) that includes an area that has a historical low-severity fire regime, has a historical fire-return interval of not more than 35 years, and is larger than 100 acres; and (2) less than half of which was burned by a wildland fire during the previous 10-year period.

Interior shall establish a collaborative prescribed fire program to provide financial assistance to eligible entities to conduct prescribed fires in priority landscapes.

Interior shall establish an incentive program to encourage the implementation of large, cross-boundary prescribed fires.

Interior and USDA shall hire additional employees and provide training to increase the number of skilled and qualified prescribed fire practitioners in the departments and other organizations.

To address the public health and safety risk of the expanded use of prescribed fire, USDA and Interior shall conduct research to improve or develop, among other things, cost-effective, and consistent mitigation strategies for communities impacted adversely by smoke from prescribed fire.</summary>
</bill>
