<bill session="117" type="s" number="354" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Metro Safety, Accountability, and Investment Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize funding to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority contingent on improvements to the governance and operations of the Transit Authority.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metro Safety, Accountability, and Investment Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2021-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-07T13:54:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Metro Safety, Accountability, and Investment Act of 2021

This bill reauthorizes funding to the Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority (WMATA) contingent on certain changes to its governance and operations.

The bill reauthorizes capital and preventive maintenance grants to WMATA for FY2021-2030 as well as additional funding for capital and preventive maintenance projects and the WMATA Inspector General (IG).

The Department of Transportation (DOT) may not provide any amounts to WMATA until certain conditions are met, including that DOT (1) certifies that the WMATA Board of Directors has passed a resolution that reaffirms the IG as an independent and objective unit, (2) establishes and maintains the Jeanice McMillan Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Track Safety Task Force, (3) establishes and maintains a Keith Dodson Washington Metropolitan Area Transit Authority Bus Safety Task Force, and (4) certifies that the WMATA General Manager has implemented procedures that establish documented policies and procedures for the capital planning process and require WMATA to improve the transit asset management planning process.</summary>
</bill>
