<bill session="117" type="s" number="1999" updated="2022-12-30T21:30:51Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to authorize the use of certain Federal funds for multiple substance impaired driving countermeasures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Multiple Substance Impaired Driving Prevention Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Multiple Substance Impaired Driving Prevention Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3757" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-27T18:13:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Multiple Substance Impaired Driving Prevention Act of 2021

This bill includes substances other than alcohol within the scope of federal programs for preventing impaired driving. It also addresses reporting of impaired driving arrests, citations, convictions, and related matters to federal and other databases.

Under current law, if a state does not have (or enforce) certain laws to address repeat intoxicated drivers, a portion of that state's Federal-aid highway funding must be reserved for alcohol-related countermeasures for impaired driving. This bill provides that reserved funds may also be used for countermeasures for single or multiple substance impaired driving.

Additionally, states may use grants for impaired driving countermeasures to improve (1) reporting of information about crashes and impaired driving to federal, state, and local databases; and (2) research using such information.

The Government Accountability Office must also study the extent to which states and localities report information about impaired driving to relevant federal databases and use the databases to identify repeat impaired driving offenders.</summary>
</bill>
