<bill session="108" type="s" number="2635" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:24Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish an intergovernmental grant program to identify and develop homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services to further the homeland security needs of the United States and to address the homeland security needs of  Federal, State, and local governments.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an intergovernmental grant program to identify and develop homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services to further the homeland security needs of the United States and to address the homeland security needs of  Federal, State, and local governments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2004-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7842"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-420.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="818">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 818.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-11-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11832-11834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11832-11833" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11834" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24T14:02:59-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24T15:40:20-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4077"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2005-01-05T16:08:47Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(Sec. 2) Establishes the United States-Israel Homeland Security Grant Program to identify, develop, or modify existing or near term homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services to further the homeland security of the United States and to address the homeland security needs of Federal, State, and local governments.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, in carrying out such program, to: (1) assess the homeland security needs of Federal, State, and local governments and first responders and areas where specific homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services could address those needs; (2) survey near-term and existing homeland security information developed within the United States and Israel; and (3) provide grants (directly or through a nonprofit, non-governmental organization) to eligible applicants to develop, manufacture, sell, or otherwise provide homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services to address such needs.

Makes eligible for grant funds those applicants who: (1) address one or more identified needs of Federal, State, and local governments and first responders; (2) are organized as joint ventures between U.S.-Israeli entities; and (3) meet other qualifications required by the Secretary.

Requires the Secretary to establish an advisory board to monitor any grant funds awarded to eligible applicants through nonprofit, nongovernmental organizations.

Authorizes the Secretary to require the Government of Israel to contribute an appropriate amount toward a grant-funded project before the disbursement of funds.

Requires the Secretary to give priority to applicants who propose to market homeland security information, equipment, technologies, or services developed or modified with grant funds to Federal, State, and local governments and first responders.

 Authorizes the Secretary to require grant recipients to: (1) make available non-Federal matching contributions of up to 50 percent of the total proposed project cost; and (2) repay the amount of the grant with interest and administrative charges.

Authorizes appropriations through FY 2006.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-420</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
