<bill session="116" type="s" number="4503" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Patient-Centered Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Patient-Centered Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to protect beneficiaries with limb loss and other orthopedic conditions by providing access to appropriate, safe, effective, patient-centered orthotic and prosthetic care, to reduce fraud, waste, and abuse with respect to orthotics and prosthetics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5262" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-09T13:30:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Orthotics and Prosthetics Patient-Centered Care Act

This bill revises payment rules and establishes several requirements relating to coverage of orthotics and prosthetics under Medicare.

Specifically, the bill requires suppliers of orthotics and prosthetics to meet certain standards with respect to licensure and accreditation, physical facilities, and liability insurance. Orthotists and prosthetists may also issue written orders for commercial purposes that meet specified standards; such orders must be signed by the treating physician.

The bill also prohibits payment under Medicare for certain prosthetics and orthotics that are delivered via drop shipment (i.e., direct shipment to a beneficiary who has not received corresponding patient care from a health care practitioner).</summary>
</bill>
