<bill session="116" type="s" number="2828" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to prepare a programmatic environmental impact statement allowing for adaptive management of certain Federal land in Malheur County, Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-380.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-09T19:49:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Malheur Community Empowerment for the Owyhee Act

This bill addresses various public land concerns in Malheur County in Oregon.

The bill directs the Department of the Interior to prepare a programmatic environmental impact statement for certain federal land in the county. Interior shall develop plans for areas that are ecologically degraded or most at risk of being ecologically degraded. Interior shall establish the Malheur Community Empowerment for Owyhee Group, which shall, among other things, use such statement to review projects proposed to the Bureau of Land Management by group members, ranchers holding grazing permits on the federal land, or other members of the public.

The bill also

 establishes a network to monitor such land, designates 1,133,481 acres of federal lands in the county as wilderness and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, designates a 14.7-mile segment of Owyhee River as a recreational river, establishes improvements for certain loop roads, requires separate feasibility studies concerning Owyhee Reservoir, requires improvements to existing Oregon State Parks and private camps on the shore of the Reservoir, establishes a dude ranch at Birch Creek, requires a feasibility study on a specified rails-to-trails project, requires a feasibility study on marketing communities or portions of the county as the Gateway to the Oregon Owyhee, requires a determination of the use and conditions under which the Jordan Valley Airstrip may be used to support firefighting, and establishes the Native Seed Center as the primary federal native seed repository in the Western States.</summary>
</bill>
