<bill session="116" type="s" number="584" updated="2022-11-01T16:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the commitment of the United States to the International Space Station, to develop advanced space suits, and to enable human space settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2019-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-15T23:06:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act

This bill addresses the establishment of U.S. policy, programs, and activities pertaining to human presence in space.

The bill declares that it is U.S. policy to permanently establish a human presence in low-Earth orbit and that such capability shall

 maintain U.S. global leadership and relations with partners and allies, contribute to the general welfare of the United States, and be affordable so as to not preclude a robust portfolio of other human space exploration activities. The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall ensure that the International Space Station (ISS) remains a viable and productive facility capable of potential U.S. use through at least FY2030.

NASA must submit a strategy that includes how it will transition to a successor platform to the ISS.

The bill expands the objectives of NASA to include the expansion of permanent human presence beyond Earth in a way that enables human space settlement and a thriving space economy.

NASA shall establish a program of developing space suits and associated technologies.</summary>
</bill>
