<bill session="115" type="s" number="1747" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:47Z">
  <state datetime="2017-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Florida Manatee Research and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Florida Manatee Research and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize research and recovery activities to provide for the protection, conservation, and recovery of the Florida manatee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-08T22:05:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Florida Manatee Research and Recovery Act

This bill requires the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) to begin to carry out research and recovery activities specific to Florida manatee populations, the subspecies Trichechus manatus latirostris, in the United States.

The Marine Mammal Commission must recommend to the USFWS steps for the protection, conservation, and recovery of the populations.

In addition, the USFWS must establish a peer-reviewed, merit-based process to award competitive grants for: (1) research regarding Florida manatees; and (2) recovery activities that assist in or promote their protection, conservation, and recovery.

Within two years, the USFWS must report on: (1) the status of Florida manatee populations, (2) research and recovery activities, (3) the manatee grant review and award process, and (4) relevant consultations conducted under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA) with respect to the Florida manatee.

Within three years, and every five years thereafter, the USFWS must report on (1) the status of the Florida manatees' health, mortality, and habitat; (2) actions taken to improve their health, reduce their mortality, and improve and protect their habitat; (3) recommendations for actions that may be taken under current law for improving their health, reducing their mortality due to humans, and improving and protecting their habitat; (4) recommendations for funding to carry out this bill; and (5) relevant consultations conducted under the ESA.</summary>
</bill>
