<bill session="117" type="h" number="1008" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Handgun Trigger Safety Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development and use of technology for personalized handguns, to require that all handguns manufactured or sold in, or imported into, the United States incorporate such technology, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Handgun Trigger Safety Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-03T21:02:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Handgun Trigger Safety Act of 2021 This bill establishes a framework to regulate handguns as consumer products. The bill establishes two general requirements: (1) new domestically manufactured handguns must be personalized handguns, and (2) handguns distributed in commerce must be personalized handguns or retrofitted personalized handguns. A personalized handgun allows only an authorized user to fire the handgun. The bill directs the National Institute of Justice to make grants to develop technology for personalized handguns. It also requires gun manufacturers to retrofit, at an owner's request, a domestically manufactured handgun that is not a personalized handgun or retrofitted personalized handgun. The bill authorizes the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to issue safety standards for personalized handguns. The CPSC and states may enforce violations, which are treated as violations under the Consumer Product Safety Act. The bill retains civil liability protections for gun manufacturers for harms resulting from the misuse of a handgun, but only if the handgun is a personalized handgun or retrofitted personalized handgun.</summary>
</bill>
