<bill session="117" type="s" number="2356" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide funding to rehabilitate, retrofit, and remove the Nation's dams to improve the health of the Nation's rivers, improve public safety, and increase clean energy production, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Twenty-First Century Dams Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Twenty-First Century Dams Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4927-4928" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4375" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-08T18:45:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Twenty-First Century Dams Act

This bill addresses dam infrastructure and safety.

First, the bill provides resources for programs related to state dam safety, the rehabilitation of high hazard potential dams, and the inspection of dams. In particular, the bill reauthorizes through FY2026 the National Dam Safety Program.

In addition, the bill reauthorizes through FY2026 a program related to the rehabilitation of structural measures and a program related to water infrastructure.

The bill directs the Department of the Army to establish a program to carry out dam removal projects.

Further, the bill establishes the Dam Removal Council to (1) coordinate with participating federal agencies to annually notify all known dam owners of the availability of dam removal funding and provide guidance on the existing programs of participating agencies; (2) evaluate and submit to Army recommendations for dam removal projects, technical assistance programs, and funding allocations; and (3) develop a dam removal strategy.

The bill requires certain dam assessments, including a joint assessment by the U.S. Geological Survey and the Department of Energy.

The bill also authorizes specified federal agencies to undertake certain activities related to federal dam infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
