<bill session="117" type="h" number="5243" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize the Fallon Range Training Complex in Churchill County, Nevada, through the withdrawal and reservation of additional public lands for military use, to provide for transfer of ownership of certain Federal lands in northern Nevada, to authorize the disposal of certain Federal lands in northern Nevada for economic development, to promote conservation in northern Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Northern Nevada Economic Development, Conservation, and Military Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Nevada Economic Development, Conservation, and Military Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Fernley Economic Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Pershing County Economic Development and Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Ruby Mountains Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-24T19:56:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Northern Nevada Economic Development, Conservation, and Military Modernization Act of 2021

This bill provides for the designation, withdrawal, conveyance, exchange, sale, or disposal of certain federal and nonfederal lands in Nevada, including land associated with the Fallon Range Training Complex, a naval training installation.

The bill designates the Fox Peak, Grimes Point, and Pistone-Black Mountain National Conservation Areas.

The bill also designates specified parcels of federal land as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill establishes a federal complex for specified Bureau of Land Management, Forest Service, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Bureau of Reclamation, and Bureau of Indian Affairs offices or headquarters in Nevada.

The bill requires the issuance of corrective patents for private lands adjacent to public land in White Pine County when (1) a cloud on the title demonstrates that the private land had been patented before 1976, and (2) the correction is for five acres or less.

The bill includes additional provisions, including ones resolving certain tribal claims.</summary>
</bill>
