<bill session="117" type="h" number="8799" updated="2022-12-29T12:33:50Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Otto Warmbier Countering North Korean Censorship and Surveillance Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Otto Warmbier Countering North Korean Censorship and Surveillance Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote freedom of information and counter censorship and surveillance in North Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000815"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2022-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2022-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2022-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2129" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-26T14:16:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Otto Warmbier Countering North Korean Censorship and Surveillance Act of 2021

This bill authorizes sanctions related to censorship in North Korea and addresses related issues.

The President may impose property-blocking sanctions on foreign individuals and entities responsible for implementing or facilitating North Korea's censorship laws and surveillance. For the individuals that meet such criteria, the President may also impose visa-blocking sanctions.

The bill also authorizes the U.S. Agency for Global Media to provide increased broadcasting and grants for various purposes, including the development of internet freedom tools to facilitate information sharing related to North Korea and the restoration of the agency's broadcasting capacity to North Korea.&#160;

The President must submit to Congress a strategy to combat North Korea's information environment. The Department of State and the Department of the Treasury must jointly report to Congress each year on U.S. government activities related to the enforcement of sanctions against North Korea.</summary>
</bill>
