<bill session="109" type="s" number="1110" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:06Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Engine Coolant and Antifreeze Bittering Agent Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Hazardous Substances Act to require engine coolant and antifreeze to contain a bittering agent in order to render the coolant or antifreeze unpalatable.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Engine Coolant and Antifreeze Bittering Agent Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Engine Coolant and Antifreeze Bittering Agent Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2006-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2005-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2005-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2005-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001162" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2005-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2005-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000059" joined="2005-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2005-11-01" withdrawn="2005-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2005-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-18">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation Subcommittee on Consumer Affairs, Product Safety, and Insurance. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-377.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Stevens with amendments. With written report No. 109-220. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-03-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="373">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 373.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSCM12" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="Consumer Affairs, Product Safety, and Insurance" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="2567" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Automobile engines"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Poisons"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-11T22:03:10Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Engine Coolant and Antifreeze Bittering Agent Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Hazardous Substances Act to require the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to: (1) commence an evaluation to determine whether there is evidence that the use of the bittering agent denatonium benzoate in engine coolant or antifreeze has an unreasonable adverse effect on the environment; and (2) publish its findings in the Federal Register.

Requires engine coolant or antifreeze that is manufactured 180 days or more after publication of the Commission's findings and that contains more than 10% ethylene glycol to include a specified concentration of denatonium benzoate to render the coolant or antifreeze unpalatable unless the Commission finds evidence that denatonium benzoate has an unreasonable adverse effect on the environment. Allows the Commission to permit use of an alternative bittering additive in lieu of denatonium benzoate if the Commission finds that it is as effective as denatonium benzoate and there is no evidence of an unreasonable adverse environmental effect.

Defines the term "unreasonable adverse effect on the environment" to mean an unreasonable risk to human health or the environment, taking into account the economic, social, and environmental costs and benefits.

Deems any engine coolant or antifreeze that is not in compliance with this Act to be a banned hazardous substance.

Requires a coolant or antifreeze manufacturer to maintain records of active ingredients of bittering agents.

Limits the liability of manufacturers, processors, distributors, recyclers, or sellers of engine coolant or antifreeze related to the inclusion of denatonium benzoate in compliance with this Act. Declares that the Act does not exempt manufactures or distributors of denatonium benzoate or an alternative bittering additive from liability related to such additive.

Preempts state or local laws that impose different requirements relating to the inclusion of a bittering agent in engine coolant or antifreeze. Declares this Act inapplicable to: (1) the sale of a motor vehicle that contains engine coolant or antifreeze; or (2) wholesale containers of 55 gallons or more of engine coolant or antifreeze.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-220</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
