<bill session="109" type="s" number="468" updated="2020-02-10T17:00:18Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Literacy in Finance and Economics (College LIFE) Act</title>
    <title type="display">College Literacy in Finance and Economics (College LIFE) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to enhance literacy in finance and economics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2005-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2005-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1796-1797"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-22T18:08:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">College Literacy in Finance and Economics (College LIFE) Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to direct the Secretary of Education, in carrying out HEA activities related to improving financial and economic literacy, education, and counseling, to emphasize, among other elements, basic personal income and household money management and financial planning skills, and basic economic decision making skills.



Requires with respect to minority-serving institutions and to student assistance: (1) educational or counseling services to improve the financial and economic literacy of students and their parents; and (2) personal finance courses and skills.

Directs the Secretary to establish a HEA pilot program to enable institutions of higher education (IHEs) to provide annual personal finance counseling for their students.

Directs the Secretary to make competitive grants to IHEs or other eligible entities under new programs for: (1) developing or sponsoring experimental, innovative delivery systems for financial literacy; (2) creating or sharing personal finance courses (with priority given to eligible entities that ban or discourage credit card proliferation and abusive credit marketing practices on campus); (3) studying and making recommendations on best ways to integrate personal finance and economics into basic educational subjects; and (4) training in economics and personal finance instruction or advising for elementary and secondary school teachers or secondary school counselors.

Directs the Comptroller General to evaluate and report to specified congressional committees on the range and effectiveness of financial and economic education and financial aid counseling activities of IHEs, lenders, servicers, and guaranty agencies as emphasized by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
