<bill session="117" type="s" number="217" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Patient Matching Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit the use of certain United States Postal Service formatting tools by health care organizations to improve the provision of patient matching services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Matching Improvement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-18T14:10:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patient Matching Improvement Act of 2021

This bill requires the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) to standardize the format of postal addresses in health information technology to improve patient matching. Patient matching is the identification and linking of one patient's data within and across health care organizations using multiple demographic fields, such as name and address.

The ONC must collaborate with the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) to make existing tools that automatically format addresses into a specific standard available to health care organizations. In particular, the ONC must focus on making the tools available to laboratories that test for COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) to improve data collection related to that disease. If the USPS determines the tools cannot be made available to health care organizations, the Department of Health and Human Services must report to Congress on the barriers that prevent such use.

In addition, the ONC must update regulations to require the use of a standard address format as a condition of certification for health information technology.</summary>
</bill>
