<bill session="116" type="hr" number="765" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:55Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-17T10:46:46-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-17T10:46:46-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1158) to authorize cyber incident response teams at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1865) to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint a coin in commemoration of the opening of the National Law Enforcement Museum in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes; and providing for the adoption of the resolution (H. Res. 761) permitting individuals to be admitted to the Hall of the House in order to obtain footage of the House in session for inclusion in the orientation film to be shown to visitors at the Capitol Visitor Center.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1158) to authorize cyber incident response teams at the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1865) to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint a coin in commemoration of the opening of the National Law Enforcement Museum in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes; and providing for the adoption of the resolution (H. Res. 761) permitting individuals to be admitted to the Hall of the House in order to obtain footage of the House in session for inclusion in the orientation film to be shown to visitors at the Capitol Visitor Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001206"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 116-353, by Mr. Morelle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T00:46:01-05:00">
      <text>Providing for the consideration of the Senate amendments to H.R. 1158, H.R. 1865; and for H. Res. 761. The Senate amendments will be debatable for one hour each. The previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions or demand for division of the question. Upon adoption of H. Res. 765, H. Res. 761 shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-17" calendar="House" number="62">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 62.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T09:07:14-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309-10312" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T09:09:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 765.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T09:31:45-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At conclusion of debate on H. Res. 765, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cole demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T10:01:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10312-10314" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T10:37:33-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 192 (Roll no. 683).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10312-10313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="684" datetime="2019-12-17T10:46:46-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 189 (Roll no. 684).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-17T10:46:49-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1158" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1865" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="761" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-22T17:02:25Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to (1) H.R. 1158 (DHS Cyber Hunt and Incident Response Teams Act of 2019), and (2) H.R. 1865 (National Law Enforcement Museum Commemorative Coin Act).

The chair of the Committee on Appropriations may insert in the Congressional Record by December 17, 2019, such material as the chair may deem explanatory of the Senate amendments and the motions specified in this resolution.

The resolution also adopts H.Res. 761 (permitting individuals to be admitted to the Hall of the House and connecting rooms to obtain footage of the House in session for inclusion in the orientation film to be shown to visitors at the Capitol Visitor Center).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-353</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
