<bill session="108" type="s" number="1106" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fishing Quota Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish National Standards for Fishing Quota Systems.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fishing Quota Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2003-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6985"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6985-6987" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Fish kills"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Overfishing"/>
    <term name="Shellfish"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sustainable fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-25T20:46:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fishing Quota Act of 2003 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to require the Regional Fishery Management Councils and the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) or his designee, when developing a limited access system for fisheries to achieve optimum yield, to take into account: (1) the conservation requirements of this Act with respect to fisheries; and (2) the fair and equitable distribution of a public resource.

Authorizes the establishment of a fishing quota system in a fishery management plan or amendment prepared by any Regional Fishery Management Council or the Secretary.

Specifies fishing quota system: (1) requirements the Councils and Secretary must ensure that any proposal meet; (2) right, tittle, and interest scope and limitations; (3) eligibility requirements; (4) duration; and (5) referendum procedures. Prohibits approval or implementation by the Secretary of any fishery management plan (or amendment) unless it has been approved by more than two-thirds of those voting in a referendum among eligible permit holders.

Authorizes the Secretary to approve and implement a program submitted by a Council which reserves up to 25 percent of the fees collected from fisheries for costs related to the management and enforcement of fishing quota programs for issuance of obligations that aid in financing the: (1) purchase of fishing quotas by small vessel fishermen; and (2) first-time purchase of fishing quotas by entry level fisherman.

Requires the National Research Council to provide an independent review, every five years, of the effectiveness of fishing quota systems conducted in Federal fisheries.

Requires the Secretary to issue regulations which establish requirements for a fishing quota system.</summary>
</bill>
