<bill session="117" type="h" number="4094" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-29T16:29:31-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-09-29T16:29:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To conduct a pilot program at foreign last point of departure airports to permit passengers and their accessible property to continue on additional flights or flight segments originating in the United States without additional security re-screening, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2021-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2021-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2021-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2021-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 117-123.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-09-17" calendar="Union" number="88">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 88.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29T16:20:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (MS) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29T16:20:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5541-5544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29T16:20:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4094.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-09-29T16:29:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5542" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29T16:29:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3375" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-28T17:07:10Z" status="Passed House">One-Stop Pilot Program Act of 2021 

This bill authorizes the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to conduct a pilot program at not more than six foreign last point of departure airports to permit passengers and their accessible property to bypass domestic security rescreening at a connecting airport in the United States.

Screening may be bypassed if (1) the country of departure has an aviation screening agreement with the United States setting standards and protocols comparable to those in the United States; (2) passengers cannot access their checked baggage until arriving at their final destination; and (3) upon arrival in the United States, passengers do not come into contact with other arriving international passengers (or their property) or persons who have not been screened.

The TSA must ensure there is no reduction in the level of security or specific aviation security standards and requirements for screening passengers and their property prior to boarding an international flight bound for the United States, including standards or requirements regarding (1) high risk passengers; and (2) weapons, explosives, and incendiaries.

If the TSA determines that the foreign countries participating in the screening agreements have not maintained and implemented comparable standards and protocols to those in the United States, it must ensure that passengers and their property arriving from the foreign airports are rescreened in the United States before they are permitted into sterile areas of the airports.

The pilot program shall terminate six years after the enactment of the bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-123</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
