<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="3158" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:54Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2400" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-05-18">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000447"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-05-18"/>
  <description>To provide that the 2005 base closure round shall apply solely to military installations located outside the United States and to provide for expedited consideration by Congress of a proposal for a base closure round in 2007 on military installations located inside the United States.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-05-18" how="roll" result="fail" roll="98">
      <text>Amendment SA 3158 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 49. Record Vote Number: 98.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Amendment SA 3158 proposed by Senator Lott. (consideration: CR S5569-5573, S5583-5593; text: CR S5569-5570) To provide that the 2005 base closure round shall apply solely to military installations located outside the United States and to provide for expedited consideration by Congress of a proposal for a base closure round in 2007 on military installations located inside the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3158 proposed by Senator Lott.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5569-5573, S5583-5593" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5569-5570" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 3158 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 49. Record Vote Number: 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3158 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 49. Record Vote Number: 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
