<bill session="117" type="s" number="2585" updated="2023-01-01T20:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize a grant program relating to the cybersecurity of State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">State and Local Cybersecurity Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State and Local Cybersecurity Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-22T19:37:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">State and Local Cybersecurity Improvement Act

This bill establishes a grant program administered by the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) for state, territorial, and tribal governments to address cybersecurity risks and threats to information systems.

A grant applicant must submit a cybersecurity plan that assesses current efforts to address cybersecurity concerns and outlines grant-funded activities. FEMA may award grant funding to support the development of a plan.

A grant recipient must make available at least 80% of funds to local governments with a particular focus on rural areas.

The bill requires various reports concerning the grant program, including an assessment of cybersecurity needs of tribal governments. The Government Accountability Office must also study the program.</summary>
</bill>
