<bill session="117" type="s" number="4058" updated="2023-05-16T14:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">C.A.R.E. for Mental Health Professionals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">C.A.R.E. for Mental Health Professionals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compacts, Access, and Responsible Expansion for Mental Health Professionals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to establish a grant program to be known as the Mental Health Licensure Portability Program to award grants to eligible entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6076" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-20T16:27:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Compacts, Access, and Responsible Expansion for Mental Health Professionals Act or the C.A.R.E. for Mental Health Professionals Act

This bill establishes a grant program to promote interstate licensure compacts for mental health professionals. These are licensure agreements enacted by two or more states to mutually recognize the licenses of counselors, psychiatrists, psychologists, or pediatric mental health professionals.

The Health Resources and Services Administration must award grants to interstate compact commissions or professional licensing boards. Recipients may use grants for projects to (1) incentivize mental health professionals to practice in states with interstate licensure compacts, and (2) develop or maintain interstate compact commissions.</summary>
</bill>
