<bill session="110" type="s" number="2730" updated="2020-01-29T20:30:07Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Energy Investment Bank Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Clean Energy Investment Bank Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the participation of private capital and skills in the strategic, economic, and environmental development of a diverse portfolio of clean energy and energy efficiency technologies within the United States, to facilitate the commercialization and market penetration of the technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001162" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2008-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1707-1708"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1708-1711" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Carbon cycle"/>
    <term name="Carbon dioxide"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-30T15:50:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Energy Investment Bank Act of 2008 - Establishes the Clean Energy Investment Bank of the United States, which shall be a U.S. agency and a government corporation.

Requires the bank to assist in the financing, and facilitate the commercial use, of clean energy and energy efficient technologies within the United States. Authorizes the Bank to make investments: (1) in projects in the United States related to the production or use of energy that use a commercial technology that avoids, reduces, or sequesters one or more air pollutants or anthropogenic emissions of greenhouse gases more effectively than other technology options available to the project developer; or (2) under provisions of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 concerning incentives for innovative technologies.

Authorizes the Bank to establish an equity finance program under which it may purchase, invest in, or otherwise acquire equity or quasi-equity securities of firms or entities for the purpose of providing capital for any project that is consistent with this Act.

Establishes in the Treasury the Clean Energy Investment Bank Fund that shall be available for discharge of Bank liabilities.

Transfers to the Bank's Board of Directors specified functions and authority of the Secretary of Energy concerning guarantees, loans, and credit assistance, including programs and authorities under the Energy Policy Act of 2005 concerning incentives for innovative technologies. Revises provisions of such Act concerning the terms and conditions of loan guarantees for such incentives.</summary>
</bill>
