<bill session="116" type="s" number="4287" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Benefits for Active Duty Servicemembers, the Reserve Components, and their Survivors Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Benefits for Active Duty Servicemembers, the Reserve Components, and their Survivors Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish presumptions of service-connection for members of the Armed Forces who contract Coronavirus Disease 2019 under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2020-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2020-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4320" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7728" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-24T16:34:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">COVID-19 Benefits for Active Duty Servicemembers, the Reserve Components, and their Survivors Act of 2020

This bill establishes, for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs benefits, a presumption of service-connection if COVID-19 symptoms manifest within a specified time period in individuals serving in the military or reserves during qualified periods of duty (i.e., active duty, training duty, or full-time National Guard duty). For individuals who become disabled or die as a result of COVID-19, it shall be presumed the individual became disabled or died during a qualified period of duty.

An individual who was disabled or died due to COVID-19 and was on training duty or full-time National Guard duty shall be furnished death or disability benefits as if the individual were a veteran, without regard to whether their duty period would constitute active military service.</summary>
</bill>
