<bill session="116" type="h" number="8084" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lethal Means Safety Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lethal Means Safety Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to update the Lethal Means Safety and Suicide Prevention training course of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2020-08-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2020-08-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-02T15:40:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Lethal Means Safety Training Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to update its Lethal Means Safety and Suicide Prevention training course at least once a year to ensure it is culturally appropriate and uses best practices identified by subject matter experts (e.g., veterans service organizations).

The bill requires certain VA employees and care providers to take the most recently updated version of the training course within 90 days after the person is hired, agrees to furnish care, or receives support and at least annually thereafter. Specifically, the bill requires the following categories of VA employees or care providers to take the training course:

 employees of the Veterans Health Administration or Veterans Benefits Administration who regularly interact with veterans, compensation and pension examiners, employees of Veterans Centers or vocational rehabilitation facilities, employees of Veterans Community Care Providers who provide care to veterans, and family caregivers receiving support under the Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers. The VA must publish the training course on a publicly available VA website. Additionally, the VA must publish a report on its website that includes the percentage of individuals in each category who have completed such training.</summary>
</bill>
