<bill session="114" type="s" number="915" updated="2021-07-10T19:56:53Z">
  <state datetime="2015-04-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="display">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt certain stock of real estate investment trusts from the tax on foreign investments in United States real property interests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-04-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hatch. With written report No. 114-25.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-04-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="48">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 48.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="2128" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2015-06-30T15:53:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Real Estate Investment and Jobs Act of 2015

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to the taxation of stock interests of foreign investors, to: (1) increase from 5% to 10% the stock ownership threshold in a&#160;real estate investment trust (REIT)&#160;for exempting such stock from treatment&#160;as a U.S. real property interest on disposition, (2) increase from from 10% to 15% the rate of withholding of tax on dispositions of U.S. real property interests, (3) require a corporation to notify the Department of the Treasury of its status as a U.S. real property holding corporation and to disclose such status on payee statements, (4) impose a penalty on a corporation for failing to make such disclosure, (5) require brokers who sell stock of a U.S. real property holding corporation to a foreign person to withhold 15% of the amount realized on the sale, and (6) deny dividends derived from regulated investment companies and REITs the tax deduction for the U.S.-sourced portion of such dividends received from a foreign-owned corporation.

The bill also increases from 30% to 35% the rate of the continuous levy on payments to Medicare providers and suppliers for unpaid taxes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-25</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
