<bill session="108" type="h" number="3568" updated="2023-01-15T08:33:23Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide extended unemployment benefits to displaced workers, and to make other improvements in the unemployment insurance system.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Unemployment Compensation Extension bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2003-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000762" joined="2003-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2003-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-19T19:06:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Unemployment Compensation Act - Amends the Temporary Extended Unemployment Compensation Act of 2002 (TEUCA) to: (1) extend the TEUC program; (2) provide for additional weeks of TEUC benefits; (3) revise unemployment rate triggers for TEUC benefit periods; and (4) provide for regular unemployment compensation for certain individuals based on part-time work or an alternative base period.

Extends the TEUC program through weeks of unemployment ending before July 1, 2004. Provides a phase-out period for individual payments up to weeks beginning after December 31, 2004.

Increases to 26 weeks an eligible individual's TEUC payments. Provides for an additional seven weeks of payments, for a total of 33 weeks, for individuals in high-unemployment States (TEUC-X). (Current law provides 13 weeks of regular TEUC payments, with an additional 13 and total 26 in TEUC-X States.)

Revises requirements for determining TEUC-X States, using certain triggers based on insured unemployment rates and on total unemployment rates.

Establishes a program of payments to States to provide regular unemployment compensation benefits for individuals who otherwise would be ineligible because: (1) the base period does not count wages earned in the most recently completed calendar quarter; or (2) the individuals seek or are available for less than full-time work.</summary>
</bill>
