<bill session="111" type="h" number="1109" updated="2019-11-15T21:28:52Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
    <title type="display">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate as wilderness additional National Forest System lands in the Monongahela National Forest in the State of West Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2009-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000844" joined="2009-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-23">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="22" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3961" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-09T16:00:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Wild Monongahela Act: A National Legacy for West Virginia's Special Places - Designates specified federal lands in the Monongahela National Forest, West Virginia, as wilderness and as either a new component, or as an addition to an existing component, of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Modifies the boundary of the Laurel Fork South Wilderness designated by P.L. 97- 466 (relating to the designation of certain lands in the Monongahela National Forest as wilderness) to exclude two specified parcels of land.

States that the boundary of the Monongahela National Forest is confirmed to include specified tracts of land.

Requires the development of a plan to provide for enhanced nonmotorized recreation trail opportunities on lands not designated as wilderness within the Monongahela National Forest.

Provides for the consideration of conversion of forest roads within Monongahela National Forest to nonmotorized uses to enhance recreational opportunities within the Forest.</summary>
</bill>
