<bill session="117" type="sc" number="41" updated="2022-10-19T04:25:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2023 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2024 through 2032.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for fiscal year 2023 and setting forth the appropriate budgetary levels for fiscal years 2024 through 2032.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-06">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Budget discharged pursuant to Section 300 of the Congressional Budget Act.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-06-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="397">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 397.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 29 - 67. Record Vote Number: 228.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2960"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits and national debt"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-17T16:33:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This concurrent resolution establishes the congressional budget for the federal government for FY2023 and sets forth budgetary levels for FY2024-FY2032.

The resolution recommends levels and amounts for FY2023-FY2032 for

 federal revenues, new budget authority, budget outlays, deficits, public debt, debt held by the public, and the major functional categories of spending. It also recommends levels and amounts for Social Security and Postal Service discretionary administrative expenses for the purpose of budget enforcement in the Senate.

In addition, the resolution establishes reserve funds that allow certain adjustments to committee allocations and other budgetary levels to accommodate legislation relating to (1) efficiencies, consolidations, and other savings; or (2) health savings accounts.

The resolution also sets forth budget enforcement procedures that address issues such as budget points of order, emergency legislation, and Congressional Budget Office cost estimates.</summary>
</bill>
