<bill session="115" type="s" number="1952" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:16Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Financial Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Financial Accountability Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve oversight and accountability of the financial processes of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2017-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-01">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-616.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T16:32:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Financial Accountability Act of 2017

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the normal Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) budget process should be grounded in sound actuarial analysis based on accurate demand forecasting, (2) the regular VA budget process should be the norm, and (3) supplemental requests for appropriations should be used sparingly and for unforeseen demand or natural occurrences.

The VA shall contract with an independent third party to: (1) to review and audit the VA's financial processes, including reporting structures and actuarial and estimation models; (2) develop recommendations to improve such structures; and (3) complete such review and development within 180 days of entering into the contract.

The VA shall submit an implementation plan to Congress within 60 days after completion of the review and development.

The VA shall appoint one individual within the Office of the VA Secretary to monitor the implementation of third party recommendations.

Whenever the VA submits to Congress a request for supplemental appropriations or other appropriation outside the standard budget process the VA shall submit a justification for the request within 45 days before the date that such budgetary issue would affect a program or service.

Concurrent with the President's annual budget request to Congress the VA Chief Financial Officer shall submit to Congress: (1) an assurance that budgetary financial projections are sufficient to provide VA benefits and services, and (2) an attestation of collaboration with the financial officers of the concerned facilities and components.</summary>
</bill>
