<bill session="117" type="s" number="3306" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SPACE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPACE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space Protection of American Command and Enterprise Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the purchase of certain telecommunications or aerospace goods or service from entities affiliated with the People's Republic of China or the Russian Federation and to require reporting relating to investment by foreign persons in the aerospace industry in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-02T20:33:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Space Protection of American Command and Enterprise Act or the SPACE Act

This bill prohibits the purchase of certain telecommunications or aerospace equipment and services from China and requires reporting on investment by foreign persons in U.S. space companies.

The National Space Council shall submit a specified report to Congress on space investment competition from China and Russia.

No funds made available to the Department of Commerce or the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) may be used to purchase or lease telecommunications or aerospace hardware or software equipment or services from any telecommunications or aerospace corporation, subsidiary, or affiliate associated with China or the Communist Party of China.

The bill reduces the threshold beyond which a person must report to the Securities and Exchange Commission the acquisition of shares in a U.S. space company. Currently, a person must make such a report when that person's ownership exceeds 5% of a company's total issue of stock. This bill reduces that to 2% for the acquisition of shares in such a company.

The Department of Defense, in coordination with Commerce and the Department of the Treasury, shall submit annual reports to Congress on investment by foreign persons in activities conducted in the United States or by U.S. persons related to exploration, manufacturing, telecommunications, or national security activities involving space.</summary>
</bill>
