<bill session="118" type="s" number="5130" updated="2025-08-21T16:07:52Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Opioid Overdose Data Collection Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opioid Overdose Data Collection Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Opioid Overdose Data Collection Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to enhance the Comprehensive Opioid Abuse Grant Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2024-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7096-7097" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7096-7097" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T18:02:26-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T18:26:40-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-21T16:05:57Z" status="Passed Senate">Opioid Overdose Data Collection Enhancement Act

This bill expands the allowable uses of grants under the Comprehensive Opioid Abuse Grant Program to include the adoption and implementation of an overdose data collection program to track fatal and nonfatal overdoses and the administration of opioid overdose reversal medication (e.g., the&#160;Overdose Detection&#160;Mapping Application Program).

Specifically, the bill allows states, local governments, coalitions of law enforcement agencies, and Indian tribes to use these grants to develop and implement a data collection tool, including mobile data mapping applications.&#160;The tool must allow these entities to easily and quickly track the locations of (1) suspected fatal and nonfatal overdoses, and (2) the administration of opioid overdose reversal medication by first responders.

An entity seeking to use a grant must first conduct an audit of available data and resources and submit the&#160;audit with the grant application.

Grant recipients must (1) support the development of coordinated public safety, behavioral health, and public health responses to the data collected by the tool; (2) focus on areas in which fatal and nonfatal overdoses occur and trends of concern; (3) provide for interoperability with existing overdose data collection tools; and (4) make data collected through the program available to federal, state, tribal, and territorial governments and coalitions of law enforcement agencies.

The Department of Justice&#160;must consult with agencies that maintain overdose data collection tools, including the Office of National Drug Control Policy.</summary>
</bill>
