<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="249" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:10Z">
  <amends type="h" number="910" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-04-06T19:08:27-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to prevent the provisions of this act from going into effect until the EPA Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, certifies that the consequences of not regulating greenhouse gas emissions, and its subsequent impact on climate change, including the potential to create sustained natural and humanitarian disasters and the ability to likely foster political instability where societal demands exceed the capacity of governments to cope, do not jeopardize American security interests at home or abroad.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 112-54 to prevent the provisions of this act from going into effect until the EPA Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, certifies that the consequences of not regulating greenhouse gas emissions, and its subsequent impact on climate change, including the potential to create sustained natural and humanitarian disasters and the ability to likely foster political instability where societal demands exceed the capacity of governments to cope, do not jeopardize American security interests at home or abroad.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-04-06T19:08:27-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="239">
      <text>On agreeing to the Rush amendment (A010) Failed by recorded vote: 165 - 260 (Roll no. 239).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T17:37:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Rush.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2380-2381, H2389-2390" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T19:08:27-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T19:08:27-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T17:37:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A010) offered by Mr. Rush.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2380-2381, H2389-2390" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06T19:08:27-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Rush amendment (A010) Failed by recorded vote: 165 - 260 (Roll no. 239).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
