<bill session="112" type="s" number="3503" updated="2022-02-03T05:54:25Z">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of work-study allowances by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to individuals who are pursuing programs of rehabilitation, education, or training under laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the provision of work-study allowances by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to individuals who are pursuing programs of rehabilitation, education, or training under laws administered by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-11-01T16:01:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Revises the authority of the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide a work-study allowance for certain activities of individuals receiving educational assistance through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to direct the Secretary to utilize the services of at least one such individual at each educational institution that has an office established to provide assistance to veterans enrolled in an approved program of education at the institution.

Includes as a qualifying work-study activity: (1) any activity of a local government veterans agency related to providing assistance in obtaining benefits under the VA or the laws of that state; and (2) any federal, state, or local government entity, as the Secretary considers appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
