<bill session="110" type="h" number="325" updated="2021-04-20T13:11:16Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SPEAK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standards to Provide Educational Achievement for Kids Act</title>
    <title type="display">SPEAK Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create or adopt, and implement, rigorous and voluntary American education content standards in mathematics and science covering kindergarten through grade 12, to provide for the assessment of student proficiency benchmarked against such standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000452" joined="2007-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2007-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2007-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2007-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2007-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2007-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2007-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E75"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="224" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-01-16T18:37:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Standards to Provide Educational Achievement for Kids Act or the SPEAK Act - Amends the National Assessment of Educational Progress Authorization Act (the Act) to require the Commissioner for Educational Statistics to add science to the mandatory biennial national and state academic achievement assessments of students in grades four, eight, and twelve in reading and mathematics. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require states receiving school improvement funds to participate in such science assessments of students in grades four and eight, beginning with the 2008-2009 school year.

Amends the Act to task the National Assessment Governing Board with creating or adopting voluntary American education content standards in mathematics and science for kindergarten through grade 12 which reflect the knowledge students need to enter college or the workforce and compete in the global economy.

Requires the Secretary of Education to establish the American Standards Incentive fund to award competitive four-year grants to states which agree to: (1) adopt such voluntary mathematics and science standards as the core of their own academic content standards in such subjects; and (2) align their teacher certification and professional development requirements to such standards. Provides additional funds to successful grantees for the enhancement of their student performance data systems.

Authorizes the Secretary to extend by two to four years for such grantees the 12-year period at the end of which students must meet or exceed state academic performance standards established under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965.</summary>
</bill>
