<bill session="117" type="hr" number="774" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-06T00:39:59-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-11-06T00:39:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5376) to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S. Con. Res. 14; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5376) to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S. Con. Res. 14; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 117-173, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T15:14:15-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5376 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-11-05" calendar="House" number="44">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 44.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T15:20:20-04:00">
      <text>By direction of the Committee on Rules, Mr. McGovern called up H. Res. 774 and asked for its immediate consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T15:20:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6213-6230" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6213" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T15:22:06-04:00">
      <text>POINT OF ORDER - Mr. Smith (MO) raised a point of order against provisions of H. Res. 774 because it violates 426(a) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974. The Chair announced that disposition of the point of order would be resolved by the question of consideration of H.Res. 774. The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the point of order at the end of which the Chair will put the question on consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T15:38:17-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McGovern moved on consideration of the resolution.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6230"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T20:21:18-04:00">
      <text>On Consideration of the Resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 215 - 212 (Roll no. 368).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T20:21:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 774.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T20:59:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 774.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T22:01:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevaled. Mr. Burgess demanded the yeas and nays and further proceedings on ordering the previous question were postponed until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05T23:53:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6232-6233" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-06T00:18:27-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 213 (Roll no. 371).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6232" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="372" datetime="2021-11-06T00:39:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 213 (Roll no. 372).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-11-06T00:40:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5376" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h139"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-12-23T17:41:04Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.R. 5376 (provides funding, establishes programs, and otherwise modifies provisions relating to a broad array of areas, including education, labor, child care, health care, taxes, immigration, and the environment).

(H.R. 5376 also provides for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S.Con.Res. 5 that directs several House and Senate committees to submit changes in laws within their jurisdictions that will increase the deficit over FY2021-FY2030 by no more than an amount specified for each committee).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-173</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
