<bill session="118" type="s" number="3286" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disclosing Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disclosing Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to amend the rules of the Commission relating to disclosures by advisors of private funds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5016" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T14:50:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Disclosing Investments in Foreign Adversaries Act of 2023&#160;

This bill requires private fund investment advisers registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to annually disclose the total assets of a private fund in countries of concern (i.e., North Korea, China, Russia, and Iran). The SEC must determine whether an asset is in a country of concern for purposes of this bill based on (1) the amount of capital invested in an entity that has a physical presence or employees in that country, or has a plurality of sales from that country; and (2) the proportion of that entity&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s total assets and liabilities located in that country.

The SEC must publish a report annually containing a list of investment advisers with private fund assets located in a country of concern.

Further, issuers of securities must report information to the SEC regarding certain large securities transactions that are exempt from registration. This information includes the issuer&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s identity, associations with entities in countries of concern, details of the transaction, the beneficial owners of the issuers, and intended use of the proceeds of the transaction.

The SEC must publish a report quarterly on transactions that involve a country of concern.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
