<bill session="108" type="sj" number="9" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:25Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Presidential Report on Iraq Resolution of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution requiring the President to report to Congress specific information relating to certain possible consequences of the use of United States Armed Forces against Iraq.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Report on Iraq Resolution of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3748-3749"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli conflict"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economic stabilization"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Presidential Report on Iraq Resolution of 2003 - Directs the President prior to using U.S. armed forces against Iraq pursuant to the Authorization for Use of Military Force Against Iraq Resolution of 2002 to report to Congress the following: (1) a determination that further diplomatic means will not adequately protect U.S. national security against the threat posed by Iraq; (2) a full accounting of the implications of initiating military action against Iraq in regard to homeland security, the war on terrorism, regional stability in the Middle East, and proliferation of weapons of mass destruction; (3) steps the United States and its allies will take to ensure that such weapons will be safeguarded from dispersal to other rogue states or international terrorist organizations; (4) the U.S. plan for achieving long-term social, economic, and political stabilization of a post-conflict Iraq, including a plan to provide humanitarian assistance to the Iraqi people and to ensure their human rights, and to bring to justice individuals responsible for serious violations of international humanitarian and human rights law committed in Iraq; (5) the extent of international support for military action against Iraq and the impact of such action on support for the broader war on terrorism; (6) steps the United States and its allies will take to protect U.S. military personnel, allied forces, and Iraqi civilians from any hazards resulting from military operations; and (7) an estimate of the full costs associated with military action against Iraq, including the anticipated effects of such action on the U.S. economy and the Federal budget.</summary>
</bill>
