<bill session="116" type="h" number="8513" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CSA Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CSA Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a standard for the reasonableness of motor carriers for the shipment of goods or household goods, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7248" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7457" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-21T18:09:44Z" status="Introduced in House">CSA Reform Act

This bill revises the Compliance, Safety, and Accountability program of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to establish a motor carrier selection standard of care for brokers and other entities that contract with motor carriers for the shipment of goods or household goods. (A broker is a person, other than a motor carrier or an employee or agent of a motor carrier, that as a principal or agent sells, offers for sale, negotiates for, or holds itself out by solicitation, advertisement, or otherwise as selling, providing, or arranging for, transportation by motor carrier for compensation.)

Specifically, the bill requires such entities to verify that a transporting motor carrier (1) is properly registered with the Department of Transportation (DOT); (2) has obtained the minimum required insurance coverage; and (3) is not determined unfit to safely operate commercial motor vehicles, or otherwise ordered to discontinue operations by the FMCSA or a state.

Additionally, DOT must (1) prescribe by regulations a process for revoking the registration of an owner or operator determined unfit to safely operate a commercial motor vehicle, and (2) establish a pilot program to conduct remote safety compliance reviews to assign a safety rating for commercial motor carriers.</summary>
</bill>
