<bill session="108" type="h" number="205" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:00Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-08T17:29:55-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-08T17:29:55-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a program to provide regulatory compliance assistance to small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001138" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2003-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T13:46:47-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Manzullo moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T13:47:41-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2879-2883" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T13:47:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 205.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T14:08:50-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:22:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2909-2910" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="116" datetime="2003-04-08T17:29:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 4 (Roll no. 116).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H2879-2880" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T17:29:56-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced in the House on January 7, 2003. However, because action occurred on the measure, the summary has been expanded.)National Small Business Regulatory Assistance Act of 2003 - Amends the Small Business Act to direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), acting through the Associate Administrator for Small Business Development Centers, to establish a program to provide regulatory compliance assistance to small businesses through participating Small Business Development Centers (Centers), the Association for Small Business Development Centers (Association), and Federal compliance partnership programs. Requires the Administrator to enter into arrangements with participating Centers to provide: (1) access to regulatory information and resources; (2) training and education activities; (3) confidential counseling to owners and operators of small businesses regarding compliance with Federal and State regulations; (4) technical assistance; and (5) referrals to experts and other providers of compliance assistance. Requires quarterly reports to the SBA from participating Centers.Directs the Administrator to act as the repository of and clearinghouse for data and information submitted by Centers and to transmit annual program reports to the President and the congressional small business committees.Requires the Administrator, giving substantial weight to the Association's recommendations, to select the Centers programs of two States from each of ten groups of States for participation in the program. Authorizes the Administrator to make additional selections after three years. Directs the Administrator to give selection preference to programs that have a plan for consulting with Federal and State agencies to ensure that assistance provided under this Act is not duplicated by any other Federal or State program. Sets forth the formula for determining program grant amounts.Requires the Comptroller General to evaluate the program and transmit evaluation results to the Administrator and the small business committees.Authorizes appropriations.Provides privacy requirements applicable to such Centers.</summary>
</bill>
