<bill session="116" type="h" number="5122" updated="2022-10-28T02:00:30Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FARM Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to require registration statements filed under such Act to be filed in a structured data format which enables the statements to be digitized for purposes of the publicly available electronic database maintained under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FARM Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-02T20:25:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2019 or the FARM Act of 2019

This bill imposes additional requirements related to the public database of registrations that are filed, as required by the Foreign Agents Registration Act (FARA),&#160;by agents that&#160;engage in certain political activities for foreign principals. Specifically, the Department of Justice shall establish the National Foreign Agents Database, which shall be a publicly searchable, sortable, and machine-processable database of the information contained in such registrations.&#160;Current law&#160;requires a database of registrations to have search and sort functions only to the extent technically practicable.

FARA-required registrations shall be filed in an electronic, structured data format. Electronically filed registrations shall be immediately available to the public over the internet.</summary>
</bill>
