<bill session="118" type="s" number="2659" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farmers&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide increased financial assistance for farmers' markets and farmers' market nutrition programs, to increase local agricultural production through food bank in-house production and local farmer contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-26T18:11:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farmers' Market and Food Bank Local Revitalization Act of 2023

This bill provides for increased support for farmers' markets.

This bill reauthorizes, and extends funding for, the Seniors Farmers' Market Nutrition Program through FY2028.The bill also (1) expands eligibility for the program by increasing the income limit, (2) increases the minimum individual benefit, and (3) removes the maximum individual benefit limit.

The bill extends the WIC Farmers' Market Nutrition Program through FY2028 and increases the minimum and maximum individual benefits under the program.

Further, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must make loans, loan guarantees, and grants to public agencies and nonprofit organizations for the construction of new farmers' markets or the improvement or rehabilitation of existing farmers' markets. The bill provides funding for these loans, loan guarantees, and grants through FY2029, with certain cost-sharing requirements.

Additionally, USDA must establish a pilot grant program to allow food banks to voluntarily contract with local farmers to grow produce for food bank programs as a way to promote local procurement of produce. The bill provides funding for the pilot program through FY2025.</summary>
</bill>
