<bill session="111" type="s" number="3727" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:39Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stalkers Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to the offense of stalking.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stalkers Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2010-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2010-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6889" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5662" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3651" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-20T16:46:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stalkers Act of 2010 - Amends the federal criminal code to revise the definition of stalking and impose criminal penalties on anyone who, with intent to kill, physically injure, harass, or intimidate another person or to place a person under surveillance with the intent to kill, physically injure, harass, or intimidate such person, travels in interstate or foreign commerce or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States or enters or leaves Indian country and: (1) causes or attempts to cause bodily injury or serious emotional distress to another person; or (2) engages in conduct that would be reasonably expected to cause serious emotional distress to another person.

Imposes the same criminal penalties on anyone who, with intent to kill, physically injure, harass, or intimidate another person, engages in a course of conduct that: (1) uses the mail, any interactive computer service, or any other facility of interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) causes or attempts to cause bodily injury or significant emotional distress to another person or occurs in circumstances where the conduct would be reasonably expected to cause another person significant emotional distress.

Increases by 5 years the penalty for a stalking offense if: (1) the offense involves conduct in violation of a protection order; or (2) the victim of the offense is under the age of 18 or over the age of 65.

Requires the annual report of the Attorney General to include an evaluation of efforts to enforce laws relating to stalking and to identify and describe elements of such efforts that constitute the best practices for the enforcement of such laws.</summary>
</bill>
