<bill session="112" type="h" number="6101" updated="2022-01-06T17:18:07Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Veteran Academic Counseling Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Veteran ACE Act</title>
    <title type="display">Student Veteran ACE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve educational counseling opportunities for veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2012-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2012-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2012-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2012-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2012-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2012-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2012-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4787"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-10-22T16:53:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Veteran Academic Counseling Enhancement Act or Student Veteran ACE Act - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to make educational counseling available to students pursuing an approved program of education while using educational assistance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA). Requires the Secretary to: (1) assign one educational counselor per 100 of such students in a geographical area, and (2) provide adequate opportunities for such counseling to such students in remote areas. Requires a student who is a veteran to receive such counseling, unless the student specifically declines, while allowing non-veteran students to elect to receive such counseling. Outlines counselor responsibilities, including assistance with applications for such educational assistance, as well as academic counseling and transition assistance. Requires each student to attend at least one counseling session per quarter, semester, or term, unless such attendance would place an undue hardship on the student. Requires an annual report from the Secretary to the congressional veterans committees on such counseling.

Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense to provide individualized, one-on-one educational counseling to an individual considering pursuing a program of education with assistance furnished through the VA or the Department of Defense (DOD), unless such individual declines. Outlines counseling elements.

Repeals the fiscal year funding limit ($6 million) for VA contract educational and vocational counseling.

Requires the Secretary to establish a system to collect, process, and track complaints submitted by individuals enrolled in VA programs of education and reporting instances of fraud, waste, and abuse by the educational institutions with respect to benefits and services provided.</summary>
</bill>
