<bill session="117" type="h" number="7120" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:50Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DASHBOARD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DASHBOARD Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Designing Accounting Safeguards to Help Broaden Oversight And Regulations on Data Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to promulgate regulations relating to the disclosure of certain commercial data, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-15T19:18:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Designing Accounting Safeguards to Help Broaden Oversight And Regulations on Data Act of 2022 or the DASHBOARD Act of 2022

This bill requires commercial data operators (i.e., large consumer online services providers or data brokers) to disclose to users what types of user data are collected, and the usage and value of that data. Commercial data operators must also provide users with a way to delete this data. Violations of these requirements are enforced by the Federal Trade Commission.

Commercial data operators that issue securities must report the value of their user data and the value of any third-party contracts made for the collection of user data.</summary>
</bill>
