<bill session="117" type="h" number="1804" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Cleanup Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the public participation requirements of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Cleanup Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-03T21:04:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Cleanup Act

This bill expands existing notice and publication requirements related to remedial action plans for Superfund sites (sites contaminated with hazardous substances).

Specifically, the bill requires the notice and analysis of a proposed plan to be transmitted to the highest ranking official of the local government with jurisdiction over the facility subject to the plan. During the public comment period, written and oral comments may be submitted regarding the use of the facility at issue after the remedial action is taken.

Notice of the final remedial action plan must be transmitted to the local government officials with jurisdiction over the facility at issue.

Finally, the bill expands the minimum publication requirements for proposed and final plans to include (1) an announcement via a radio or television station in the broadcast area surrounding the facility at issue, (2) digital or social media publications, and (3) a posting to the website of the person proposing to adopt a plan for remediation (e.g., the state or Environmental Protection Agency website).</summary>
</bill>
