<bill session="119" type="sj" number="55" updated="2025-06-02T14:25:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration relating to "Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards; Fuel System Integrity of Hydrogen Vehicles; Compressed Hydrogen Storage System Integrity; Incorporation by Reference".</title>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration relating to "Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards; Fuel System Integrity of Hydrogen Vehicles; Compressed Hydrogen Storage System Integrity; Incorporation by Reference".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged, by petition, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 802(c).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-05-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="85">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 85.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 46. Record Vote Number: 264.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3025, S3031-3034, S3038, S3047-3051" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Point of order by Senator Thune that points of order are in order under the Congressional Review Act given sections 802(d)(1), 802(d)(2), and 802(d)(4) are in conflict with one another raised in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>The Chair, under the provisions of Rule XX, submits the question to the Senate for its decision: Shall points of order be in order under the Congressional Review Act?.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Motion to table the point of order made by Senator Thune, the question being: Shall points of order be in order under the Congressional Review Act? rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 52. Record Vote Number: 265.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Point of order by Senator Schumer that points of order are not in order under section 802(d)(1) of the Congressional Review Act raised in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair that the point of order raised by Senator Schumer with respect to points of order not in order under section 802(d)(1) ruled out of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to appeal the ruling of the chair that two points of order are not in order at the same time.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Motion to table the appeal that two points of order are not in order at the same time agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 266.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair that the point of order raised by Senator Schumer that two points of order are not in order at the same time sustained.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Point of order by Senator Thune: Shall points of order be in order under the Congressional Review Act? agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 273.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair that the point of order raised by Senator Thune that points of order be in order under the Congressional Review Act sustained.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Point of order by Senator Thune: Shall Joint Resolutions that meet all the requirements of Section 802 of the Congressional Review Act or are disapproving of agency actions which have been determined to be rules subject to the Congressional Review Act by a legal decision from the Government Accountability Office, be entitled to expedited procedures under the Congressional Review Act? agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 274.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-21">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair that the point of order raised by Senator Thune with respect to Joint Resolutions that meet all the requirements of Section 802 of the Congressional Review Act or are disapproving of agency actions which have been determined to be rules subject to the Congressional Review Act by a legal decision from the Government Accountability Office, be entitled to expedited procedures under the Congressional Review Act was sustained.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="275" datetime="2025-05-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 46. Record Vote Number: 275.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3051" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-05-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-26T09:02:39-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-26T09:16:36-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
</bill>
