<bill session="109" type="h" number="1021" updated="2019-11-15T21:40:41Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Space and Aeronautics Prize Act</title>
    <title type="display">Space and Aeronautics Prize Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a prize program to encourage development of space and aeronautics technologies and establish an endowment to further educate and inspire the public's interest in space and aeronautics.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Launch vehicles"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space commercialization"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Space shuttles"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-29T14:25:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Space and Aeronautics Prize Act - Establishes a National Endowment for Space and Aeronautics, to be headed by a Chairman appointed by the President, to: (1) further the public's knowledge of and inspiration by the Earth, the Earth's atmosphere, human and robotic spaceflight and science missions, and celestial bodies; (2) carry out a program to award cash prizes for outstanding achievements in basic, advanced, and applied research, technology development, and prototype demonstration in conjunction with or independent of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); (3) carry out advertising of commercial products and services in conjunction with such endeavors; and (4) encourage private gifts for the benefit of such endeavors.

Requires the Endowment annually to report to Congress.

Authorizes the Chairman to carry out a program to award cash prizes for outstanding achievements in basic, advanced, and applied research, technology development, and prototype demonstration that have potential for application to the activities of NASA. Requires the Chairman annually to report to specified congressional committees on the administration of such program.

Requires the Endowment to carry out a program to award a prize for the demonstration of a space flight vehicle to carry at least one person to a minimum altitude of 400 kilometers from within the United States or its territories, complete at least three Earth orbits, and return safely.</summary>
</bill>
