<bill session="119" type="h" number="386" updated="2025-02-13T03:08:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-10T16:32:33-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-02-10T16:32:33-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the United States Governor of, and the United States Executive Director at, the International Monetary Fund to oppose an increase in the weight of the Chinese renminbi in the Special Drawing Rights basket of the Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2025-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10T16:19:32-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hill (AR) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10T16:19:45-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H595-596" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10T16:19:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 386.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-02-10T16:32:33-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H595" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10T16:32:44-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-11T17:12:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Chinese Currency Accountability Act of 2025

This bill requires the United States to oppose, absent specified conditions, any increase in the weight of Chinese currency (i.e., the renminbi) in the basket of currencies (currently, a set of five currencies, each with different weightings) used to determine the value of Special Drawing Rights. Special Drawing Rights are international reserve assets created by the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to supplement member countries' official foreign exchange reserves.

Specifically, the Department of the Treasury must instruct certain U.S. officials at the IMF to oppose any such increase unless Treasury has certified that China is in compliance with certain standards and international agreements, including that (1) China is in compliance with all general obligations of members of the IMF, (2) China has not been found to have manipulated its currency in the preceding 12 months, and (3) China&#160;adheres to the rules and principles of the Paris Club and the Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development (OECD) Arrangement on Officially Supported Export Credits.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
