<bill session="112" type="h" number="3617" updated="2019-11-15T21:04:39Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">See Something, Say Something Act</title>
    <title type="display">See Something, Say Something Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require States receiving funds under section 106 of such Act to have in effect a State law providing for a criminal penalty on a person who has knowledge of child abuse or neglect, but fails to report such abuse or neglect to a law enforcement official or child protective services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-01-26T22:54:28Z" status="Introduced in House">See Something, Say Something Act - Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require the state plan under a grant from the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) for child abuse and neglect prevention and treatment programs to contain an assurance in the form of a certification by the state governor that the state has in effect and is enforcing a state law prescribing a criminal penalty against any person age 18 or older who fails to report to a state or local law enforcement official or child protective services that the person has knowledge of child abuse or neglect that occurred in the state.</summary>
</bill>
