<bill session="118" type="h" number="4502" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-02T19:06:09-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-10-02T19:06:09-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing the Acquisition of Cybersecurity Experts Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Modernizing the Acquisition of Cybersecurity Experts Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Acquisition of Cybersecurity Experts Act</title>
    <title type="short">Modernizing the Acquisition of Cybersecurity Experts Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend title 5, United States Code, to limit the use of educational requirements or qualifications in evaluating candidates for certain cybersecurity positions in the competitive service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to allow Federal agencies to establish educational requirements for certain cybersecurity positions in the competitive service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2023-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T16:26:59-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Comer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T16:27:11-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4944-4946" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T16:27:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4502.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T16:42:36-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T18:56:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4947-4948" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="515" datetime="2023-10-02T19:06:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 394 - 1 (Roll no. 515).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4944" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T19:06:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02T19:06:13-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-10T20:35:25Z" status="Passed House">Modernizing the Acquisition of Cybersecurity Experts Act of 2023

This bill modifies educational requirements for cybersecurity positions in the federal government.

Specifically, the bill prohibits federal agencies from establishing minimum educational requirements for cybersecurity positions unless such requirements are mandated by law for the position in the state or locality in which the work is to be performed. Agencies may also only consider an applicant's education in conjunction with other minimum qualifications for a position if the applicant's education directly reflects the required competencies for the position.

 The bill applies to positions in the competitive service that are classified under the Information Technology Management Series or any other position that is designated as a cybersecurity position under the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework.

The Office of Personnel Management must annually publish on its website (1) any changes to minimum qualifications relating to education for these positions, and (2) data on the level of education of those occupying these positions.</summary>
</bill>
