<bill session="116" type="h" number="7987" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:28Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TSA Security Threat Assessment Application Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TSA Security Threat Assessment Application Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Transportation Security Administration to standardize the enrollment process for individuals applying for multiple TSA Security Threat Assessment programs, including the TWIC, HAZMAT Endorsement, and TSA PreCheck programs of the Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-13T18:56:03Z" status="Introduced in House">TSA Security Threat Assessment Application Modernization Act 

This bill requires the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to standardize the enrollment and renewal system for individuals applying for or renewing multiple TSA Security Threat Assessment programs, including the Transportation Worker Identification Credential, Hazardous Materials Endorsement, and TSA PreCheck programs.

The standardization shall permit an individual to (1) enroll at a TSA-designated universal enrollment center once and use the application for one of such programs to enroll in two or more of such programs, (2) pay a fee that is less than the sum of the fees charged individually for each separate application, and (3) undergo a streamlined and expeditious renewal process.

Additionally, the TSA must publish on its website information relating to the standardization of the enrollment system.</summary>
</bill>
