<bill session="117" type="h" number="5039" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose certain measures with respect to Hizballah-affected areas in Latin America and the Caribbean and to impose sanctions with respect to senior foreign political figures in Latin America who support Hizballah, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Hizballah in Latin America Accountability Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hizballah in Latin America Accountability Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2021-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2021-08-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1651" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-04T15:03:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Hizballah in Latin America Accountability Act of 2021

This bill establishes requirements related to activities of Hizballah in Latin America and the Caribbean.

Specifically, the President must impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on foreign persons determined to have knowingly engaged in significant transactions with, or provided material support to, Hizballah in a Latin American or Caribbean country.

The Department of the Treasury, in consultation with the Department of State, must report on illicit activities of Hizballah in Latin America and the Caribbean. This report must include (1) an estimate of how much of Hizbollah's budget derives from such activities, (2) an assessment of interagency efforts and progress in countering such activities, and (3) an identification of financial institutions in Latin America and the Caribbean known to be operating on behalf of or with ties to Hizballah.

The Department of Homeland Security must seek to improve (1) data sharing among trade transparency units with respect to operations against malign actors among Latin American and Caribbean countries, and (2) cooperation with federal agencies with respect to trade transparency units.</summary>
</bill>
