<bill session="117" type="h" number="4465" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federally Funded Research and Technology Development Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance transparency and accountability measures in Federal grantmaking to safeguard federally funded research and technology development, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federally Funded Research and Technology Development Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-14T21:02:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Federally Funded Research and Technology Development Protection Act

This bill addresses issues of transparency and accountability in federal grant-making to safeguard federally funded research and technology development.

Specifically, the Office of Management and Budget must (1) require that any agency that makes a federal grant maintains compliance operations to guard against malign foreign talent recruitment programs, and (2) prescribe standardized disclosure and accountability measures to support such operations.

Malign foreign talent recruitment is defined as an effort organized, managed, or funded by a foreign government to recruit any individual or public or private entity engaged in research funded by a federal agency to share information with, or otherwise act on behalf of, such government.</summary>
</bill>
