<bill session="111" type="s" number="1608" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:09Z">
  <state datetime="2009-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reengaging Americans in Serious Education by Uniting Programs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prepare young people in disadvantaged situations for a competitive future.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reengaging Americans in Serious Education by Uniting Programs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2009-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3982" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-05T20:41:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reengaging Americans in Serious Education by Uniting Programs Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor to award competitive, renewable, five-year grants to eligible partnerships to assist them in providing disadvantaged youth with the support needed to: (1) graduate from secondary school; (2) attain a postsecondary credential, including those offered by institutions of higher education, industry groups, or registered apprenticeship programs; and (3) secure and succeed in a family-supporting career.

Requires each eligible partnership to include: (1) the head of the local government assisted by the grant; (2) disadvantaged youth and their caregivers; (3) representatives from certain state and local service agencies; (4) representatives from certain educational entities; and (5) a representative from a community-based organization, a youth-serving nonprofit agency, a labor-management committee, and a business.

Requires grantees to award subgrants and contracts to community-based organizations and other entities for the provision of a comprehensive array of coordinated services to disadvantaged youth that include workforce preparation, education support, and youth support services.

Establishes an accountability system for measuring the performance of each grantee against specified interim, transitional, and long-term indicators of success.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) award a grant or contract to an entity outside the Department of Labor for an evaluation of grant-assisted activities; (2) disseminate best practices that emerge from the partnership grant program; and (3) provide training, technical assistance, and professional development for organizations serving disadvantaged youth, including organizations that do not receive funding under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
