<bill session="117" type="h" number="8677" updated="2022-12-29T19:03:41Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IMPROVE Nursing Homes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMPROVE Nursing Homes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure Modernization Project Related to the OVerall Enhancement of Nursing Homes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with State health departments, to establish a grant program to award grants to nursing facilities to replace traditional nursing facilities with small-house nursing facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-21T16:02:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Infrastructure Modernization Project Related to the OVerall Enhancement of Nursing Homes Act or the IMPROVE Nursing Homes Act

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to establish a grant program to support the conversion of traditional nursing facilities to small-house nursing facilities (i.e., facilities that offer private rooms for up to 12 residents in separate buildings or areas). Grant funds may be used to convert facilities but not for facility operation; grant recipients must agree to provide person-centered care that supports certain resident flexibilities and to operate such facilities for at least 20 years.</summary>
</bill>
