<amendment session="109" chamber="s" number="4208" updated="2022-02-03T05:31:51Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2766" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-06-13">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-06-12"/>
  <description>To express the sense of Congress that the United States Armed Forces, the intelligence community, and other agencies, as well as the coalition partners of the United States and the Iraqi Security Forces should be commended for their actions that resulted in the death of Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, the leader of the al-Qaeda in Iraq terrorist organization and the most wanted terrorist in Iraq.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-06-13" how="roll" result="pass" roll="168">
      <text>Amendment SA 4208 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 0. Record Vote Number: 168.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5740, S5744" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Amendment SA 4208 proposed by Senator Warner for Senator Frist. (consideration: CR S5711; text: CR S5711) To express the sense of Congress that the United States Armed Forces, the intelligence community, and other agencies, as well as the coalition partners of the United States and the Iraqi Security Forces should be commended for their actions that resulted in the death of Abu Musab al-Zarqawi, the leader of the al-Qaeda in Iraq terrorist organization and the most wanted terrorist in Iraq.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 4208 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 0. Record Vote Number: 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-13">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 4208 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 0. Record Vote Number: 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4208 proposed by Senator Warner for Senator Frist.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5711" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5711" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
