<bill session="117" type="h" number="6549" updated="2023-08-07T17:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide support for international initiatives to provide debt relief to developing countries with unsustainable levels of debt, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide support for international initiatives to provide debt relief to developing countries with unsustainable levels of debt, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000172"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T17:31:36Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to support and advocate for debt relief for developing countries.

Treasury must engage with international financial institutions and creditors to advocate for support, implementation, and improvement of the Common Framework for Debt Treatments beyond the Debt Service Suspension Initiative (DSSI) (and any successor framework or similar coordinated international debt treatment process). (The DSSI is an initiative established by the Group of 20, the informal grouping of 19 major economies and the European Union, that provides temporary debt restructuring for the world's poorest countries. The common framework is a framework endorsed by 39 creditors to provide permanent debt forgiveness.)

Treasury must also engage with international financial institutions and creditors to advocate for a comprehensive debt payment standstill for each participating debtor while the debtor's application for relief under the common framework and negotiations related to such relief are pending or ongoing.

Treasury must also order U.S. representatives to the International Monetary Fund and the World Bank to advocate and vote for such initiatives and policies without undermining the respective institution's ability to provide new and additional aid and assistance.</summary>
</bill>
