<bill session="118" type="s" number="3787" updated="2025-01-14T17:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the credit for employers establishing workplace child care facilities, to increase the child care credit to encourage greater use of quality child care services, to provide incentives for students to earn child care-related degrees and to work in child care facilities, and to increase the exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2024-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-10T18:00:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Right Start Child Care and Education Act of 2024

This bill increases or allows new child care tax credits and increases the tax exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance.&#160;

Specifically, the bill doubles the rate and the maximum allowable amount of the employer-provided child care credit. It also allows an additional increase for certain small businesses.&#160;

The bill allows a new three-year tax credit for individuals who hold child care-related educational degrees and who work in licensed child care facilities.&#160;

The bill increases the tax exclusion for employer-provided dependent care assistance.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
