<bill session="117" type="s" number="1767" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Credit Union Employee and Member Safety Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Credit Union Act to modernize certain processes regarding expulsion of credit union members for cause, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Employee and Member Safety Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2022-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2022-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2311" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-17T15:16:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Credit Union Employee and Member Safety Act of 2021

This bill revises the procedure for expelling members from a federal credit union. Specifically, a member may be expelled for cause pursuant to a policy adopted by a majority vote of a quorum of the directors of a credit union. Currently, a member may be expelled by a two-thirds vote of the credit union membership present at a special meeting.

The member may request a hearing from the board of directors. After the hearing, the board shall hold a vote on expelling the member.

The expelled member may request reinstatement through a two-thirds vote of the members present at a meeting.

Member conduct that may be cause for expulsion includes

 a material loss to the credit union, a violation of the credit union membership agreement, a substantial disruption to the operations of a credit union, fraud or attempted fraud, and other illegal or inappropriate behavior.</summary>
</bill>
