<bill session="111" type="h" number="5838" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:53Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeless Veterans Transitional Housing Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the multifamily transitional housing loan program of the Department of Veterans Affairs by requiring the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to issue loans for the construction of, rehabilitation of, or acquisition of land for multifamily transitional housing projects instead of guaranteeing loans for such purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeless Veterans Transitional Housing Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001044"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2010-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3377" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-08T21:04:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeless Veterans Transitional Housing Act of 2010 - Revises the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) multifamily transitional housing loan program (program) to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to issue at least five loans for the construction, rehabilitation, or acquisition of land for multifamily transitional housing projects. Authorizes the Secretary to delegate loan approval authority to a state or local government entity.

Terminates, as of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary's authority under the program to guarantee loans for such purposes.

Establishes the Department of Veterans Affairs Multifamily Transitional Housing Loan Program Revolving Fund to fund such loans.

Prohibits any federal or state law from prohibiting a program project offering preferential treatment to veterans.</summary>
</bill>
