<bill session="118" type="h" number="3888" updated="2025-11-19T04:47:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, to strengthen benefits for children of Vietnam veterans born with spina bifida, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to strengthen benefits for children of Vietnam veterans born with spina bifida, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="112" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Musculoskeletal and skin diseases"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-29T23:59:33Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill addresses Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) benefits and care for certain children with spina bifida or other birth defects. The bill requires the VA to provide health care, job training, and monetary benefits for the duration of the child's life. The bills covers a child, regardless of age or marital status, who: (1) has spina bifida and is the natural child of a Vietnam veteran or a veteran of specified service in Korea or Thailand who was conceived after the date on which the veteran entered service in Vietnam, Korea, or Thailand; or (2) has certain birth defects and is the natural child of a woman Vietnam veteran.

The bill requires the VA to establish an advisory council on health care and benefits for covered children. Additionally, the VA must establish care and coordination teams for covered children. At least every 180 days, the teams must conduct outreach to ensure the continued care of the children and assist with any necessary changes in care.

The VA must report to Congress a list of conditions that will trigger outreach to covered children, and must attempt to contact such children as soon as practicable after the identification of a condition.

The Veterans Benefits Administration and the Veterans Health Administration must enter into a memorandum of understanding to better assist covered children.</summary>
</bill>
