<bill session="108" type="h" number="903" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:56Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sandpoint Land and Facilities Conveyance Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance by the Secretary of Agriculture of the Sandpoint Federal Building and adjacent land in Sandpoint, Idaho, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sandpoint Land and Facilities Conveyance Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000166"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="435" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Sandpoint Land and Facilities Act of 2003 - Directs the Administrator of General Services to transfer to the Secretary of Agriculture jurisdiction over certain land in Sandpoint, Idaho (the property), with the Secretary assuming the obligation of the Administrator to repay to the Federal Finance Bank the debt incurred with respect to the property.Permits the Secretary to exchange all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property in an exchange of equal value, in which the recipient of the property may agree to construct administrative facilities for the National Forest System in Bonner County, Idaho. Requires a recipient to honor any outstanding indebtedness on the property to the Federal Finance Bank.Directs the Secretary to use proceeds from the sale of the property for: (1) the acquisition, construction, or improvement of administrative facilities and associated land in the Northern Region of the Forest Service in Idaho; and (2) the acquisition of land and interests in land for addition to National Forest System land in such region. Forbids any proceeds from being distributed to States or counties or from being considered moneys received from units of the National Forest System under specified laws.Requires the Secretary to manage any land acquired under this Act in accordance with the Weeks Act.</summary>
</bill>
