<bill session="110" type="s" number="3442" updated="2020-01-29T20:30:07Z">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to reauthorize the National Oilheat Reliance Alliance Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the National Oilheat Reliance Alliance Act of 2000, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2008-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Trade associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-12-05T20:55:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the National Oilheat Research Alliance Act of 2000 to adjust its focus upon oilheat to a focus upon oilheat fuel.

Defines "oilheat fuel" as distillate liquid used as a fuel for nonindustrial commercial or residential space or hot water heating.

Makes technical and conforming amendments.

Revises the membership of the National Oilheat Research Alliance. Provides that, other than the public members of the Alliance, members shall be full-time managerial owners or employees of members of the oilheat fuel industry.

Revises assessment requirements. States that the assessment rate for calendar years 2008 and 2009 shall be equal to two-tenths of 1% per gallon of distillate liquid (currently, No. 1 distillate and No. 2 dyed distillate).

Declares that, beginning with calendar year 2010, the annual assessment rate shall be sufficient to cover the costs of the plans and programs developed by the Alliance.

Sets forth: (1) a maximum assessment rate; and (2) limitations on any assessment increase.

Prohibits any consumer education activity undertaken with funds derived from Alliance assessments from including a direct reference to a competing product.

Repeals the termination date for the Act (thus making it permanent).</summary>
</bill>
