<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="1562" updated="2021-05-28T09:06:39Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1260" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-05-19">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-05-19"/>
  <description>To ensure trade is conducted consistent with American values, to ensure resiliency in critical supply chains, to improve transparency and administration of trade programs and oversight and accountability of trade agencies, and to promote American competitiveness.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 1562 as modified, under the order of 5/27/21, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 4. Record Vote Number: 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 1562 proposed by Senator Crapo to Amendment SA 1502. (consideration: CR S3549, S3552-3838, S3839; text as modified: CR S3552-3836) To ensure trade is conducted consistent with American values, to ensure resiliency in critical supply chains, to improve transparency and administration of trade programs and oversight and accountability of trade agencies, and to promote American competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1562 proposed by Senator Crapo to Amendment SA 1502.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1562 as modified, under the order of 5/27/21, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 4. Record Vote Number: 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1562 as modified, under the order of 5/27/21, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 4. Record Vote Number: 216.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
