<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3864</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-12T17:52:07Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-12T17:52:07Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2006-09-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2006-09-07T15:24:13Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-09-07</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. (text of measure as introduced: CR S9125-9126)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-09-07</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9124-9125)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-09-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001162</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Martinez, Mel [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mel</firstName>
        <lastName>Martinez</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001056</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cornyn, John [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Cornyn</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2006-09-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Academic performance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Compensatory education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Conflict of interests</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Educational accountability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nonprofit organizations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parent-school relationships</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Performance measurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School buildings</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School districts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School-age child care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2006-09-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-10-06T16:41:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Raising Achievement through Improving Supplemental Education Act of 2006, or the RAISE Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct local educational agencies (LEAs) to make supplemental educational services (SES) (after-school tutoring programs) available to eligible children attending schools identified as needing improvement because of their having failed, for two consecutive years, to make adequate yearly progress (AYP) pursuant to state academic performance standards. (Currently such services are required only after an additional year of failing to meet such standards.)</p> <p>Makes low-performing children from such schools who are not from low-income families eligible for SES and gives them priority, in the case of insufficient funding, over children who are poor but not low-performing.</p> <p>Requires LEAs to: (1) create a streamlined SES notification, registration, and provider selection process designed to increase the number of eligible children receiving such services and the information available to parents and SES providers; (2) grant approved providers access to school facilities that is equivalent to access provided to other after-school and extracurricular programs; and (3) enter into a written agreement with the parents' chosen provider, within a specified period, requiring such provider to render services within 20 days after the LEA and provider receive the child's contact information.</p> <p>Requires states to: (1) provide advance notice to LEAs of their SES duties; (2) make a downloadable SES application form available to LEAs and parents; (3) evaluate providers in a valid and reliable manner that considers student achievement and parent satisfaction; (4) safeguard against conflicts of interest and underperformance when LEAs provide SES themselves; and (5) prohibit LEAs from reprogramming SES funds when there is inadequate parental notification or unsatisfied demand for services.</p> <p>Prohibits the offering, by providers, of selection incentives to parents and eligible children.</p> <p>Allows states to shift to nonprofit organizations, under a contract or cooperative agreement, performance of the SES responsibilities of LEAs that face conflicts of interest or are unreliable.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a model program coordinating the provision of SES with 21st century community learning centers.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Raising Achievement through Improving Supplemental Education Act of 2006</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Raising Achievement through Improving Supplemental Education Act of 2006</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve supplemental educational services, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Raising Achievement through Improving Supplemental Education Act of 2006</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>RAISE Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2006-09-07T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s3864is/xml/BILLS-109s3864is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2006-09-07</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. (text of measure as introduced: CR S9125-9126)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
