<bill session="108" type="s" number="969" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Gun Safety Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the security and safety of the Nation by increasing the time allowed to track terrorists during periods of elevated alert, closing loopholes that have allowed terrorists to acquire firearms, maintaining records of certain handgun transfers during periods of heightened terrorist risk, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Gun Safety Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2003-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5655-5657"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeland Security Gun Safety Act of 2003 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to make certain requirements with respect to the destruction of records of firearms transfers inapplicable during periods in which the Homeland Security Advisory System threat condition is elevated, high, or severe.Prohibits a licensed dealer from selling or delivering a firearm to a qualified purchaser if the dealer has reasonable cause to believe that: (1) the purchaser intends to transfer the firearm to an ineligible individual; or (2) the gun will be used in a crime.Requires a chief law enforcement officer who determines that a person is ineligible to receive a handgun to notify the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives (BATFE) of the person's attempt to purchase a firearm.Prohibits the sale to, or purchase by, an unlicensed individual of two or more handguns during any 30-day period.Directs the Attorney General to prescribe security standards for the storage and display of firearms by licensed firearms dealers to prevent theft or other loss.Authorizes inspections of the inventory and records of a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer at any time without reasonable cause or warrant.Requires a licensed importer, dealer, or collector, before purchasing a firearm from an unlicensed person, to check the firearm against the Stolen Gun File of the National Crime Information Center.Increases penalties for specified violations. Provides for: (1) mandatory license suspension when the licensee is charged with a crime; and (2) license suspension for at least 48 hours for failure to report a missing firearm.Reduces from 50 pounds to five pounds of commercially manufactured black powder the threshold amount covered by certain explosives provisions.Authorizes appropriations to hire new BATFE inspectors and agents.</summary>
</bill>
