<bill session="108" type="s" number="404" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Modeling Exploitation Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children from exploitive child modeling, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Modeling Exploitation Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2003-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2004-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2479"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2479-2480" label="text  of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="756" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child labor"/>
    <term name="Child pornography"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Modeling Exploitation Prevention Act - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prohibit an employer from employing a child model in exploitive child modeling. Defines "exploitive child modeling" as modeling involving the use of a child under 17 years old for financial gain without the purpose of marketing a product or service other than the child's image, regardless of whether the employment relationship of the child is direct or indirect, contractual or non-contractual, or is termed that of an independent contractor. Provides that such term does not apply to an image which, taken as a whole, has serious literary, artistic, political, or scientific value.Sets penalties for violations. Includes employment of a minor in violation of such provision within the definition of "oppressive child labor."Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit displaying or offering to provide the image of an individual engaged in exploitive child modeling, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, with the intent to make a financial gain, except with respect to an image which has serious literary, artistic, political, or scientific value.</summary>
</bill>
