<bill session="112" type="s" number="1734" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:58Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Generating Antibiotic Incentives Now Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide incentives for the development of qualified infectious disease products.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generating Antibiotic Incentives Now Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2012-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2012-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2012-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2011-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2012-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2011-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2012-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2182" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-17T16:21:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Generating Antibiotic Incentives Now Act of 2011 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to extend the exclusivity period for a new prescription drug by five years for a drug that the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) determines to be a qualified infectious disease product. Defines "qualified infectious disease product" to mean an antibiotic drug for treating, detecting, preventing, or identifying a qualifying pathogen (certain pathogens that are resistant to antibiotics). Excludes drugs that are: (1) a supplement to a new drug application for which an extension is in effect or has expired; or (2) a subsequent application for a change that results in a new indication, route of administration, dosing schedule, dosage form, delivery system, delivery device or strength, or a modification to the structure of the product that does not result in a change in safety or effectiveness.

Extends such period of exclusivity an additional six months for a sponsor or manufacturer of a qualified infectious disease product that identifies a companion diagnostic test.

Requires the Secretary to give priority review to any drug determined to be a qualified infectious disease product.

Includes qualified infectious disease products as fast track products for which the Secretary shall facilitate development and expedite review.

Directs the Comptroller General to study the need for incentives to encourage the research, development, and marketing of qualified infectious disease biological products.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) review Food and Drug Administration (FDA) guidelines for clinical trials of antibiotic drugs; and (2) revise such guidelines, as appropriate, to reflect developments in scientific and medical information and technology and to ensure clarity regarding the procedures and requirements for approval of an antibiotic drug.</summary>
</bill>
