<bill session="118" type="s" number="5300" updated="2025-08-04T20:20:22Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Contaminated Wells Relocation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contaminated Wells Relocation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Contaminated Wells Relocation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to reimburse the Town of Chincoteague, Virginia, for costs directly associated with the removal and replacement of certain drinking water wells.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2024-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-16">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7057" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7057" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17T10:44:15-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17T10:47:20-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-04T20:20:18Z" status="Passed Senate">Contaminated Wells Relocation Act

This bill permits the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to enter into an agreement to reimburse the town of Chincoteague, Virginia for costs directly associated with the removal and relocation of drinking water wells currently situated on NASA property. &#160;

(Drinking water wells located at NASA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Wallops Flight Facility near Chincoteague have tested positive for perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS, resulting from the use of certain firefighting foams at the site beginning in the 1970s. NASA currently operates a water treatment system to remove PFAS from the affected water supply.)&#160;

Any such agreement must include, to the extent practicable, (1) a provision for the removal and relocation of the wells remaining on NASA property, (2) a description of the location to which the wells are planned to be relocated, and (3) a current cost estimate of such relocation. Replacement wells must be established on property under the administrative control of the town of Chincoteague.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
