<bill session="118" type="s" number="1803" updated="2025-11-19T04:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Air Ambulance Services for Americans Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Air Ambulance Services for Americans Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to revise payment for air ambulance services under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2024-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2024-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3691" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-25T20:15:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Air Ambulance Services for Americans Act of 2023

This bill authorizes payment changes under Medicare for air ambulance services based on certain collected data and requires additional reporting from providers of these services.

Current law requires providers of air ambulance services to report certain information regarding general costs and utilization to the Department of Health and Human Services; private health insurers are also required to report information relating to coverage of these services. The bill authorizes the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to revise payment rates under Medicare for air ambulance services based on this data, and it requires providers of air ambulance services to specifically report information relating to costs and utilization under Medicare.

The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office to report on the data that is collected under current law requirements and to recommend changes to Medicare payment rates accordingly.</summary>
</bill>
