<bill session="116" type="s" number="3392" updated="2022-02-09T03:42:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Immigrants' Mental Health Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigrants' Mental Health Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand and improve access to trauma-informed mental health interventions for newly arriving immigrants at the border, to alleviate the stress of and provide education for border agents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6075" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-26T16:13:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Immigrants' Mental Health Act of 2020

This bill directs Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to take steps to address mental health issues among immigrants and CBP agents and officers. It also restricts the sharing of mental health information for use in certain immigration proceedings.

CBP shall develop training to enable its agents and officers to (1) identify mental health issues and risk factors in immigrants and refugees, (2) provide crisis intervention using a trauma-informed approach, and (3) better manage work-related stress and psychological pressures.

CBP shall assign at least one qualified mental or behavioral health expert to each Border Patrol station, port of entry, checkpoint, forward operating base, secondary inspection area, and short-term custody facility.

The Department of Health and Human Services may not provide to the Department of Homeland Security information about the mental health of an alien that was obtained by a mental health professional while the alien was in federal government custody if the information will be used for (1) an asylum determination, (2) an immigration hearing, or (3) a deportation hearing.</summary>
</bill>
