<bill session="110" type="s" number="2037" updated="2023-01-11T20:28:00Z">
  <state datetime="2007-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to make it unlawful to sell a recalled product, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to make it unlawful to sell a recalled product, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2007-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-04T21:50:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to make it unlawful to sell a product that is: (1) not in conformity with an applicable consumer product safety standard; (2) subject to voluntary corrective action taken by the manufacturer and determined by the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC) to be unsafe; (3) subject to an order issued under provisions relating to imminent hazards or substantial product hazards; or (4) designated a banned hazardous substance under the Federal Hazardous Substances Act.

Requires the manufacturer of a consumer product, regardless of whether it is subject to a consumer product safety standard, to place distinguishing marks on the product (as much as feasible), and on its packaging, that will enable the ultimate purchaser to determine the source, date, and cohort of production of the product by reference to those marks.</summary>
</bill>
