<bill session="119" type="s" number="132" updated="2025-06-11T22:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Filing Relief for Natural Disasters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Filing Relief for Natural Disasters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the rules for postponing certain deadlines by reason of disaster.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2025-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2025-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="517" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-27T10:40:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Filing Relief for Natural Disasters Act

This bill authorizes the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to postpone federal tax deadlines for taxpayers affected by a qualified state declared disaster, upon written request by the state governor. The bill also increases the automatic extension of federal tax deadlines for certain taxpayers.

Under current law, the IRS may postpone federal tax deadlines for taxpayers affected by a federally declared disaster, including (but not limited to) deadlines for (1) filing federal tax returns, (2) paying federal taxes, (3) making retirement plan contributions, and (4) tax assessments and collections.

The bill authorizes the IRS to postpone such federal tax deadlines for taxpayers affected by a qualified state declared disaster upon written request by the state&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s governor (or the District of&#160;Columbia mayor). Under the bill, a state includes the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the U.S. Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.

The bill defines qualified state declared disaster as any natural catastrophe,&#160;fire, flood, or explosion that causes damage of sufficient severity and magnitude to warrant a request to postpone such federal tax deadlines.

Further, under current law, an automatic 60-day extension of such federal tax deadlines applies to certain relief workers, individuals killed or injured as a result of a federally declared disaster, and taxpayers whose principal residence, business, or tax records are located in a federally declared disaster area.

The bill increases to 120 days the automatic extension of federal tax deadlines for these&#160;taxpayers.</summary>
</bill>
