<bill session="109" type="h" number="160" updated="2019-11-15T21:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep America Healthy Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Keep America Healthy Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to permit States to expand Medicaid eligibility to uninsured, poor adults.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000714"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-24T16:49:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep America Healthy Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to make a new optional Medicaid eligibility group for individuals between ages 21 and 65 whose family income does not exceed a State-specified percentage up to 200 percent of the applicable poverty line. Authorizes the State also to require the individual's resources not to exceed whatever level the State may establish, so long as it is not more restrictive than the requirements of SSA title XVI (Supplemental Security Income). Provides for the application to such new group of the enhanced Federal medical assistance percentage dtermined under SSA title XXI (State Children's Health Insurance Program) (SCHIP).

Amends SSA title XI to provide for an increase in the Medicaid payment limit for territories to accommodate expanded coverage for residents of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</summary>
</bill>
