<bill session="111" type="h" number="4497" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:44Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildlife and Zoological Veterinary Medicine Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the workforce of veterinarians specialized in the care and conservation of wild animals and their ecosystems, and to develop educational programs focused on wildlife and zoological veterinary medicine.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildlife and Zoological Veterinary Medicine Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001235" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001037" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000369" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2010-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E73"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterinary medicine and animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-19T20:23:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildlife and Zoological Veterinary Medicine Enhancement Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to award grants to wildlife or veterinary institutions to create additional clinical and research positions for wildlife and zoological veterinarians, with preference to institutions that will create positions in areas of need, including wildlife disease research and training, disease surveillance, ecology and wildlife population management, and conservation and management of the health of endangered, threatened, and sensitive species.

Directs the Secretary to establish: (1) the Wildlife and Zoological Veterinary Workforce Loan Repayment Program to repay educational loans of applicants who have received, in the previous ten years, a doctoral degree in veterinary medicine or a graduate degree in veterinary medicine after receiving such doctoral degree, or who are enrolled in an accredited school or college of veterinary medicine program that leads to such a degree, and who agree to serve for at least four consecutive years at a wildlife or veterinary institution as a wildlife or zoological veterinarian; and (2) the Wildlife and Zoological Veterinary Workforce Scholarship Program to award students enrolled in an accredited school or college of veterinary medicine scholarships for up to four years in exchange for entering a contract to serve for at least four consecutive years as wildlife or zoological veterinarians at wildlife or veterinary institutions beginning no later than four years after graduation.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a pilot program to award competitive grants to accredited schools and colleges of veterinary medicine to develop and provide new or existing curricula that specialize in wildlife or zoological veterinary medicine; and (2) award competitive grants to eligible wildlife or veterinary institutions to establish or expand training programs (i.e., externship, internship, fellowship, or residency programs) in veterinary medicine for wildlife or zoological populations, under which financial assistance will be provided to traineeship candidates (i.e., individuals who hold, or who are enrolled in a program leading to, a doctoral degree in veterinary medicine).</summary>
</bill>
