<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3068</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:15Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:15Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-03-03</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-03-03T21:30:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>4804</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-03-16</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S1026-1030)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-03</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1024-1026)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-03-03</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001016</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hutchison, Kay Bailey [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>KAY</firstName>
        <lastName>HUTCHISON</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <middleName>BAILEY</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000572</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. LeMieux, George S. [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>LeMieux</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-04-13</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National Aeronautics and Space Administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Space flight and exploration</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-03-03</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-05-07T12:53:15Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010 - Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) to: (1) take all necessary steps to ensure that all Space Shuttle Program activities and operations are able to continue, or to be resumed, including flight operations and support, pending the completion of required reviews, requirements, and reports; and (2) ensure space shuttle launch capability through FY2011 by enabling launch, at a minimum, of all payloads manifested as of February 28, 2010. </p> <p>Instructs the Administrator to ask the National Academies of Science (NAS) to appoint a Flight Certification Review Committee to: (1) review space shuttle certification activities undertaken or initiated after February 2003; and (2) assess their adequacy in assuring vehicle durability, flight-worthiness, and sustainability for continued operations of up to five years beyond the flight manifest planned as February 2010. </p> <p>Requires NASA to operate the Space Shuttle Program at a flight rate of not more than 2 missions in any consecutive 12-month period during FY2010-FY2012. </p> <p>Prohibits termination of such Program as of a scheduled date certain. </p> <p>Specifies the conditions for termination of space shuttle missions operations. Requires a determination by the President regarding termination of missions in support of International Space Station (ISS) operations and Congress to be notified of any such determination. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements for the decommissioning of the remaining space shuttles and the preservation of shuttle vehicle and systems design and engineering data.</p> <p>States that it shall be the policy of the United States, in consultation with its ISS International Partners, to support full and complete utilization of the Space Station through at least the year 2020.</p> <p>Requires a review of all essential vehicles, components, and permanent scientific equipment on board or planned for installation aboard the ISS, including international partner elements, and the Comptroller General to monitor such review. </p> <p>Establishes responsibility for the ISS United States National Laboratory in the Space Operations Mission Directorate, ISS Program Office. Delegates to a Deputy Associate Administrator for ISS the conduct of ISS operations by NASA and non-NASA organizations. </p> <p>Establishes a management entity for the National Laboratory to implement research and development projects using the ISS U.S. segment. </p> <p>Guarantees National Laboratory-managed experiments access to 50% of the U.S.'s research facilities allocation through FY2014, increased by an additional 10% annually through FY2020. </p> <p>Establishes a National Space Transportation System. Requires a technology development plan. Provides for specified crew and cargo studies, reviews, and activities.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reauthorize the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Human Space Flight Activities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Human Space Flight Capability Assurance and Enhancement Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-03-03T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-03-03</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S1026-1030)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
