<bill session="116" type="h" number="7063" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Influence Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to limit the exemption from the registration requirements of such Act for persons engaging in activities in furtherance of bona fide religious, scholastic, academic, or scientific pursuits or the fine arts to activities which do not promote the political agenda of a foreign government, to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to clarify the disclosures of foreign gifts by institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Influence Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2020-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2020-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2020-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3313" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Art, artists, authorship"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="General science and technology matters"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-27T23:20:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Influence Transparency Act

This bill addresses foreign influence in higher education and in certain other academic, religious, and artistic pursuits.

Current law exempts from foreign agent registration requirements a person engaging in activities in furtherance of religious, scholastic, academic, or scientific pursuits or of the fine arts. The bill specifies that this exemption applies only to those activities that do not promote the political agenda of a foreign government.

 Under current law, an institution of higher education is required to disclose to the Department of Education a gift or contract that is from a foreign source and is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with a foreign source. The bill instead requires the institution to disclose such a gift or contract that is valued at $50,000 or more.

An institution must include in its disclosure report the contents of any such contract and make the contents available for public disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
