<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="178" updated="2022-03-03T14:31:16Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3967" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-03-02T16:47:27-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-03-02"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 5 printed in Part B of House Report 117-253 to replace the text of the bill with the Health Care for Burn Pit Veterans Act, which expands healthcare eligibility for certain combat veterans exposed to toxic substances to last for ten years after separation instead of five years, to require toxic exposure-related education and training for VA personnel, and to require screenings and studies to better identify potential associations between veteran medical conditions and toxic exposure.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to replace the text of the bill with the Health Care for Burn Pit Veterans Act, which expands healthcare eligibility for certain combat veterans exposed to toxic substances to last for ten years after separation instead of five years, to require toxic exposure-related education and training for VA personnel, and to require screenings and studies to better identify potential associations between veteran medical conditions and toxic exposure.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-03-02T16:47:27-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="53">
      <text>On agreeing to the Miller-Meeks amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 223 (Roll no. 53).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T14:08:12-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A003) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T13:58:40-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mrs. Miller-Meeks.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1242-1245" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1242-1243" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T16:47:27-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Miller-Meeks amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 223 (Roll no. 53).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T16:47:27-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Miller-Meeks amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 203 - 223 (Roll no. 53).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T13:58:40-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mrs. Miller-Meeks.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1242-1245" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1242-1243" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02T16:47:27-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
