<bill session="116" type="h" number="6200" updated="2022-08-10T23:37:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic EBT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide certain food assistance for eligible children during periods when their schools are closed due to a public health emergency; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic EBT Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000455"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2020-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2020-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-25T19:49:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Pandemic EBT Act of 2020

This bill expands authority in FY2020 for the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide assistance under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) during a public health emergency based on COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill authorizes USDA to approve state agency plans to provide SNAP benefits to households that include at least one eligible child and may or may not be participating in SNAP. An eligible child is a child who would be receiving free or reduced-price school meals if the child's school had not been closed for at least five consecutive days due to the public health emergency based on COVID-19.

SNAP benefits provided must be no less than the value of school meals at the federal free rate over the course of five school days for each eligible child in the household.

A state agency may provide SNAP benefits in accordance with the bill through the electronic benefits transfer card system.</summary>
</bill>
