<bill session="116" type="h" number="3209" updated="2022-11-01T07:02:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Airport Transfer of License Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to codify requirements for changes in airport sponsorship or operations with respect to airport operating certificates, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Transfer of License Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2019-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2019-09-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-21T20:50:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Airport Transfer of License Act

This bill sets forth requirements for a change in airport sponsorship or operations with respect to airport operating certificates.

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must issue an airport operating certificate to a new sponsor or operator if (1) the holder of the airport operating certificate for such airport consents to the transfer of sponsorship or operations, and (2) the new sponsor or operator satisfies all requirements for obtaining a certificate.

If the holder of the airport operating certificate disputes the transfer, the FAA must issue a certificate to the new sponsor if all requirements are satisfied and the dispute is resolved through legal action, including the issuance of a final, non-appealable judicial decision requiring a change of sponsorship or operations.</summary>
</bill>
