<bill session="111" type="h" number="3798" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:53Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to eligible entities to train elementary and secondary school nurses on how to respond to a biological or chemical attack or an outbreak of pandemic influenza in a school building or on school grounds.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Protection Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2009-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-26T20:56:23Z" status="Introduced in House">School Protection Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants to, and enter contracts with, eligible entities to train elementary and secondary school nurses to serve as first responders and crisis managers in the event of: (1) a biological or chemical attack affecting individuals in a school building or on school grounds; or (2) an outbreak of pandemic influenza among students, faculty, or other individuals under their care.

Requires any such training to prepare school nurses to: (1) take necessary measures, particularly in critical early stages, to protect and preserve life; (2) notify public health authorities as appropriate to help contain or mitigate the effects of an attack or outbreak; and (3) preserve evidence of a biological or chemical attack.</summary>
</bill>
