<bill session="118" type="hr" number="166" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28T14:04:50-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-28T14:04:50-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 347) to require the Executive Office of the President to provide an inflation estimate with respect to Executive orders with a significant effect on the annual gross budget, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 30) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of Labor relating to "Prudence and Loyalty in Selecting Plan Investments and Exercising Shareholder Rights".</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 347) to require the Executive Office of the President to provide an inflation estimate with respect to Executive orders with a significant effect on the annual gross budget, and for other purposes, and providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 30) providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Department of Labor relating to "Prudence and Loyalty in Selecting Plan Investments and Exercising Shareholder Rights".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-4, by Mr. Burgess.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27T20:37:30-05:00">
      <text>Provides for consideration of H.R. 347 and H.J. Res. 30 and one hour of debate on each measure. The rule makes in order amendments to H.R. 347 printed in the report and provides for one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-02-27" calendar="House" number="4">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 4.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T12:06:08-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H924-930" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T12:08:55-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 166.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T12:37:56-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 166, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T13:30:37-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H931-932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T13:57:12-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 213 - 201 (Roll no. 122).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="123" datetime="2023-02-28T14:04:50-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 205 (Roll No. 123).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H924" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28T14:04:51-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="347" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="30" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-23T15:37:52Z" status="Reported to House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of

 H.R. 347 (Reduce Exacerbated Inflation Negatively Impacting the Nation Act, which requires the Office of Management and Budget and the President's Council of Economic Advisors to provide an inflation estimate for each executive order that is projected to cause an annual gross budgetary or economic effect of at least $1 million), and H.J. Res 30 (nullifies a Department of Labor rule that permits fiduciaries of employee benefit plans to consider climate change and other environmental, social, and governance factors in investment decisions or when exercising shareholder rights).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-4</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-4</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
