<bill session="117" type="h" number="5780" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disaster Equity and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Equity and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve the provision of certain disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2021-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3093" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-22T13:09:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Equity and Fairness Act

This bill makes changes in the provision of federal disaster assistance to underserved communities and other specified recipients.

Underserved community means populations sharing a particular characteristic and geographic communities that have been systematically denied a full opportunity to participate in aspects of economic, social, and civic life.

Specifically, the bill increases the federal cost share to a local government or Indian tribal government in connection with a second or subsequent major disaster during any three-year period.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) may provide assistance to a state, local government, or Indian tribal government to reimburse the cost of coordinating food delivery, production, and distribution in the event of a major disaster.

FEMA must provide direct technical assistance to eligible entities for applications and prioritize specified categories of communities, including underserved communities, those that have demonstrated a compelling need, and those that are exposed to increased hazards or vulnerabilities.

The bill increases the federal cost share for a recipient (1) that will use the assistance in, or for the benefit of persons who are members of, an undeserved community; or (2) who is in, or who is a member of, an underserved community.</summary>
</bill>
