<bill session="117" type="h" number="5626" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Biomedical Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Biomedical Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing And Fortifying Everyday Biomedical Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, to consult with certain heads of Federal agencies with respect to biomedical research that may affect national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-11T16:35:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing And Fortifying Everyday Biomedical Research Act or the SAFE Biomedical Research Act

This bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to address national security concerns with respect to the biomedical research it conducts or supports.

Specifically, the NIH must consult with relevant agencies within the Department of Health and Human Services and other federal partners, including the Federal Bureau of Investigation, regarding research that may affect or be affected by matters of national security. The NIH must also ensure that recipients of its funding adhere to appropriate technology practices and policies to safeguard identifiable, sensitive information.</summary>
</bill>
