<bill session="116" type="h" number="6224" updated="2022-08-10T23:36:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Building Much Needed Rail Grade Separations Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to establish a dedicated, competitive highway-rail grade separation program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Much Needed Rail Grade Separations Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-29T14:15:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Building Much Needed Rail Grade Separations Act of 2020

This bill establishes a grade separation investment program to award competitive grants to certain entities for projects that

 separate railway-highway grade crossings, improve safety by reducing the number of deaths and injuries at rail-highway crossings, increase the efficiency and reliability of the movement of people and freight over rail-highway crossings, increase the capacity of the freight and passenger rail system, reduce the amount of noise from trains, and improve air quality and reduce greenhouse gas emissions from less idling at rail-highway crossings. Among other requirements, the bill (1) requires grant awards for large projects (projects with total costs of greater than $100 million) to be at least $50 million, and for any other projects not less than $2.5 million; and (2) directs the Department of Transportation to consider a number of factors in awarding grants, including accident history at the rail-highway crossing over the last 10 years, the annual average daily traffic at the crossing, the likelihood of a collision based on the geometry of the crossing, and the number of critical facilities near the crossing.</summary>
</bill>
