<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2850" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:22Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="95" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-03-12">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <description>to increase budget authority and outlays in Function 450 (Community and Regional Development) and Function 500 (Education, Training, Employment, and Social Security) to establish a New Homestead Venture Capital Fund to make equity and near equity investments in start-up and expanding businesses located in high out-migration rural counties and to repay up to 50 percent of college loans (up to $10,000) for recent graduates who live and work in such counties for five years, respectively; and to express the sense of the Senate that any revenue measure passed by Congress in the future should include tax incentives designed to address the devastating problem of chronic out-migration from rural communities in America's Heartland and that those tax incentives should be fully offset.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-03-12" how="Voice Vote" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 2850 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Amendment SA 2850 proposed by Senator Nickles for Senator Dorgan. (consideration: CR 3/12/2004 S2676-2677; text: CR 3/12/2004 S2676) to increase budget authority and outlays in Function 450 (Community and Regional Development) and Function 500 (Education, Training, Employment, and Social Security) to establish a New Homestead Venture Capital Fund to make equity and near equity investments in start-up and expanding businesses located in high out-migration rural counties and to repay up to 50 percent of college loans (up to $10,000) for recent graduates who live and work in such counties for five years, respectively; and to express the sense of the Senate that any revenue measure passed by Congress in the future should include tax incentives designed to address the devastating problem of chronic out-migration from rural communities in America's Heartland and that those tax incentives should be fully offset.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 2850 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2850 proposed by Senator Nickles for Senator Dorgan.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/12/2004 S2676-2677" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 3/12/2004 S2676" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
