<bill session="108" type="s" number="1832" updated="2021-09-29T22:19:22Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-06">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senator Paul Wellstone Mental Health Equitable Treatment Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="display">Senator Paul Wellstone Mental Health Equitable Treatment Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled "The Senator Paul Wellstone Mental Health Equitable Treatment Act of 2003".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="382">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 382.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5730, S5731, S5732-5733"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Health services administration"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-07T21:35:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Senator Paul Wellstone Mental Health Equitable Treatment Act of 2003 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Public Health Service Act to prohibit certain employee group health plans or related insurances providing both medical-surgical and mental health benefits from imposing mental health treatment limitations or financial requirements unless comparable limitations and requirements are imposed upon medical-surgical benefits. States that the foregoing shall not be construed as requiring a group health plan (or related insurance) to: (1) provide any mental health benefits; (2) prevent the medical management of mental health benefits; or (3) require the provision of specific mental health services, except to the extent that failure to provide such services would result in a disparity between the coverage of mental health and medical-surgical benefits.

Exempts specified small employers from such requirements.Requires that, in the case of a group health plan that offers a participant or beneficiary two or more benefit package options, the coverage requirements shall be applied separately with respect to each such option.Provides that, in the case of a plan or insurance providing in-network mental health benefits, out-of-network mental health benefits need not be provided at parity to medical-surgical benefits, as long as in-network mental health benefits are provided at parity with medical-surgical benefits and the plan or insurance provides reasonable access to in-network providers and facilities. Requires a General Accounting Office study of such requirements' effects upon health insurance costs, access, and quality and a cost estimation of extending such requirements to the treatment of substance abuse and chemical dependency.</summary>
</bill>
