<bill session="108" type="s" number="36" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:07Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Equity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to eliminate the geographic physician work adjustment factor from the geographic indices used to adjust payments under the physician fee schedule, to provide incentives necessary to attract educators and clinical practitioners to underserved areas, and to revise the area wage adjustment applicable under the prospective payment system for skilled nursing facilities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Equity Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2003-01-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2003-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2003-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S43"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Equity Act of 2003 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to eliminate the geographic physician work adjustment factor from the geographic indices used to adjust payments under the physician fee schedule.Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration project that provides for demonstration grants designed to provide financial or other incentives to hospitals to attract educators and clinical practitioners so that hospitals that serve beneficiaries under the Medicare program who are residents of underserved areas may host clinical rotations.Amends SSA title XVIII to provide for the use of skilled nursing facility wage data under the prospective payment system for skilled nursing facility services.</summary>
</bill>
