<bill session="117" type="hr" number="41" updated="2023-12-05T10:26:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-13T12:23:59-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-01-13T12:23:59-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 24) impeaching Donald John Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the resolution (H. Res. 24) impeaching Donald John Trump, President of the United States, for high crimes and misdemeanors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 117-2, by Mr. McGovern.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-12T22:59:05-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 24 with 2 hours of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-01-12" calendar="House" number="2">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 2.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13T09:17:45-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H151-165" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13T09:19:11-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13T11:32:19-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 205 (Roll no. 15).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="16" datetime="2021-01-13T12:23:59-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 221 - 203 (Roll no. 16).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H151-152" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13T12:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="24" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="40" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-29T13:58:29Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of H.Res. 24 (impeaching President Donald John Trump for high crimes and misdemeanors) and adopts H.Res. 40 (appointing and authorizing managers for the impeachment trial).

The resolution also prohibits resolutions incidental to impeachment relating to H.Res. 24 from being privileged during the remainder of the 117th Congress.

In addition, this resolution extends the following dates in H.Res. 8 (establishing the Rules of the House of Representatives for the 117th Congress by adopting and modifying the House Rules from the 116th Congress, including measures to facilitate the operation of Congress during the ongoing COVID-19 [i.e., coronavirus disease 2019] pandemic), as agreed to January 4, 2021, through:

 the legislative day of February 11, 2021, by which certain proceedings may take place in the House; the legislative day of February 11, 2021, the authority of the Speaker of the House to suspend the rules; and the legislative day of February 11, 2021, provisions waiving a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration of resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules through such legislative day, on the same day they are presented to the House.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-2</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
