<bill session="117" type="s" number="4983" updated="2023-08-29T21:00:37Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BIDIRECTIONAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BIDIRECTIONAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bus Integration Dedicated to Improving Resilience, Eliminating Congestion, and Triggering Innovation Over Numerous Applications and Localities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to encourage deployment of electric school buses and vehicle-to-grid technologies and applications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2022-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-29T20:46:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bus Integration Dedicated to Improving Resilience, Eliminating Congestion, and Triggering Innovation Over Numerous Applications and Localities Act or the BIDIRECTIONAL Act

This bill establishes requirements to encourage the deployment of vehicle-to-grid and vehicle-to-everything technologies and applications that enable bidirectional charging, such as technologies that enable electric vehicles to use their batteries to power the energy grid or homes when they are not being driven. Specifically, the bill requires states to consider measures to promote vehicle-to-grid integration under the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act.

The bill also directs the Department of Energy to establish a grant program for projects that use at least one electric school bus with such technology. Grants may be awarded to electric energy suppliers, state public utility commissions, school bus manufacturers, school districts, suppliers of charging infrastructure, renewable energy developers, and other eligible entities.</summary>
</bill>
