<bill session="119" type="h" number="1969" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-22T06:58:49-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-05-22T06:58:49-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="display">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend and reauthorize the Staff Sergeant Parker Gordon Fox Suicide Prevention Grant Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2025-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 7 - 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 119-103.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-05-19" calendar="Union" number="76">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20T15:21:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bost moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20T15:21:43-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2175-2177" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2175-2176" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20T15:21:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1969.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-20T15:39:17-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bost objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-22T06:57:50-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-05-22T06:58:49-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-05-22T06:58:52-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Reporting, Markup, Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-20T23:55:56Z" status="Introduced in House">No Wrong Door for Veterans Act

This bill&#160;reauthorizes through FY2028 and modifies the Staff Sergeant Parker Gordon Fox Suicide Prevention Grant Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), which awards grants to eligible entities to provide or coordinate suicide prevention services for veterans and members of the Armed Forces and their families.

Among other elements, the bill

adjusts the maximum amount for grants awarded under the program and provides for additional funding per individual who receives suicide prevention services provided or coordinated by a grantee;requires the VA to provide briefings about the grant program at least once a year to certain personnel at each VA medical center located within 100 miles from the primary location of a grantee;requires baseline mental health screenings for risk provided as suicide prevention services under the program to use a protocol selected by the VA; andmodifies eligibility requirements for entities seeking grants, including by authorizing applications from health care providers.In subsequent applications, grantees who have previously received funds under the program must include evidence that previously awarded funds served a significant number of veterans.

The bill requires grantees to notify (1) eligible individuals that they may receive emergent suicide care furnished or paid for by the VA, and (2) the VA if eligible individuals request emergent suicide care.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-103</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
