<bill session="109" type="s" number="2079" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:32Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forests for Future Generations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the ability of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to promptly implement recovery treatments in response to catastrophic events affecting the natural resources of Forest Service land and Bureau of Land Management Land, respectively, to support the recovery of non-Federal land damaged by catastrophic events, to assist impacted communities, to revitalize Forest Service experimental forests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forests for Future Generations Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001142"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2006-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2006-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000162" joined="2005-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4200" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-06T15:12:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forests for Future Generations Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to develop research protocols for collecting and analyzing scientific information about the effectiveness and ecological impacts of catastrophic event recovery projects and emergency stabilization treatments undertaken as part of a burned area emergency response to increase the long-term benefits of management activities and to decrease short-term impacts. Requires such Secretaries to enter into at least one cooperative agreement with one land-grant college or university in each Forest Service Region to form forest health partnerships to utilize the education, research, and outreach capacity of land-grant colleges and universities to address the recovery of forested land after a catastrophic event.

Requires such Secretaries to conduct catastrophic event recovery evaluations of damaged federal lands.

Directs such Secretaries to prepare a list of pre-approved management practices that may be immediately implemented as part of catastrophic event recovery projects or catastrophic event research projects.

 Requires determinations of whether or not to: (1) use any pre-approved management practices that can be immediately implemented; and (2) develop and carry out a recovery or research project or part of such a project using the alternative arrangements authorized by this Act.

Directs such Secretaries to clarify agency-wide guidance regarding reforestation in response to catastrophic events.

Provides for assistance to restore landscapes and communities affected by catastrophic events.

Directs such Secretaries to establish a community protection and recovery fund for each recovery project.

Provides for the availability and use of pre-approved management practices and alternative arrangements on National Forest experimental forests.</summary>
</bill>
