<bill session="114" type="h" number="527" updated="2023-01-11T13:28:38Z">
  <state datetime="2015-02-05T11:44:34-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-02-05T11:44:34-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 6 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Regulatory Flexibility Act), to ensure complete analysis of potential impacts on small entities of rules, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001092" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001107" joined="2015-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001070" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001057" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2015-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000387" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2015-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2015-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2015-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Regulatory Reform, Commercial And Antitrust Law Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-01-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 114-12, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-02">
      <text>Committee on Small Business discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-02-02" calendar="Union" number="8">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 8.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-02-03T18:20:46-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 78 Reported to House. For H.R. 527, the rule provides for one hour of debate; makes in order as original text the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Rules Committee Print 114-3; and makes specified additional amendments in order. For H.R. 50, the rule provides for one hour of debate; provides that an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 114-4, modified by the amendment printed in Part B of the report shall be considered as adopted. Further specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T09:10:19-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 78.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H816-834" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H822-825" label="text of the amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T09:10:24-05:00">
      <text>For H.R. 527, the rule provides for one hour of debate; makes in order as original text the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Rules Committee Print 114-3; and makes specified additional amendments in order. For H.R. 50, the rule provides for one hour of debate; provides that an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 114-4, modified by the amendment printed in Part B of the report shall be considered as adopted. Further specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T09:10:52-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Lynn A. Westmoreland to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T09:10:52-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 78 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T09:11:00-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 527.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:03:02-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 78, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peters Part A amendment no. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:08:21-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 78, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conyers Part A amendment no. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:15:50-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 78, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrader Part A amendment no. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:21:40-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Schrader amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Schrader demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:22:36-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 78, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Johnson(GA) Part A amendment no. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:31:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 78, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee Part A amendment no. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T10:42:33-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:18:23-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 527.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:19:01-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H831" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:19:40-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Deutch moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H831-833" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H831-832" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:19:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Deutch motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add at the end of the bill the following section pertaining to Preventing the Spread of Nuclear Weapons.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:29:14-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H832" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:36:37-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 182 - 240 (Roll no. 67).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="68" datetime="2015-02-05T11:44:34-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 260 - 163 (Roll no. 68).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-02-05T11:44:35-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-02-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="hr" number="78" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="426" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="86" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="1536" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h20"/>
    <amendment number="h19"/>
    <amendment number="h18"/>
    <amendment number="h17"/>
    <amendment number="h16"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-03-02T22:56:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Regulatory Flexibility Improvements Act of 2015

This bill modifies the rule making requirements and procedures of federal agencies (excluding Congress, U.S. courts, U.S. territories and possession, and the District of Columbia) under the Regulatory Flexibility Act of 1980 (RFA) and the Small Business Regulatory Enforcement Fairness Act of 1996 (SBREFA). The definition of "rule" under RFA is expanded to include all agency rules, except for rules that pertain to the protection of the rights of and benefits for veterans or rules of particular (and not general) applicability relating to rates, wages, and other financial indicators. Under a new definition of "economic impact," agencies are required to consider any direct economic effect of a proposed rule on small entities and any indirect economic effect on small entities that is reasonably foreseeable and that results from such rule.

Under the bill, agencies are required to modify their rulemaking procedures to:

 include within initial and final regulatory flexibility analyses a detailed statement of information relating to a proposed rule; include in the agency regulatory flexibility agenda a description of the sector of the North American Industrial Classification System that is affected by a proposed agency rule that is likely to have a significant economic impact of a substantial number of small entities; require each initial regulatory flexibility analysis to contain detailed information about a proposed rule, including why agency action is being considered, the objectives and legal basis for the proposed rule, and an estimate of the number and types of small entities to which the proposed rule will apply; eliminate waivers or delays of an initial regulatory flexibility analysis; modify the procedures for participation of small entities in the promulgation of a proposed rule and the review panel advocacy process; and publish a plan for the periodic review of existing rules and new rules that have a significant impact on a substantial number of small entities to determine whether such rules should be continued, changed, or rescinded. Judicial review of an agency final rule for compliance with RFA requirements is allowed after the publication of such rule, instead of after completion of the rulemaking process.

The Small Business Act is amended to authorize the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make small business size standard determinations for all purposes other than for the purposes of such Act or the Small Business Investment Act of 1958.

SBREFA is amended to require agencies, in preparing small entity compliance guides, to solicit input from affected small entities or associations of small entities.

The Comptroller General must complete and publish a study that examines whether the SBA Chief Counsel for Advocacy has the capacity and resources to carry out duties under this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-12</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
