<bill session="119" type="h" number="2431" updated="2025-08-11T19:06:43Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Don't Cut FAA Workers Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Don't Cut FAA Workers Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to limit mass layoffs of employees of the Federal Aviation Administration within 1 year of a major aviation accident, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-11T19:02:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Don't Cut FAA Workers Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) from carrying out a mass layoff within one&#160;year of a major aviation accident&#160;(i.e., an aircraft accident in which a fatal aviation injury occurs), unless the FAA receives congressional approval.&#160;

Specifically, the FAA must notify Congress of plans to carry out or&#160;facilitate a mass layoff following a major aviation accident. The notification must&#160;include&#160;the number and type of employees proposed to be laid off. The FAA may only carry out the layoff if Congress enacts a joint resolution approving the proposal no later than 60 days after receiving the notification.

Under the bill, a&#160;mass layoff means a reduction in force or other termination of employment that results in a personnel loss during any 90-day period of (1) 10 or more FAA employees at a single&#160;employment site; or (2) 250 or more FAA employees, irrespective of the employment site.</summary>
</bill>
