<bill session="117" type="h" number="4447" updated="2023-08-30T18:15:29Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to provide the Commission with notice and comment rulemaking authority respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices and to provide for civil penalties for violations of such Act respecting unfair or deceptive acts or practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century FTC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century FTC Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-30T18:03:52Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century FTC Act

This bill eliminates certain requirements with respect to the rulemaking authority of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

Specifically, the FTC may promulgate a rule under the Administrative Procedure Act defining an unfair or deceptive trade practice without (1) publishing advance notice of the rulemaking, (2) finding a widespread pattern of an applicable unfair practice, or (3) providing the opportunity for an informal hearing. It also limits the opportunity for the FTC or a petitioner of a rule to make additional oral submissions and written presentations while a rule is under judicial review.

Further, a court may not set aside a rule promulgated through such notice and comment process on the basis that the FTC failed to complete a regulatory analysis.</summary>
</bill>
