<bill session="118" type="h" number="4763" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:53Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-22T17:41:12-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-22T17:41:12-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="display">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a system of regulation of digital assets by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2024-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2023-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2024-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001221" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2024-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 35 - 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Agriculture. H. Rept. 118-484, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-484, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-05-06" calendar="Union" number="401">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 401.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T20:01:03-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1243 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4763, H.R. 5403 and H.R. 192. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each bill. H.R. 4763 and H.R. 5403 are considered under a structured rule and H.R. 192 is considered under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:48:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1243.</text>
      <reference ref="H3419&#226;&#8364;&#8220;3463" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:48:20-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4763, H.R. 5403 and H.R. 192. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each bill. H.R. 4763 and H.R. 5403 are considered under a structured rule and H.R. 192 is considered under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:49:06-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1243 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:49:07-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Michael Guest to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:49:55-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4763.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:06:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Casar amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:15:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Casar amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes prevailed. Mr. Casar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:16:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pettersen amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:23:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:34:43-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:35:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1243, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T16:47:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes prevailed. Ms. Waters demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T17:33:24-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4763.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T17:34:20-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T17:34:31-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="226" datetime="2024-05-22T17:41:12-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 279 - 136 (Roll no. 226).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3432-3455" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T17:41:14-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1243" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="9579" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h922"/>
    <amendment number="h921"/>
    <amendment number="h920"/>
    <amendment number="h919"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-05-20T19:44:06Z" status="Reported to House">Financial Innovation and Technology for the 21st Century Act 

This bill establishes a regulatory framework for digital assets.

The Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) must regulate a digital asset as a commodity if the blockchain, or digital ledger, on which it runs is functional and decentralized. The bill classifies a blockchain as decentralized if, among other requirements, no person has unilateral authority to control the blockchain or its usage, and no issuer or affiliated person has control of 20% or more of the digital asset or the voting power of the digital asset. In addition, the bill provides the CFTC with exclusive regulatory authority over cash or spot markets for digital commodities.

The Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) must regulate a digital asset as a security if its associated blockchain is functional but not decentralized. However, the bill establishes certain exceptions to SEC regulation for digital assets that limit annual sales, restrict nonaccredited investor access, and satisfy disclosure and compliance requirements. The bill also sets forth requirements for primary and secondary market transactions.

The CFTC and SEC must jointly issue rules to define terms and exempt dually registered exchanges from duplicative rules.

&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-484</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-484,Part 2</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
