<bill session="117" type="s" number="3621" updated="2023-01-18T05:17:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CASC Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a National Climate Adaptation Science Center and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers to respond to the effects of extreme weather events and climate trends, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CASC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Adaptation Science Centers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2022-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2022-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2022-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2022-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2022-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S613-614" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6654" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-24T22:06:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Climate Adaptation Science Centers Act or the CASC Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the National and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers of the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS). The centers must provide scientific expertise to managers of natural resources, cultural resources, and ecosystem services to inform decisions that aid adaptation to a changing climate and extreme weather events. The program shall include a National Climate Adaptation Science Center and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers.

Among its activities, the National Center shall

 serve as the national office for the regional centers, develop and facilitate coordination among the regional centers, and conduct research on cross-regional and national science priorities. Regional centers shall develop research, education, training, and advisory service priorities regarding the impacts of climate trends and variability on natural and cultural resource management.

The USGS shall establish an Advisory Committee on Climate and Natural Resource Sciences to identify and recommend priorities for ongoing research needs on such impacts in informing the research priorities of the National Center.</summary>
</bill>
