<bill session="118" type="h" number="3840" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Sufficient Supply of Testing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Sufficient Supply of Testing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize certain contracts and cooperative agreements with clinical laboratories for purposes of delivery of medical products to the Strategic National Stockpile.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000628"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2023-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-27T15:59:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Sufficient Supply of Testing Act

This bill expressly authorizes the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to enter into certain contracts and cooperative agreements with clinical laboratories as part of maintaining the Strategic National Stockpile. The Strategic National Stockpile consists of drugs, vaccines, medical products, and other supplies that may be deployed to respond to bioterrorist attacks or other public health emergencies.

Current law permits HHS to enter into specified types of contracts and cooperative agreements with vendors (e.g., manufacturers and distributors of medical products) for managing inventory of and ensuring production capacity for supplies needed for the stockpile. The bill specifies that clinical laboratories may participate as vendors in those types of contracts and agreements.</summary>
</bill>
