<bill session="108" type="s" number="2505" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Federal Communications Commission report to the Congress regarding low power FM service.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Federal Communications Commission report to the Congress regarding low power FM service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2004-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2004-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6481-6482"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6482" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain with an amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="813">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 813.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>By Senator McCain from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 108-426.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-04T20:58:16Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Repeals provisions in the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2001, that required the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to: (1) modify rules authorizing the operation of low-power FM radio stations to prescribe minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels; (2) prohibit applicants who have engaged in the unlicensed operation of any station from obtaining a low-power FM license; and (3) conduct a program to test whether low-power FM radio stations will result in harmful interference to existing FM radio stations if minimum distance separations for third-adjacent channels are not required.

Requires the FCC to modify its rules to eliminate third-adjacent minimum distance separation requirements between specified stations.

Requires the FCC to retain rules that provide third-adjacent channel protection for full-power noncommercial FM stations that broadcast radio reading services via a subcarrier frequency from potential low-power FM station interference.

Requires the FCC to retain its rules that provide third-adjacent channel protection for full-power FM stations that are licensed in significantly populated States with more than 3 million housing units and a population density greater than 1,000 people per square mile.

Requires the FCC to: (1) evaluate the impact of translator licensing on low and full power radio stations; and (2) implement policies that promote opportunities for locally based low power radio stations while protecting full power stations from harmful interference from translator networks.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-426</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
