<bill session="118" type="h" number="975" updated="2025-11-19T02:45:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rachael Booth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rachael Booth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make transitional compensation available to dependents of members of the Armed Forces convicted of dependent abuse in Federal or State court and dependents of members accused of dependent abuse who have forfeited all pay and allowances for an unrelated offense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001066" joined="2023-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="286" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-14T10:12:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Rachel Booth Act

This bill expands eligibility for transitional compensation payments to dependents (or former dependents) of certain members of the Armed Forces who have committed a dependent-abuse offense.

Specifically, the bill provides eligibility for transitional compensation to dependents of members of the Armed Forces in situations where a member (1) has been convicted of a dependent-abuse offense in a civilian court but has been separated from duty for an offense other than the abuse offense; or (2) has been accused but not convicted of such an offense, but has been determined to have committed the offense by a commander and required to forfeit pay and allowances for an offense other than the abuse offense.

For purposes of determining a recipient of payments under such circumstances, an individual's status as a dependent child must be determined as of the first date on which an individual is held in pretrial confinement relating to the dependent-abuse offense or the date on which the commander determines there is probable cause the individual has committed the offense.

The bill prescribes when transitional compensation payments must commence based on the status of the conviction or confinement.

The military department concerned may delegate authority to authorize eligibility for benefits for dependents (and former dependents) to the first general or flag officer (or civilian equivalent) in the chain of command of the offending member.</summary>
</bill>
