<bill session="111" type="s" number="3758" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:38Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish and enforce a maximum somatic cell count requirement for fluid milk.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish and enforce a maximum somatic cell count requirement for fluid milk.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-21T19:19:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act limit the somatic cell count in all dairy products sold, transported, or offered for sale or transport in interstate commerce to a maximum of 400,000 cells per milliliter of fluid milk, or equivalent, as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS). Authorizes the Secretary to lower the maximum somatic cell count after consideration of any recommendations submitted by the National Conference on Interstate Milk Shipments. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations to require that the calculation of a herd average somatic cell count under this Act be made using a geometric, rather than an arithmetic, mean.

Subjects any person that sells, transports, or offers for sale or transport in interstate commerce any dairy product in violation of this Act to a civil penalty.</summary>
</bill>
