<bill session="117" type="h" number="2034" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:09Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Income-Driven Student Loan Forgiveness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to forgive the Federal student loans of borrowers meeting certain income requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Income-Driven Student Loan Forgiveness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000586"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-22T15:57:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Income-Driven Student Loan Forgiveness Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to forgive the outstanding balance of principal, interest, and fees due on federal student loans for eligible borrowers who meet certain income requirements.

Eligible borrower refers to an individual who (1) has an eligible federal student loan in repayment, (2) filed a federal income tax return for the most recent tax year, (3) is employed or was employed during the three-year period immediately preceding March 1, 2020, and (4) meets income requirements (e.g., an adjusted gross income of $100,000 or less for a borrower who is not married). Further, the borrower must submit an application to ED for loan forgiveness.

 The bill prohibits borrowers from receiving refunds for any previously made payments.

Further, the bill specifies the notification requirements related to the availability of loan forgiveness.

The bill also excludes discharged student loan debt from an individual's gross income for tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
