<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="273" updated="2022-07-15T07:16:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="7900" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-07-14T14:15:17-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000375"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 391 printed in Part A of House Report 117-405 to require the State Department to establish and staff Climate Change Officer positions to be posted at U.S. embassies, consulates, or diplomatic missions to provide climate change mitigation expertise, engage with international entities on climate change, and facilitate bilateral and multilateral cooperation on climate change, taking specific actions to develop a strategy to improve and increase the study of, mitigation of, and adaptation to climate change and certify that considerations related to the climate are incorporated at U.S. embassies or other diplomatic posts, while also establishing a curriculum at the Foreign Service Institute to provide employees with specialized climate change training.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to require the State Department to establish and staff Climate Change Officer positions to be posted at U.S. embassies, consulates, or diplomatic missions to provide climate change mitigation expertise, engage with international entities on climate change, and facilitate bilateral and multilateral cooperation on climate change, taking specific actions to develop a strategy to improve and increase the study of, mitigation of, and adaptation to climate change and certify that considerations related to the climate are incorporated at U.S. embassies or other diplomatic posts, while also establishing a curriculum at the Foreign Service Institute to provide employees with specialized climate change training.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-07-14T14:15:17-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="336">
      <text>On agreeing to the Keating amendment (A029) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 217 (Roll no. 336).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6593-6594" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T00:03:04-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A029) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13T23:51:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A029) offered by Mr. Keating.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6449-6451" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6449-6450" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13"/>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13T23:51:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A029) offered by Mr. Keating.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:15:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Keating amendment (A029) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 217 (Roll no. 336).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:15:17-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:15:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Keating amendment (A029) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 208 - 217 (Roll no. 336).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
