<bill session="118" type="h" number="5865" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Army to establish a pilot program to protect Native American burial sites, village sites, and cultural resources discovered at Corps of Engineers civil works projects in the Sacramento River watershed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000578"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2023-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2024-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8812" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-30T15:39:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Native American Burial Sites and Cultural Resources Protection Act

This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers (USACE) to establish a pilot program to protect Native American burial sites, village sites, and cultural resources identified or discovered at covered civil works projects in the watershed of the Sacramento River and its tributaries, including the American, Bear,&#160;Yuba, and Feather Rivers, in California.

In carrying out this pilot program, USACE must identify, and cooperate with appropriate government property owners to set aside, areas that may be used for the reburial of Native American human remains and funerary objects that

have been identified or discovered at the site of a covered civil works project that is being constructed, reconstructed, or repaired, or operated and maintained, using federal funds;have been rightfully claimed by any affected Indian tribe; andcan be reburied in a manner secure from future disturbances.</summary>
</bill>
