<bill session="119" type="h" number="1235" updated="2025-11-05T09:05:43Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Infrastructure Bank Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Infrastructure Bank Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Federal Infrastructure Bank to facilitate investment in, and the long-term financing of, economically viable United States infrastructure projects that provide a public benefit, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000806"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2025-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2025-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-09T18:46:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Infrastructure Bank Act of 2025

This bill establishes the Federal Infrastructure Bank and the Federal Infrastructure Bank Holding Company (FIBHC). The bank shall be a wholly owned subsidiary of the FIBHC.

The bank must provide equity investments, direct loans, and loan guarantees for the planning, predevelopment, design, construction, operation, or maintenance of revenue-producing infrastructure projects in the United States with sufficient revenue sources and guarantees to support the interest and principal payments to the bank. At least 10% of the loans, equity investments, and loan guarantees must be for infrastructure projects in rural areas.

Entities eligible for loans, equity investments, and loan guarantees include corporations, joint ventures, states, and governmental entities. The bank is prohibited from providing funding for infrastructure projects that are owned, directed, controlled, financed, or influenced by the Chinese government or the Chinese Communist Party.

The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall have oversight and supervisory authority over the FIBHC and the bank. The bank must establish an Infrastructure Guarantee Fund to cover loans and loan guarantees in the event of nonpayment by loan recipients.

The FIBHC may issue equity securities, make dividend payments on the securities, and issue bonds.&#160;

The bill provides for a tax credit in an amount equal to 10% of the amount a taxpayer paid to the FIBHC for an equity investment issued within three years of&#160;the formation of the FIBHC.</summary>
</bill>
