<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1053" updated="2022-02-03T05:20:43Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5658" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-05-22T15:57:47-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001254"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <description>Amendment clarified language regarding the procurement by a federal agency of alternative or synthetic fuels and the conditions by which DOD and other federal agencies would be allowed to enter into a contract to purchase a generally available fuel, if it is not predominantly an alternative or synthetic fuel. The amendment would also set forth a set of conditions pursuant to these changes.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 110-666 to include clarifying language regarding the procurement by a federal agency of alternative or synthetic fuels; would clarify conditions by which DOD and other federal agencies would be allowed to enter into a contract to purchase a generally available fuel, if it is not predominantly an alternative or synthetic fuel. The amendment would also set forth a set of conditions pursuant to these changes.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-05-22T15:57:47-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Boren amendment (A008) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T15:45:41-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Boren.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4764-4766" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4764" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T15:57:47-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T15:57:47-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Boren amendment (A008) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T15:45:41-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Boren.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4764-4766" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4764" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
