<bill session="117" type="h" number="4796" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for enhanced Federal enforcement of, and State and local assistance in the enforcement of, the immigration laws of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Empowering Law Enforcement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Empowering Law Enforcement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001104" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1582" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4370" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-14T18:43:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Empowering Law Enforcement Act of 2021

This bill addresses issues relating to immigration enforcement.

The bill declares that state and local law enforcement have inherent authority to investigate and arrest individuals to assist federal immigration enforcement. (Currently, state and local law enforcement may take certain immigration enforcement actions upon entering into an agreement with U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement.)

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must reimburse state and local law enforcement for the costs of holding or transporting a detained alien.

DHS may detain an alien beyond the removal period (generally the window in which DHS must remove an alien after a final order of removal) upon making certain certifications, such as a certification that the alien's release would threaten community safety. DHS may renew this certification every six months after giving the alien an opportunity to request reconsideration of the certification. An alien challenging such detention may only do so by filing an application for a writ of habeas corpus.

Certain aliens subject to mandatory detention may be held without time limitation while removal proceedings are pending.

DHS must detain an alien who is present in the United States without lawful status if the alien has been convicted for driving while intoxicated.

DHS must establish a process to determine whether an alien not subject to mandatory detention and who has tried to comply with a removal order should be detained or released with conditions.

The Department of Justice must include information about immigration law violations in the National Crime Information Center database.</summary>
</bill>
