<bill session="112" type="s" number="1223" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:53Z">
  <state datetime="2012-12-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Location Privacy Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address voluntary location tracking of electronic communications devices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Location Privacy Protection Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Location Privacy Protection Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2011-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2011-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2011-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2012-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2011-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2011-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3894-3896" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="567">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 567.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-06-04T15:12:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Location Privacy Protection Act of 2011 - Amends the federal criminal code to prohibit a nongovernmental individual or entity engaged in the business of offering or providing a service to electronic communications devices from knowingly collecting, obtaining, or disclosing to a nongovernmental individual or entity geolocation information from an electronic communications device without the express authorization of the individual using the device. Defines "geolocation information" as any information concerning the location of an electronic communications device and used to identify or approximate the location of the electronic communications device or the individual using the device. Makes exceptions: (1) necessary to locate a minor child or provide fire, medical, public safety, or other emergency services; (2) for the sole purpose of transmitting the geolocation information to the individual or another authorized recipient; or (3) expressly required by state, regulation, or appropriate judicial process.

Requires an entity that provides geolocation information to: (1) provide notice that geolocation information relating to an individual is being disclosed to another individual; and (2) inform an individual on how such individual may revoke consent to the collection, receipt, recording, obtaining, and disclosure of geolocation information relating to the individual.

Authorizes civil actions by the Attorney General, state attorneys general, and aggrieved individuals for violations of this Act, subject to specified limitations.

Prohibits: (1) the unauthorized disclosure of geolocation information in aid of interstate domestic violence or stalking, and (2) the sale of geolocation information of not less than 1,000 children under age 11.

Directs: (1) the National Institute of Justice to conduct a national baseline study to examine the role of geolocation information in violence against women; (2) the Director of the Office on Violence Against Women to establish a task force to assist in the study's development and implementation; (3) the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), in conjunction with the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, to create a mechanism using the Internet Crime Complaint Center to register complaints of crimes the conduct of which was aided by use of geolocation information; and (4) the Attorney General to develop a national education curriculum to ensure that all courts, victim advocates, and state and local law enforcement personnel have access to information about relevant laws, practices, procedures, and policies for investigating and prosecuting the misuse of geolocation information.</summary>
</bill>
