<bill session="110" type="h" number="5028" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2008-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness in Autism Treatment Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require that group health plans provide coverage for pervasive developmental disorders such as autism.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Autism Treatment Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000366" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000043" joined="2008-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2008-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2008-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2008-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2008-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Autism"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-07T15:09:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Fairness in Autism Treatment Act of 2007 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to require a group health plan that provides both medical and surgical benefits to also provide coverage for pervasive developmental disorders, including coverage for therapeutic, respite, and rehabilitative care for participants or beneficiaries who have not attained 22 years of age.

Applies the requirements of this Act separately with respect to benefits provided in-network and out-of-network.

Prohibits a group health plan from: (1) imposing any annual or lifetime dollar limitation on benefits for pervasive developmental disorders unless such limitation applies to all medical and surgical benefits as well; (2) imposing a deductible, coinsurance, or other cost-sharing for such disorders that is greater than the cost-sharing imposed for medical and surgical benefits; or (3) denying eligibility, or continued eligibility, to enroll or renew coverage under the term of the plan solely for the purpose of avoiding the requirements of this Act.

Considers the requirements of this Act a material change for the purpose of notice requirements.

Excludes from the requirements of this Act: (1) a group health plan of a small employer; or (2) a group health plan if the application of this Act results in an increase in the cost under the plan of at least 1%.

Provides that this Act shall not be construed to preempt any state law that at least meets the requirements of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
