<bill session="118" type="h" number="4522" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Military Recruitment Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Military Recruitment Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to ensure access of Armed Forces recruiters to secondary school campuses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001222"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001126" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2024-08-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-06T18:28:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Military Recruitment Access Act

This bill revises requirements for military recruitment access to secondary school students.

Currently, each local educational agency that receives federal elementary and secondary education funds must provide military recruiters with the same access to secondary school students that is provided to institutions of higher education (IHEs) or prospective employers of those students. This bill further specifies that this access must include access to the campus of the secondary school and that such access must be for the same amount of time that is provided to&#160;IHEs and prospective employers.

Further, the Department of Education must annually notify school leaders, school administrators, and other educators about (1) the requirement to allow for military recruitment access, and (2) the actions that may be taken to enforcement this requirement. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
