<bill session="117" type="s" number="3515" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to remove the bronze plaque and concrete block bearing the name of Francis Newlands from the grounds of the memorial fountain located at Chevy Chase Circle in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2022-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1256" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-25T16:29:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act 

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to (1) remove the brass plaque bearing the name Senator Francis G. Newlands from the grounds of the memorial fountain located at Chevy Chase Circle in the District of Columbia; (2) remove from the south end of the memorial fountain's face, the stone, tablet-like projection bearing the name of Francis Griffith Newlands and a related inscription; (3) remove the name Newlands Memorial Fountain carved into the upper face of the memorial fountain's coping stones; and (4) offer the items removed to the descendants of Francis Griffith Newlands for a 60-day period, and if not claimed within that period, direct the removed items to be maintained by the National Park Service as federal property and accessioned into the Rock Creek Park museum collection.</summary>
</bill>
