<bill session="116" type="s" number="3106" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:13Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reforestation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforestation Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 to promote reforestation following unplanned events on Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2019-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4357" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7843" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-22T19:55:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reforestation Act of 2019

This bill addresses the need for reforestation of National Forest System (NFS) lands following certain unplanned events, including wildfires, weather events, and infestations of insects or diseases.

The bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to transmit to Congress annually, for 10 years, an estimate of the funds needed to replant and otherwise treat an acreage equal to the acreage to be cut over that year plus a sufficient portion of the backlog of lands in need of treatment to eliminate the backlog in the 10-year period.

The Forest Service shall create a priority list of projects that promote effective reforestation following specified unplanned events.

The bill sets 2029 as the target year for when the renewable resources of the NFS must be operating where there are no longer any backlogs and the major portion of planned intensive multiple-use sustained-yield management procedures must be installed and operating on an environmentally-sound basis.

The bill increases the amount that may be transferred to the reforestation trust fund for any fiscal year.

The land management goals of Forest Service stewardship end result contracting projects may include reforestation in accordance with the priority list.

USDA may enter into good neighbor agreements for reforestation activities in accordance with the priority list.</summary>
</bill>
