<bill session="117" type="s" number="3793" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Technology-Enabled Care in the Home (TECH) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology-Enabled Care in the Home (TECH) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to recommend the Center of Medicare and Medicaid Innovation test the effect of technology-enabled care interventions in the home to coordinate care over time and across settings, improve quality, and lower costs for certain Medicare Advantage beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2022-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T13:35:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Technology-Enabled Care in the Home (TECH) Act

This bill provides for the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a model for furnishing at-home telehealth, remote patient monitoring, and other technology-enabled care interventions for chronically ill individuals who are enrolled in certain Medicare Advantage plans. The model must test the effect of such technology on Medicare Advantage spending and the overall quality of care for beneficiaries.

The bill also repeals provisions that prohibit the correction of earnings records for purposes of Social Security benefits after certain time limitations expire and determinations become final.</summary>
</bill>
