<bill session="111" type="s" number="3688" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:09Z">
  <state datetime="2010-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">International Professional Exchange Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an international professional exchange program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">International Professional Exchange Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Professional Exchange Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Kerry without amendment. With written report No. 111-383.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-12-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="727">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 727.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-30T17:55:02Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

International Professional Exchange Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of State to establish a three-year international professional exchange pilot program for: (1) young professionals in the United States to live and work in a Muslim-majority country; and (2) young professionals in Muslim-majority countries to live and work in the United States.

Provides for fellowships of between three and six months, during which: (1) time should be allocated for professional training, community service, and cultural immersion activities, including site visits and domestic travel; and (2) the majority of time should be spent in a professional job setting that complements the fellow's professional background and builds relevant professional skill sets.

States that the selection of inbound and outbound fellows shall reflect geographic diversity from the Middle East, North Africa, Central Asia, South Asia, and Southeast Asia.

Requires each fellow to complete at least 40 hours of community service in the local community in which the fellow is placed.

Encourages the Secretary to defray program costs through public-private partnerships.

Requires three reports from the Secretary describing the administration and outcomes of the program.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-383</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
