<bill session="108" type="h" number="2321" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:34Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Group Health Plan Coverage Expansion Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote and facilitate expansion of coverage under group health plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Group Health Plan Coverage Expansion Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2003-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2003-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Labor contracts"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Group Health Plan Coverage Expansion Act of 2003 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish a program to promote and facilitate expansion of coverage under group health plans.Requires administrators of employee benefit plans under ERISA to notify plan participants, in plan descriptions, of the availability of : (1) child health insurance assistance, through the State Children's Health Insurance Program (SCHIP) under title XXI of the Social Security Act (SSA); and (2) cash benefits for eligible elderly or disabled individuals, through Supplemental Security Income (SSI) payments under title XVI of SSA.Prohibits group health plans, and health insurance issuers offering group health insurance coverage, under ERISA, from imposing: (1) any aggregate lifetime limit on benefits, including any category of benefits; or (2) any change in the premium rates charged to any participant or beneficiary to make them more than those charged to otherwise similarly situated individuals solely on the basis of a pre-existing condition.Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow pension or annuity plans to make payments for premiums for continuation coverage (COBRA benefits, in reference to requirements of title X of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985) under a group health plan on behalf of a qualified beneficiary, if such COBRA benefits are subordinate to retirement benefits provided by the plan and to the qualified current retiree health liabilities of a health benefits account which is part of such plan.Amends ERISA to authorize the Secretary or a State to bring a civil action for equitable relief against a qualified individual for not maintaining substantial health insurance coverage while obtaining emergency room services. Authorizes a court to order such a defendant to maintain at least two years of substantial health insurance coverage on the patient involved.</summary>
</bill>
