<bill session="110" type="h" number="5263" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:07Z">
  <state datetime="2008-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forest Landscape Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the collaborative, science-based ecosystem restoration of priority forest landscapes on Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service through a joint Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Landscape Restoration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2008-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E136"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2593" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest health"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-07-01T21:45:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Forest Landscape Restoration Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a Collaborative Forest Landscape Restoration Program to select and fund ecological restoration treatments for priority forest landscapes.

Sets forth provisions concerning the eligibility criteria for, and nomination and selection of, collaborative forest landscape restoration proposals for carrying out such treatments.

Requires the Secretary to establish a scientific advisory panel to evaluate, and provide recommendations on, any proposal with respect to: (1) the strength of the ecological case of the proposal for landscape restoration and the proposed restoration strategies; and (2) whether the proposal is likely to achieve reductions in long-term wildfire management costs.

Authorizes the Secretary to establish a technical advisory panel to evaluate, and provide recommendations on, any proposal with respect to whether the proposal is likely to reduce the relative costs of carrying out treatments resulting from the use of woody biomass and small-diameter trees and to provide local economic benefit.

Establishes the Collaborative Forest Landscape Fund, to be used for paying up to 50% of the cost of carrying out ecological restoration treatments on National Forest System land for each proposal selected.

Requires: (1) creation of implementation work plans and budgets to implement proposals; (2) submission of annual reports on the accomplishments of selected proposals; (3) use of a multiparty monitoring, evaluation, and accountability process to assess the ecological, social, and economic effects of projects implementing proposals; and (4) submission of reports every five years on the Program.</summary>
</bill>
