<bill session="118" type="h" number="3044" updated="2025-11-19T02:31:28Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REAL Political Advertisements Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REAL Political Advertisements Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Require the Exposure of AI&#226;&#8364;&#8220;Led Political Advertisements Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide further transparency and accountability for the use of content that is generated by artificial intelligence (generative AI) in political advertisements by requiring such advertisements to include a statement within the contents of the advertisements if generative AI was used to generate any image or video footage in the advertisements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1596" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-07T16:29:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Require the Exposure of AI-Led Political Advertisements Act or the REAL Political Advertisements Act

This bill expands certain disclosure and disclaimer requirements for political campaigns, including by requiring disclaimers on advertisements containing content generated by artificial intelligence (AI).

Specifically, the bill requires a communication (e.g., a political advertisement) to include, in a clear and conspicuous manner, a statement if the communication contains an image or video footage that was generated in whole or in part with the use of AI. The bill outlines the requirements for determining a clear and conspicuous manner as it applies to specified communications (e.g., text or video communications).

The bill directs the Federal Election Commission (FEC) to issue a regulation related to generative AI, including the criteria for determining whether an advertisement contains an image or video footage created through generative AI.

The bill also requires reporting to the FEC of paid internet or digital communications.</summary>
</bill>
