<bill session="108" type="h" number="2493" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nationwide Gun Buyback Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assist local governments in conducting gun buyback programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nationwide Gun Buyback Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1285-1286"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Amnesties"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Nationwide Gun Buyback Act of 2003 - Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to make grants to local governments to conduct gun buyback programs. Directs the Secretary, in assessing grant applications, to give greater weight to the incidence of gun violence and the need to reduce the availability of guns in the jurisdictions involved than to any other factors. Permits such units to use the grant only to conduct a gun buyback program in accordance with the approved grant application.Directs the chief executive of a local government desiring a grant to submit to the Secretary an application that contains assurances that: (1) within 60 days after the program collects a gun, the gun will be destroyed (or, if it is an inoperable curio or relic with historic significance, donated to a museum for display); (2) the local law enforcement authority is able to collect guns safely under the program; and (3) the government has the authority to grant an appropriate amnesty to persons from whom guns are obtained under the program.</summary>
</bill>
