<bill session="116" type="h" number="8749" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DATA Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DATA Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Accountability and Transparency to Advance Privacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for digital accountability and transparency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000132"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="583" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-27T17:02:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Accountability and Transparency to Advance Privacy Act or the DATA Privacy Act

This bill establishes information security requirements for businesses that collect, process, store, or disclose information relating to at least 3,000 people in a 12-month period. The bill applies to information that may be linked to a specific individual or a device associated with a specific individual. It does not cover data related to employment or publicly available government records. Specifically, covered businesses must provide consumers with accessible notice of the business&#8217; privacy practices with respect to such information; and if meeting a certain revenue threshold, appoint a privacy officer to oversee compliance with the information privacy standards of this bill. The bill further requires the Federal Trade Commission to promulgate rules requiring covered businesses to

 limit the purpose and amount of consumer data collection to reasonable business purposes, provide consumers with clear methods to opt-in and opt-out of such collection, and refrain from using such data for discriminatory purposes; provide consumers with a method to access, revise, transmit, and delete such collected information; and establish information security practices based on the sensitivity and level of identifiability of the collected data, risk of exposure of such data, widely-accepted practices of securing such data, and cost and impact of implementing such practices. The bill further revises the National Science Foundation information security grants program to include research about methods to encrypt or remove identifiable elements from collected consumer data.</summary>
</bill>
