<bill session="112" type="h" number="1691" updated="2020-02-14T19:19:50Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention of Unreasonable Fees Act</title>
    <title type="display">Prevention of Unreasonable Fees Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the application of section 14501(d) of title 49, United States Code, to prevent the imposition of unreasonable transportation terminal fees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000581"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000807" joined="2011-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1922" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-17T16:43:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevention of Unreasonable Fees Act - Prohibits an operator of a transportation terminal that uses federal funds for terminal construction, or for the purchase or lease of equipment installed there, from charging a fee to a provider of pre-arranged ground transportation service that meets state vehicle and intrastate passenger licensing requirements. Exempts from such prohibition: (1) fees charged to the general public for access to, or use of, the terminal; (2) any fee for the availability of ancillary facilities located there; or (3) any fee for such access or use that the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) has approved in advance as reasonable, nonburdensome, nondiscriminatory, and necessary to the provision of prearranged ground transportation service.

Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) prohibit or restrict a transportation terminal operator from requiring vehicles that cannot safely use public parking facilities to use segregated facilities provided the fee for segregated facilities is no more than that charged to the public for similar facilities, or (2) restrict the right of a state or its political subdivisions to require a license or fee (other than a prohibited transportation terminal fee) for a motor vehicle providing certain other prearranged ground transportation.</summary>
</bill>
