<bill session="117" type="h" number="3021" updated="2023-03-08T19:59:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coronavirus Provider Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for liability protection for health care providers for damages with respect to any harm caused by any act or omission of such health care professional or related health care entity in the course of arranging for or providing health care services during the COVID-19 public health emergency period, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coronavirus Provider Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2021-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-23T21:22:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Coronavirus Provider Protection Act 

This bill generally exempts health care professionals and related health care entities (e.g., hospitals and medical clinics) from liability for harm caused in the course of arranging or providing health care services during the COVID-19 public health emergency. To be exempt from liability, professionals and entities must provide these services in good faith, even if a service is outside a professional's normal area of practice, or withhold these services for reasons related to the COVID-19 public health emergency.

However, this exemption does not apply (1) if the act or omission constitutes willful or criminal misconduct, gross negligence, reckless misconduct, or a conscious flagrant indifference to the rights or safety of the individual harmed; or (2) if the professional provides the services while under the influence of alcohol or certain drugs.</summary>
</bill>
