<bill session="118" type="s" number="3195" updated="2025-08-15T15:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-20">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate the General George C. Marshall House, in the Commonwealth of Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5317" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="596">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 596.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7275" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7275" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:12:09-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-15T15:16:10Z" status="Passed Senate">This bill establishes the General George C. Marshall House in Leesburg, Virginia, as an affiliated area of the National Park System to promote public appreciation of the historic contributions made by George Catlett Marshall, Jr. (George Catlett Marshall, Jr. served as Army Chief of Staff during World War II, and later as Secretary of State, president of the American Red Cross, and Secretary of Defense.)

The bill designates the George C. Marshall International Center as the management entity for the affiliated area. The Department of the Interior must enter into an agreement with the center that describes the roles and responsibilities for management of the affiliated area. Further, Interior may provide technical assistance and enter into cooperative agreements with the center for the purpose of providing financial assistance for the marketing, marking, interpretation, and preservation of the affiliated area.&#160;

Interior may not acquire property at the affiliated area or assume overall financial responsibility for the operation, maintenance, or management of the affiliated area.</summary>
</bill>
