<bill session="118" type="h" number="1000" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">OATHS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OATHS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ordering Authentication in The House&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Swearing-in Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Clerk of the House of Representatives to provide Members-elect of the House with written copies of the oath of office prior to the first session of a Congress and to provide that a Member-elect who signs such copies shall be considered to have taken the oath of office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000450"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2023-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-11T21:24:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Ordering Authentication in The House's Swearing-in Act or the OATHS Act

This bill modifies procedures related to the oath of office that is taken by Members of the House of Representatives.

First, the bill eliminates the statutory requirement that the oath of office be administered at the first session of Congress after every general election of Representatives.

Second, the bill requires that the Clerk of the House of Representatives provide Members with two printed copies of the oath of office to sign before the first session of Congress rather than on the first day of that session. Generally, a Member shall be deemed to have taken the oath of office when they return the signed oath to the clerk for filing in official records. However, if a Member returns the signed oath before noon on the first day of the first session, the signed oath is effective at noon on the first day of that session.</summary>
</bill>
