<bill session="119" type="s" number="43" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Skinny Labels, Big Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Skinny Labels, Big Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to provide for a safe harbor from infringement of a method of use patent relating to drugs or biological products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-31T14:51:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Skinny Labels, Big Savings Act

This bill provides a statutory safe harbor from patent infringement claims for generic or&#160;biosimilar manufacturers that seek or obtain approval for skinny labels of their drugs.

Under current law, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) may approve generic and&#160;biosimilar drugs through a process known as skinny labeling, which allows a generic manufacturer to seek approval only for approved uses of the drug that are no longer protected by patents. However, in GlaxoSmithKline LLC v. Teva Pharmaceuticals USA, Inc., a court held that a generic manufacturer may sometimes be liable for patent infringement when it markets skinny label generics.

The bill specifically lists the following as actions that are not considered infringement of a method of use claim in a patent under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act:

submitting or seeking approval of a skinny label for a generic or biosimilar drug;promoting or commercially marketing a drug with skinny labeling approved by the FDA; ordescribing a drug product approved by the FDA as a generic of, or therapeutically equivalent to, the branded drug.The bill also applies the safe harbor to similar actions under the Public Health Service Act.</summary>
</bill>
