<bill session="118" type="s" number="818" updated="2025-11-19T02:56:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MORE Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maximizing Opioid Recovery Emergency Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote affordable access to evidence-based opioid treatments under the Medicare program and require coverage of medication assisted treatment for opioid use disorders, opioid overdose reversal medications, and recovery support services by health plans without cost-sharing requirements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1620" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Physical fitness and lifestyle"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-17T14:55:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maximizing Opioid Recovery Emergency Savings Act or the MORE Savings Act

This bill modifies coverage of opioid treatments and recovery support services under Medicare, Medicaid, and private health insurance.

Specifically, the bill requires the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a model in which specified opioid treatments and recovery support services are provided under Medicare without cost-sharing (e.g., coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles).

The bill also allows state Medicaid programs to cover recovery support services as part of medication-assisted treatment (MAT) and increases the applicable Federal Medical Assistance Percentage for MAT.

Additionally, beginning in 2025, private health insurers must cover specified opioid treatments and MAT-associated recovery support services without cost-sharing.</summary>
</bill>
