<bill session="117" type="h" number="3766" updated="2022-12-30T17:32:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Optimizing the Cattle Market Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, to establish a cattle contract library, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Optimizing the Cattle Market Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2021-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="543" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5609" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3229" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-07T12:23:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Optimizing the Cattle Market Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish and maintain a library or catalog of each type of contract offered by packers to producers for the purchase of all or part of the production of fed cattle (including cattle that are purchased or committed for delivery). Fed cattle means a steer or heifer that has been feeding on a ration of roughage and feed concentrates prior to slaughter, including grains, protein meal, grass, and other nutrient-rich feeds.

USDA must create and maintain a publicly available library or catalog of the types of contracts that are being offered by packers to, and are open to acceptance by, producers for the purchase of fed cattle. It must also conduct educational outreach activities for producers on how best to use the library or catalog.

Additionally, USDA must also establish (1) regional mandatory minimum thresholds to enhance price discovery and transparency for cattle market participants; and (2) methods for establishing such thresholds, which shall be publicly available.

Further, the bill revises daily reporting requirements for packer processing plants by requiring them to include the number of cattle scheduled to be delivered for slaughter each day for the subsequent 14 days.</summary>
</bill>
