<bill session="111" type="h" number="5889" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Public Health Service Act and title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase the number of primary care physicians and medical residents serving health professional shortage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act and title XVIII of the Social Security Act to increase the number of primary care physicians and medical residents serving health professional shortage areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-08T19:26:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to obligate, for scholarships for individuals who are accepted or enrolled in a course of study or program that leads to a degree in medicine or osteopathic medicine, the greater of : (1) 10% of amounts appropriated for the National Health Service Corps; or (2) the amount necessary to fund such scholarships activities.

Amends title XVIIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require nonrural hospitals operating training programs in rural areas to include rural and emergency medicine rotations and obstetrical and pediatric training in such programs for purposes of payments for direct graduate medical education costs.</summary>
</bill>
