<bill session="117" type="h" number="7665" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REC Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mt. Hood and Columbia River Gorge Recreation Enhancement and Conservation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REC Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for conservation and recreation enhancement for Mount Hood and the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2022-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E461"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-16T21:17:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Mt. Hood and Columbia River Gorge Recreation Enhancement and Conservation Act of 2022 or the REC Act of 2022

This bill establishes programs and requirements to support the conservation of and recreational access to the Mount Hood National Forest and the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area in Oregon.

Specifically, the bill establishes within Mount Hood National Forest one or more Indian Treaty Resources Emphasis Zones to protect and enhance treaty resources, protect reservations from wildfires, and enable a co-management strategy between the Forest Service and the Confederated Tribes of Warm Springs.

The bill expands the Mount Hood National Recreation Area. The bill also requires the publication of a comprehensive sustainable recreation management plan for the recreation area and Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area. It also establishes Centers for Recreation Excellence to support the management and enhancement of outdoor recreation in these areas.

Additionally, the bill

 provides for a wildfire assessment that covers Mount Hood National Forest, federal land within the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area, and any adjacent private, state, or tribal land; designates specified river segments in Oregon as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and specified areas in Oregon as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System; establishes committees to develop strategies for sustainable access to the Columbia River Gorge National Scenic Area and Mount Hood National Forest; and requires the Department of Agriculture to enter into cooperative agreements with certain entities to provide search and rescue, firefighting, and law enforcement services.</summary>
</bill>
