<bill session="118" type="h" number="3628" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Disabled National Guardsmen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Disabled National Guardsmen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 10 and 38, United States Code, to extend certain benefits to members of the National Guard who incur disabilities while performing State active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000740"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2024-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2024-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000600" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2024-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T18:01:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Disabled National Guardsmen Act

This bill provides disability pay and medical care for members of the National Guard who were physically disabled as a result of state active duty. State active duty includes training or other duty in service to the governor of a state for which the member is not entitled to federal pay, but excludes required drills and field exercises.

The bill expands eligibility for Department of Defense retired pay to such members who are physically disabled as a result of state active duty after September 23, 1996. Such pay must be reduced if it is determined to duplicate any other federal or state benefit to such members based on disability.

The bill also makes such members eligible for hospital care and medical services from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to treat the disability and any illness or condition arising from the disability. The VA may provide reimbursement for hospital care or medical services provided to such members only after a member or the provider of care has exhausted (without success) all claims and remedies reasonably available against a third party.</summary>
</bill>
