<bill session="117" type="h" number="3581" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COMMUTE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a pilot program to develop and provide to States and transportation planning organizations accessibility data sets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COMMUTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting Opportunities through Mobility Metrics and Unlocking Transportation Efficiencies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1697" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1827" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1931" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1953" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2038" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1629" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3473" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-02T19:26:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Connecting Opportunities through Mobility Metrics and Unlocking Transportation Efficiencies Act or the COMMUTE Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation to establish an accessibility data pilot program.

The purpose of the pilot program is to develop or procure an accessibility data set and make such data available for states and metropolitan or rural planning organizations to improve their transportation planning by

 measuring the level of access to important destinations such as jobs, health care facilities, child care services, educational and workforce training facilities, affordable housing, and food sources; disaggregating the level of access by multiple transportation modes by a variety of population categories, including minority populations; assessing the change in accessibility that would result from new transportation investments; and providing data necessary to prioritize transportation investments that will improve access by all modes of travel.</summary>
</bill>
