<bill session="115" type="s" number="512" updated="2023-03-22T19:50:59Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modernize the regulation of nuclear energy.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2017-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2017-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2017-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2017-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2017-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2017-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2017-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2017-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2018-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2017-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2017-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-08">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 115-52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-03-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Barrasso with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 115-86. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2017-05-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="108">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 108.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2017-05-25">
      <text>An errata sheet on written report number No. 115-86 was printed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-12-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7957-7962" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7962" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20T12:42:50-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-20T20:30:34-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T11:10:50-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Kinzinger moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T11:11:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10553-10558" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T11:11:14-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 512.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T11:19:10-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T16:44:35-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10577-10578" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="493" datetime="2018-12-21T16:47:47-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 361 - 10 (Roll no. 493).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10553-10557" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-12-21T16:47:48-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2019-01-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2019-01-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-439" type="public" datetime="2019-01-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-439.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4175"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2019-08-21T18:54:59Z" status="Public Law">Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act

This bill revises the budget and fee structure of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) and requires the NRC to develop new processes for licensing nuclear reactors, including staged licensing of advanced nuclear reactors.

TITLE I--ADVANCED NUCLEAR REACTORS AND USER FEES

(Sec.101)The bill amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1990 to remove amounts appropriated for the development of regulations for advanced nuclear reactor technologies from the amount the NRC must recover through fees.

(Sec.102)Effective FY2021, the bill:

 excludes additional amounts from the amount the NRC must recover through fees, including amounts for research and development at universities; directs the NRC to collect fees equal to its budget authority, less excluded amounts; limits NRC's spending on corporate support costs; and places a cap on the amount of the annual fee that may be charged to an operating reactor,which the NRC may waive if the cap compromises the NRC's safety and security mission. Performance metrics and milestone schedules must be developed for activities requested by applicants and licensees.In addition, the NRC must implement processes to ensure accurate invoicing.

(Sec.103) For commercial advanced nuclear reactors, the NRC must (1) establish stages within the licensing process; (2) increase the use of risk-informed, performance-based licensing evaluation techniques and guidance; and (3) establish by the end of 2027 a technology-inclusive regulatory framework that encourages greater technological innovation.

The NRC must develop research and test reactor licensing.

The NRC is also directed to train staff and develop the expertise required to implement the new licensing processes.

The NRC must report to Congress on (1) the implementation of stages in the advanced reactor licensing process, and (2) the use of risk-informed and performance-based techniques within the existing regulatory framework.

(Sec.104)The NRC must publish any necessary revisions to the guidance on the examination schedule for baffle-former bolts in certain reactors.

(Sec.105)The NRC must submit to Congress a report describing the actions it has taken, or plans to take, to consider lessons learned from recent disasters regarding directed or spontaneous evacuations in densely populated urban and suburban areas.

(Sec.106)The bill increases the percentage of operating costs that research reactors are allowed to recover from 50% to 75%, with up to 50% coming from energy sales.

(Sec.107)The NRC must submit to Congress a report describing the status of the licensing process for accident tolerant fuel. (Accident tolerant fuel is a new technology that makes an existing commercial nuclear reactor more resistant to a nuclear incident and lowers the cost of electricity over the licensed lifetime of a reactor.)

(Sec.108)The NRC must submit to Congress a report on the best practices for establishing and operating local community advisory boards.

(Sec.109)The NRC must submit to Congress a report on actions it is taking to address the appearance of workplace reprisals.

TITLE II--URANIUM

(Sec.201)The NRC must (1) report to Congress on the duration of uranium recovery licenses and recommendations to improve the efficiency and transparency of uranium recovery licensing, and (2) complete a voluntary pilot program to determine the feasibility of establishing a flat fee structure for routine licensing matters relating to uranium recovery.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-86</report>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-86</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
