<bill session="118" type="h" number="1530" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-20T14:32:10-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-20T14:32:10-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Benefits Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the requirement to publish disability benefit questionnaire forms of Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001220" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2023-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2023-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. H. Rept. 118-199.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-09-14" calendar="Union" number="162">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 162.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18T16:24:02-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bost moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18T16:24:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4358-4361" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18T16:24:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1530.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-18T16:37:01-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bost objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20T14:20:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4426-4427" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="401" datetime="2023-09-20T14:32:10-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 401).</text>
      <reference ref="9/18/2023 CR H4358-4359" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-09-20T14:32:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Discharged, Markup, Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1329" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2513" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-02T16:51:54Z" status="Passed House">Veterans Benefits Improvement Act of 2023

This bill addresses certain requirements related to Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical disability examinations for purposes of benefit claims and other administrative matters related to the benefit claims processes and personnel.

First, the bill updates procedures related to the publishing of VA disability benefit questionnaire forms. Specifically, the VA does not have to publish certain forms if it determines the form could not reasonably be completed to a clinically acceptable standard by someone who is not an employee or contractor of the VA.

The bill also requires the VA to report on its efforts to provide reimbursement for a veteran's travel to a facility, regardless of whether the facility is inside or outside of the United States, when such travel is incident to a medical disability examination for purposes of VA benefits.

The VA must also include certain elements in contracts it enters with non-VA providers to provide medical disability examinations. Specifically, the contracts must require that every communication from the provider to the applicant regarding the scheduling of a medical disability examination must be transmitted to any person or organization that is legally designated by the applicant and is recognized for the preparation, presentation, and prosecution of claims.

Additionally, the VA must partner with veterans service organizations and other stakeholders (as determined by the VA) to implement an outreach program for veterans regarding (1) contact information for non-VA providers that are providing medical disability examinations, and (2) the requirement for veterans to provide personally identifiable information when contacted by such providers to verify their identity.

The VA must report on improving its support of governmental veterans service officers.

The VA must establish a Board of Veterans' Appeals internship program for individuals enrolled in the first or second year of law school.

The VA must also implement a program to furnish student loan repayment benefits or reimbursements for courses, bar exams, or bar membership dues to certain attorneys who agree to work for the VA for at least 3 years.

The bill increases the maximum possible number of judges presiding over the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims to nine judges.

Finally, the VA must report on improving access to telehearings for Board of Veterans' Appeals hearings.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-199</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
