<bill session="118" type="h" number="5961" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-30T17:00:04-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-11-30T17:00:04-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="short">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To freeze certain Iranian funds involved in the 2023 hostage deal between the United States and Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001309" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000594" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001093" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000307" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2023-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2023-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001218" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001216" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2023-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001224" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001176" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2023-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2023-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Foreign Affairs. H. Rept. 118-270, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Referred sequentially to the House Committee on Financial Services for a period ending not later than Nov. 9, 2023 for consideration of such provisions of the bill and amendment as fall within the jurisdiction of that committee pursuant to clause 1(h) of rule X.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-09">
      <text>Committee on Financial Services discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-11-09" calendar="Union" number="218">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 218.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14T16:28:01-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 869 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5893 and H.R. 5961. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5893, under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5961 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15T11:15:53-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 869 failed passage of House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-28T20:01:28-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 891 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5283, H.R. 5961 and S.J. Res. 32. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5283 and H.R. 5961 under a structured rule and S. J. Res. 32 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on each measure with one motion to recommit on H.R. 5283 and H.R. 5961 and one motion to commit on S. J. Res. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T12:23:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 891.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6000-6015" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6005-6006" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T12:24:00-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5283, H.R. 5961 and S.J. Res. 32. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5283 and H.R. 5961 under a structured rule and S. J. Res. 32 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on each measure with one motion to recommit on H.R. 5283 and H.R. 5961 and one motion to commit on S. J. Res. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T12:24:22-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 891 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T12:24:23-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Julia Letlow to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T12:25:30-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5961.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:23:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fitzpatrick amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:26:38-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Fitzpatrick amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Fitzpatrick demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:27:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cherfilus-McCormick amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:31:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gottheimer amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:38:05-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:43:42-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:48:24-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ogles demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:48:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:55:02-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ogles demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T13:55:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:09:10-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:19:50-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ogles demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:20:25-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pfluger amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:28:36-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pfluger amendment No. 9, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Meeks demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:29:15-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:32:55-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Porter amendment No. 10, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Porter demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:33:20-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:36:50-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 891, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson (IL) amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:43:28-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jackson (IL) amendment No. 12, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jackson (IL) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:44:18-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Self moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:44:35-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T14:44:52-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5961 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T15:57:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6021-6027" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T15:57:32-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T16:52:01-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5961.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T16:52:59-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T16:53:10-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="687" datetime="2023-11-30T17:00:04-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 307 - 119, 1 Present (Roll no. 687).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T17:00:05-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-30T17:13:46-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5961.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="869" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="891" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Qatar"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h824"/>
    <amendment number="h823"/>
    <amendment number="h822"/>
    <amendment number="h821"/>
    <amendment number="h820"/>
    <amendment number="h819"/>
    <amendment number="h818"/>
    <amendment number="h817"/>
    <amendment number="h816"/>
    <amendment number="h815"/>
    <amendment number="h814"/>
    <amendment number="h813"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-12-01T12:59:21Z" status="Reported to House, Part I">No Funds for Iranian Terrorism Act 

This bill requires the President to impose property-blocking sanctions on foreign financial institutions and international financial institutions that process, participate in, or facilitate a transaction involving certain Iranian funds (namely, the approximately $6 billion of Iranian funds that the Biden administration permitted to be transferred from restricted accounts in South Korea to restricted accounts in Qatar to facilitate the release of five U.S. citizens detained in Iran).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-270</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
