<bill session="118" type="s" number="2951" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Butcher Block Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Butcher Block Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program to provide loans and loan guarantees to assist new and expanded meat processors and renderers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2023-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-13T15:02:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Butcher Block Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide loans, loan guarantees, and grants to assist and expand meat processing and rendering.&#160;

USDA must establish a loan and loan guarantee program for individuals and entities for the construction, expansion, modification, refurbishment, or re-equipping of meat processing facilities (with less than 500 employees) and rendering facilities (with less than 200 employees).&#160;

Those eligible for the program include (1) public, private, or cooperative organizations; (2) Indian tribes; and (3) individual farmers, ranchers, or business owners.

The bill generally prohibits the amount of a loan or loan guarantee from exceeding $50 million. However, USDA may provide&#160;a loan or loan guarantee of up to $100 million&#160;to public, private, or cooperative organizations for projects that significantly increase meat processing or rendering in a state or region that has insufficient processing or rendering capacity.

USDA must also make grants to establish or support new, innovative, or expanded meat processing or rendering activities, or other activities that will increase the customer base or revenue returns of livestock and poultry producers. Projects may include identifying and analyzing business opportunities, providing technical assistance and training, and incentivizing innovative or mobile enterprises.&#160;

Those eligible for the grants are (1) governmental entities; (2) public, private, or cooperative organizations; (3) Indian tribes; and (4) institutions of higher education.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
