<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1531</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T23:03:23Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T23:03:23Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-04-01</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2003-04-09T16:30:52Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2003-04-03T14:38:35Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-04-01T15:28:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>H. Rept. 108-67</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Energy Policy Act of 2003</title>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <number>6</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2003-11-21</actionDate>
          <text>Motion by Senator Frist to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the conference report to accompnay H. R. 6 was not invoked (Roll Call Vote No. 456) entered in Senate.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 41.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
        <actionCode>H12410</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <calendarNumber>
          <calendar>U00041</calendar>
        </calendarNumber>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 108-67.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>H12200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-09</actionDate>
        <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 108-67.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>5000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 12.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-03</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-01</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-04-01</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000388</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. McCrery, Jim [R-LA-4]</fullName>
        <firstName>JIM</firstName>
        <lastName>MCCRERY</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>LA</state>
        <district>4</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-04-07T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 1531, Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/14393</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the House Committee on Ways and Means on April 3, 2003&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-04-07T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>H.R. 1531, Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/14393</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the House Committee on Ways and Means on April 3, 2003</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agricultural wastes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative energy sources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Biomass energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Building construction</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Capital investments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coal</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Cogeneration of electric power and heat</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Construction industries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Cooperative societies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Corporation taxes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Depletion allowances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Depreciation and amortization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Diesel motor</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electric power production</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electric power transmission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electric vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employee health benefits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy efficiency</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Excise tax</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fuel cells</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gas pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Heating</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Inland water transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Insurance premiums</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Landfills</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical economics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Methane</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Miners</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minimum tax</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicle pollution control</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Natural gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear reactors</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil well drilling</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Petroleum refineries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prospecting</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Railroads</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Refuse as fuel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Renewable natural resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rent</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Secondary recovery of gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Secondary recovery of oil</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Solar energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sulphur</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax credits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax deductions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wind power</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wood</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-04-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish credits for the following: (1) residential solar energy property; (2) qualified fuel cell power plants; (3) energy efficiency improvements to existing homes; (4) construction of new energy efficient home; (5) combined heat and power system property; (6) production of low sulphur diesel fuel; and (7) producing oil and gas from marginal wells.<p>Repeals: (1) the 4.3-cent per gallon diesel fuel excise taxes on railroads and inland waterway transportation; (2) phaseouts for qualified electric vehicle credit and the deduction for clean fuel-vehicles; and (3) for two years, the alternative minimum tax preference for intangible drilling costs for certain taxpayers and the minimum tax limitation on the oil recovery credit.<p>Treats: (1) natural gas gathering lines as 7-year property; (2) natural gas distribution lines as 15-year property; and (3) electric transmission property treated as 15-year property.<p>Extends and modifies the credits for: (1) electricity produced from renewable resources; (2) producing fuel from a nonconventional source.<p>Provides for: (1) reduced motor fuel excise tax on certain mixtures of diesel fuel; (2) the expensing of capital costs incurred in complying with environmental protection agency sulfur regulations; (3) an increase in the barrel per day small refiner exception to oil depletion deduction; (4) treating of gain ratably over an 8-year period with respect to sales or dispositions to implement Federal energy regulatory commission or State electric restructuring policy; (5) modifications to the special rules for nuclear decommissioning costs; (6) the treatment of certain income of rural electric cooperatives; and (7) amortization, over a 2-year period, of delay rental payments and of geological and geophysical expenditures.<p>Allows: (1) the prepayment of premium liability for coal industry health benefits; (2) generally, for the inapplicability of arbitrage rules to prepayments for natural gas; (3) the suspension, until December 31, 2006, of the limitation based on 65 percent of taxable income and of taxable income limit with respect to marginal production; and (4) certain business related energy credits against the regular and minimum tax.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>17</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-04-09</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to House with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-07-21T20:35:44Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003 - <b>Title I: Conservation</b> - (Sec. 101) Allows a credit of up to $2,000 annually each for qualified photovoltaic property expenditures and qualified solar water heating property expenditures. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Extends the placed-in-service date for wind facilities and closed-loop biomass facilities to facilities placed in service after December 31, 1993 (December 31, 1992, in the case of closed-loop biomass facilities) and before January 1, 2007. Defines three new qualifying facilities: (1) open-loop biomass facilities; (2) landfill gas facilities; and (3) trash combustion facilities. <p>(Sec. 103) Provides a ten-percent credit for the purchase of qualified fuel cell power plants for businesses and individuals. Prohibits the credit from exceeding $500 for each 0.5 kilowatt of capacity. <p>(Sec. 104) Provides a 20-percent nonrefundable credit ($2,000 maximum) for the purchase of qualified energy efficiency improvements to existing homes. <p>(Sec. 105) Provides, for an eligible contractor, for a new energy efficient home credit of up to $2,000 for energy efficient property installed in a qualified new energy efficient home. <p>(Sec. 106) Provides a ten-percent credit for the purchase of combined heat and power property. <p>(Sec. 107) Allows the personal energy credits added by this Act (the residential solar energy property credit, the individual fuel power plant credit, and the energy efficient improvements to existing homes credit) to offset both the regular tax and the alternative minimum tax. <p>(Sec. 108) Repeals the 4.3-cents-per-gallon General Fund excise tax on diesel fuel used in trains and fuels used in barges operating on the designated inland waterways system. <p>(Sec. 109) Provides for tax rate of 19.7 cents per gallon for diesel fuel blended with water into a diesel-water fuel emulsion that is at least 14 percent water. <p>(Sec. 110) Repeals the phaseouts on the credit for qualified electric vehicles and on the deduction for clean fuel vehicles. <p>(Sec. 111) Establishes credits for the purchase of new qualified fuel cell motor vehicles (between $4,000 and $40,000 depending on vehicle weight, with increases for fuel efficiency) and new advanced lean burn technology motor vehicles (between $500 and $3,000, with increases for lifetime fuel savings). <p><b>Title II: Reliability</b> - (Sec. 201) Establishes a statutory seven-year recovery period and a class life of ten years for natural gas gathering lines. <p>(Sec. 202) Establishes a statutory 15-year recovery period and a class life of 20 years for natural gas distribution lines. <p>(Sec. 203) Establishes a statutory 15-year recovery period and a class life of 20 years for certain electric transmission property. <p>(Sec. 204) Permits small business refiners to expense up to 75 percent of the qualified capital costs paid or incurred for the purpose of complying with the Highway Diesel Fuel Sulfur Control Requirements of the Environmental Protection Agency. <p>(Sec. 205) Provides that a small business refiner may claim a limited credit equal to five cents per gallon of low sulfur diesel fuel produced. <p>(Sec. 206) Increases, for independent producers, the current 50,000 barrel-per-day limitation based on actual daily production to 75,000 based on average daily production for the taxable year. <p>(Sec. 207) Permits recognition of gain from a qualifying electric transmission transaction ratably over an eight year period, if the gain is used to purchase exempt utility property. <p>(Sec. 208) Modifies the special rules concerning nuclear decommissioning costs. <p>(Sec. 209) Provides that income received or accrued by a rural electric cooperative from any provision or sale of transmission service or ancillary services if such services are performed on a nondiscriminatory open access basis under an independent transmission provider agreement approved by FERC (other than income received or accrued directly or indirectly from a member of the cooperative), from any nuclear decommissioning transaction, or from any asset exchange or conversion transaction is excluded in determining whether a rural electric cooperative satisfies the 85-percent test for tax exemption. <p>(Sec. 210) Creates an exception to the arbitrage bond rules by excluding from the term &quot;investment-type property&quot; a prepayment under a qualified natural gas contract. <p>(Sec. 211) Permits assigned operator members of a controlled group of corporations to prepay their premium liability to the United Mine Workers of America Combined Fund. <p><b>Title III: Production</b> - Establishes a specified credit for producing oil and gas from marginal wells. <p>(Sec. 302) Suspends the limit on percentage depletion deductions to no more than 65 percent of overall taxable income for years beginning after December 31, 2003, and before January 1, 2007. Extends the suspension of the 100 percent net-income limitation for marginal wells an additional three years. <p>(Sec. 303) Allows any delay rental payment in connection with the development of oil or gas wells within the United States to be allowed as a deduction ratably over two years. <p>(Sec. 304) Allows any geological and geophysical expenses in connection with the development of oil or gas wells within the United States to be allowed as a deduction ratably over two years. <p>(Sec. 305) Permits taxpayers to claim credit for production of certain non-conventional fuels produced at wells placed in service after the date of enactment and before January 1, 2007. Permits production from certain existing wells (any well drilled after December 31, 1979, and before January 1, 1993) to claim a credit through 2006. <p>(Sec. 306) Makes the alternative minimum tax limitation inapplicable to the business energy credits added by this Act. <p>(Sec. 307) Repeals, for two years, the alternative minimum tax preference for intangible drilling or development costs for oil and gas wells for taxpayers other than integrated oil companies. <p>(Sec. 308) Repeals, for two years, the alternative minimum tax limitation on the enhanced oil recovery credit. <p><b>Title IV: Corporate Expatriation</b> - (Sec. 401) Treats as a domestic corporation a foreign incorporated entity treated as an inverted domestic corporation, with respect to inversion transactions completed after March 4, 2003 and before January 1, 2005. <p>(Sec. 402) Expresses the sense of Congress that passage of legislation to fix the underlying problems with our tax laws is essential and should occur as soon as possible, so U.S. corporations will not face the current pressures to engage in inversion transactions.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance energy conservation and to provide for reliability and diversity in the energy supply for the American people, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to House</titleType>
        <title>Energy Tax Policy Act of 2003</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported in House</type>
        <date>2003-04-09T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2003-04-01T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-04-09</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 41.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
