<bill session="117" type="s" number="3745" updated="2022-12-29T22:18:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TAILOR Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TAILOR Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal financial institutions regulatory agencies to take risk profiles and business models of institutions into account when taking regulatory actions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2022-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="766" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-13T12:47:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Taking Account of Institutions with Low Operation Risk Act of 2022 or the TAILOR Act of 2022

This bill addresses the supervision of financial institutions.

The bill requires federal financial regulatory agencies to (1) tailor any regulatory actions so as to limit burdens on the institutions involved,&#160;with consideration of the risk profiles and business models of those institutions; and (2) report to Congress on specific actions taken to do so, as well as on other related issues. The bill's&#160;tailoring requirement applies not only to future regulatory actions but also to regulations adopted within the last seven years.

The bill also reduces certain reporting requirements for banks eligible for the community bank leverage ratio.

Finally, federal banking agencies must report on the modernization of bank supervision, including examiner workforce and training and statutory changes necessary to achieve more effective supervision.</summary>
</bill>
