<bill session="116" type="h" number="3357" updated="2022-11-01T13:51:01Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Merit Systems Protection Board Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize and modify the authority of the Merit Systems Protection Board, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Merit Systems Protection Board Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000597" joined="2019-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-08T18:48:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Merit Systems Protection Board Reauthorization Act of 2019

This bill reauthorizes the Merit Systems Protection Board through FY2024 and modifies its authority.

Specifically, the bill requires the board to establish and collect a filing fee to be paid by any individual filing a claim or appeal. The bill requires the board to make a decision in a matter after receiving the written representations of the parties and after an opportunity for a hearing, and the bill authorizes the board to grant a motion for summary judgment. With respect to an appeal from a performance or conduct-based adverse action, the bill prohibits the board from mitigating the personnel action unless it is so disproportionate as to be without justification. Further, the bill requires that all decisions of the agency be supported by substantial evidence.

In addition, the bill limits furlough appeals and provides for the reappointment of board members (currently, board members may not be reappointed).

The bill also makes the board the arbiter of appeals involving the removal, demotion, or suspension of an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</summary>
</bill>
