<bill session="118" type="h" number="636" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forest Litigation Reform Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Litigation Reform Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an arbitration process pilot program as an alternative dispute resolution process for certain objections or protests to qualified forest management activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000103"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-17T14:00:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Forest Litigation Reform Act of 2023

This bill sets forth provisions regarding legal challenges to federal forest management activities on land suitable for timber production.

The bill revises the standard of review for a court considering a request for injunctive relief applicable to an agency's qualified forest management activity. Specifically, a court must balance the impact to the ecosystem of undertaking the agency action against not undertaking the agency action.

The bill also limits the length of preliminary injunctive relief and stays pending appeal in such cases to 60 days.

Additionally, the bill directs the Department of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands, and the Department of the Interior, with respect to public lands, to each establish a discretionary arbitration pilot program as an alternative dispute resolution process for challenges to qualified forest management activities.

The bill prohibits amounts from being obligated or expended from the Claims and Judgment Fund and awards to pay any fees or other expenses to any plaintiff related to an action challenging a qualified forest management activity.</summary>
</bill>
