<bill session="118" type="s" number="782" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FREE American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FREE American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Furthering Resource Exploration and Empowering American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require applicable Federal agencies to take action on applications for Federal energy authorizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-20T13:48:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Furthering Resource Exploration and Empowering American Energy Act or the FREE American Energy Act

This bill expedites the review of energy projects, limits executive power over certain energy projects, delegates certain energy permitting authority to states, provides statutory authority for specified environmental rules, and terminates tax credits for certain vehicles.

Specifically, the bill establishes deadlines by which applicable federal agencies must approve or deny permits or other authorizations for certain natural gas, oil, alternative energy (e.g., solar), oil or gas pipelines, liquefied natural gas terminals, or hydropower projects.

In addition, the bill limits executive power by (1) exempting certain projects related to oil pipelines, natural gas pipelines, or electric transmission facilities from permits required under any executive orders; and (2) rescinding Executive Order 13990, which is about protecting public health and the environment and addressing climate change.

Further, the Office of Management and Budget must initiate a rule making that establishes a process to delegate the authority to approve or deny certain oil or gas projects on federal land to states that contain the federal land.

The bill also provides statutory authority for rules issued in 2020 and titled (1) Update to the Regulations Implementing the Procedural Provisions of the National Environmental Policy Act; and (2) The Navigable Waters Protection Rule: Definition of "Waters of the United States."

Finally, the bill terminates a tax credit for certain clean vehicles placed in service after 2024 (currently 2032).</summary>
</bill>
