<bill session="118" type="s" number="684" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">This Land Is Our Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">This Land Is Our Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the acquisition and ownership of agricultural land by certain foreign entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-28T20:11:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This Land Is Our Land Act

This bill prohibits certain entities related to China or the Chinese government from acquiring, leasing, or owning any interest in U.S. agricultural land.

Specifically, this prohibition applies to certain foreign individuals and entities with connections to China, including (1) a business incorporated in China; (2) a person, company, university, or organization that can legally enter into contracts, own properties, or pay taxes on behalf of the Chinese government; and (3) an individual or organization affiliated with the Chinese Communist Party.

An entity must divest itself from any ownership or leased interest in U.S. agricultural land within two years of the bill's enactment. Further, within one year of enactment, an entity must sign a letter of intent to divest its interests in the land.

Under the bill, U.S. agricultural land includes land in a U.S. state or territory that is used for (1) food processing; or (2) farming, ranching, or timber production, including currently idle land that was used within the previous five years for one of these purposes.

The bill establishes civil and criminal penalties for violations and provides for property forfeiture and sale by public auction.

The Department of Agriculture must establish an office to monitor compliance and impose civil fines.

 Finally, the bill nullifies any noncompete agreement between a covered foreign entity with an ownership or leased interest in U.S. agricultural land and an employee of the entity.</summary>
</bill>
