<bill session="116" type="s" number="4369" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:33Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect clean air and public health by expanding fenceline and ambient air monitoring and access to air quality information for communities affected by air pollution; to require immediate toxic air monitoring at the fenceline of facilities with pollution linked to local health threats; to ensure the Environmental Protection Agency promulgates rules that require fenceline air monitoring in communities with air polluting industrial source categories; to expand and strengthen the national ambient air quality monitoring network; to deploy air sensors in communities affected by air pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7822" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-23T18:56:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2020

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to implement policies, programs, and regulations related to air quality monitoring.

Specifically, the EPA must implement a program using specified methods and technologies to administer or conduct the best available form of fenceline monitoring (i.e., monitoring of ambient air concentration using technology at a site's property line) of specified stationary sources of hazardous air pollutants. The stationary sources to be monitored must include the 25 high-priority facilities named in the EPA Inspector General report (#20-N-0128) from March 31, 2020, and at least another 25 major sources or synthetic area sources.

Among other requirements, the EPA must also

 determine whether whether to add fenceline monitoring for any additional stationary sources, complete an evaluation and promulgate a determination on whether any existing emission factors must be updated to better reflect or account for the results of fenceline monitoring data collected under the established program, promulgate regulations establishing emission standards for specified source categories, require an additional 80 National Core multi-pollutant monitoring stations, and deploy at least 1,000 air quality sensors to monitor specified pollutants in census tracts or counties with per capita death rates from COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) that are at least 10% higher than the national average. Finally, the Department of Health and Human Services and the EPA must carry out a Centers of Excellence on Environmental Health Disparities Research grant program to establish and support at least 10 research centers.</summary>
</bill>
