<bill session="117" type="h" number="3634" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:29Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Taiwan Diplomatic Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To seek negotiations to rename the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States, to make the Director of the American Institute in Taiwan a position requiring Senate confirmation, to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide nonimmigrant status for diplomats from Taiwan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taiwan Diplomatic Review Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-08T16:20:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Taiwan Diplomatic Review Act

This bill addresses issues concerning diplomatic relations with Taiwan.

The bill directs the Department of State to seek to enter into negotiations with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office (TECRO) in the United States to rename its office in the District of Columbia as the Taiwan Representative Office in the United States. (The U.S.-Taiwan relationship is unofficial, and TECRO is Taiwan's principal representative in the United States.)

In addition, the bill establishes a W nonimmigrant visa for aliens affiliated with Taiwan's diplomatic operations, including (1) an ambassador, public minister, or career diplomatic or consular officer accredited by Taiwan and accepted by the United States; (2) a designated principal representative of Taiwan to an international organization; and (3) the immediate family members of such individuals. Specified holders of a W visa shall be entitled to certain immunities afforded to holders of diplomatic visas.

The bill also requires the President to appoint the Director of the American Institute in Taiwan with the advice and consent of the Senate. (After the U.S.-Taiwan relationship became unofficial, the United States conducted relations with Taiwan through the American Institute in Taiwan. The institute's office in Taipei performs many of the same functions as an embassy.)</summary>
</bill>
