<bill session="119" type="h" number="1318" updated="2025-08-08T20:26:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-24T14:51:30-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-24T14:51:30-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Research Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States Research Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short">United States Research Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">United States Research Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act to clarify the definition of foreign country for purposes of malign foreign talent recruitment restriction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2025-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24T14:37:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Babin moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24T14:37:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1201-1202" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24T14:37:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1318.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-03-24T14:51:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1201" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24T14:51:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-19T19:51:10Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Research Protection Act

This bill clarifies the definition of a&#160;malign foreign talent recruitment program under the Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act.&#160;

The Research and Development, Competition, and Innovation Act, which was included in the CHIPS and Science Act, prohibits researchers who receive federal funds from participating in malign foreign talent recruitment programs, in which foreign countries incentivize or compensate researchers for activities that present a conflict&#160;of&#160;interest for the researcher or that are otherwise unauthorized (e.g., sharing proprietary information without proper authorization).

The bill clarifies that these restrictions apply to programs that are sponsored by a foreign country of concern, including China, Iran, North Korea, and Russia. The bill also clarifies that malign foreign talent recruitment programs may involve direct or indirect compensation or incentives from such&#160;countries.</summary>
</bill>
