<bill session="109" type="h" number="4618" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Compliance, Examinations, and Inspections Restructuring Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish rules and procedures for the delegation of compliance and inspections authority to the operating divisions of the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compliance, Examinations, and Inspections Restructuring Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000243" joined="2005-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2006-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-27T19:17:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Compliance, Examinations, and Inspections Restructuring Act of 2005 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to vest the inspections and examinations authority of the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) in those administrative divisions or offices to which the SEC has delegated its administrative responsibilities.



Requires the subject of an SEC inquiry or inspection to be notified in writing at least every 120 days regarding the status of an ongoing proceeding.

Requires an SEC administrative division or office to obtain permission to conduct a sweep examination in the same manner and subject to the same procedures as SEC enforcement divisions or offices must follow in conducting a formal investigation or inquiry of registered entities.



Instructs the Chairman of the SEC to appoint an Ombudsman with respect to any problems resulting from SEC regulatory activities.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the SEC should develop and publish guidelines setting forth explicitly the benefit to either an issuer of securities or a registered entity if it self-reports an apparent violation of law, and subsequently becomes the respondent in an SEC civil injunctive action or administrative proceeding regarding the matter that was self-reported.</summary>
</bill>
