<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2031" updated="2022-02-25T17:32:55Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1904" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-10-30">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-10-30"/>
  <description>To provide the Secretary of Agriculture with the authority to borrow funds from the Treasury to pay for firefighting costs that exceed funds available and to provide funding to conduct hazardous fuels reduction and burned area restoration projects on non-Federal lands in and around communities.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Amendment SA 2031 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to amendment SA 2031 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 60. Record Vote Number: 421.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Point of order raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 2031.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Amendment SA 2031 proposed by Senator Bingaman. (consideration: CR S13601-13605; text: CR S13601) To provide the Secretary of Agriculture with the authority to borrow funds from the Treasury to pay for firefighting costs that exceed funds available and to provide funding to conduct hazardous fuels reduction and burned area restoration projects on non-Federal lands in and around communities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to amendment SA 2031 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 60. Record Vote Number: 421.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2031 proposed by Senator Bingaman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13601-13605" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S13601" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
