<bill session="117" type="h" number="6420" updated="2022-12-30T03:49:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sex Trafficking Demand Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sex Trafficking Demand Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 relating to determinations with respect to efforts of foreign countries to reduce demand for commercial sex acts under the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000812"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2022-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2022-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-27T19:04:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Sex Trafficking Demand Reduction Act

This bill expands requirements&#160;for fighting human trafficking that apply to foreign countries receiving U.S. foreign assistance. (The President is authorized to reduce assistance to, or take other actions against, countries that fail to meet such requirements&#160;and&#160;are not making significant efforts to do so.)

The Department of State, when evaluating whether a country has met such requirements, shall assess whether&#160;the country has made serious efforts to prohibit the purchase of commercial sex acts if the government has authority to do so, whereas currently the State Department must assess whether a country has made serious efforts to reduce such activities. The State Department shall also assess whether a country has made serious efforts to (1) educate buyers of commercial sex acts on how traffickers exploit prostituted persons, and (2) ensure that anti-trafficking training and provisions are incorporated into codes of conduct for government staff.</summary>
</bill>
