<bill session="108" type="h" number="3798" updated="2023-01-15T09:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Secure Existing Aviation Loopholes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to improve aviation security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Existing Aviation Loopholes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001146" joined="2004-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2004-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2004-04-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E178-179"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft construction"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear security measures"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surface-to-air missiles"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-09T21:44:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure Existing Aviation Loopholes Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) establish a system and plan to screen or inspect all cargo to be transported in passenger aircraft operated by an air carrier or foreign air carrier in air transportation or intrastate air transportation; (2) monitor and evaluate research and development (R&amp;D) of effective cargo screening; and (3) impose a cargo security fee to be collected by the air carrier or foreign air carrier that provides the air transportation.

Amends Federal transportation law to authorize the Under Secretary of Transportation for Security to provide for the deployment of Federal air marshals on: (1) any passenger flight of an air carrier in charter air transportation for which the Under Secretary determines such deployment is in the interest of aviation security; (2) every passenger flight of foreign air carriers in air transportation; and (3) flights of all-cargo air transportation. (Currently, the deployment of Federal air marshals may be provided on every passenger flight of air carriers in air transportation or intrastate air transportation). Prohibits the flight of a foreign air carrier from landing in or taking off from a U.S. airport unless it has on board a Federal marshal or an equivalent officer of the government of the foreign country if the Secretary of Homeland Security requests the presence of a Federal marshal or officer on such flight.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) require all flight crews of air carriers to have improved communication systems for providing flight attendants with a wireless method of communicating with pilots that meet certain standards; (2) develop a plan to improve coordination between the Department of Homeland Security and counterpart agencies and departments of foreign governments in the area of aviation security; (3) issue regulations to improve preflight screening of passenger aircraft for dangerous objects and training of screeners of passenger aircraft and to reduce the time between preflight screening and the departure time for a flight; (4) issue a rule setting forth certain training requirements for flight attendants; (5) issue regulations to improve control over access to the secured area of U.S. airports; (6) issue regulations requiring air carriers to provide pilots with certain training, including aircraft maneuvers to respond to attacks on the aircraft; (7) issue an order requiring cargo aircraft engaged in cargo transportation or intrastate air transportation to have a door between the cargo and pilot compartments that can be locked and cannot be forced open from the cargo compartment, prohibiting access to the flight deck of the cargo aircraft, except by authorized persons, and requiring flight deck doors to remain locked while in flight, except to permit access by authorized persons; (8) issue an order to modify certain aviation security requirements to ensure that the wall surrounding the flight deck door on any passenger aircraft engaged in air transportation or intrastate air transportation is sufficient to secure the cockpit; (9) establish during a high threat level no fly zones around sensitive nuclear facilities, certain chemical facilities, and any other facilities designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security; and (10) require airport operators that serve general aviation aircraft and landing facilities for such aircraft to complete vulnerability assessments for evaluation of the security at such airports and facilities, including a plan for addressing any vulnerabilities.

Subjects airport workers: (1) employed in, or applying for, positions as aircraft maintenance and catering personnel, aircraft cargo handlers, and aircraft support facilities personnel whether having escorted or unescorted access to aircraft or secured areas of airports to a social security check and a check against all terrorist watch lists in addition to other required background checks; and (2) to physical screening for metallic objects and having their personal bags inspected for prohibited items such as chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear materials.</summary>
</bill>
