<bill session="112" type="h" number="3740" updated="2019-11-15T20:46:31Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers Disaster Assistance Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Farmers Disaster Assistance Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide supplemental emergency disaster assistance to agricultural producers for certain crop losses during the 2011 crop year, to eliminate limitations on certain waivers for borrowers eligible for direct farm operating loans, and to suspend the limitation on the period for which borrowers are eligible for guaranteed farm operating loans, for farming or ranching operations in counties subject to a disaster declaration issued in 2011.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000369" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000207" joined="2011-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-03T13:21:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Farmers Disaster Assistance Act of 2011 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to make supplemental payments to agricultural producers receiving direct payments for covered commodities, direct payments for peanuts, or average crop revenue election (ACRE) payments in disaster counties that had qualifying losses for the 2011 crop year.

Sets forth related insurance requirements.

Directs the Secretary to provide grants to qualifying states through September 30, 2012, to assist specialty crop producers for losses due to excessive rainfall and related conditions affecting the 2011 crops.

Eliminates numerical and durational limitations on operating loan waivers for a farm or a ranch in a county which in 2011: (1) has been substantially affected by a natural disaster, or (2) is included in a presidentially-designated major disaster or emergency area.

Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to suspend through December 31, 2013, the limitation on the period for which borrowers are eligible for guaranteed farm operating loans in a county which in 2011: (1) has been substantially affected by a natural disaster, or (2) is included in a presidentially-designated major disaster or emergency area.</summary>
</bill>
