<bill session="116" type="s" number="2092" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Needs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Needs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to modernize the funding of wildlife conservation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2019-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="877" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1865" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3051" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-22T16:49:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Modernizing the Pittman-Robertson Fund for Tomorrow's Needs Act

This bill revises provisions of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act relating to the funding of wildlife conservation. Specifically, the bill

 adds new definitions, including a definition of hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment; apportions to states revenues from taxes on pistols, revolvers, bows, and arrows at a rate not greater than 3% and not less than 1% of such revenues; removes the existing prohibition on public relations to allow spending by states for management of wildlife areas and promotion of hunting and recreational shooting; allows the use of grant funds for the enhancement of hunter recruitment and recreational shooter recruitment; and expands the Multistate Conservation Grant program by providing $5 million exclusively for making hunter and recreational shooter recruitment project grants that promote a national hunting and shooting sport recruitment program, including related communication and outreach activities. The Fish and Wildlife Service shall review and evaluate the effects of funds used for hunter and recreational shooter recruitment on funds available for wildlife conservation.</summary>
</bill>
