<bill session="119" type="h" number="981" updated="2025-04-29T15:14:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-09T20:21:15-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-09T20:21:15-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education Transparency and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VETT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Veterans Education Transparency and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VETT Act</title>
    <title type="short">Veterans Education Transparency and Training Act</title>
    <title type="short">VETT Act</title>
    <title type="display">VETT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the processes to approve programs of education for purposes of the educational assistance programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000135"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07T16:10:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bost moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07T16:10:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1430-4132: 3" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07T16:10:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 981.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-07T16:17:16-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Bost objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09T20:20:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1553: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-04-09T20:21:15-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="4/7/2025 CR H1431" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-04-09T20:21:23-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-07T15:13:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Education Transparency and Training Act or the VETT Act

This bill modifies the approval process for certain courses of education for purposes of Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) educational assistance benefits.

Under current law, educational institutions must provide a personalized form to an individual with certain information (e.g., cost, financial aid, and graduation and job placement rates) prior to enrollment in a course, otherwise such institutions may be subject to certain disciplinary action from the VA or state approving agency. The bill provides that if an educational institution cannot provide the required personalized form to an individual prior to enrollment, the institution must provide notice that specifies which information in the form may be inaccurate or incomplete and the best estimate available for such information.

The bill requires the VA to establish and regularly update a website to serve as a central location for information about training for school certifying officials regarding VA educational benefits.</summary>
</bill>
