<bill session="109" type="s" number="1312" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reducing Conflicts of Interests in the Representation of Indian Tribes Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Reducing Conflicts of Interests in the Representation of Indian Tribes Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Conflicts of Interests in the Representation of Indian Tribes Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend a provision relating to employees of the United States assigned to, or employed by, and Indian tribe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2005-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7429"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7429" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator McCain without amendment. With written report No. 109-208.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-12-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="329">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-12-16">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2005-12-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17T18:23:17-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2687"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-01-13T17:22:03Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Reducing Conflicts of Interests in the Representation of Indian Tribes Act of 2005 - Amends the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act with respect to certain additional employment rights (exemption from conflict-of-interest prohibitions) of U.S. officers and employees assigned to an Indian tribe, or former U.S. officers and employees employed by Indian tribes, to act as agents or attorneys for or appear on behalf of such tribes in connection with any matter pending before any department, agency, court, or commission.

Limits these additional employment rights of a former U.S. officer or employee employed by an Indian tribe to any former U.S. officer or employee who is a tribal employee or an elected or appointed official of an Indian tribe carrying out an official duty.

Defines tribal employee as an individual acting under the day-to-day control or supervision of the Indian tribal government, unaffected by the control or supervision of any independent contractor, agency or organization, or intervening sovereignty.

Repeals the specific authority of such current or former U.S. officers or employees to act as agents or attorneys for or to appear on behalf of such tribes in connection with any matter pending before any department, agency, court, or commission. Authorizes such individuals, however, to communicate with and appear before any such department, agency, court, or commission on behalf of the Indian tribe on any matter (including, as currently, any matter in which the United States is a party or has direct and substantial interest).

Revises requirements for notification by a former U.S. officer or employee of any personal and substantial involvement the individual may have had as a U.S. officer or employee with respect to the pending matter.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-208</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
