<bill session="117" type="s" number="1185" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 and title 5, United States Code, to permit leave to care for a domestic partner, parent-in-law, or adult child, or another related individual, who has a serious health condition, and to allow employees to take, as additional leave, parental involvement and family wellness leave to participate in or attend their children's and grandchildren's educational and extracurricular activities or meet family care needs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1988-1990" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2589" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-03T10:40:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Family Medical Leave Modernization Act

This bill expands who is permitted to take qualifying family and medical leave and provides additional leave for parents and family caregivers.

The bill grants leave to private sector and federal employees to care for a domestic partner and any individual whose close association with such employees is like a family relationship, regardless of biological or legal relationship, if (1) such individual has a serious health condition, or (2) there is a qualifying exigency due to such employees' active duty in the Armed Forces.

The bill entitles an employee who is a domestic partner, next of kin of a member of the Armed Forces, or any individual whose close association is like a family relationship, regardless of biological or legal relationship, to take leave to care for the service member.

The bill entitles private&#160;sector and&#160;federal employees to take additional leave to participate in or attend their children's and grandchildren's school or community organization activities, meet routine family medical care needs, or care for their elderly relatives.</summary>
</bill>
