<bill session="117" type="s" number="2283" updated="2022-12-31T05:25:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the Veterans Crisis Line of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REACH for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REACH for Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Revising and Expediting Actions for the Crisis Hotline for Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2021-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2021-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2021-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2021-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5073" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-29T11:37:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Revising and Expediting Actions for the Crisis Hotline for Veterans Act or the REACH for Veterans Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to update training and procedures for call responders of the Veterans Crisis Line.

Specifically, the VA must enter into an agreement with an outside organization to review the training for crisis line call responders. The VA must update the training if any deficiencies are identified after the review.

Among other requirements, the VA must

 develop guidelines on retraining and quality management for when a call responder has an adverse event or needs improvement, annually perform a common cause analysis for identified callers to the crisis line who died by suicide in situations where the crisis line was the last point of contact, develop enhanced guidance and procedures to respond to calls to the crisis line related to substance use and overdose risk, review the current emergency dispatch standard operating procedure of the crisis line, and solicit feedback from veterans service organizations on how to conduct outreach regarding the move to 988 as the new suicide and mental health crisis hotline. Each call responder must be subject to at least two calls per month that are silently monitored by a supervisor to check for quality of conduct.

The Veterans Crisis Line, Office of Mental Health and Suicide Prevention of the VA, and National Center for Patient Safety of the VA must establish quality management processes and expectations for staff of the crisis line.</summary>
</bill>
