<bill session="108" type="s" number="1324" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:41Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Agricultural Products Market Access Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to establish procedures for identifying countries that deny market access for agricultural products of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Agricultural Products Market Access Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2003-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2003-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8442-8443"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8443-8444" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2579" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-26T16:06:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">United States Agricultural Products Market Access Act of 2003 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to direct the United States Trade Representative (USTR) to identify those foreign countries that: (1) deny fair and equitable market access to U.S. agricultural products or apply standards for the importation of U.S. agricultural products that are not related to public health concerns or cannot be substantiated by reliable analytical methods; and (2) are determined by the USTR to be priority foreign countries. Limits the identification of priority foreign countries to those that engage in the most onerous or egregious acts which have the greatest adverse impact on the relevant U.S. products. Provides that if available information indicates that such action is appropriate, the USTR may at any time: (1) revoke the identification of any foreign country as a priority foreign country; or (2) identify any foreign country as a priority foreign country. Provides funding for additional staff for the Office of the Assistant U.S. Trade Representative for Agricultural Affairs and Office of the Assistant U.S. Trade Representative for Monitoring and Enforcement. Requires the U.S. Trade Representative to initiate an investigation (without waiting for a petition by an interested person) regarding any act, policy, or practice of a priority foreign country identified under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
