<bill session="117" type="h" number="5559" updated="2023-01-01T23:51:06Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a website for Federal Government apps, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">APP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing and Promoting Programming Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">APP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2021-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2021-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-06T14:59:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing and Promoting Programming or the APP Act

This bill establishes a centralized website to provide information regarding sources of federal funding for the creation of apps (software applications that enable the performance of specific tasks that may be run on a computer, mobile device, or any other electronic device). The website must also allow the public to download publicly available federal government apps.

Specifically, the bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish a publicly available website that includes a database of federal funding opportunities for the creation of apps, options for rating and reviewing apps, tools for app developers, and resources related to education and training in computer science.

The GSA shall review any app for which an update has not been released in more than two years and shall remove any app from the website that is no longer functional or compatible.</summary>
</bill>
