<bill session="117" type="s" number="5261" updated="2023-09-14T15:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Continued Presence Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continued Presence Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect certain victims of human trafficking by expanding the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to grant such aliens continued presence in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-14T14:46:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continued Presence Improvement Act

This bill expands immigration-related protections for non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) who are victims of human trafficking.

Currently, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may permit such an individual to remain in the United States for a certain period of time if (1) the individual may be a potential witness to the trafficking, and (2) a federal law enforcement agency has applied to DHS for such permission on the individual's behalf. Under this bill, DHS may grant such relief even if the individual is not a potential witness. Furthermore, the bill expands the types of agencies that may apply for permission on the individual's behalf to include agencies such as local law enforcement and other authorities that have responsibility for investigating or prosecuting human trafficking.

The bill also limits the enforcement of immigration laws against an individual who has received permission from DHS to remain in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
