<bill session="118" type="s" number="2897" updated="2025-11-19T03:11:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Give Kids a Chance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Give Kids a Chance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to molecularly targeted pediatric cancer investigations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2024-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2024-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3433" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-09T18:31:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Give Kids a Chance Act of 2023

This bill authorizes certain targeted clinical trials involving combinations of drugs to treat pediatric cancer.

Specifically, the bill modifies requirements relating to molecularly targeted pediatric cancer investigations so as to authorize investigations of new drugs that are used in combination with active ingredients that have already been approved and that (1) have been determined to be the standard of care for treating a pediatric cancer, or (2) have been approved to treat an adult cancer and are directed at molecular targets for pediatric cancer.

The Food and Drug Administration must issue guidance and report on the bill's implementation. The Government Accountability Office must report on the effectiveness of the bill's changes with respect to the development of pediatric cancer drugs.</summary>
</bill>
