<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1024" updated="2022-02-03T05:38:22Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2830" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-04-24T11:56:42-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000553"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-04-24"/>
  <description>Amendment amended section 720 of the substitute (regarding waterside security around liquified natural gas tankers and terminals) to state that the Coast Guard may consider security assets and personnel provided by state and local officials contracted or otherwise made available to an LNG terminal operator in determining whether security resources are available to carry out necessary waterside security measures.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part B of House Report 110-604 to amend section 720 of the substitute (regarding waterside security around liquified natural gas tankers and terminals) to state that the Coast Guard may consider security assets and personnel provided by state and local officials contracted or otherwise made available to an LNG terminal operator in determining whether security resources are available to carry out necessary waterside security measures.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-04-24T11:56:42-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the LaTourette amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24T11:48:10-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. LaTourette.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2714-2715" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2714" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24T11:48:10-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. LaTourette.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2714-2715" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2714" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24T11:56:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24T11:56:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the LaTourette amendment (A002) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-24">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
