<bill session="110" type="s" number="3570" updated="2020-02-10T17:02:40Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Coordinating Council Act</title>
    <title type="display">Public Health Coordinating Council Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Public Health Coordinating Council to assess the impact of Federal health-related socio-economic and environmental policies across Federal agencies to improve the public's health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9423"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Public health administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-12-05T20:06:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Coordinating Council Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a National Public Health Coordinating Council to: (1) facilitate and strengthen sustained communication and coordination across federal agencies and offices regarding public health; and (2) review and make recommendations concerning socioeconomic and environmental policies to reduce health disparities and improve the public's health.

Requires the Secretary to determine the duties of the Council, which shall include: (1) reviewing existing federal health programs and policies for the availability of equitable public health services across communities; (2) making recommendations for the modification of such federal programs and policies to improve public health; and (3) seeking to strengthen the impact of federal public health efforts by improving interagency collaboration and promoting a dialogue on broad public health issues.</summary>
</bill>
