<bill session="119" type="h" number="872" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-03T16:02:45-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-03T16:02:45-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require covered contractors implement a vulnerability disclosure policy consistent with NIST guidelines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2025-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03T15:51:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Comer moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03T15:51:10-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H930-932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03T15:51:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 872.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-03-03T16:02:45-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H930-931" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03T16:02:48-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-03T22:07:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Contractor Cybersecurity Vulnerability Reduction Act of 2025

This bill requires revisions to acquisition regulations&#160;related to information systems vulnerabilities&#160;for certain federal contractors. The revisions apply to contractors whose contract is at or above the simplified acquisition threshold ($250,000 in most cases) or that use, operate, manage, or maintain a federal information system on behalf of an agency.&#160;

Under the bill, the Office of Management and Budget must review the Federal Acquisition Regulation (FAR) and recommend updated contract requirements and language for contractor vulnerability disclosure programs. (Such programs establish processes for identifying, reporting, and mitigating information system vulnerabilities discovered by security researchers, software developers, and others.) The recommendations must include requirements to ensure that such contractors implement vulnerability disclosure policies consistent with guidelines from the National Institute of Standards and Technology. The Federal Acquisition Regulation Council must review these recommendations and update the FAR as necessary to incorporate requirements for such contractors to receive information about potential security vulnerabilities in contractor information systems used in performance of contract.

The Department of Defense (DOD) must conduct a similar review and update of regulations with respect to the DOD Supplement to the FAR.</summary>
</bill>
