<bill session="118" type="s" number="927" updated="2025-11-19T03:52:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Continued Rapid Ohia Death Response Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continued Rapid Ohia Death Response Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to partner and collaborate with the Secretary of Agriculture and the State of Hawaii to address Rapid Ohia Death, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1726" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-16T17:12:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continued Rapid Ohia Death Response Act of 2023

This bill establishes requirements to research and control the fungus Ceratocystis, known as Rapid Ohia Death, which has killed more than a million native trees in Hawaii.

 Specifically, the Department of the Interior must partner with the Department of Agriculture and Hawaii to control and address the fungus.

In addition, the U.S. Geological Survey must continue to research Rapid Ohia Death vectors and transmission.

 The U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service must continue to partner with Hawaii and local stakeholders to manage ungulates (e.g., certain mammals such as deer) in Rapid Ohia Death control areas on federal, state, and private land.

Finally, the Forest Service must continue to provide (1) financial assistance to prevent the spread of the fungus and to restore the native forests of Hawaii, and (2) staff and necessary infrastructure funding to the Institute of Pacific Islands Forestry to research the fungus.</summary>
</bill>
