<bill session="116" type="h" number="7687" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Firefighters from PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect firefighters from exposure to per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, to establish a presumption of service connection for certain veterans exposed to such substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Firefighters from PFAS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2020-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Science, Space, and Technology, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digestive and metabolic diseases"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-08T20:40:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Firefighters from PFAS Act

This bill addresses firefighter and veteran exposure to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS. These substances are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds (e.g., weatherproof clothing).

The bill authorizes the use of pre-disaster hazard mitigation funding for the remediation of PFAS at fire training facilities.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology in the Department of Commerce must commence a study and report on the contents and composition of new and unused personal protective equipment worn by firefighters in relation to PFAS.

For certain conditions associated with exposure to PFAS, the bill provides eligibility for Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) hospital care and medical services to veterans who served on active duty at military installations at which individuals were exposed to PFAS. Service by veterans as reservists or civilian firefighters shall be considered active duty service for eligibility purposes if such service occurred during a period specified by the VA on the applicable military installations. The bill also provides eligibility for VA hospital care and medical services for exposure-related conditions to the family members of such veterans and civilian firefighters.

The bill establishes a presumption of service-connection for specified illnesses or diseases related to PFAS exposure that manifest in veterans (including reservists or veterans serving as civilian firefighters) who served on active duty at a military installation where they were exposed to PFAS. Under a presumption of service-connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.</summary>
</bill>
