<bill session="109" type="s" number="681" updated="2022-02-03T05:27:53Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cord Blood Stem Cell Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="popular">Stem Cell Research bill</title>
    <title type="display">Cord Blood Stem Cell Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a National Cord Blood Stem Cell Bank Network to prepare, store, and distribute human umbilical cord blood stem cells for the treatment of patients and to support peer-reviewed research using such cells.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2005-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2005-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2005-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2005-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2005-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000024" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2005-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3060-3061"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="596" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Blood banks"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-27T19:32:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cord Blood Stem Cell Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA), to enter into contracts with qualified cord blood stem cell banks to assist in establishing and maintaining a National Cord Blood Stem Cell Bank Network to: (1) acquire, tissue-type, test, cryopreserve, and store donated units of human cord blood acquired with the informed consent of the donor; (2) make cord blood units available to transplant centers for stem cell transplantations; and (3) allocate up to 10 percent of the cord blood inventory each year for peer-reviewed research. Requires the Secretary to provide for the establishment of a Board of Directors to administer the Network.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, to establish as part of the Network a National Cord Blood Stem Cell Registry to: (1) operate a system for identifying, acquiring, and distributing donated units of cord blood; (2) provide health care professionals with the ability to search the registry for suitable matches for patients; and (3) maintain a database to document the collection, storage, distribution, and clinical outcomes related to the Network.

Requires the Administrator to report to the Secretary regarding the safety, efficacy, and cost-effectiveness of the clinical, research, and education activities of the Network.

Requires the Board to ensure that: (1) the Network donor banks meet eligibility requirements; and (2) the Network is geographically distributed throughout the United States.</summary>
</bill>
