<bill session="108" type="h" number="3188" updated="2023-01-15T06:48:02Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pesticide Registration Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to provide for the enhanced review of covered pesticide products, to authorize fees for certain pesticide products, and to extend and improve the collection of maintenance fees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pesticide Registration Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2003-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001029" joined="2003-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000712" joined="2003-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000051" joined="2003-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000851" joined="2003-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Rural Development and Research.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1664" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-08T15:31:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Pesticide Registration Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to revise registration and maintenance fee requirements for pesticides. (Fees collected are used to help defray the administrative costs of pesticide regulation.)

 Modifies certain timing requirements as they concern the submission of product-specific data and other regulatory action.

Increases and then decreases the maximum amount of maintenance fees payable by registrants, including small businesses, through FY 2008, with the highest levels of fees occurring during FY 2005 and 2006.

Extends the Environmental Protection Agency's (EPA's) authority to collect maintenance, but not tolerance, fees through FY 2008. (Maintenance fees are assessed on already registered or reregistered pesticides; tolerance fees are assessed on pesticides used on food or animal feed which are subject to more stringent regulatory requirements.)

Directs the Administrator of the EPA to assess and collect covered pesticide registration service fees for applications submitted from FY 2004 onward. (Registration fees would apply to new pesticide applications only.) Provides transitional requirements for pending applications.

Sets forth the Administrator's responsibilities concerning the publication and revision of the schedule of registration service fees, including a mandatory increase by FY 2006.

Permits the waiver or reduction of these fees for minor uses or small businesses. Provides for partial fee refunds when an application is withdrawn or at the Administrator's discretion.

Establishes the Pesticide Registration Fund in the Treasury to collect registration fees. Limits the use of these funds to associated regulatory costs, except for limited earmarks for worker protection and the review of new inert ingredients.

Makes these funds available only to the extent provided in advance through appropriations acts. Prohibits the assessment of registration fees in any year where the amount appropriated for the Office of Pesticide Programs of the EPA is less than the amount appropriated for that Office for FY 2002.

Addresses several issues concerning decision time review periods, including the goal of reducing existing periods, schedule publication requirements, determining their start, and how they are impacted by waiver or reduction requests.

Provides for judicial review if the Administrator fails to make a determination on an application before the expiration of the applicable decision time review period.

Terminates the registration service fee after FY 2010, with a phase out occuring during the final two years.</summary>
</bill>
