<bill session="111" type="h" number="5413" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:07Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001254" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2010-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2010-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4285" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2956" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-08T16:13:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Pechanga Band of Luiseno Mission Indians Water Rights Settlement Act of 2010 - Authorizes, ratifies, and confirms the Pechanga Settlement Agreement.



Ratifies, confirms, and declares valid the Tribal Water Right which shall be held in trust by the United States for the use and benefit of the Band and allottees.

States that the Band shall: (1) have authority to use, allocate, and lease the Tribal Water Right; and (2) enact a Pechanga Water Code.

Authorizes the execution of waivers of claims by the Band and the United States with respect to Santa Margarita River Watershed water rights and with respect subsidence damage to lands within the Reservation.

Directs the Secretary to provide specified funds: (1) to fulfill the Band's obligations under the Recycled Water Infrastructure Agreement and the ESAA Capacity Agreement; (2) for the Storage Pond and the Demineralization and Brine Disposal Project; (3) to fulfill the Band's obligations under the Recycled Water Infrastructure Agreement for the Storage Pond's design and construction; and (4) for Interim Capacity and Permanent Capacity.

 Establishes in the Treasury the Pechanga Settlement Fund.

Repeals this Act and voids any related agreements effective January 1, 2016, if the Secretary does not publish a statement of findings required under this Act by December 31, 2015. Returns any appropriations and unobligated amounts to the general fund of the Treasury.</summary>
</bill>
