<bill session="116" type="s" number="2924" updated="2022-10-28T02:15:18Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bandelier National Park and Preserve Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bandelier National Park and Preserve Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Bandelier National Park and Preserve in the State of New Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-367.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-12T19:55:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bandelier National Park and Preserve Establishment Act

This bill converts the Bandelier National Monument in Sandoval County, New Mexico, into a unit of the National Park System known as the Bandelier National Park and Preserve.

The Department of the Interior shall permit hunting on land in the preserve in the same manner as hunting is managed in the Valles Caldera National Preserve.

Interior shall provide access to traditional cultural and religious sites in the park and preserve by members of Indian tribes for traditional cultural and customary uses.

Interior shall allow an enrolled member of any tribe that is culturally affiliated with the land within the park and preserve or the Valles Caldera National Preserve to collect plants and mineral resources for noncommercial traditional and cultural uses.

Interior shall establish a tribal commission for the park and preserve to provide guidance and recommendations on the development and implementation of management plans for and policies of the park and preserve.

Interior and the Department of Agriculture shall seek to enter into an agreement to adjust the boundary between the Valles Caldera National Preserve and the Santa Fe National Forest to improve management of those areas.</summary>
</bill>
