<bill session="119" type="sj" number="89" updated="2025-11-24T23:02:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to "Buffalo Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan Amendment".</title>
    <title type="display">A joint resolution providing for congressional disapproval under chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, of the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management relating to "Buffalo Field Office Record of Decision and Approved Resource Management Plan Amendment".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2025-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-18">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged, by petition, pursuant to 5 U.S.C. 802(c).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="270">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 270.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-11-19">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 47. Record Vote Number: 621.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-19">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-20">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8395" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hj" number="130" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-19T14:48:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This joint resolution nullifies the rule submitted by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) on November 20, 2024, which amended the 2015 resource management plan (RMP) for the Buffalo Field Office in Wyoming&#160;to make no federal coal available for future leasing. Thus, the joint resolution requires the&#160;BLM to follow the 2015 RMP as it was before it was amended in 2024 and make coal available for leasing.

By way of background, the BLM developed the amendment to the&#160;plan in response to&#160;Western Organization of Resource Councils v. Bureau of Land Management.&#160;In that case, the court held that the BLM must evaluate the climate impacts of federal coal leasing in the Buffalo Field Office and include alternatives to limit or stop coal leasing in the evaluation in order to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act. After conducting the evaluation, the&#160;BLM amended the RMP and made&#160;BLM-managed coal resources in the Buffalo Field Office planning area unavailable for future leasing.</summary>
</bill>
