<bill session="117" type="h" number="5286" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Chinese Corporate Human Rights Abusers List, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protecting Americans from Corporate Human Rights Abusers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans from Corporate Human Rights Abusers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Asia, the Pacific, Central Asia and Nonproliferation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA05" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Indo-Pacific" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-08T15:00:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Americans from Corporate Human Rights Abusers Act

This bill prohibits transactions in the securities of certain Chinese entities.

The Department of State must report to Congress a list identifying entities incorporated in China that have a presence in U.S. capital markets and (1) are responsible for or complicit in gross violations of human rights in China; (2) pose an unusual or extraordinary threat to U.S. national security, foreign policy, or economic interests; or (3) pose an increased financial risk exposure to U.S.-based investors.

A U.S. entity or individual may not purchase or sell the publicly traded securities (or derivatives of such securities) of (1) the entities on the above list; or (2) certain entities that have been designated as Communist Chinese military companies or Chinese military-industrial complex companies.

The bill provides certain exceptions for transactions that are made solely for the purpose of divesting in such securities.

The bill prohibits judicial review of certain actions related to this bill, including a decision by the State Department to list a company as one that is responsible for gross human rights violations in China.</summary>
</bill>
