<bill session="118" type="h" number="2763" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT 911 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT 911 Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Resources and Occupational Training for Emotional Crisis and Trauma in 911 Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to improve the detection, prevention, and treatment of mental health issues among public safety telecommunicators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2024-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2024-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001221" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000474" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2023-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-22T02:57:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Resources and Occupational Training for Emotional Crisis and Trauma in 911 Act or the PROTECT 911 Act

This bill establishes a grant program, and requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop resources, for addressing mental health conditions among public safety telecommunicators. These include 9-1-1 operators and other public safety personnel who are responsible for responding to requests for emergency assistance.

Specifically, HHS must award grants to state, local, and regional emergency communications centers or nonprofits for behavioral health and wellness programs to prevent and mitigate job-related mental health issues among public safety telecommunicators.

Additionally, HHS must develop and disseminate (1) best practices for identifying, preventing, and treating post-traumatic stress disorder among public safety telecommunicators; and (2) resources for educating mental health professionals about the workplace culture of, stressors and challenges experienced by, and therapies for treating mental health issues common to public safety telecommunicators.</summary>
</bill>
