<bill session="118" type="h" number="7804" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Coordination Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Coordination Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Coordination Committee and facilitate the disclosure and reporting of information regarding complaints and investigations related to proprietary institutions of higher education eligible to receive Federal education assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2024-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2024-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3727" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-22T18:33:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Coordination Improvement Act

This bill requires certain actions to increase federal oversight of proprietary (i.e., for-profit) institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Specifically, the bill establishes the Proprietary Education Interagency Oversight Coordination Committee and sets forth its duties and membership.

The bill also directs the Department of Education (ED) to collect and track student complaints regarding the services or activities of any proprietary IHE that is eligible for federal education assistance. Further, ED must publish a warning list for parents and students that is comprised of proprietary IHEs that have engaged in certain activities, including those that have been sued for financial relief or have pending claims for borrower relief discharge.&#160; &#160; &#160; &#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
