<bill session="118" type="s" number="1889" updated="2025-08-30T11:03:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the recognition of certain Alaska Native communities and the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-311.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment. With written report No. 118-221.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="500">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 500.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4748" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T13:27:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act

This bill allows five Alaska Native communities in Southeast Alaska to form urban corporations and receive land entitlements.

Specifically, the bill allows the Alaska Native residents of each of the Alaska Native villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell, Alaska, to organize as Alaska Native urban corporations and to receive certain settlement land.

The bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey specified land to each urban corporation. Further, Interior must convey the subsurface estate for that land to the regional corporation for Southeast Alaska.

The land conveyed to each urban corporation must include any U.S. interest in all roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and appurtenances on or related to the land conveyed to the urban corporation.

The bill also allows each urban corporation to establish a settlement trust to (1) promote the health, education, and welfare of the trust beneficiaries; and (2) preserve the Alaska Native heritage and culture of their communities. The bill also directs Interior to convey certain Bureau of Land Management land to the City of Tenakee Springs, Alaska (upon written request of the city and subject to specified terms and conditions).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-221</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
