<bill session="108" type="s" number="823" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:12Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Innovation Responsiveness Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for the expeditious coverage of new medical technology under the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Innovation Responsiveness Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2003-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001057" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2003-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4972-4973"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="941" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Clinical trials"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Depositions"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health care industry"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospital rates"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medical innovations"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Innovation Responsiveness Act of 2003 - Amends part D (Miscellaneous Provisions) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to: (1) prescribe criteria for the Secretary of Health and Human Services to use in making national coverage determinations; (2) direct the Secretary to establish a Council for Technology and Innovation within the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services to coordinate coverage, coding, and payment processes with respect to new technologies and procedures under Medicare in order to expedite patient access to new technologies and therapies; and (3) revise the Medicare coverage determination appeals process.Directs the Secretary to establish a process that provides for the assignment of inpatient hospital codes for new medical services and related technologies as of April 1 of each year.Requires the Secretary to establish a process for the assignment of Health Care Financing Administration Common Procedure Coding System (HCPCS) Level II codes each calendar quarter for new medical services and technologies.Amends SSA title XI to provide that, if the National Committee on Vital and Health Statistics has not made a recommendation to the Secretary before April 1, 2003, with respect to the adoption of the International Classification of Diseases, 10th Revision, Procedure Coding System (ICD-10-PCS) as a standard for the reporting of inpatient hospital services, the Secretary may adopt ICD-10-PCS as such a standard without receiving such a recommendation.Revises requirements for the use of internal and external data for annual adjustments to the inpatient hospital prospective payment system (PPS) and outpatient hospital PPS.Provides for limitation on use of foreign payer data in determining Medicare payment amounts.Revises requirements for the recognition of the costs of new medical services and technologies under the inpatient hospital PPS.Establishes requirements for any agreement or contract to perform the function of making local coverage determinations.Modifies requirements for the use of carriers for administration of benefits with respect to national inherent reasonableness determinations.</summary>
</bill>
