<bill session="109" type="h" number="4160" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:52Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Recreation Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Army to evaluate, construct, operate, and maintain capital improvements to the Intracoastal Waterway, Delaware River to Chesapeake Bay, Delaware and Maryland (Chesapeake and Delaware Canal) for public recreation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Recreation Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2005-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Intracoastal waterways"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-20T16:09:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Chesapeake and Delaware Canal Recreation Authorization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Army, with the consent of appropriate local and state entities, to enter into arrangements, contracts, and leases with public, private, and nonprofit entities to: (1) evaluate, construct, operate, and maintain capital improvements for recreational use of the Intracoastal Waterway, Delaware River to Chesapeake Bay, Delaware and Maryland (Chesapeake and Delaware Canal) and its related facilities; and (2) provide security for the canal and such facilities. Sets the federal share of the cost of capital improvements at 50% and of operation and maintenance costs at 100%. Directs the Secretary to credit toward the non-federal share of project costs design and construction work carried out by the non-federal interest before the date of an agreement if such work is integral to the project.</summary>
</bill>
