<bill session="108" type="s" number="178" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:10Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Comprehensive Immunosuppressive Drug Coverage for Transplant Patients Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide adequate coverage for immunosuppressive drugs furnished to beneficiaries under the medicare program that have received an organ transplant.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Immunosuppressive Drug Coverage for Transplant Patients Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2003-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1071"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S1071-1072" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2223" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Immunosuppressive drugs"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Comprehensive Immunosuppressive Drug Coverage for Transplant Patients Act of 2003 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as amended by the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Benefits Improvement and Protection Act of 2000, to remove time limitations on the coverage of immunosuppressive drugs for individuals who have received organ transplants. (Current law provides coverage for such drugs only for certain time periods after the transplant procedure.)Amends SSA title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) to: (1) continue entitlement to prescription drugs used in immunosuppressive therapy furnished to an individual who receives a kidney or other organ transplant for which payment is made under Medicare; and (2) extend Medicare secondary payer requirements for end stage renal disease beneficiaries.Amends the Public Health Service Act, the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), and the Internal Revenue Code to set forth requirements for group health plans to provide coverage of immunosuppressive drugs.</summary>
</bill>
