<bill session="117" type="h" number="9094" updated="2022-12-29T12:48:51Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STAAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategies To Address Antimicrobial Resistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance efforts to address antimicrobial resistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2022-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3291" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-16T01:39:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Strategies To Address Antimicrobial Resistance Act or the STAAR Act This bill expands various initiatives to address antimicrobial resistance.

The bill&#160;reestablishes the interagency Antimicrobial Resistance Task Force to coordinate and develop efforts addressing antimicrobial resistance.

The Department of Health and Human Services must&#160;encourage health care facilities to implement antimicrobial stewardship programs to evaluate and improve the use of antimicrobial drugs.

The bill also requires the use of the National Healthcare Safety Network and similar surveillance systems to collect and report data about the usage of antimicrobial drugs, changes in resistance to such drugs, and other trends impacting patient outcomes.

Additionally, the bill increases nationwide efforts to monitor, research, and prevent the spread of infection from resistant organisms by

 establishing the Antimicrobial Resistance Surveillance and Laboratory Network in at least seven geographic regions, maintaining the Clinical Trials Network on Antimicrobial Resistance to conduct clinical research, and requiring collaboration with state and local agencies that support health care facilities that focus on preventing the spread of antibiotic-resistant bacteria.</summary>
</bill>
