<bill session="117" type="h" number="1180" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to clarify when the time period for the issuance of citations under such Act begins and to require a rule to clarify that an employer's duty to make and maintain accurate records of work-related injuries and illnesses is an ongoing obligation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2021-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2876" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-14T15:41:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Accurate Workplace Injury and Illness Records Restoration Act

This bill expands the authority of the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) to cite employers for workplace safety violations and requires OSHA to issue a rule on record keeping related to workplace injuries.

Under current law OSHA may cite employers only during the six-month period following a violation. This bill provides that, for a violation that occurs over a period of time, the six-month period does not begin until the violation has ended.

The bill also requires OSHA to issue a rule on maintaining records of workplace injuries and illnesses. Congress nullified a similar rule on April 3, 2017.

In the rule required by the bill, OSHA must clarify that an employer's duty to make and maintain accurate records

 is an ongoing obligation, continues for as long as the employer is required to keep records of the recordable injury or illness (typically five years under current OSHA rules), and does not expire solely because the employer fails to create the necessary records when first required to do so.</summary>
</bill>
