<bill session="119" type="h" number="344" updated="2025-03-12T08:06:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Anti-Congestion Tax Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Congestion Tax Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To condition the receipt of certain grants by the Metropolitan Transportation Authority on exempting certain drivers from congestion fees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-19T19:00:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Anti-Congestion Tax Act 

This bill prohibits the Department of Transportation (DOT) from awarding capital investment grants to the Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) for projects in New York until DOT certifies that vehicles using certain crossings to enter into Manhattan's congestion tolling zone&#160;receive exemptions from congestion tolls.&#160;The vehicular crossings include the Holland Tunnel, the Lincoln Tunnel, the George Washington Bridge,&#160;and any other crossing immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone.

As background, the&#160;MTA's Central Business District Tolling Program for New York City charges drivers a toll to enter an area in Manhattan designated as the Congestion Relief Zone.&#160;Under the bill, congestion tolling zone generally means any roadways, bridges, tunnels, approaches, or ramps that are located within, or enter to, the Congestion Relief Zone, with some modifications.

Specifically, the bill requires the MTA to credit a vehicle for the vehicular crossing toll from the amount of the congestion toll charged to the vehicle for entering the congestion tolling zone.

Further,&#160;the bill allows drivers entering Manhattan using any of the vehicular&#160;crossings immediately before entry into the congestion tolling zone&#160;to receive a federal tax credit at the end of the year equal to the amount paid in congestion tolls for using the crossing.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
