<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1387</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T06:02:43Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T06:02:43Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-07-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-07-10T22:05:55Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-01-28</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S312)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001056</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cornyn, John [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Cornyn</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000445</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gregg, Judd [R-NH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Judd</firstName>
        <lastName>Gregg</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NH</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-07-15</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Immigration</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Admission of nonimmigrants</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alien labor</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Illegal aliens</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Visas</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Immigration</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-07-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-07-31T14:30:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2003 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to direct the Secretaries of Homeland Security and State to jointly establish a seasonal and nonseasonal guest worker program with an eligible foreign country. Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) alien worker and program eligibility; and (2) employer applications and petitions.</p> <p>Gives permanent resident status adjustment priority to guest workers who have participated in the program for at least three years. (Requires such application to be filed after the worker has returned to his or her home country.) Prohibits status adjustment before such three-year period.</p> <p>Establishes W-1 (seasonal) and W-2 (nonseasonal) nonimmigrant visas for such workers.</p> <p>Amends the Social Security Act to: (1) direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer at least quarterly from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund 100 percent of the guest worker taxes to the Guest Worker Investment Fund for deposit in a guest worker investment account for each guest worker; (2) direct the Secretary of the Guest Worker Investment Fund to create a guest worker investment account for each covered guest worker; (3) establish in the Treasury the Guest Worker Investment Fund; and (4) provide for account distribution after the worker leaves the program and returns to his or her home country.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) adjust the status of certain unlawfully present aliens to nonimmigrant guest worker status (requires adjustment applications to be filed within 12 months of enactment of this Act); and (2) impose additional civil penalties upon employers who knowingly employ unauthorized aliens after such date.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the establishment of guest worker programs, to provide for the adjustment of status of certain aliens unlawfully present in the United States to the status of a non-immigrant guest worker, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Border Security and Immigration Reform Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-07-10T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-01-28</actionDate>
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S312)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
