<bill session="117" type="s" number="1903" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise certain ethylene oxide emissions standards under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise certain ethylene oxide emissions standards under the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3899" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3631" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-12T17:59:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to amend its regulations to revise the standards for the emission of ethylene oxide. Specifically, regulations must be revised based on results from the National Center for Environmental Assessment report titled Evaluation of the Inhalation Carcinogenicity of Ethylene Oxide.

The bill also requires revisions to apply maximum achievable control technology requirements to chamber exhaust vents. Maximum achievable control technology standards are established for sources of hazardous air pollutants to limit or control emissions. Additionally, the revisions must apply to area sources and major sources of ethylene oxide.

The EPA must carry out a residual risk assessment with respect to the revised standards.

Finally, the EPA must notify the public of violations under the revised standards, and failure to do so will result in an investigation to assess the health risks and prevent a future failure of notification.</summary>
</bill>
