<bill session="117" type="h" number="5792" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State and Local Digital Service Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State and Local Digital Service Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of General Services to establish the Digital Service Agreement Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 23 - 13.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-01T19:03:45Z" status="Introduced in House">State and Local Digital Service Act of 2021

This bill directs the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish a Digital Service Agreement Program, under which GSA shall award grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements or memoranda of understanding with, eligible applicants (state, local, and eligible tribal governments) for the purpose of planning, establishing, or supporting a digital service team or supporting digital services collaboration to improve the delivery of government assistance through digital services.

The GSA must (1) minimize the burden on eligible applicants in the development of proposals for a digital service agreement, including by providing technical assistance to applicants in the preparation of applications; (2) require semiannual progress reports from applicants awarded or entering into a digital service agreement; and (3) make publicly available a dashboard of service delivery metrics, performance measures, and progress.</summary>
</bill>
