<bill session="116" type="h" number="6409" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ABLE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Emergency Social Insurance Program in the Social Security Administration and Small Business Administration in order to address the injury concerns of certain small businesses and idle workers disproportionally affected by the COVID-19 crisis.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ABLE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assistance for Businesses and Local Economies Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000172" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2020-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2020-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2020-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2020-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-21T13:23:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Assistance for Businesses and Local Economies Act or the ABLE Act of 2020

This bill establishes the Emergency Social Insurance Program to coordinate and deliver direct payments to small businesses and workers affected by COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the Social Security Administration and the Department of Labor shall assist participating states, through existing state agency mechanisms, to offer expanded unemployment insurance for workers who are unemployed or idle because of COVID-19. Through an agreement with Labor, participating states must provide temporary emergency COVID-19 unemployment or short-time compensation payments to such workers, plus specified additional amounts for certain categories of workers. Such compensation payments shall not be regarded as income. If an individual receives compensation payments through a knowing false statement or misrepresentation, such individual shall be ineligible for further assistance and subject to prosecution.

The Small Business Administration must provide grants to certain small businesses that have suffered substantial economic injury as a result of COVID-19, giving priority consideration to (1) small businesses with fewer than 100 employees per location; (2) small businesses owned by minorities, women, or veterans; (3) small businesses where the owner's pay is equal to or less than 25 times the average employee's pay; and (4) small businesses that have not fired or laid off employees, reduced salaries, or changed any labor contracts. The amount of such grants shall not exceed necessary maintenance costs (e.g., payroll support and increased costs of obtaining unavailable materials), and any overpayment of grants shall be automatically considered as zero-interest loans. Such grant amounts shall be excluded from gross income, for income tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
