<bill session="117" type="h" number="7010" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Relief from Duties Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a temporary waiver of countervailing and antidumping duties relating to fertilizer or fertilizer ingredients if an emergency situation impacts the domestic production or supply of merchandise subject to those duties, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Relief from Duties Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000871"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2022-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2022-03-18" withdrawn="2022-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2022-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000302" joined="2022-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3812" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-14T14:18:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Relief from Duties Act

This bill provides for a temporary waiver of countervailing and antidumping duties relating to fertilizer or fertilizer ingredients in emergency situations.

Specifically, a covered party (e.g., a manufacturer, trade association, or other interested party) may petition the U.S. International Trade Commission (USITC) to waive countervailing or antidumping duties assessed for fertilizer or fertilizer ingredients (or renew such a waiver) in emergency situations that limit the production or supply of fertilizer or fertilizer ingredients.

The bill requires the USITC to (1) allow the public to submit comments on any petition for a waiver or renewal; and (2) issue, within 30 days after the close of the public comment period, a final decision concerning the waiver or renewal. Any waiver or renewal shall be for a period of one year.</summary>
</bill>
