<bill session="118" type="h" number="8633" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Copay Overpay Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Copay Overpay Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense to limit copayments for outpatient visits for mental health or behavioral health under the TRICARE program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2024-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4891" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-11T14:28:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Copay Overpay Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Defense (DOD) from charging a covered individual (i.e., individuals enrolled under the TRICARE program) a co-payment exceeding a certain rate for an outpatient visit for mental health or behavioral health under the TRICARE program, regardless of whether the visit is furnished by a specialty care provider. Specifically, the co-payment amount may not exceed the amount of a co-payment that would be charged under the TRICARE program for an outpatient visit for primary care services.

During the one-year period beginning after this bill is enacted, DOD may not increase the co-payment amount charged to a covered individual above the amount that would have been charged in FY2021&#160;for any service (1) furnished by a specialty care provider under the TRICARE program, and (2) that is not an outpatient visit for&#160;mental or behavioral health care.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
