<bill session="118" type="s" number="938" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Water Affordability, Transparency, Equity, and Reliability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Affordability, Transparency, Equity, and Reliability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a trust fund to provide for adequate funding for water and sewer infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1729" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-17T01:59:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water Affordability, Transparency, Equity, and Reliability Act of 2023

This bill increases funding for water infrastructure to control water pollution or protect drinking water.

 Specifically, it establishes a Water Affordability, Transparency, Equity, and Reliability Trust Fund. The fund may be used for specified grant programs. The bill increases the corporate income tax rate to 24.5% to provide revenues for the fund.

In addition, the bill revises requirements concerning the clean water state revolving fund (SRF) and the drinking water SRF, including by prohibiting states from providing financial assistance using amounts from the clean water SRF for projects that will provide substantial direct benefits to new communities other than projects for constructing an advanced decentralized wastewater system.

It also creates or reauthorizes several grant programs related to water infrastructure, such as grants for removing lead from drinking water.</summary>
</bill>
