<bill session="117" type="h" number="8457" updated="2023-08-10T18:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Making College More Affordable Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making College More Affordable Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To carry out an income-contingent repayment program for Federal Direct Interest-Free Education Loans for undergraduate students, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-10T18:40:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Making College More Affordable Act

This bill creates federal interest-free education loans for undergraduate students. The loans must generally have the same terms and conditions and benefits to borrowers as Federal Direct Stafford Loans. Interest on these loans may only accrue during periods when a borrower is earning taxable income, is in repayment on such loans, and is not making payments under a repayment plan.

The Department of Education (ED) must carry out a repayment plan program for the interest-free loans under which loan payments are automatically withheld from the wages of the borrower.

ED must cancel any outstanding balance of principal or interest due on those interest-free loans made to a borrower who has made 360 monthly payments.

The bill also allows for a tax deduction for amounts paid on these loans.</summary>
</bill>
