<bill session="118" type="h" number="7684" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Udall Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Udall Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2024-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1311" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-19T18:42:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Udall Foundation Reauthorization Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2029 the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation's trust fund, its Environmental Dispute Resolution Fund, and the foundation's support for training of health care and public policy professionals through the Native Nations Institute. The mission of the foundation, an independent executive branch agency, is to provide programs to promote leadership, education, collaboration, and conflict resolution in the areas of environment, public lands, and natural resources in order to strengthen Native nations, assist federal agencies and others to resolve environmental conflicts, and to encourage the continued use and appreciation of our nation's rich resources.

For appropriations to the trust fund occurring October 1, 2023, or after, the bill makes interest earned from investments made with those appropriations only available subject to appropriations.

The bill also directs the Office of Inspector General of the Department of the Interior to complete an audit of the foundation within four years.</summary>
</bill>
