<bill session="117" type="h" number="1151" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CPR Fund Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Consumer Protection Relief Fund to empower lenders to deploy credit to vulnerable borrowers needing access to credit as a result of the COVID-19 pandemic.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Protection Relief Fund Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CPR Fund Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-07T18:14:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Protection Relief Fund Act or the CPR Fund Act 

This bill establishes the Consumer Protection Relief Fund for the purpose of repaying certain loans owed by vulnerable borrowers who are experiencing financial difficulty due to the impact of COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019). To qualify for repayment, the holder of the loan must

 commit to issuing or purchasing other loans to vulnerable borrowers in an amount at least equal to the payment received, forgive the borrower's remaining loan balance, and terminate any negative reporting to consumer reporting agencies with respect to the borrower's loan. A loan must be a closed-end installment loan&#8212;a loan extended at a set amount and repaid by the borrower with a fixed amount over a limited number of payment periods&#8212;to qualify for repayment. However, the bill excludes from eligibility a student, auto, or mortgage loan.

Aggregate payments with respect to a borrower may not exceed $9,500.</summary>
</bill>
