<bill session="108" type="sr" number="138" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:07Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution to amend rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate relating to the consideration of nominations requiring the advice and consent of the Senate.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate relating to the consideration of nominations requiring the advice and consent of the Senate.</title>
    <title type="popular">Senate Committee Organizing resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000121" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000059" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000888" joined="2003-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6002" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Rules and Administration. Reported by Senator Lott without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="180">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 180.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)Amends rule XXII (Precedence of Motions) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to authorize a cloture motion on a nomination requiring the advice and consent of the Senate after such nomination has been pending before the Senate for at least 12 hours. Outlines procedures and limitations on the debate of the nomination after cloture is invoked.Provides that if the Senate fails to invoke cloture on a pending nomination, subsequent cloture motions may be made with respect to the same nomination. Makes it out of order to file subsequent cloture motions on any nomination, except by unanimous consent, until the previous motion has been disposed of. Reduces the affirmative vote (three-fifths, or 60 out of 100) required to invoke cloture on such nomination by three votes on the motion and by three additional votes on each succeeding motion, until the affirmative vote is reduced to a number equal or less than an affirmative vote of a majority of the Senators duly chosen and sworn and after that, a simple majority.</summary>
</bill>
