<bill session="118" type="h" number="262" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:43Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ALERT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ALERT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">ALERT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the publication, by the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs, of information relating to rulemakings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2023-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Accountability. H. Rept. 118-904, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-18" calendar="Union" number="739">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 739.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4200" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-01T22:12:17Z" status="Introduced in House">All Economic Regulations are Transparent Act of 2023 or the ALERT Act of 2023

This bill establishes various reporting requirements with respect to federal agency rulemaking. Specifically, each agency must submit a monthly report to the Office of Information and Regulatory Affairs (OIRA) for each rule the agency expects to propose or finalize during the following year, including information about the objectives and legal basis for the rule as well as whether the rule is subject to periodic review based on its significant economic impact. Additionally, each agency must submit a monthly report for any rule expected to be finalized during the following year for which the agency has issued a general notice of proposed rulemaking, including an approximate schedule for completing action on the rule and an estimate of its cost and economic effects. OIRA must publish this information online and, subject to certain exceptions, a rule may not take effect until the information has been published for at least six months. The bill also requires OIRA to annually publish in the Federal Register specified information it receives from agencies under this bill, including a list of each rule an agency has proposed and the total cost of all rules proposed or finalized. OIRA must further publish online (1) any analysis of the costs or benefits of rules that were proposed or finalized during the previous year, and (2) a list of rules that were subjected to various forms of review during the previous year.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-904</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
