<bill session="117" type="s" number="3817" updated="2023-08-15T21:30:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TORNADO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TORNADO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tornado Observations Research and Notification Assessment for Development of Operations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">TORNADO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tornado Observations Research and Notification Assessment for Development of Operations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the forecasting and understanding of tornadoes and other hazardous weather, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2022-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2022-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="629">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 629.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T21:27:58Z" status="Reported to Senate">Tornado Observations Research and Notification Assessment for Development of Operations Act or the TORNADO Act

This bill establishes programs and activities to improve the forecasting of hazardous weather and water events, including tornadoes.

The bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to maintain and improve the system by which the risks of hazardous weather and water events are communicated to the general public, with the goal of informing action and encouraging response to prevent loss of life and property.

NOAA shall also

 maintain a hazard risk communication office; establish or maintain a research program to modernize the creation and communication of risk-based, statistically reliable, probabilistic hazard information to inform effective responses to hazardous weather and water events; establish a pilot program for tornado hazard communication to test the effectiveness of the implementation of the research conducted pursuant to this bill; submit to Congress a strategic plan for developing and prioritizing the implementation of high-resolution probabilistic forecast guidance for hazardous weather and water events using a next-generation weather forecast and warning framework; perform one or more post-storm surveys and assessments following each hazardous weather or water event that is of sufficient societal importance; update, if necessary, the system for rating tornado severity; and maintain the Vortex USA tornado research program. The Government Accountability Office shall submit a report that examines the information technology infrastructure of the National Weather Service.</summary>
</bill>
