<bill session="117" type="s" number="1946" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Disaster Revictimization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Disaster Recovery Reform Act of 2018 to require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to waive certain debts owed to the United States related to covered assistance provided to an individual or household, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Disaster Revictimization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="539" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-13T19:42:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Disaster Revictimization Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to waive certain debts owed to the United States related to disaster assistance provided to an individual or household.

Specifically, FEMA must waive a debt owed to the United States related to disaster assistance provided to an individual or household if such assistance (1) was distributed based on an error by FEMA and such debt is construed as a hardship, and (2) is subject to a claim or legal action.

FEMA must report to Congress on (1) actions that it will take to reduce the error rate, and (2) the internal processes used to make decisions regarding the distribution of federal disaster assistance to individuals and households and any changes made to such processes.</summary>
</bill>
