<bill session="117" type="hc" number="102" updated="2023-01-13T19:16:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of Congress that it is the duty of the Federal Government to establish a new royalty program to provide income to featured and non-featured performing artists whose music or audio content is listened to on streaming music services, like Spotify.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that it is the duty of the Federal Government to establish a new royalty program to provide income to featured and non-featured performing artists whose music or audio content is listened to on streaming music services, like Spotify.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2022-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2022-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-13T19:03:01Z" status="Introduced in House">This concurrent resolution expresses the sense of Congress that it is the duty of the federal government to establish a new statutory royalty program that

 provides musicians whose recorded work is listened to on streaming music services reasonable remuneration through a royalty payment earned on a per-stream basis, ensures streaming music services compensate musicians at fair rates that are not significantly lower than rates earned on traditional physical record sales, and avoids falling behind in investing in musicians within the United States compared to other countries that have already proposed legislation to address inequalities in the music industry. The concurrent resolution also expresses that such statutory royalty program should be

 administered by SoundExchange and the Copyright Royalty Board, who will together calculate, collect, retain, and distribute the royalty payments to all eligible musicians whose recorded work is listened to on streaming music services; and funded by mandatory pro rata contributions collected by SoundExchange from eligible providers of music-streaming service with the option for SoundExchange to request additional direct public funding.</summary>
</bill>
