<bill session="108" type="h" number="3296" updated="2023-01-15T07:32:53Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prevent Identity Theft From Affecting Lives and Livelihoods (PITFALL) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend various provisions of the Consumer Credit Protection Act to provide relief for victims of identity theft, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Identity Theft From Affecting Lives and Livelihoods (PITFALL) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000549"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001033" joined="2004-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1749" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Liens"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Police records"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-07T21:09:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Identity Theft From Affecting Lives and Livelihoods (PITFALL) Act - Amends the Truth in Lending Act to provide nonliability for victims of identity theft following issuance of a no-fault letter by a State agency upon completion of its investigation into the matter.

Cites duties of a creditor with respect to other creditors and credit reporting agencies following receipt of such State-issued no-fault letter.



Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to prohibit a consumer reporting agency from including or maintaining information concerning any transaction involved in the identity theft with respect to which such no-fault letter has been issued.

Cites duties of a consumer reporting agency with respect to other creditors and credit reporting agencies following receipt of such State-issued no-fault letter.

Amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to set forth the duties of a debt collector following receipt of such a State-issued no-fault letter.

Amends the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to shield a person from liability for any electronic fund transfer with respect to which such no-fault letter has been issued.

Cites duties of a financial institution following receipt of such State-issued no-fault letter.</summary>
</bill>
