<bill session="110" type="h" number="4835" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:01Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Media Ownership Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Media Ownership Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote transparency in the adoption of new media ownership rules by the Federal Communications Commission, and to establish an independent panel to make recommendations on how to increase the representation of women and minorities in broadcast media ownership.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2008-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2008-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2008-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2008-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000085" joined="2008-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2008-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2007-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2008-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2008-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2007-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2332" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-01-03T20:03:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Media Ownership Act of 2007 - Amends the Telecommunications Act of 1996 to require the Federal Communications Commission (FCC), in changing any of its regulations related to broadcast ownership, to publish notice in the Federal Register for least 90 days, followed by at least 60 days for public comment, followed by at least 30 days to reply to comments. Applies those requirements to any any changes related to broadcast and newspaper ownership made after October 1, 2007.

Requires the FCC, before voting on any change in broadcast and newspaper ownership rules, to complete a separate rulemaking to promote the broadcast of local programming and content by broadcasters, including radio and television broadcast stations, and newspapers. Requires the FCC, before issuing a final rule, to: (1) conduct a study on the overall impact of television station duopolies and newspaper-broadcast cross-ownership on the quantity and quality of local news, public affairs, local news media jobs, and local cultural programming at the market level; and (2) publish a proposed final rule at least 90 days before a vote, followed by at least 60 days for public comment, followed by at least 30 days to reply to comments.

Requires the FCC to establish an independent panel on increasing the representation of women and minorities in broadcast media ownership and to act on the panel's recommendations before voting on any changes to its broadcast and newspaper ownership rules.</summary>
</bill>
