<bill session="119" type="s" number="111" updated="2025-11-18T19:33:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Red Snapper Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red Snapper Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that the Secretary of Commerce shall not issue an interim or final rule or Secretarial Amendment that includes an area or bottom closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Fishery Management Plan for the Snapper-Grouper Fishery of the South Atlantic Region until the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete and the data related to that study is integrated into the stock assessment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="470" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-28T15:14:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Red Snapper Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) from restricting certain fishing activities in the South Atlantic until data from the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is integrated into the next South Atlantic red snapper Southeast&#160;Data, Assessment, and Review (SEDAR) stock assessment.&#160;

The bill provides that NOAA may not issue an interim rule,&#160;final rule, or Secretarial Amendment&#160;establishing an area closure or a bottom fishing closure for specified species&#160;until (1) the study is complete; and (2) the study data is integrated into the first South Atlantic red snapper SEDAR stock assessment&#160;that is carried out after the bill's enactment.&#160;The limitation applies to fishing for species managed under the Fishery Management Plan for the Snapper-Grouper Fishery of the South Atlantic Region, including red snapper, grouper, and porgy.

(Closures generally&#160;restrict&#160;recreational and commercial fishing to prevent overfishing and for other conservation purposes.)</summary>
</bill>
