<bill session="108" type="s" number="2529" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:20Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend and modify the trade benefits under the African Growth and Opportunity Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2004-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2004-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000442" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000439" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2004-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000102" joined="2004-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000059" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001078" joined="2004-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4103" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Chambers of commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Debt relief"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Diversification in industry"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic integration"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecotourism"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Handicraft"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human immunodeficiency viruses"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Malaria"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Railroad engineering"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regionalism (International organization)"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Tuberculosis"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-01T21:44:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">AGOA Acceleration Act of 2004 - Declares the sense of Congress that the preferential market access opportunities for eligible sub-Saharan African countries (SSA countries) will be complemented and enhanced if those countries implement specified existing obligations under the World Trade Organization (WTO). Urges such countries to participate in and support mutual trade liberalization in ongoing negotiations under WTO auspices, recognizing that such commitments may need to reflect special and differential treatment for developing countries. States that eligible SSA countries will benefit from reduction of trade barriers in other developing countries. Urges all countries to make sanitary and phytosanitary decisions on the basis of sound science.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the executive branch, including specified Federal agencies, should enforce African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA) provisions relating to preferential treatment of textile and apparel articles, broadly in order to expand trade by maximizing opportunities for imports of such articles from eligible SSA countries.

Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to extend duty-free treatment for AGOA articles: (1) from FY 2008 through 2015; and (2) made from material produced in former beneficiary SSA countries.

Defines former beneficiary sub-Saharan African country as a country that, after being designated as a beneficiary sub-Saharan African country under AGOA, ceased to be designated as such a country by reason of its entering into a free trade agreement with the United States.

Amends AGOA to revise requirements for textile and apparel products from SSA countries receiving duty-free and other preferential import treatment, including extensions of such treatment to certain apparels.

Authorizes duty-free and preferential treatment for certain apparel articles such as ethnic printed fabric of an SSA country that meets certain conditions.

Extends preferential treatment to an article containing fibers or yarns not wholly formed in former beneficiary SSA countries (currently, the United States or one or more beneficiary SSA countries) if the total weight of all such fibers and yarns is not more than ten (currently, seven) percent of the total weight of the article.

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury, under specified conditions, to liquidate or reliquidate as free of duty and free of any quantitative restrictions, limitations, or consultative levels any entries of certain apparel.

Requires the President to: (1) study each eligible SSA country, identifying sectors of its economy with the greatest potential for growth, including through export sales, and identifying both domestic and international barriers impeding such growth; (2) make recommendations on how the Federal Government and the private sector can provide technical assistance to assist that country in dismantling such barriers and promoting investment in such sectors; and (3) disseminate information to appropriate Federal agencies on each such country.

Requires the President to develop and implement policies to encourage the development of investment in SSA countries, particularly in: (1) infrastructure projects supporting development of land transport road and railroad networks and ports, and the continued upgrading and liberalization of the energy and telecommunications sectors; (2) establishment and expansion of modern information and communication technologies and practices to improve the ability of citizens to research and disseminate specified information; and (3) agriculture, particularly in processing and capacity enhancement.

Requires the President to: (1) foster improved port-to-port and airport-to-airport relationships in order to facilitate and increase trade flows between eligible SSA countries; (2) encourage the development of infrastructure projects that will help increase trade capacity and a sustainable ecotourism industry in such countries; (3) identify at least ten eligible SSA countries as having the greatest potential to increase marketable exports of agricultural products to the United States and the greatest need for technical assistance, particularly with respect to pest risk assessments and complying with U.S. sanitary and phytosanitary rules; (4) assign at least 20 full-time personnel to provide assistance to such countries to ensure that their exports of agricultural products meet Federal law requirements; and (5) convene the trade advisory committee on Africa established by Executive Order 11846 of March 27, 1975, under the Trade Act of 1974.</summary>
</bill>
