<bill session="119" type="s" number="27" updated="2025-05-14T17:27:07Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Employee Return to Work Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employee Return to Work Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain telework employees from receiving certain annual adjustments to pay schedules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="236" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-14T17:26:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Employee Return to Work Act

This bill prohibits providing certain annual or locality-based&#160;pay increases to teleworking federal employees.

Currently, federal law mandates annual adjustments to General Schedule (GS) pay rates according to (1) a formula based on the annual percentage change in the Employment Cost Index (a measure of labor costs in the private sector); and (2) the difference between public and private sector pay rates in an employee's locality, if that difference exceeds 5%. For example, in 2025, the default annual rate of pay for a GS-7 (step 1) employee is $49,960; the adjusted annual rate of pay for a GS-7 (step 1) employee in the locality pay area that includes Washington, DC, is $57,164.&#160;

The bill makes executive agency employees who telework at least one&#160;day each week (or, in the case of an alternative work schedule, 20% or more each week) ineligible for these&#160;payments.

The bill is effective on the first day of the fiscal year beginning after the bill's enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
