<bill session="119" type="s" number="657" updated="2025-08-04T18:56:30Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Retirement Security for American Hostages Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Retirement Security for American Hostages Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to provide retirement security to United States nationals who were unlawfully or wrongfully detained or held hostage abroad.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2025-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2025-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-02-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-04T18:55:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Retirement Security for American Hostages Act of 2025

This bill permits individuals held hostage or wrongfully detained abroad to collect Social Security benefits based on average national wages for months in which they were held hostage or detained.&#160;

Specifically, for purposes of determining Social Security benefits based on an individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s wages or self-employment income, the bill directs the Social Security Administration (SSA) to deem qualifying individuals to have been paid a monthly portion of the national average wage index for any month during which the individual was held hostage or unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad. (The national average wage index is determined annually by the SSA.) Deemed wages must apply for any affected month before the individual reaches the statutory retirement age (generally between ages 65 and 67).&#160;

A qualifying individual is a U.S. national (1) determined by the Department of State to have been unlawfully or wrongfully detained abroad, or (2) determined by the interagency Hostage Recovery Fusion Cell to have been taken hostage abroad.&#160;

A qualifying individual or an individual entitled to benefits on the basis of a qualifying individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s wages and income must apply to the SSA in order to receive deemed wages for affected months. These provisions do not apply if a larger benefit would be available without the application of deemed wages. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
