<bill session="117" type="h" number="5697" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Attorney General to make grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, States and units of local government to develop, implement, or expand one or more programs to provide medication-assisted treatment to individuals who have opioid use disorder and are incarcerated within the jurisdictions of the States or units of local government.</title>
    <title type="display">CREATE Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Re-Entry through Addiction Treatment to Enhance Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CREATE Opportunities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000813" joined="2021-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3028" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-09T10:36:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Re-Entry through Addiction Treatment to Enhance Opportunities Act or the CREATE Opportunities Act

This bill establishes the Medication-Assisted Treatment Corrections and Community Reentry Program in the Department of Justice. Under the program, the National Institute of Corrections may award grants to support state or local programs that provide medication-assisted treatment for incarcerated individuals who have opioid-use disorders.</summary>
</bill>
