<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="164" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:10Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2200" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-06-04T16:01:27-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000689"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <description>Amendment alters the standard for when TSA can issue an emergency regulation or security device without adhering to the rulemaking and public notice and comment provisions of the Administrative Procedures Act (APA). The amendment also allows TSA to issue a regulation or security directive when needed "to respond to an imminent threat of finite duration" and would require TSA to comply with the rule making requirements of the APA when a security directive or emergency order has been in place for more than 180 days.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 111-127 to alter the standard for when TSA can issue an emergency regulation or security device without adhering to the rule making and public notice and comment provisions of the Administrative Procedures Act (APA). Allows TSA to issue a regulation or security directive when needed "to respond to an imminent threat of finite duration" and would require TSA to comply with the rule making requirements of the APA when a security directive or emergency order has been in place for more than 180 days.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-06-04T16:01:27-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="304">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mica amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 219 - 211 (Roll no. 304).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T13:48:41-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Mica.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6196-6198, H6212" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6196-6197" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T13:48:41-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Mica.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6196-6198, H6212" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6196-6197" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T16:01:27-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T16:01:27-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Mica amendment (A002) Agreed to by recorded vote: 219 - 211 (Roll no. 304).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04T16:01:27-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
