<bill session="116" type="h" number="8762" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to make a determination on whether to approve an occupation as an apprenticeable occupation in a timely manner, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2020-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8294" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-22T13:35:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to review and make a determination on whether to approve an occupation as an apprenticeable occupation within 45 days after receiving an individual's application seeking such approval and if not, to provide the applicant with a written explanation for the delay and offer an estimated time line for a determination within 90 days after the date of such written explanation.

The bill also requires Labor to convene, on an ongoing basis and taking into consideration recommendations of the National Advisory Committee on Apprenticeships, particular industry sector leaders and experts for the purposes of establishing or updating specific frameworks of industry-recognized occupational standards for existing and potential apprenticeable occupations.</summary>
</bill>
