<bill session="108" type="s" number="1696" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:21Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Health and Human Services Tribal Self-Governance Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Self-Determination  and Education Assistance Act to provide further self-governance by Indian tribes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Health and Human Services Tribal Self-Governance Amendments Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Health and Human Services Tribal Self-Governance Amendments Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12285"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12285-12287" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-584.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-412.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="803">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 803.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tribes and tribal system"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-22T22:11:59Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Department of Health and Human Services Tribal Self-Governance Amendments Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act to provide for further self-governance by Indian tribes.

Establishes a five-year project to demonstrate the effectiveness of tribal operation of certain programs currently operated by the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS).

Entitles up to 50 eligible Indian tribes to participate in the demonstration project; but authorizes the Secretary of HHS, if more than 50 request participation, to select additional tribes to participate. Makes a tribe eligible for a project only if it is party to a tribal self-governance compact or a funding agreement relating to certain Federal programs. Directs the Secretary to establish a program to award planning and negotiation grants to eligible tribes, but states that receipt of such a grant is not a requirement for project participation.

Sets forth requirements for compacts and funding agreements.

Makes eligible for inclusion in a funding agreement the following programs: (1) grants for older Native Americans; (2) tribal temporary assistance for needy families; (3) Low-Income Home Energy Assistance; (4) Community Services Block Grant; (5) Child Care and Development Fund; (6) native employment works; (7) Head Start; (8) child welfare services; (9) promoting safe and stable families; (10) family violence prevention grants for battered women's shelters; (11) targeted capacity expansion, related to substance abuse and mental health services; (12) mental health and substance abuse block grant; and (13) community health center grants.

Authorizes the Secretary to identify up to six additional programs annually for inclusion in the demonstration project, including: (1) all other programs in which Indian tribes are eligible to participate, or for which Indians are eligible beneficiaries; and (2) competitive grants for which an Indian tribe receives an individual or cooperative award, upon agreement to such grant restrictions regarding program redesign and budget reallocation.

Prescribes requirements for: (1) contents of funding agreements; (2) transfer of funds; (3) waivers for redesign, consolidation, and reallocation; (4) procedures in cases of inability to agree on a compact or funding agreement; and (5) reports.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-412</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
