<bill session="119" type="h" number="5062" updated="2025-11-14T21:26:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-08-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Pipeline Security Act</title>
    <title type="display">Pipeline Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 to codify the Transportation Security Administration's responsibility relating to securing pipeline transportation and pipeline facilities against cybersecurity threats, acts of terrorism, and other nefarious acts that jeopardize the physical security or cybersecurity of pipelines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000598" joined="2025-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2025-08-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-08-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-12">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 119-376.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-11-12" calendar="Union" number="327">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 327.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-14T19:34:32Z" status="Reported to House">Pipeline Security Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Transportation Security Administration's (TSA's) role as the agency responsible&#160;for securing pipeline transportation and pipeline facilities&#160;against cybersecurity threats, acts of terrorism, and other security threats.

The bill specifies that, among other things, the TSA must (1) develop and update pipeline security guidelines; (2) promulgate additional related security directives or regulations, as necessary; and (3) inspect pipeline transportation and pipeline facilities&#160;that are&#160;designated as critical by the owners and operators.

Under the bill, the&#160;TSA must convene at least one industry day to engage with relevant pipeline stakeholders on security-related matters.

The TSA must report to Congress biennially on its efforts to secure pipelines.

Further,&#160;the TSA must develop a personnel strategy to carry out the&#160;TSA's responsibilities for securing&#160;pipelines. The strategy must include an assessment of (1) the cybersecurity expertise necessary to secure pipelines and a plan for expanding&#160;the TSA's expertise, and (2) the resources necessary to carry out the personnel strategy.

Finally, the Government Accountability Office must conduct a review of the implementation of this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-376</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
