<bill session="117" type="h" number="7610" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century Dyslexia Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Dyslexia Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act to improve provisions relating to dyslexia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000821"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001135" joined="2022-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2022-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3302" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-02T15:26:32Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Dyslexia Act

This bill addresses the education of children with disabilities, with a particular focus on children with dyslexia.

Currently, dyslexia is listed as one of the disabilities under the definition of specific learning disability in the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA). This bill instead removes dyslexia from the definition of specific learning disability and establishes a stand-alone definition for dyslexia within IDEA.

Specifically, the bill defines dyslexia for purposes of IDEA as an unexpected difficulty in reading for an individual who has the intelligence to be a much better reader, most commonly caused by a difficulty in the phonological processing (the appreciation of the individual sounds of spoken language), which affects the ability of an individual to speak, read, and spell.

 Additionally, the bill requires a local educational agency or other agency, in determining eligibility for or providing an accommodation or service under IDEA, to provide equal access to (1) children from low-income families or from families with low socioeconomic status, and (2) other children.</summary>
</bill>
