<bill session="110" type="h" number="3055" updated="2023-01-11T21:19:17Z">
  <state datetime="2007-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide expanded resources, technical assistance, reasonable accountability, and professional development to eligible entities implementing Even Start programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Families Conquering Literacy Together Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Families Conquering Literacy Together Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2007-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000362" joined="2007-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2007-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2007-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2007-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2007-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Migrant education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-09-27T19:31:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Families Conquering Literacy Together Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to change funding formulas under the Even Start Family Literacy program to reserve potentially larger amounts, depending on overall appropriations, for migrant, outlying area, Indian, and research programs.

 Eliminates the Even Start competitive grant program awarding reserved funds to states for statewide coordination of federal, state, and local literacy resources.

Increases the minimum Even Start grant to states and state subgrant to Even Start entities, as well as the floor on the federal share of program costs.

Allows states to use federal funds to provide subgrantees with technical assistance for professional development and collaborative activities.

Requires all Even Start instructors to have at least an associate's degree related to early childhood education, elementary or secondary education, or adult education.

Requires state, migrant, and tribal grantees to report annually to the Secretary of Education on their progress in achieving program quality.

Revises required indicators of program quality to stress the quality of services provided and training received by program providers, rather than participant achievements.

Requires the creation of an independent research panel to set the agenda for research into successful family literacy services.

Directs the Secretary, after receiving design recommendations from an expert panel, to arrange for an independent longitudinal evaluation of the impact of Even Start programs that compares participants against nonparticipant control groups and addresses variations in the impact of such programs.</summary>
</bill>
