<bill session="116" type="h" number="8115" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DIGIT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure appropriate prioritization, spectrum planning, and interagency coordination to support the Internet of Things.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2020-08-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1611" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-22T16:26:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Developing Innovation and Growing the Internet of Things Act or the DIGIT Act

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to convene a working group of federal stakeholders to provide recommendations regarding the Internet of Things (IoT), and it establishes a steering committee composed of stakeholders outside the federal government to advise the working group. The IoT is a system of interrelated devices connected to a network and each other that exchange data without requiring human interaction (e.g., smart home devices, medical monitoring devices, and wearable fitness trackers).

The working group must (1) identify federal laws and regulations, grant practices, budgetary or jurisdictional challenges, and other sector-specific policies that affect IoT development; (2) consider policies or programs that encourage and improve coordination among federal agencies with relevant responsibilities; (3) consider implementing recommendations from the steering committee; (4) examine how federal agencies can benefit from, use, prepare for, and secure the IoT; and (5) consult with nongovernmental stakeholders.

The steering committee must advise the working group about laws, budgets, individual privacy, security, small business challenges, and any international proceedings or negotiations affecting the IoT.

Lastly, the Federal Communications Commission must (1) seek public comment on the IoT's spectrum needs, regulatory barriers, and growth with licensed and unlicensed spectrum; and (2) submit a summary of those comments to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
