<bill session="118" type="h" number="5355" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Our Airports Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Airports Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to submit to Congress progress reports on the development and implementation of a national plan to transition to the use of a fluorine-free firefighting foam, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001112"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001221" joined="2023-11-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2023-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1929" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4319" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-22T18:47:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Our Airports Reporting Act 

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to submit regular progress reports to Congress on the development and implementation of a national transition plan related to fluorine-free firefighting foam. (Fluorine-free foams do not contain any perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS.)

Specifically, the FAA reports must include information on the development and implementation of a national transition plan for a fluorine-free firefighting foam that meets certain performance standards for use at Part 139 airports (Part 139 airports include airports that serve scheduled and unscheduled air carrier operations for aircraft with more than 30 seats or serve scheduled air carrier operations for aircraft with 10-30 seats.)

The reports must also assess the progress in providing airports that are not Part 139 airports and local authorities with responsibility for inspection and oversight with guidance relating to&#160;the use of fluorine-free firefighting foam at such airports.&#160;

The FAA must submit a progress report to Congress every 180 days until the FAA completes the development and implementation of the national transition plan.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
