<bill session="118" type="h" number="3430" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Spectrum Relocation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spectrum Relocation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to enhance Federal spectrum relocation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-12T20:58:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Spectrum Relocation Enhancement Act

This bill modifies procedures related to the relocation or sharing of federal portions of the electromagnetic spectrum, including the uses of and requirements for the Spectrum Relocation Fund (SRF), which is a funding mechanism through which federal agencies can recover certain costs associated with spectrum relocation or sharing. The bill permits the SRF to more broadly cover those costs.

Currently, the SRF covers costs to achieve comparable capabilities, while the bill permits it to cover costs to deploy systems that satisfy operational requirements. Further, the SRF may cover costs for more extensive operational requirements than those being met before the relocation or sharing provided that the more extensive costs do not jeopardize an auction, sharing, or other nonfederal use of the spectrum.

Additionally, the bill expands planning and coordination requirements. This includes (1) specifying more detailed requirements for transition plans that federal agencies must submit to receive SRF payments, and (2) requiring agencies to coordinate with the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) on their transition plans and other activities.

The bill also funds administrative support for a technical panel that reviews the plans for transitioning federal use of spectrum to nonfederal or shared use.</summary>
</bill>
