<bill session="109" type="s" number="1500" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Environmental Health Research Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to develop multidisciplinary research centers regarding women's health and disease prevention and to conduct and coordinate a research program on hormone disruption, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Health Research Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2005-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2005-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3313" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental estrogens"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hormones"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-13T17:45:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Environmental Health Research Act of 2005 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to make grants for the development and operation of not more than six centers to conduct multidisciplinary research on environmental factors that may be related to the development of women's health conditions. Requires each center to conduct basic and clinical research, develop training protocols, conduct training, develop model continuing education programs, and disseminate information to professionals and the public, with priority to prevention activities.

Allows a center to use grant funds to provide stipends for health and allied health professionals enrolled in training programs.

Requires the Director to establish a comprehensive program to: (1) conduct research on the impact of chemicals that affect the health of women and children through disruption of the hormone system; (2) conduct research on the occurrence of hormone-disrupting chemicals in the environment and their effects on ecological and wildlife health; (3) coordinate the design of a multiagency research initiative on hormone disruption; and (4) coordinate research on hormone disruption in the United States with such research conducted in other nations.

 Requires the Director to establish the Hormone Disruption Research Interagency Commission to advise the Director of the Institute and the Director of the United States Geological Survey on the development of a comprehensive agenda for conducting research on hormone disruption.

Establishes a Hormone Disruption Research Panel to advise the Director of the Institute on the scientific hormone-disruption research program.</summary>
</bill>
