<bill session="117" type="s" number="1918" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Battery and Critical Mineral Recycling Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the reuse and recycling of batteries and critical minerals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Battery and Critical Mineral Recycling Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2021-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2021-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2021-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-07T00:44:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Battery and Critical Mineral Recycling Act of 2021

This bill provides support to reuse and recycle batteries and the critical minerals contained in them.

Specifically, the bill establishes incentives for reusing and recycling batteries, including by establishing three grant programs. It also requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to continue carrying out its Lithium-Ion Battery Recycling Prize competition.

In addition, the bill establishes within DOE and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) a voluntary labeling program to improve battery collection and reduce battery waste.

The EPA must also develop best practices for the collection of batteries that states and local governments may follow.

Additionally, DOE must convene a task force to develop an extended battery producer responsibility framework that outlines regulatory pathways for effective recycling.</summary>
</bill>
