<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="606" updated="2022-02-03T05:36:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="420" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-10-27T15:35:16-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001150"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-10-27"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute sought to provide "three-strikes-and-you're-out" provisions for attorneys who file frivolous lawsuits or engage in frivolous conduct during discovery; enhance sanctions for document destruction; and require that court records not be sealed unless the court finds that a sealing is justified.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in House Report 109-253 to provide strong "three strikes and you're out" mandatory sanctions for attorneys who file frivolous lawsuits or engage in frivolous conduct during discovery. Enhances sanctions for document destruction, ensures that corporations can be sued in the U.S., cracks down on parties attempting to relitigate the same issue on consecutive occasions, bans the concealment of unlawful conduct, and protects civil rights claims.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-10-27T15:35:16-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="551">
      <text>On agreeing to the Schiff amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 226 (Roll no. 551).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T14:33:44-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Schiff.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9320-9327" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9321-9322" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T14:33:44-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Schiff.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9320-9327" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H9321-9322" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T15:35:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Schiff amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 184 - 226 (Roll no. 551).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T15:35:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27T15:35:16-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
