<bill session="117" type="s" number="4356" updated="2023-09-01T14:00:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for responsible financial innovation and to bring digital assets within the regulatory perimeter.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Hearings"/>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-03T14:27:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lummis-Gillibrand Responsible Financial Innovation Act 

This bill provides for the regulation of digital assets.

The bill delineates the jurisdiction over digital assets held by the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC). For example, the bill provides that the SEC has jurisdiction over digital assets that provide their holders with financial interest in a business entity, while the CFTC has jurisdiction over digital assets that do not.

In addition, digital asset exchanges are allowed to register with the CFTC.

Under the bill, depository institutions are allowed to issue payment stablecoins. The bill sets forth requirements, including that institutions must hold in reserves 100% of the value of all outstanding stablecoins and allow stablecoins to be redeemed on a one-to-one basis.

The bill also provides for the tax treatment of digital assets, including an exemption from income tax for purchases using digital assets that result in a gain or loss of $200 or less.

Finally, the bill provides for various reports, studies, and consumer protection standards.</summary>
</bill>
