<bill session="116" type="s" number="4523" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Natural Gas Blowout Prevention, Oversight, and Liability Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Gas Blowout Prevention, Oversight, and Liability Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate large-scale emissions of methane and natural gas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-27T17:21:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Natural Gas Blowout Prevention, Oversight, and Liability Act of 2020

This bill sets forth federal standards related to natural gas blowouts. A blowout is the loss of control of any well that leads to the release of combusted or uncombusted natural gas into the atmosphere.

Specifically, the bill

 requires operators of wells to report natural gas blowouts to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) within 72 hours after a blowout occurs; directs the EPA to establish and maintain a public database of all blowouts; imposes penalties for natural gas or flared natural gas that is released as a result of a well blowout, based on the volume released; establishes a grant program to reduce the scale and regularity of blowouts and the burden to states and local governments with respect to emergency responses to blowouts; and directs the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board to submit a report that describes each natural gas blowout from the past 10 years and includes recommendations to reduce the number of blowouts.</summary>
</bill>
