<bill session="115" type="s" number="2561" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:59Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stopping Suspicious Orders of Opioids Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Attorney General to suspend a controlled substances registration if there is a likelihood of a threat of diversion of a controlled substance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Suspicious Orders of Opioids Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2018-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1766-1767" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-07-23T20:27:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Suspicious Orders of Opioids Act

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to modify enforcement authorities of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA).

Currently, the DEA may deny, revoke, or suspend a registration for a CSA violation. It must first issue an order to show cause which, among other things, notifies an applicant or registrant of the opportunity to submit a corrective plan (CAP). This bill specifies that if the DEA does not approve a CAP, or if an applicant or registrant fails to implement a DEA-approved CAP within 30 days, then the DEA must: (1) reinstate administrative proceedings to deny, revoke, or suspend the registration; and (2) immediately suspend the registration, in the case of a registrant.



 Additionally, the bill modifies the standard of review to immediately suspend a registration. Currently, the DEA may immediately suspend the registration of a controlled substances manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser to prevent imminent danger to the public health and safety. This bill lowers the standard for determining imminent danger to the public health and safety&#8212;from substantial likelihood of an immediate threat to likelihood of a threat.</summary>
</bill>
