<bill session="118" type="h" number="3515" updated="2025-11-19T03:29:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop the Outlay of Payments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop the Outlay of Payments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require agencies to notify the Director of the Office of Management and Budget when the agency suspends or terminates a Federal award, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1807" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-12T20:40:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop the Outlay of Payments Act

This bill prohibits the award of federal funds to entities that have had prior awards suspended or terminated due to certain legal violations and that have failed to take necessary remedial action.

Specifically, the bill requires federal agencies to notify the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) within 120 days of suspending or terminating any portion of a federal award to a recipient for failure to comply with (1) the terms and conditions of the award, (2) a federal law or regulation, or (3) a request by the agency making the award for information or materials relating to that award.

The OMB must maintain an up-to-date list of suspended entities on its website.

An agency may not make a federal award or disburse funds under an award to a suspended entity until that entity remedies the reason for the suspension or termination, with specified exceptions.</summary>
</bill>
