<bill session="109" type="hr" number="503" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:50Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Condemning the actions taken by the Government of Cameroon against Henry Fossung and others, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the actions taken by the Government of Cameroon against Henry Fossung and others, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Cameroon"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="Equality before the law"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-01T14:34:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Condemns the actions taken by the government of the Republic of Cameroon against Ambassador Henry Fossung, his family, his house guests, and the members of the Southern Cameroons National Council.

Affirms that the United States holds the government of the Republic of Cameroon responsible for upholding the rights of its citizens and nationals, regardless of political views, and urges the government to extend to all Cameroon's citizens the rights guaranteed by the Universal Declaration of Human Rights of the United Nations and other international covenants on human rights.

 Calls upon the President of the United States to: (1) assert U.S. concerns regarding such matters, and emphasize that the United States regards the government of the Republic of Cameroon's human rights practices as having a negative impact on U.S.-Cameroon relations; (2) urge the government of the Republic of Cameroon to emancipate members of the Southern Cameroons National Council; and (3) cooperate with international organizations and other governments to protect the human rights of freedom of thought and speech of all citizens and nationals of Cameroon.</summary>
</bill>
