<bill session="116" type="h" number="7374" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RAPID Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that the deployment of a small personal wireless service facility shall not constitute an undertaking under section 300320 of title 54, United States Code, or a major Federal action for the purposes of section 102(2)(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RAPID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Antiquated Permitting for Infrastructure Deployment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-18T17:08:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Antiquated Permitting for Infrastructure Deployment Act or the RAPID Act

 This bill modifies review requirements for deployment of a small personal wireless service facility and establishes a presumption related to the deployment of wireless facilities on properties owned by an Indian tribe or a Native Hawaiian organization.

Specifically, the bill exempts the deployment of a small personal wireless service facility from specified environmental and historic preservation review requirements.

The bill also establishes a rebuttable presumption that a wireless provider has completed a request for review if an Indian tribe or a Native Hawaiian organization has received certain completed forms with information reasonably necessary to ascertain whether historic properties of religious and cultural significance may be affected by the deployment of new or collocated wireless facilities.</summary>
</bill>
