<bill session="108" type="s" number="176" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:10Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Health Care Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a program to provide for medicare reimbursement for health care services provided to certain medicare-eligible veterans in facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Reimbursement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Health Care Reimbursement Act of 2003 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to authorize the Secretaries of Health and Human Services (HHS) and of Veterans Affairs (VA), under a new Medicare Reimbursement Program for Veterans, to establish a program under which the HHS Secretary shall reimburse the VA Secretary from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for Medicare health care services furnished to targeted Medicare-eligible veterans who volunteer for such program. Directs the VA Secretary to establish and operate coordinated care health plans to provide benefits to the enrolled veterans consistent with the program under SSA title XVIII part C (Medicare+Choice).Expresses the sense of Congress that the amount of funds appropriated for the Department of Veterans Affairs for medical care in any fiscal year beginning after the enactment of this Act should not be reduced because of the implementation of the Medicare Reimbursement Program for Veterans.</summary>
</bill>
