<bill session="111" type="s" number="552" updated="2019-11-15T21:44:28Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maple Tapping Access Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Maple Tapping Access Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to encourage owners and operators of privately held farm, ranch, and forest land to voluntarily make their land available for access by the public for maple-tapping activities under programs administered by States and tribal governments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2009-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1399" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-24T14:04:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maple Tapping Access Program Act of 2009 - Amends the the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a voluntary public access program under which states and tribal governments may apply for grants to encourage owners and operators of privately held farm, ranch, and forest land to voluntarily make such land available for public maple-tapping activities.

Gives priority to states and tribal governments that propose to: (1) maximize participation by offering program terms likely to meet with landowner acceptance; (2) ensure that enrolled land has appropriate tree stock; and (3) use additional federal, state, tribal, or private resources in carrying out the program.</summary>
</bill>
