<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1126" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:19Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03T14:15:57-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-03T14:15:57-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4247) to prevent and reduce the use of physical restraint and seclusion in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4247) to prevent and reduce the use of physical restraint and seclusion in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-425, by Mr. Cardoza.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02T18:49:55-05:00">
      <text>All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and Labor now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted. It shall be in order at any time through the legislative day of March 4, 2010, for the Speaker to entertain motions that the House suspend the rules. The requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII for a two-thirds vote to consider a report from the Committee on Rules on the same day it is presented to the House is waived with respect to any resolution reported through the legislative day of March 4, 2010.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="House" number="168">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T12:30:59-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1037-1043" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T12:33:59-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T13:17:26-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1043" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T13:18:50-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1126, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on agreeing to the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T13:47:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1045-1046" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="78" datetime="2010-03-03T14:15:57-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 184 (Roll no. 78).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1037-1038" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03T14:15:59-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4247" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-03T09:07:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4247) to prevent and reduce the use of physical restraint and seclusion in schools.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-425</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
