<bill session="108" type="h" number="2649" updated="2023-01-15T16:33:39Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Schools Safely Acquiring Faculty Excellence Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of Education from making any funds available to a State under any program administered by the Department of Education unless the Secretary determines that the State has in place a criminal information sharing system.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Schools Safely Acquiring Faculty Excellence Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2003-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2003-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-08-29T18:46:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Schools Safely Acquiring Faculty Excellence Act of 2003 - Prohibits the Secretary of Education from making any funds available to a State under any program administered by the Department of Education unless the Secretary determines that the State has in place a criminal information sharing system.

Directs the Secretary to make such determination with regard to each State within one year after enactment of this Act.

Requires such a system to be one under which the State shares with the Federal Government information (including for non-criminal justice purposes) on each arrest, charge, or conviction (including any no contest plea) in such State for specified covered offenses. Requires such information to include the identity of: (1) each individual so arrested, charged, or convicted; and (2) the identity of each individual under suspicion for such an offense. Requires such system to cover any offense that: (1) is a felony or involves violence, a controlled substance, child abuse, statutory rape, rape, molestation, or sexual abuse; and (2) occurs on or after the date that is 15 years before the date of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
