<bill session="116" type="s" number="4085" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ending Taxpayer Funding of Anarchy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Taxpayer Funding of Anarchy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make certain States and political subdivisions of States ineligible to receive Federal finance assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2020-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000594" joined="2020-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T21:12:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ending Taxpayer Funding of Anarchy Act

This bill prohibits, for FY2021 and each fiscal year thereafter, a state or political subdivision of a state (state) that is an anarchist jurisdiction at any time during a fiscal year from receiving federal financial assistance from an executive agency during that fiscal year.

Anarchist jurisdiction is defined as a state that has a statute, ordinance, policy, or practice in effect that, despite ongoing danger to individuals or property, allows any entity or official to purposefully (1) abdicate the reserved powers of the state to be performed by non-governmental actors in a manner that is detrimental to the health, safety, and welfare of its citizens; and (2) refuse to provide police, fire, or emergency medical services to one or more individuals in the state as a consequence of such abdication.

If a state that is ineligible to receive such assistance during a fiscal year receives federal financial assistance, the agency shall direct the state to immediately return it and reallocate such assistance to states that are not anarchist jurisdictions.</summary>
</bill>
