<bill session="110" type="s" number="2143" updated="2023-01-11T20:21:07Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act to establish a program to improve the health and education of children through grants to expand school breakfast programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Student Breakfast and Education Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Breakfast and Education Improvement Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2008-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2007-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2007-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3978" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-20T15:51:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Student Breakfast and Education Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states or local educational agencies (LEAs) for the establishment or enhancement of school breakfast programs at, and through the provision of subgrants to, schools where at least 65% of the students are eligible for free or reduced-price school lunches under the school lunch program.

Authorizes schools to use the school breakfast subgrants to: (1) increase the quantity of local or fresh food available under their programs; (2) provide nutrition education and first-hand knowledge of food systems to students; (3) extend the period during which breakfast is available, including during the school day; (4) increase participation in their breakfast programs, including through the provision of universal free breakfasts; or (5) collaborate with institutions of higher education or other research entities in compiling data and reports on their breakfast programs.

Gives priority to subgrant applicant schools at least 75% of whose students are eligible for free or reduced-price school lunches and which intend to use the funds to procure local produce, provide universal free breakfasts, or provide breakfast during the school day.

Directs state and LEA grantees, at least 180 days before the end of a grant term, to evaluate whether it would be cost-effective for subgrantee schools to provide universal free breakfasts under the school breakfast program.</summary>
</bill>
