<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3452</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:19:57Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:19:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-05-27</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-09-27T19:35:53Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-08-05T20:40:52Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2010-06-30T21:37:55Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-05-28T00:29:22Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-321</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 607.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-321.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-321.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-08-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-06-30</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-753.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-27</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-27</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4551-4553)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-05-27</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000039</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Tom [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>TOM</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-05-27</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-09-10T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3452, Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21821</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Seante Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on August 5, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-09-10T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3452, Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21821</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Seante Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on August 5, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-05-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-08-03T16:23:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act - Designates the Valles Caldera National Preserve in New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System for the protection and preservation of the fish, wildlife, watershed, natural, scientific, scenic, geologic, historic, cultural, archaeological, and recreational values of the area. </p> <p>Gives the Secretary of the Interior sole management responsibility for the Preserve. </p> <p>Requires coordination of the management and operations of the Preserve with the Bandelier National Monument.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to prepare a management plan for the Preserve. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a new science and education program for the Preserve.</p> <p>Authorizes the establishment of a science and education center outside of the Preserve to promote research and education of the Preserve's natural and cultural resources. </p> <p>Prohibits road or facilities construction and motorized access within the area of volcanic domes and other peaks in the Preserve. </p> <p>Permits the continuation of livestock grazing and hunting and fishing on land and waters within the Preserve. </p> <p>Ensures the protection of, and access to, traditional cultural and religious sites. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to study the feasibility of establishing a hiking trail along the rim of the Valles Caldera.</p> <p>Transfers administrative jurisdiction over the Preserve from the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary of the Interior. Modifies the boundaries of Santa Fe National Forest to exclude the Preserve. </p> <p>Terminates the Valles Caldera Trust.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-02T21:20:32Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act - (Sec. 3) Designates the Valles Caldera National Preserve in New Mexico as a unit of the National Park System for the protection, preservation, and restoration of the fish, wildlife, watershed, natural, scientific, scenic, geologic, historic, cultural, archaeological, and recreational values of the area. </p> <p>Authorizes coordination of the management and operations of the Preserve with the Bandelier National Monument.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to prepare a management plan for the Preserve. </p> <p>Authorizes the United States to acquire by purchase with donated or appropriated funds, donation, or transfer from another federal agency, land and interests within the boundaries of the Preserve. Requires acquired lands and interests to be administered as part of the Preserve. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a new science and education program for the Preserve. Authorizes the establishment of a science and education center outside of the Preserve.</p> <p>Permits the continuation of livestock grazing and hunting and fishing on land and water within the Preserve. Allows zones and periods to be established when hunting or fishing shall not be permitted. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary to undertake activities for improving the health of forest, grassland, and riparian areas within the Preserve. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with adjacent pueblos to coordinate such activities on the Preserve and adjacent public land. </p> <p>Withdraws lands and interests within the Preserve from specified public land, mining, mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, and mineral materials laws. </p> <p>Prohibits road or building construction and motorized access within the area of volcanic domes and other peaks in the Preserve, except for administrative purposes.</p> <p>Ensures the protection of, and access to, traditional cultural and religious sites.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to study the feasibility of establishing a hiking trail along the rim of the Valles Caldera. Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to seek to enter into an agreement with the Indian tribe or pueblo respecting the establishment of a Caldera Rim Trail that will provide for the protection of cultural and religious sites. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Transfers administrative jurisdiction over the Preserve from the Secretary of Agriculture and the Valles Caldera Trust to the Secretary. Modifies the boundaries of Santa Fe National Forest to exclude the Preserve. </p> <p>Terminates the Valles Caldera Trust and sets forth provisions concerning its assets and liabilities, personnel, records, and funds.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Repeals the Valles Caldera Preservation Act and sets forth provisions concerning the effects of the repeal, including transfers of authority and boundaries.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Authorizes appropriations. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to designate the Valles Caldera National Preserve as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Valles Caldera National Preserve Management Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3452rs/xml/BILLS-111s3452rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-05-27T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3452is/xml/BILLS-111s3452is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-27</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 607.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
