<bill session="117" type="h" number="8012" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">State Department Training Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Department Training Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address the importance of foreign affairs training to national security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2022-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3492" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4653" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-13T14:32:34Z" status="Introduced in House">State Department Training Modernization Act

This bill makes changes to the Foreign Service Institute and addresses other issues related to training Foreign Service and Department of State Civil Service personnel.

The bill establishes within the institute (1) the Board of Visitors, which shall provide the State Department with advice and recommendations pertaining to the institute; and (2) the position of provost, which shall have duties such as overseeing and coordinating the institute's academic curriculum.

The State Department may establish and implement an incentive program to encourage Foreign Service members with critical foreign language skills to maintain such skills.

The bill also requires the State Department to expand its professional development and training, including by increasing offerings at partner organizations and offering courses using computer-based or computer-assisted simulations.

The Foreign Service must (1) establish new fellowship programs for Foreign Service and Civil Service officers that include opportunities in certain organizations, such as think tanks and industry entities; and (2) report to Congress on how to expand certain existing fellowship programs to allow fellows in those programs to undertake follow-on State Department opportunities that will benefit from practical knowledge of the people and processes of Congress.

The State Department must report to Congress on (1) offering certain training and professional development opportunities to congressional staff at State Department facilities, (2) a strategy for adapting and evolving training requirements to better meet current and future needs for 21st century diplomacy, and (3) a strategy for broadening and deepening training at the State Department.</summary>
</bill>
