<bill session="118" type="h" number="1824" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Food and Farm Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food and Farm Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the safety net for farmers and ranchers, enhance soil, water, and habitat conservation, encourage beginning farmers and ranchers, strengthen nutrition for Americans, support agriculture research and innovation, reduce food waste, improve animal welfare, and invest in regional food systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2023-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E271"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, Education and the Workforce, and Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Work and Welfare.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-27T16:22:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Food and Farm Act

 This bill reauthorizes and modifies several Department of Agriculture (USDA) programs that address

 commodity support, crop insurance, conservation, food assistance, nutrition, farm credit, beginning farmers and ranchers, food waste, research and educational programs, animal welfare, and regional food systems. The bill modifies agriculture and nutrition policies to

 repeal the Agriculture Risk Coverage Program and the Price Loss Coverage Program; impose additional limits on farm subsidies; extend crop insurance premium subsidies to farmers who plant crops to reduce erosion; require recipients of farm subsidies to comply with additional conservation requirements; authorize increased funding for conservation programs; authorize additional assistance under the Environmental Quality Incentives Program for organic farmers; establish a loan program for conservation-based structural improvements; increase Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program benefits; establish tax credits for the sale of qualified farming property to socially disadvantaged farmers or ranchers, veteran farmers or ranchers, and beginning farmers or ranchers (and the purchase of farming property by such farmers or ranchers); establish the Office of Food Waste within USDA; authorize additional funding for research and education programs; establish an independent animal welfare certification tax credit; require USDA to comply with certain animal welfare standards at federal agricultural research centers; and expand grant and loan programs for local and regional food systems.</summary>
</bill>
