<bill session="116" type="h" number="6216" updated="2022-08-10T23:33:14Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000126"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000588" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001083" joined="2020-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2020-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2020-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2020-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000168" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Office of Science and Technology Policy"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research ethics"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-14T20:30:10Z" status="Introduced in House">National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Act of 2020 

This bill establishes the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative and sets forth related activities.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy (OSTP) shall establish or designate the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative Office to carry out the responsibilities described in this bill with respect to the initiative.

The National Science and Technology Council shall establish or designate an Interagency Committee to coordinate federal programs and activities in support of the initiative.

The Department of Energy (DOE) shall establish the National Artificial Intelligence Advisory Committee to advise the President and the Initiative Office on matters related to the initiative. DOE must also carry out an artificial intelligence research and development program to (1) advance artificial intelligence tools, systems, capabilities, and workforce needs; and (2) improve the reliability of artificial intelligence methods and solutions relevant to DOE's mission.

The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall enter into a contract with the National Research Council of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a study of the current and future impact of artificial intelligence on the workforce of the United States.

The General Accountability Office shall conduct a study of artificial intelligence computer hardware and computing required in order to maintain U.S. leadership in artificial intelligence research and development.

The NSF shall establish a program to award financial assistance to eligible entities or their consortia to establish and support Artificial Intelligence Research Institutes.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology shall develop voluntary standards for artificial intelligence systems, among other things.

The NSF shall fund research and education activities in artificial intelligence systems and related fields.</summary>
</bill>
