<bill session="118" type="s" number="2018" updated="2025-11-19T03:21:26Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Connect Our Parks Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to conduct an assessment to identify locations in National Parks in which there is the greatest need for broadband internet access service and areas in National Parks in which there is the greatest need for cellular service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Connect Our Parks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connect Our Parks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Connect Our Parks Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-284.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-154.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-01-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="306">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 306.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7145" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7148-7149" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T17:26:20-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T18:05:04-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5919" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6492" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T14:12:04Z" status="Passed Senate">Connect Our Parks Act

This bill requires the National Park Service (NPS) to assess locations within the National Park System with the greatest need for broadband internet or cellular service, and to develop a plan for the placement of broadband and cellular infrastructure in parks.&#160;

In assessing where broadband service is most needed, the NPS must consider the current availability of broadband in housing, lodging, administrative facilities, developed campgrounds, and other areas within each park. In assessing where cellular service is most needed, the NPS must consider locations where the availability of cellular service in a developed area of a park would increase public access to emergency services and traveler information or the communications capabilities of NPS employees. The NPS must complete the assessment within one year of the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.&#160;

Further, within three years of the bill's enactment, the NPS must develop a plan based on the results of the assessment to install broadband and cellular service infrastructure at locations within the National Park System. In developing the plan, the NPS must consult with affected tribes and local stakeholders.&#160;

The plan must (1) be technology neutral; (2) provide for infrastructure to be located in previously developed areas or areas zoned for uses that would support infrastructure; and (3) avoid or minimize impacts to cultural and natural resources, the visitor experience, and park viewsheds. The plan must also provide for the use of public-private partnerships for the installation of equipment and provision of broadband or cellular service.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-154</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
