<bill session="116" type="h" number="7958" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Suppress COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Suppress COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To grant the authority for States to enter into interstate compacts or agreements for the purpose of procuring COVID-19 tests.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2020-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000582" joined="2020-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4458" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-02T15:59:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Suppress COVID-19 Act of 2020

This bill provides additional funding for states, tribes, and territories to procure tests and related supplies and undertake contact tracing and other public health measures to suppress COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) and the virus that causes it. It also reallocates certain other funding to jurisdictions for such public health measures. The additional amounts provided by the bill are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO) and the Senate PAYGO rule, which excludes the budget effects from being counted for purposes of enforcing the PAYGO rules.

In particular, the bill authorizes the formation of interstate compacts of states, tribes, and territories to procure COVID-19 tests and supplies, and it specifically reserves a portion of funding for jurisdictions that join compacts that meet requirements for transparency, governance, anti-corruption, and timeliness of test results. The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must also support the formation of, and cooperate with, these compacts.

The bill also provides additional funding, and reallocates existing funding, specifically for contact tracing and other public health measures. To receive such funding, a jurisdiction must submit a plan, developed with relevant stakeholders, to HHS that details how it will suppress COVID-19 to levels recommended by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. HHS must provide guidance and undertake other efforts to coordinate these plans, such as by developing shared indicators.

HHS must report within 30 days to Congress concerning the timeline for the distribution of these funds.</summary>
</bill>
