<bill session="116" type="s" number="3430" updated="2022-02-08T23:23:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of State Inclusivity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State Inclusivity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Lavender Offense Victim Exoneration Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">LOVE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote diversity at the Department of State, to direct the Secretary of State to review the termination characterization of former members of the Department who were fired by reason of the sexual orientation of the official, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1252" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-24T16:49:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of State Inclusivity Act of 2020

This bill establishes measures to promote diversity at the Department of State, and it offers a formal apology from Congress for encouraging policies at the State Department such as the Lavender Scare, which resulted in the wrongful termination of at least 1,000 people for alleged homosexuality.

The bill establishes a Chief Diversity Officer at the State Department to lead inclusion initiatives, support recruitment of a diverse workforce, recommend trainings on inclusivity, and ensure continued compliance with applicable laws and regulations.

The bill requires the State Department to

 report certain data regarding the diversity of its workforce; conduct interviews with current employees, and exit interviews with separating employees, to receive feedback on workplace policies, professional development opportunities, and other issues affecting diversity; expand anti-harassment, antidiscrimination, and implicit bias training and make such training mandatory for certain individuals; develop a pilot program to use gender-neutral terms in evaluation forms; review employee terminations to determine wrongful terminations based on sexual orientation and issue a report on the findings; establish a Reconciliation Board to contact an employee (or family member) improperly terminated during the Lavender Scare and offer to change the employee's record; establish a board to address issues faced by lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex Foreign Service employees and their families; and report on which countries refuse to issue spousal visas for Foreign Service employee spouses due to sexual orientation and recommend how to address this issue.</summary>
</bill>
