<bill session="117" type="s" number="4246" updated="2023-09-08T13:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AAIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AAIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advanced Aviation Infrastructure Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">AAIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Advanced Aviation Infrastructure Modernization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to provide grants related to advance air mobility infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2022-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2587-2588" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="646">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 646.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6270" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-27T15:33:23Z" status="Reported to Senate">Advanced Aviation Infrastructure Modernization Act or the AAIM Act

This bill establishes a pilot grant program to support advanced air mobility (AAM) infrastructure. AAM infrastructure refers to an air transportation system that transports individuals and property between points in the United States in both controlled and uncontrolled airspace using certain aircraft, including remotely piloted, autonomous, or vertical take-off and landing aircraft.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) must award planning grants for AAM infrastructure to (1) state, local, or tribal governments; (2) airport sponsors; (3) transit agencies; (4) port authorities; (5) metropolitan planning organizations; or (6) consortia of such entities. Entities that receive these grants must develop a comprehensive plan for AAM infrastructure, including vertiports (sites that support the landing, takeoff, loading, and other operations of vertical take-off and landing aircraft). Topics covered in the plan must address matters such as identifying locations for AAM infrastructure and available sources of funding. DOT must brief Congress about the plans it receives. The briefing must include an evaluation of the planned or proposed locations for vertiports and a description of best practices or lessons learned through the review of comprehensive plans.

Grants may not be awarded after September 30, 2023.

The Government Accountability Office must conduct a study on the interests, roles, and responsibilities of federal, state, local, and tribal government affected by AAM aircraft and operations.</summary>
</bill>
