<bill session="118" type="s" number="4446" updated="2025-11-19T04:30:03Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Construction Safety Team Enhancement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Construction Safety Team Enhancement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Construction Safety Team Act to enable the National Institute of Standards and Technology to investigate structures other than buildings to inform the development of engineering standards, best practices, and building codes related to such structures, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2024-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4143" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-06T22:25:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Construction Safety Team Enhancement Act of 2024

This bill expands the authority of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to investigate structural failures other than those involving buildings and to recommend related improvements to engineering standards and practices.

Specifically, the bill expands the investigative authority of NIST's National Construction Safety Teams. Currently, these teams are authorized to investigate the structural failure of a building that has resulted in substantial loss of life or that had the significant potential to cause a substantial loss of life. These teams must (1) identify the likely cause of the failure, (2) evaluate the technical aspects of evacuation and response procedures, and (3) recommend ways to improve building standards, codes, and practices and other related actions based on their findings.

The bill expands this authority beyond buildings to include other types of structures and related engineering standards and practices.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
