<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>275</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T20:05:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T20:05:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2007-01-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2007-02-16T21:29:26Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2007-01-31T17:54:13Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2007-01-11T23:55:15Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 110-27</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-02-16</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 53.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-02-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-27.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-02-16</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with amendments. With written report No. 110-27.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-01-31</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-01-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S458-459)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-01-11</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S458)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-01-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000407</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Domenici, Pete V. [R-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>PETE</firstName>
        <lastName>DOMENICI</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>VICHI</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2007-01-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2007-02-16T06:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 275, Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/18378</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on January 31, 2007&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2007-02-16T06:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 275, Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/18378</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on January 31, 2007</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Commemorations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National monuments</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Outdoor recreation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Paleontology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sports and Recreation</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-01-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-02-15T22:02:24Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act - Establishes the Prehistoric Trackways National Monument in New Mexico in order to conserve, protect, and enhance the unique and nationally important paleontological, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational resources and values of specified public land in Dona Ana County, New Mexico. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Monument; and (2) provide for public interpretation of, and education and scientific research on, the paleontological resources of the Monument, with priority given to exhibiting and curating the resources in Dona Ana County.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-02-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-03-22T22:03:04Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act - Establishes the Prehistoric Trackways National Monument in New Mexico in order to conserve, protect, and enhance the unique and nationally important paleontological, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational resources and values of specified public land in Dona Ana County, New Mexico. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary of the Interior, if additional paleontological resources are discovered on public land adjacent to the Monument, to make minor boundary adjustments to the Monument to include the resources in the Monument. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to manage the Monument: (1) in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources and values of the Monument; and (2) in accordance with this Act, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, and other applicable laws. </p> <p>Requires that the Monument be managed as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to develop a comprehensive management plan for the long-term protection and management of the Monument: (1) which shall describe the appropriate uses and management of the Monument and shall allow for continued scientific research at the Monument during the development of the plan; and (2) which may incorporate any appropriate decisions contained in any current management or activity plan for the land for the Monument and use information developed in studies of any land within or adjacent to the Monument that were conducted before the enactment of this Act. </p> <p>Instructs the Secretary to only allow uses of the Monument that would further the purposes for which it has been established. </p> <p> Requires the Secretary to provide for public interpretation of, and education and scientific research on, the paleontological resources of the Monument, with priority given to exhibiting and curating the resources in Dona Ana County. Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with appropriate public entities to carry out such activities.</p> <p>Prohibits the establishment of the Monument from changing the management status of any area within the boundary of the Monument that is: (1) designated as a wilderness study area and managed in accordance with provisions regarding the status of lands during the period of review and determination for designation as wilderness under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976; or (2) managed as an area of critical environmental concern. Provides that, if there is a conflict between the laws applicable to such areas and this Act, the more restrictive provision shall control.</p> <p>Permits the use of motorized vehicles in the Monument only on roads and trails designated for use by such vehicles under the management plan, except as needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency. </p> <p>Allows the Secretary to issue permits for special recreation events involving motorized vehicles within the Monument's boundaries, including the &quot;Chile Challenge:&quot; (1) to the extent the events do not harm paleontological resources; and (2) subject to any terms and conditions that the Secretary determines to be necessary. </p> <p>Withdraws any federal land within the Monument and any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States for inclusion in the Monument from: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing laws, geothermal leasing laws, and minerals materials laws. </p> <p>Permits grazing to continue in any area of the Monument in which grazing is currently allowed, subject to applicable laws (including regulations). </p> <p>Prohibits anything in this Act from constituting an express or implied reservation by the United States of any water or water rights with respect to the Monument. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish the Prehistoric Trackways National Monument in the State of New Mexico.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Prehistoric Trackways National Monument Establishment Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2007-02-16T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s275rs/xml/BILLS-110s275rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2007-01-11T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s275is/xml/BILLS-110s275is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2007-02-16</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 53.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
