<bill session="118" type="h" number="1775" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AUDIT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assessing Unintended Drivers of Illegal Trafficking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AUDIT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain bureaus of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development to release quarterly reviews of certain grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001218"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000317" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2024-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2024-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-29T21:45:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Assessing Unintended Drivers of Illegal Trafficking Act or the AUDIT Act

This bill prohibits certain federal agencies from giving grants to implementing partners that provide abortion services to asylum seekers. The bill also requires these agencies to submit quarterly reports to Congress on grants that the agencies have provided for migrant services programs in Central and South America.

The reporting requirements and grant prohibitions apply to (1) the U.S. Agency for International Development; (2) the Department of State's Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration; and (3) the State Department's Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor.

These federal agencies may not give grants to any implementing partners that (1) perform abortions, (2) provide health services that include referrals for abortions, or (3) provide assistance or funding in any manner for obtaining abortions.

Among other required elements, the quarterly reports for specified migrant services grants shall explain why each implementing partner was chosen, the amount of money the partner received, the availability of asylum claims processing in countries where those partners operate, and the number of asylum claims processed in those countries.</summary>
</bill>
