<bill session="110" type="s" number="2724" updated="2017-12-14T23:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CJ's Home Protection Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">CJ's Home Protection Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 to require that weather radios be installed in all manufactured homes manufactured or sold in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001233"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2008-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2008-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="2787" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Prefabricated buildings"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tornadoes"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-18T14:47:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CJ's Home Protection Act of 2008 - Amends the National Manufactured Housing Construction and Safety Standards Act of 1974 to revise federal standards for manufactured homes (other than one affixed to a permanent foundation) to require each such home to be installed with a weather radio: (1) capable of broadcasting emergency information relating to local weather conditions; (2) equipped with a tone alarm and Specific Alert Message Encoding, or SAME technology; and (3) compliant with the Consumer Electronics Association (CEA) Standard 2009-A Performance Specification for Public Alert Receivers (or its current revision).





Shields from common law civil liability: (1) manufacturers, installers, or retailers of manufactured homes for any aspect of the installation, furnishing, function, operation, performance, capabilities, or utilization of such a weather radio; and (2) the operator, owner, or employee of a manufactured home community, or the home manufacturer, with respect to the functionality of such a radio owing to any reminder, assistance, or instructions the community operator provides.

Exempts modular homes from such installation standards.

Requires the consensus committee established under such Act to develop and submit to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development a proposed standard for installed weather radios.

Requires the Secretary to study and report to specified congressional committees on conditioning the applicability of the weather radio installation requirement on the geographic location at which a manufactured home is placed.</summary>
</bill>
