<bill session="117" type="s" number="4107" updated="2023-08-08T19:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Civilian Harm Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Civilian Harm Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to establish in the Department of Defense a civilian harm investigation coordinator, to improve and make permanent the requirement that the Secretary of Defense submit an annual report on civilian harm in connection with United States military operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2022-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7621" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T19:03:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Defense Civilian Harm Transparency Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to designate a senior official to serve as the civilian harm investigation coordinator to conduct a review of each investigation of civilian harm and assess whether applicable laws, policies, guidelines, and processes were followed during the investigations. DOD must also appoint a general counsel to assist the coordinator with such duties.

The coordinator must annually submit to Congress a report on civilian harm resulting from U.S. military operations during the preceding year.

DOD must make publicly available in an electronic format a detailed list of all ex gratia payments (i.e., payments that are not legally required) and other payments in response to civilian harm paid by the United States. Some information may be excluded to ensure safety or privacy of payment recipients. DOD must provide specified information to Congress to certify the need for confidentiality.

DOD must provide an easily accessible electronic method by which individuals may request ex gratia or other condolence payments.</summary>
</bill>
