<bill session="117" type="sr" number="704" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing concern about economic and security conditions in Mexico and reaffirming the interest of the United States in mutually beneficial relations with Mexico based on shared interests on security, economic prosperity, and democratic values, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing concern about economic and security conditions in Mexico and reaffirming the interest of the United States in mutually beneficial relations with Mexico based on shared interests on security, economic prosperity, and democratic values, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2022-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3274-3275" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-14T19:30:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution reaffirms the interest of the United States in mutually beneficial relations with Mexico based on shared interests on security, economic prosperity, and democratic values.

The resolution reaffirms support for stronger economic relations with Mexico, including to strengthen the resiliency of critical supply chains in North America and the Western Hemisphere in general.

The resolution expresses deep concerns about the worsening investment climate in Mexico, and calls on the President to take meaningful actions to defend U.S. economic interests in Mexico and uphold the integrity of the United States-Mexico-Canada Agreement (USMCA).

The resolution also urges the President to address the humanitarian and security crisis at the border with Mexico.

Finally, the resolution urges the Mexican government to reduce the threat of deadly synthetic opioids.</summary>
</bill>
