<bill session="119" type="s" number="848" updated="2025-11-05T03:53:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2025-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-03">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Paul without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-11-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="255">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 255.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-10T16:39:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2025 or the REPORT Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and (as appropriate) the National&#160;Counterterrorism Center to submit a report to specified congressional committees whenever an act of domestic or international terrorism occurs in the United States.

Specifically, within one year after completion of the government investigation of the act of terrorism, these entities must submit a publicly accessible report including the facts of the event and recommendations for improving homeland or national security to prevent similar future acts. Information that could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution may be withheld. The requirement sunsets five years after the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.</summary>
</bill>
