<bill session="109" type="s" number="1904" updated="2018-02-03T22:27:41Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-20">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hurricane Katrina Elementary and Secondary Education Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Hurricane Katrina Students and Schools Impacted bill</title>
    <title type="display">Hurricane Katrina Elementary and Secondary Education Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide elementary and secondary education assistance to students and schools impacted by Hurricane Katrina.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2005-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11698-11699"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-10-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="253">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 253.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Impact aid"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Paraprofessional school personnel"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-02T22:34:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hurricane Katrina Elementary and Secondary Education Recovery Act - Provides elementary and secondary education assistance for schools and students affected by Hurricane Katrina.

Encourages the Secretary of Education to exercise the maximum waiver authority available or exercise other actions for affected states, local educational agencies (LEAs), and schools with respect to waiver authority or authorization of actions provided under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA). Directs the Secretary to report on affected state and LEA requests for waivers under ESEA and the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA).

Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to states for subgrants to LEAs: (1) to provide supplemental educational services or additional programs and activities to displaced students or students attending a school in an affected disaster area; and (2) in Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama, to restart operations of schools serving affected disaster areas.

Gives LEAS serving affected disaster areas special hold-harmless provisions for ESEA funding.

Provides reciprocity for affected teachers and paraprofessionals with respect to standards of other states. Authorizes the Secretary to delay certain teacher personnel standards requirements for Louisiana, Mississippi, and Alabama under ESEA and IDEA.

Directs the Secretary to provide: (1) assistance to LEAs serving affected homeless children and youth; (2) grants to states for alternative education programs for affected displaced adolescent students; and (3) temporary emergency impact aid to states and LEAs for affected displaced students.</summary>
</bill>
