<bill session="108" type="s" number="1230" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:44Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for additional responsibilities for the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security relating to geospatial information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-348.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="702">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 702.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3367" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Geographic information systems"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-27T16:20:21Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Office of the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) an Office of Geospatial Management to be administered by a Geospatial Information Officer, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of DHS and serve under the direction of the Chief Information Officer. Directs the Geospatial Information Officer to assist the Chief Information Officer in carrying out all functions under this Act and in coordinating the department's geographic information needs.

Directs the Chief Information Officer to establish and carry out a program to provide for the efficient use of geographic information, which shall include: (1) providing such geographic information as may be necessary to implement the critical infrastructure protection programs; (2) providing leadership and coordination in meeting the requirements of those responsible for planning, prevention, mitigation, assessment and response to emergencies, critical infrastructure protection, and other DHS functions; and (3) coordinating with users of geographic information within DHS to assure interoperability and prevent unnecessary duplication.

Includes among the Chief Information Officer's responsibilities: (1) coordinating DHS's geographic information needs and activities; (2) implementing standards, as adopted by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the processes established under provisions of the E-Government Act of 2002 relating to common protocols for geographic information systems, to facilitate the interoperability of geographic information pertaining to homeland security among all users of such information within DHS, State and local government, and the private sector; (3) coordinating with the Federal Geographic Data Committee and carrying out DHS's responsibilities pursuant to OMB Circular A-16 and Executive Order 12906; and (4) making recommendations to the Secretary and the Executive Director of the Office for State and Local Government Coordination and Preparedness on grants to fund the creation of geographic data and execute information sharing agreements regarding such data with State, local, and tribal governments.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-348</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
