<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1230</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T16:48:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T16:48:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-06-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2004-09-20T19:23:58Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2004-07-21T14:51:30Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-06-11T17:01:27Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 108-348</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>To provide for additional responsibilities for the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security relating to geospatial information.</title>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <number>3367</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2003-11-12</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and the Census.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 702.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-348.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-348.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-07-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000109</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Allard, Wayne [R-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>A.</firstName>
        <lastName>ALLARD</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <middleName>WAYNE</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2004-09-03T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1230, Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/15960</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs on July 21, 2004&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2004-09-03T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1230, Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/15960</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs on July 21, 2004</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Data banks</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Homeland Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>EBB Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electronic government information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive reorganization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-local relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-state relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Geodesy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Geographic information systems</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government procurement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Grants-in-aid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure (Economics)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maps</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Photography</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Remote sensing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Space activities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Standards</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Surveying</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-08-11T12:31:35Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Directs the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish and carry out a program to provide for the efficient use of geospatial information, which shall include: (1) providing such geospatial information as may be necessary to implement the critical infrastructure protection programs; (2) providing leadership in meeting the requirements of, and populating the databases used by, those responsible for planning, prevention, mitigation, assessment and response to emergencies, critical infrastructure and other DHS functions; and (3) assuring interoperability and preventing unnecessary duplication of geospatial information among all users.</p> Includes among the Chief Information Officer's responsibilities: (1) managing DHS geospatial information needs and activities; (2) establishing standards to assure the interoperability of geospatial information pertaining to homeland security among all users of such information within DHS, other agencies, State and local government, and the private sector; (3) coordinating with and providing liaison to the Federal Geographic Data Committee and carrying out DHS's responsibilities pursuant to Office of Management and Budget Circular A-16 and Executive Order 12906; (4) providing grants to fund data creation and to execute information sharing agreements with State, local, and tribal governments; and (5) ensuring that DHS utilizes available commercial geospatial data and services by awarding contracts to entities in the private sector.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-09-27T16:20:21Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish within the Office of the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) an Office of Geospatial Management to be administered by a Geospatial Information Officer, who shall be appointed by the Secretary of DHS and serve under the direction of the Chief Information Officer. Directs the Geospatial Information Officer to assist the Chief Information Officer in carrying out all functions under this Act and in coordinating the department's geographic information needs.</p> <p>Directs the Chief Information Officer to establish and carry out a program to provide for the efficient use of geographic information, which shall include: (1) providing such geographic information as may be necessary to implement the critical infrastructure protection programs; (2) providing leadership and coordination in meeting the requirements of those responsible for planning, prevention, mitigation, assessment and response to emergencies, critical infrastructure protection, and other DHS functions; and (3) coordinating with users of geographic information within DHS to assure interoperability and prevent unnecessary duplication.</p> <p>Includes among the Chief Information Officer's responsibilities: (1) coordinating DHS's geographic information needs and activities; (2) implementing standards, as adopted by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) under the processes established under provisions of the E-Government Act of 2002 relating to common protocols for geographic information systems, to facilitate the interoperability of geographic information pertaining to homeland security among all users of such information within DHS, State and local government, and the private sector; (3) coordinating with the Federal Geographic Data Committee and carrying out DHS's responsibilities pursuant to OMB Circular A-16 and Executive Order 12906; and (4) making recommendations to the Secretary and the Executive Director of the Office for State and Local Government Coordination and Preparedness on grants to fund the creation of geographic data and execute information sharing agreements regarding such data with State, local, and tribal governments.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for additional responsibilities for the Chief Information Officer of the Department of Homeland Security relating to geospatial information.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Homeland Security Geographic Information Act of 2004</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2004-09-20T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-06-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 702.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
