<bill session="111" type="h" number="2192" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:28Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate Change Safeguards for Natural Resources Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an integrated Federal program to protect, restore, and conserve the Nation's natural resources in response to the threats of climate change and ocean acidification.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Change Safeguards for Natural Resources Conservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000327" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000011" joined="2009-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2009-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1025-1026"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Science and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-06T15:40:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Climate Change Safeguards for Natural Resources Conservation Act - Requires the President to establish: (1) a national Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Strategy to protect, restore, and conserve natural resources to enable them to become more resilient, adapt to, and withstand the impacts of climate change and ocean acidification and to identity opportunities to mitigate those impacts; and (2) a Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Panel to serve as a forum for interagency consultation on and the coordination of the development and implementation of such Strategy. Requires each agency represented on the Panel to complete and revise every five years an adaptation plan implementing such Strategy.

Directs the Chair of the Council of Environmental Quality to: (1) chair the Panel; (2) advise the President on the Strategy and agency adaptation plans; and (3) coordinate agency natural resources actions in response to climate change and ocean acidification.

Requires the Secretaries of Commerce and the Interior to: (1) establish a coordinated process for developing and providing science and information needed to assess and address the impacts of climate change and ocean acidification on natural resources; (2) undertake a climate change and ocean acidification impact survey; and (3) establish a Science Advisory Board to advise the Secretaries on state-of-the-art science regarding the impacts of climate change and ocean acidification on natural resources and on scientific strategies and mechanisms for protecting, restoring, and conserving natural resources.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) establish the National Climate Change and Wildlife Science Center within the U.S. Geological Survey (USGS); (2) establish a National Fish and Wildlife Habitat and Corridors Information Program; and (3) develop a Habitat and Corridors Information System.



Establishes in the Treasury the Natural Resources Climate Change Adaptation Account. Requires each state, to be eligible for funding from such Account, to prepare and update every five years a natural resources adaptation plan to address the potential impacts of climate change and ocean acidification on its natural resources and coastal areas. Provides for the allocation of such Account funds for specified state and federal natural resources adaptation activities.</summary>
</bill>
