<bill session="116" type="h" number="6893" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">More PPP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the CARES Act and the Small Business Act to make certain adjustments to the paycheck protection program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Opportunities a Reality for Entrepreneurs Paycheck Protection Program</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More PPP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2020-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-23T14:46:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Making Opportunities a Reality for Entrepreneurs Paycheck Protection Program or the More PPP Act

This bill provides additional funding for and modifies the Paycheck Protection Program established to support small businesses in response to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill increases funding for paycheck protection loans by $560 billion, and it provides additional funding of $571 billion for paycheck protection loans through FY2021. Further, the bill sets aside $200 billion for paycheck protection loans to businesses and nonprofit organizations with 25 or fewer employees, sole proprietors, independent contractors, and self-employed individuals.

The bill also modifies eligibility for the program by (1) making publicly traded companies ineligible to participate, and (2) requiring borrowers to certify a decline in revenue of 20% or more. Further, the bill makes it unlawful for a lender to discriminate against or give preferential treatment to any eligible recipient.

The Small Business Administration must report on the demographic data, including race, gender, and ethnicity, of paycheck protection loan recipients.</summary>
</bill>
