<bill session="112" type="h" number="3536" updated="2021-09-28T14:18:19Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Roads for America Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Safe Roads for America Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to delay certain target compliance dates for minimum retroreflectivity level standards applicable to traffic signs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000362" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2012-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2011-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-03-05T22:03:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Roads for America Act of 2011 - Requires the Secretary of Transportation to modify the target compliance dates for the following minimum retroreflectivity level standards: (1) implementation and continued use of an assessment or management method that is designed to maintain traffic sign retroreflectivity at or above the established minimum levels; (2) replacement of regulatory, warning, and post-mounted guide (except street name) signs identified using the assessment or management method as failing to meet the established minimum levels; and (3) replacement of street name signs and overhead guide signs that are identified using the assessment or management method as failing to meet the established minimum levels.

 Requires the Secretary to revise the notice of proposed amendments published in the Federal Register on August 31, 2011, to incorporate the new target compliance dates.

Includes measures designed to meet a state-established performance standard, federal regulation, or requirement contained in the Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices relating to minimum levels of retroreflectivity as projects for purposes of the highway safety improvement program.

Allows a maximum 100% federal share of the costs of construction related to maintaining minimum levels of retroreflectivity of highway signs or pavement markings.

Directs the Secretary to issue standards for the use of funds apportioned to a state for highway safety improvement projects to upgrade highway signs and pavement markings in order to meet or exceed minimum maintained levels of retroreflectivity. Requires such standards to prohibit fund use for maintenance activities.</summary>
</bill>
