<bill session="109" type="h" number="5893" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:35Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Private Security Officer Employment Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to provide for National Crime Information Center criminal history records checks of the employees and prospective employees of providers of private security services and to require such providers to employ only those employees whose records checks do not show a history of certain offenses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Private Security Officer Employment Enhancement Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Receiving stolen goods"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-28T22:00:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Private Security Officer Employment Enhancement Act of 2006 - Amends the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security, upon request by a covered employer (certain non-governmental companies that provide security guard services or that have more than 50 employees of which at least three are internal security employees), to provide for a National Crime Information Center (NCIC) criminal history records check on a current or prospective employee. Requires such request to include fingerprints.

Prohibits such an employer from employing such an employee to provide any security service unless: (1) the employer first obtains the results of an NCIC criminal history records check; and (2) neither the results of that check nor any other information made available to the employer indicate that the employee has any unpardoned convictions under federal or state law of any felony or specified offenses.

Prohibits such an employer from making such a request without the employee's consent. Requires an employer to ensure that information received is maintained confidentially, not misused, and destroyed within a specified time. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures to ensure that the Department of Homeland Security properly uses the results.

Provides criminal penalties for knowingly and intentionally using any information obtained for a purpose other than determining suitability for employment.</summary>
</bill>
