<bill session="118" type="h" number="5862" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:16Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-17T17:11:56-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-01-17T17:11:56-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 relating to authority of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to consolidate, modify, or reorganize Customs revenue functions.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 relating to authority of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to consolidate, modify, or reorganize Customs revenue functions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2023-10-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 40 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16T17:09:09-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (NE) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16T17:09:25-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H141-143" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16T17:09:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5862.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-16T17:20:02-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17T16:30:48-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H175-176" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="12" datetime="2024-01-17T17:11:56-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 403 - 9 (Roll no. 12).</text>
      <reference ref="1/16/2024 CR H141" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17T17:11:57-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4183" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-16T21:13:56Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill expands the authority of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to consolidate, modify, or reorganize customs revenue functions.

For example, this bill authorizes CBP to add functions to existing positions that perform these revenue functions. CBP may also establish new job series and grades for personnel that perform these functions.

The bill also modifies a provision that prohibits CBP from reducing the staffing level of certain revenue functions (e.g., import specialists, entry specialists, and customs auditors). Specifically, this bill relaxes this prohibition by allowing for reductions if the reduction will not result in a staffing level below the optimal level as determined in a specified resource allocation model. (Currently, CBP is required to report to Congress every two years the results of this model to determine the optimal staffing levels for carrying out CBP commercial operations.)

The bill also expands this staffing level reduction restriction to also apply to national account managers and international trade analysts.</summary>
</bill>
