<bill session="119" type="s" number="323" updated="2025-10-23T16:50:16Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLAN for Broadband Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLAN for Broadband Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to develop a National Strategy to Synchronize Federal Broadband Programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="866" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-16T12:18:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Proper Leadership to Align Networks for Broadband Act or the PLAN for Broadband Act

This bill requires the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to develop and implement a national strategy to improve the coordination and management of federal broadband programs and agency consideration of applications to build or maintain broadband infrastructure on federal property.&#160;

The NTIA must also develop and publish for public comment a plan for the implementation of the national strategy. Among other requirements, the implementation plan must establish, for federal broadband programs that are not technologically neutral (i.e., programs&#160;that involve a preference for certain broadband technologies), a ceiling on the amount of funding that may be awarded to support the provision of broadband service to a single location.&#160;

The bill also requires executive branch agencies to identify and address factors that contribute to delays in their review of applications for easements, rights-of-way, or leases related to communications infrastructure projects on federal property. (Under current law, agencies are generally required to act on such applications within 270 days.) Agencies must also establish methods to alert employees when the agency is at risk of failing to meet the 270-day deadline with respect to a particular application.&#160;

Finally, the bill lowers the cost threshold for certain broadband infrastructure projects to qualify as covered projects under the Fixing America's Surface Transportation (FAST) Act from $200 million to $5 million. Such projects qualify for expedited federal environmental review.</summary>
</bill>
