<bill session="117" type="h" number="3629" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PARK IT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to finalize rules to protect consumers from the risks of motor vehicle rollaways and carbon monoxide poisoning from keyless ignition motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PARK IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Americans from the Risks of Keyless Ignition Technology Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1551" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1268" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-10T18:38:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Americans from the Risks of Keyless Ignition Technology Act or the PARK IT Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to finalize regulations relating to automatic shutoff systems for motor vehicles and standards to prevent the movement of vehicles in specific situations.

Specifically, DOT must require manufacturers to install technology in each motor vehicle with a keyless ignition device and an internal combustion engine to automatically shut off the motor vehicle after the motor vehicle has idled for a period necessary to prevent carbon monoxide poisoning. It must also require the technology in each motor vehicle with a keyless ignition device and automatic transmission to prevent movement (i.e., rollaway) of the motor vehicle if (1) the transmission of the motor vehicle is not in the park setting, (2) the motor vehicle does not exceed the speed determined by DOT, (3) the door for the operator of the motor vehicle is open, (4) the seat belt of the operator of the motor vehicle is unbuckled, and (5) the service brake of the motor vehicle is not engaged.</summary>
</bill>
