<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1215" updated="2022-02-03T05:59:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5325" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-06-06T13:47:46-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000822"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-06-05"/>
  <description>Amendment prohibits the use of funds to be used by the Department of Energy to subordinate any loan obligation to other financing in violation of section 1702 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 or to subordinate any Guaranteed Obligation to any loan or other debt obligations in violation of section 609.10 of title 10 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to be used by the Department of Energy to subordinate any loan obligation to other financing in violation of section 1702 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 or to subordinate any Guaranteed Obligation to any loan or other debt obligations in violation of section 609.10 of title 10 of the Code of Federal Regulations.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-06-06T13:47:46-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="320">
      <text>On agreeing to the Stearns amendment (A046) Agreed to by recorded vote: 348 - 60 (Roll no. 320).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3496" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T21:15:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A046) offered by Mr. Stearns.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3465-3466" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3465" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T13:47:46-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T13:47:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Stearns amendment (A046) Agreed to by recorded vote: 348 - 60 (Roll no. 320).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3496" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-06T13:47:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05T21:15:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A046) offered by Mr. Stearns.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3465-3466" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3465" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-05">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
