<bill session="117" type="h" number="2205" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Incentivizing Value Capture for Greener Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide grants and develop value capture policy.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Incentivizing Value Capture for Greener Transportation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-22T15:53:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Incentivizing Value Capture for Greener Transportation Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Transportation (DOT) to provide technical assistance grants to states and local governments to (1) develop more state and local value capture mechanisms for long-term funding that promote mobility, public transportation, and affordable transit-oriented development; (2) improve public transportation and mobility; and (3) develop strategic partnerships that create greater self-help capacity that leads to greater long term and robust investments in public transportation, mobility, inclusive economic development, and affordable transit-oriented development.

DOT must

 establish voluntary and consensus-based value capture standards, policies, and best practices for state and local value capture mechanisms that promote greater investments in public transportation and affordable transit-oriented development; make available to the public a report cataloging examples of state and local laws and policies that provide for value capture and value sharing that promote such investments; and identify and disseminate examples of best practices where states and local governments have adopted value capture and value sharing mechanisms that have successfully provided for such investments.</summary>
</bill>
