<bill session="118" type="s" number="197" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Values Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Values Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permanently enact certain appropriations Act restrictions on the use of funds for abortions and involuntary sterilizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2023-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-24T21:22:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Values Act

This bill expands restrictions on using U.S. foreign assistance to pay for or promote abortions, involuntary sterilizations, or other related activities.

Specifically, the bill expands existing prohibitions, including prohibitions against using foreign assistance to pay for abortions or involuntary sterilization for family planning, to apply to all assistance provided under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (FAA). (Currently, these prohibitions apply to only certain parts of the FAA.)

Furthermore, assistance provided under the FAA may not be made available to (1) pay for lobbying for or against abortion, or (2) any organization involved in managing a program of coercive abortion or involuntary sterilization. (These prohibitions have typically been in appropriations acts, but the bill would make the prohibitions a permanent part of the FAA.)

The bill also makes permanent a prohibition against using funds made available to the Peace Corps to pay for abortions.</summary>
</bill>
