<bill session="116" type="h" number="4175" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:10Z">
  <state datetime="2019-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to promote safe and reliable interconnection and net billing for community solar facilities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001111" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2019-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-25T20:14:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Renewable Energy with Shared Solar Act of 2019

This bill requires an electric utility to provide interconnection and net billing service for community solar facilities. (A community solar facility is a solar photovoltaic system that allocates electricity to multiple individual electric consumers of an electric utility and has a nameplate rating of 2 megawatts or less.)

Specifically, the bill requires each state regulatory authority and nonregulated electric utility to commence consideration of and determine ratemaking standards that allow community solar facilities to be connected to the power distribution system.

The bill does not apply in the case of any electric utility in a state if (1) the state has implemented the standard in accordance with the bill (or a comparable one) for the electric utility, (2) the state regulatory authority or the relevant nonregulated electric utility has conducted a proceeding to consider implementation of the standard (or a comparable one) for the electric utility, or (3) the state legislature has voted on the implementation of the standard (or a comparable one) for the electric utility.</summary>
</bill>
