<bill session="108" type="h" number="957" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Broker Accountability through Enhanced Transparency Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance investor confidence by providing investors with easy online access to complete information about securities firms and their brokers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broker Accountability through Enhanced Transparency Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000163" joined="2003-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2003-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets, Insurance and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Brokers"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Stock exchanges"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Broker Accountability Through Enhanced Transparency Act of 2003 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to revise the requirements a registered securities association must meet for receiving and responding to inquiries regarding disciplinary actions involving its members and their associated persons. Requires such an association to establish and maintain: (1) a system for collecting and retaining registration information, including disciplinary actions, on its members and their associated persons; and (2) a readily accessible electronic or other process (in addition to the currently required toll-free telephone listing) to receive and promptly respond to inquiries pertaining to such information, including registration information that has been reported to the association by any registered national securities exchange involving its members and their associated persons.Shields such association from liability for actions taken or omitted to implement this Act.Amends the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to shield from liability for actions taken or omitted by any entity designated by the Securities Exchange Commission as the entity through which an investment adviser may be required to file any required fee, application, report, or notice.</summary>
</bill>
