<bill session="116" type="h" number="6017" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Twenty-First Century Courts Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for the establishment of a code of conduct for the justices of the Supreme Court, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Twenty-First Century Courts Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2020-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2020-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8235" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4988" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T15:57:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Twenty-First Century Courts Act

This bill requires that certain information regarding Supreme Court Justices, federal judges, and court proceedings be made publicly available. It also requires the Supreme Court to establish a code of ethics for Justices.

If a Justice or judge disqualifies himself or herself from a case, the relevant court must publish on its website a notice explaining the circumstances of the disqualification, with exceptions for health and privacy concerns. In addition, the financial disclosure of each Justice and judge must be available on a public website.

Audio recordings of public proceedings before the Supreme Court or a federal court of appeals must be made available online in real time to the extent practicable. The recordings must remain available online for specified lengths of time.

Additionally, the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts must establish a single system for all public federal court records. The system must be publicly accessible at no cost.</summary>
</bill>
