<bill session="119" type="h" number="1784" updated="2025-03-27T15:18:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Fraud Detection and Deterrence Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Fraud Detection and Deterrence Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to strengthen health care waste, fraud, and abuse provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000399"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-26T20:53:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicare Fraud Detection and Deterrence Act of 2025

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to deactivate the standard unique health identifiers of health care providers that are excluded from federal health care programs because of fraud, waste, or abuse.

The bill also requires (1) any data submitted by Medicare Advantage plans with respect to durable medical equipment, prosthetics or orthotics, laboratory tests, imaging tests, or home health services to include the standard unique health identifier of the associated provider or supplier; and (2) health care practitioners who are employed by or contract with telehealth companies to use a specialized claims modifier (developed by CMS) for Medicare telehealth services.</summary>
</bill>
