<bill session="117" type="h" number="2910" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program to improve the ability of veterans to access medical care in medical facilities of the Department of Veterans Affairs and in the community by providing the veterans the ability to choose health care providers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Health Care Freedom Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2022-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000596" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2021-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001136" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2022-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2021-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3603" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-28T11:28:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Health Care Freedom Act

This bill requires the Center for Innovation for Care and Payment within the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a three-year pilot program to improve the ability of veterans who are enrolled in the VA health care system to access hospital care, medical services, and extended care services through the covered care system by providing such veterans with the ability to choose health care providers. Under the bill, the covered care system includes VA medical facilities, health care providers participating in the Veterans Community Care Program (VCCP), and eligible entities or providers that have entered into a Veterans Care Agreement.

A veteran participating in the program may elect to receive care at any provider in the covered care system.

The pilot program removes certain requirements (e.g., location of the veteran) to access care at VA and non-VA facilities. After four years, the bill permanently phases out the requirements for accessing care under the VCCP and Veterans Care Agreements and requires the VA to provide such care under the same conditions of the pilot program. Additionally, after four years, veterans may receive care at a VA medical facility regardless of whether the facility is in the same Veterans Integrated Service Network as the veteran.</summary>
</bill>
