<bill session="115" type="s" number="2035" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing America's Voting Equipment Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide increased security for the voting systems of the United States, to protect against intrusion, theft, manipulation, and deletion of voter registration data and ballots, or votes cast, and to prevent cyberattacks from malicious computer hackers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2017-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-22T14:12:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing America's Voting Equipment Act of 2017 or the SAVE Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security to (1) designate voting systems as critical infrastructure and include threats to such systems in national planning scenarios, (2) conduct a threat assessment of voting systems and develop best practices to address such threats, (3) establish a program to award grants to states to implement such best practices, and (4) establish a hacking contest and bug bounty program directed at finding voting-system vulnerabilities.

The bill also directs (1) the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to establish a program for sharing classified information about voting-system threats with state election officials, and (2) the Government Accountability Office to conduct periodic voting-system audits.</summary>
</bill>
