<bill session="118" type="s" number="945" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with amendments. With written report No. 118-46.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="112">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 112.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1693" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-06T22:13:32Z" status="Reported to Senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2023 or the REPORT Act of 2023

This bill requires specified federal agencies to report to Congress concerning any act of terrorism that occurs in the United States.

Whenever an act of terrorism occurs, the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Justice, the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and, as appropriate, the National Counterterrorism Center, must submit to Congress an unclassified report, which may be accompanied by a classified annex. The unclassified report shall be made available on a publicly available website. Each unclassified report and classified annex shall be made available upon request by any Member of Congress.

Such report shall (1) include a statement of the facts of the act of terrorism, (2) identify any gaps in homeland or national security to prevent future acts of terrorism, and (3) include any recommendations for additional measures to improve homeland or national security.

If the reporting agencies determine that any information required to be reported could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution, such agencies may withhold such information from reporting and shall notify Congress of that determination.

Reports required under this bill may be combined into a quarterly report submitted to Congress.

This bill shall terminate five years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-46</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
