<bill session="118" type="s" number="3621" updated="2025-11-19T04:52:44Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medical Device Nonvisual Accessibility Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Device Nonvisual Accessibility Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish nonvisual accessibility standards for certain devices with digital interfaces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-01-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1328" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-24T19:38:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medical Device Nonvisual Accessibility Act of 2024

This bill requires certain medical devices with a digital interface to meet nonvisual accessibility standards established by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA).

Specifically, the FDA must establish regulations to require a Class II or Class III medical device with a digital interface to provide a blind or low-vision user access to the same services and information, and generally the same ease of use, as provided to a user who is not low-vision or blind. (The FDA classifies medical devices in three classes. Class I devices are low-risk, Class II devices are moderate-risk, and Class III devices are high-risk.)

A Class II or Class III medical device that does not meet the nonvisual accessibility standards established under this bill may not be sold. However, the FDA may waive the bill's requirements for a device upon a showing that applying the standards would fundamentally alter the nature of the device or create an undue hardship for the manufacturer. The bill also does not apply to devices that are intended solely for use by a health care provider or in a setting outside the home.</summary>
</bill>
