<bill session="118" type="h" number="4154" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Welfare for the Wealthy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Welfare for the Wealthy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to close the nominal benefits loophole.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001118"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001317" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2023-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2023-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001082" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2024-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2024-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-19T22:19:23Z" status="Introduced in House">No Welfare for the Wealthy Act of 2023

This bill requires all households participating in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) to meet the program's income and asset requirements.

Federal requirements generally provide two pathways for SNAP financial eligibility. A household may meet program-specific federal eligibility requirements, which include both income eligibility and an asset test. A household may also be automatically or&#160;categorically eligible for SNAP based on eligibility for or receiving cash benefits from other specified low-income assistance programs (e.g., Temporary Assistance for Needy Families [TANF]). Under this categorical eligibility, households that already meet financial eligibility rules in a program like TANF are not required to go through another financial eligibility determination in SNAP.

Further, a majority of states also provide broad-based categorical eligibility (BBCE), a policy that makes most households with an income below a certain threshold categorically eligible for SNAP. Under BBCE, these states typically make households&#160;categorically eligible through receiving or being authorized to receive a minimal non-cash TANF benefit or service (e.g., a pamphlet). A state may set its own BBCE financial eligibility requirements for a household so long as the income requirement is below a certain level. A state's&#160;requirements do not have to match SNAP program-specific eligibility requirements. For example, most states that provide BBCE do not have an asset test for SNAP eligibility.&#160;

The bill requires all SNAP households, including those that qualify under categorical eligibility, to meet the SNAP program's income and asset requirements. These requirements take effect one year after the bill's enactment and do not apply to certification periods that begin before the effective date.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
