<bill session="111" type="s" number="2762" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:07Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">San Juan Mountains Wilderness Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain lands in San Miguel, Ouray, and San Juan Counties, Colorado, as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">San Juan Mountains Wilderness Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11346-11347"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11347-11349" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3914" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-02T17:30:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">San Juan Mountains Wilderness Act of 2009 - Designates specified lands in the Grand Mesa, Uncompahgre, and Gunnison National Forests and the San Juan Resource Area of the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) in Colorado as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Designates specified lands in such National Forests and San Juan National Forest as the Sheep Mountain Special Management Area.

Withdraws lands designated as wilderness or a special management area under this Act, as well as land within the Naturita Canyon Mineral Withdrawal Area, from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.

Sets forth provisions regarding water rights and access to and the operation of water resource facilities in lands designated as wilderness or a special management area by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
