<bill session="118" type="h" number="2603" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:00Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise certain thresholds related to smaller reporting companies, accelerated filers, and large accelerated filers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise certain thresholds related to smaller reporting companies, accelerated filers, and large accelerated filers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-27T19:57:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to increase threshold amounts that qualify companies as smaller reporting companies, accelerated filers, and large accelerated filers for purposes of SEC reporting requirements. The bill (1) increases the revenue and public float amounts under which a company qualifies as a smaller reporting company, (2) changes threshold requirements for smaller reporting companies from annual revenues to three-year rolling average revenues, (3) increases the aggregate worldwide market value of equity for a company to qualify as a large accelerated filer, (4) increases the market values below which a company exits accelerated filer or large accelerated filer status, and (5) excludes smaller reporting companies from status as accelerated filers or large accelerated filers.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
