<bill session="114" type="s" number="2376" updated="2023-01-11T13:32:22Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2015-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Attorney General to make competitive grants to State, tribal, and local governments to establish and maintain witness protection and assistance programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="4194" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-03-24T15:05:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2015

 This bill directs the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award competitive matching grants to state, local, and tribal governments to establish or maintain witness protection programs in cases related to: (1) a homicide, serious violent felony, or serious drug offense; or (2) gangs or organized crime.

DOJ must evaluate grant applications based on certain criteria, including the prevalence of witness intimidation, the presence of organized crime, and the per capita number of homicides, violent felonies, or serious drug offenses.

 The bill also requires DOJ to: (1) consider urban and rural applicants and ensure equitable geographic distribution of grant awards; and (2) develop and disseminate best practice models to help state, local, and tribal governments address witness protection and assistance issues.</summary>
</bill>
