<bill session="111" type="h" number="3743" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:21Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-06T10:39:35-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-11-06T10:39:35-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Disaster Readiness and Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to improve the disaster relief programs of the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Small Business Disaster Readiness and Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Disaster Readiness and Reform Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000557"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Finance and Tax.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-21">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated into H.R. 3854.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:30:17-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Velazquez moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:30:18-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12471-12473" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:30:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3743.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2009-11-06T10:39:35-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12471-12472" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-11-06T10:39:36-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM19" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="Finance and Tax" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3854" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-15T14:39:55Z" status="Passed House amended">Small Business Disaster Readiness and Reform Act of 2009 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Small Business Act to prohibit the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA), in making a small business disaster loan of $250,000 or less, from requiring a borrower to use the borrower's home as collateral.

(Sec. 3) Increases the SBA disaster loan limit to $3 million. Prohibits the Administrator from requiring repayment on such loans until 12 months after final disbursement of the approved loan amount.

(Sec. 5) Provides specific disbursement directions for each of the following categories of loans: (1) $150,000 or less; (2) more than $150,000 up to $500,000; and (3) more than $500,000.

(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Administrator to make a disaster assistance grant of up to $100,000 to a small business that: (1) is located in an area affected by a major disaster; (2) certifies its intention to reestablish the business in the same county as originally located; (3) has applied and was rejected for a conventional disaster assistance loan; and (4) was in existence for at least two years before the disaster declaration. Provides a grant priority for small businesses determined to be economically viable but unable to meet short-term financial obligations. Authorizes grants of $100 million for each of FY2010-FY2011 and authorizes appropriations for such grants.

(Sec. 7) Directs the Administrator to develop a disaster preparedness and response plan for each SBA region. Requires each plan to identify the three disasters, natural or manmade, most likely to occur in such region.

(Sec. 8) Authorizes the Administrator to make outreach grants for loan application assistance to the following in areas affected by a disaster: (1) a women's business center; (2) a small business development center; (3) a veterans business outreach center; and (4) a chamber of commerce. Authorizes grants for each of FY2010-FY2011.

(Sec. 9) Authorizes the Administrator to make a loan to any homeowner whose primary residence has been adversely impacted by the installation of toxic drywall manufactured in China. Allows the loan to be used only for the repair or replacement of such drywall.

(Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations for FY2010-FY2011 for administrative expenses and small business disaster assistance loans.</summary>
</bill>
