<bill session="109" type="h" number="2417" updated="2022-02-03T05:27:42Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Drinking Water Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="display">Community Drinking Water Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to establish a program to provide assistance to small communities for use in carrying out projects and activities necessary to achieve or maintain compliance with drinking water standards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000789"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2005-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF15" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="689" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arsenic"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-07T18:25:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Drinking Water Assistance Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a program of grants for small public water systems (those serving populations of not more than 200,000 or located in specified communities) in disadvantaged communities, or in those that may become disadvantaged as a result of compliance with drinking water standards, for use in carrying out projects and activities to comply with such standards. Requires the Administrator to: (1) give priority in awarding grants based on, first, the financial need of the community and, second, the per capita cost of the community's compliance; and (2) ensure that not less than 20 percent of grant funds are used for activities in communities with populations of less than 50,000. Sets forth the process for applications. Limits the Federal share of costs for grant-funded activities to 90 percent of the total.

Provides temporary relief from enforcement of drinking water standards for eligible entities during and after the grant application process.

Delays implementation or enforcement by the Administrator of an arsenic standard in any State until the earlier of January 1, 2006, or the date on which the Administrator certifies that the program has been implemented in that State and the State has made substantial progress in drinking water standards compliance.</summary>
</bill>
