<bill session="117" type="s" number="876" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Food Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to make loan guarantees and grants to finance certain improvements to school lunch facilities, to train school food service personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Food Modernization Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1651" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4379" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-01T15:43:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Food Modernization Act of 2021

This bill provides for loan guarantees and grants to support healthy meals under the National School Lunch Program and School Breakfast Program.

The bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to issue loan guarantees to local educational agencies (LEAs), school food authorities, tribal organizations, and other eligible entities to finance infrastructure improvements or equipment purchases to facilitate their provision of healthy meals through the school meal programs.

USDA must also award competitive matching grants to assist LEAs, school food authorities, tribal organizations, and other eligible entities in purchasing the durable equipment and infrastructure they need to serve healthier meals and improve food safety.

USDA must give preference under both programs to applicants that demonstrate a substantial or disproportionate need for food service infrastructure or durable equipment, and shall establish fees for the loan guarantee program.

In addition, USDA must award competitive matching grants to experienced third-party training institutions to provide school food service personnel with the training and technical assistance they need to (1) meet or exceed nutrition standards under the school meal programs, and (2) improve the efficacy and efficiency of the school meal programs.</summary>
</bill>
