<bill session="118" type="h" number="8488" updated="2024-11-15T09:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farmer to Farmer Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmer to Farmer Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to expand the provision of farmer-led technical assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2024-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2024-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2024-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2614" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-28T18:12:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Farmer to Farmer Education Act of 2024

This bill expands the authority of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to provide technical assistance for farmer-to-farmer networks. A farmer-to-farmer network means any affiliation or association of farmers that share information, technical assistance, or any other type of mutually beneficial support.

Under the bill, USDA may enter into cooperative agreements with eligible entities to provide assistance to farmer-to-farmer networks to (1) build network capacity, connect farmers with mentors or group learning opportunities, and support goal setting; (2) increase technical assistance for farmers, ranchers, and forest owners who use different farming models, practices, and scales; and (3) establish and steward the networks.

Those eligible for the program include nonprofit entities, farmer-to-farmer networks, tribal entities, local governments, institutions of higher education, and states. USDA must prioritize&#160;agreements with entities that seek to meet the specific needs of certain farmers, ranchers, and forest owners who are historically underserved or operating in high-poverty areas.

The bill also provides for subawards to plan and conduct events, as well as to identify and develop innovative activities, in order to increase farmer access to farmer-to-farmer assistance. USDA and the Natural Resources Conservation Service must establish any necessary additional requirements for subawards.</summary>
</bill>
