<bill session="117" type="h" number="4681" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish a new class of nonimmigrant visas for entrepreneurs and essential employees affiliated with start-up entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">LIKE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Let Immigrants Kickstart Employment Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LIKE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2021-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2022-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2022-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-05T17:00:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Let Immigrants Kickstart Employment Act of 2021 or the LIKE Act

This bill establishes a new class of nonimmigrant visa (W visa) for qualifying start-up owners and essential employees (and the accompanying spouse or child of such aliens) and addresses related issues.

Under this bill, a start-up is a U.S. entity that has lawfully conducted business and was formed in the five years preceding an application for a start-up owner visa.

To be eligible for an initial visa as a start-up owner, an individual must (1) possess at least a 10% interest in the start-up; (2) play a central and active role in the start-up's management or operations; (3) possess knowledge, skills, or experience to substantially assist in the start-up's growth and success; and (4) provide evidence that the start-up has received certain investments, created jobs, or generated revenue.

The holder of a nonimmigrant start-up owner visa may receive lawful permanent resident status upon meeting certain requirements, including by establishing that the start-up has created a certain number of jobs and has met certain revenue targets.

To be eligible for a visa as an essential employee of a start-up, an individual must (1) have an offer of employment in an executive or managerial capacity at a start-up; and (2) possess knowledge, skills, or experience to substantially assist in the start-up's growth and success.

The bill limits the number of employees on essential employee visas that a start-up may have.</summary>
</bill>
