<bill session="118" type="h" number="4479" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Positioning the Election Assistance Commission for the Future Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Positioning the Election Assistance Commission for the Future Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to improve the administration and operation of the Election Assistance Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000632"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-28T14:03:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Positioning the Election Assistance Commission for the Future Act of 2023

This bill makes changes to the Election Assistance Commission (EAC).&#160;

The bill revises certain requirements related to staffing and funding of the EAC. For example, the bill (1) limits the number of full-time equivalent employees that may be hired to carry out the duties and responsibilities of the EAC, and (2) permits an individual serving a term of service on the EAC to hold a position at an institution of higher education under specified circumstances.

Additionally, the bill provides the EAC with exclusive authority to make election administration payments to states.

The bill authorizes the Executive Board of the Standards Board to enter into certain contracts to enable the Standards Board to discharge its duties with respect to the examination and release of voluntary considerations for states to administer federal elections.&#160;

Further, the bill specifies that the EAC has primary jurisdiction to address issues with respect to the administration of federal elections.&#160;

The bill prohibits states and local governments from using payments from the EAC for any get-out-the-vote activity (i.e., activities that assist, encourage, or urge potential voters to vote).

The bill also requires public communications that are funded by EAC payments to include a specified disclaimer. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
