<bill session="111" type="h" number="3498" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Statewide PTV Access Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 119 of title 17, United States Code, and the Communications Act of 1934 to permit satellite carriers to retransmit the signals of certain noncommercial, educational broadcast stations outside their local markets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Statewide PTV Access Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000055" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000395" joined="2009-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications, Technology, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-03T22:29:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Statewide PTV Access Act of 2009 - Permits a satellite carrier to retransmit the signals of a state-wide network of noncommercial educational broadcast stations to any subscriber in any county within such state that is: (1) outside that station's local market; and (2) not served by an in-state noncommercial educational television broadcast station.

Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to permit a satellite carrier to retransmit the signals of a television broadcast station outside the station's local market directly to its subscribers if: (1) such station is a part of a network of three or more noncommercial educational broadcast stations that are licensed to a single state, political, educational, or special purpose subdivision of a state, or to a single public agency; and (2) the carrier retransmits such signal only to subscribers in a county within that state that is outside the station's local market and is not served by another in-state noncommercial educational broadcast station.</summary>
</bill>
