<bill session="118" type="h" number="4761" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing American Future from Exploitative Communist Autonomous Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing American Future from Exploitative Communist Autonomous Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide additional safety measures for motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-12T16:27:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing American Future from Exploitative Communist Autonomous Research Act or the SAFE CAR Act

This bill prohibits certain Chinese-manufactured motor vehicles and equipment (or those of a foreign adversary) that do not meet U.S. safety standards from being imported into or sold in the United States.&#160;&#160;

Specifically, a person domiciled in China or a manufacturer who is under the control of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP) or the Chinese government may not import into or sell in the United States any motor vehicle or equipment that the Department of Transportation (DOT) determines poses a U.S. security risk.&#160;

Further, a motor vehicle may not be granted an exemption from certain safety standards (e.g., for autonomous driving technology testing) if the vehicle manufacturer is under the control of or shares information with the CCP or the Chinese government.

DOT may revoke the existing registration for an exemption for a&#160;low-volume&#160;manufacturer if the manufacturer is&#160;determined to be a U.S. security risk and is owned by, or located in, a country that is classified&#160;as a foreign adversary.

An intermediate or final stage manufacturer must also certify (for vehicle safety standard compliance requirements) that (1) DOT has determined that&#160;the manufacturer is not a threat to&#160;security, and (2) it&#160;is not under the control of and does not share information with the CCP or the Chinese government.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
