<bill session="110" type="h" number="2641" updated="2023-01-12T17:53:03Z">
  <state datetime="2007-07-17T15:57:29-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-07-17T15:57:29-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2008, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000108"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-11">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-185, by Mr. Visclosky.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-06-11" calendar="Union" number="109">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 109.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-06-13T02:23:33-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 481 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2641 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:42:06-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 481 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:44:00-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Visclosky asked unanimous consent that, during consideration of H.R. 2641 pursuant to House Resolution 481, the Chair may reduce to two minutes the minimum time for electronic voting under clause 6 of rule 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:44:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 481.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6669-6686" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6678, H6679, H6681, H6684, H6689-6690, H6692" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6695-6696, H6698, H6701" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6701, H6703, H6706, H6710-6711, H6712, CR 6/20/2007 H6757, H6759, H6759-6760, H6762-6763" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR 6/20/2007 H6763, H6764, H6765" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR 6/20/2007 H6765" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:44:31-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2641 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:45:21-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 481 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:45:22-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Artur Davis to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T10:45:41-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2641.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T12:07:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Westmoreland amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T12:20:25-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westmoreland amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T12:27:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Westmoreland amendment No.26 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T12:44:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westmoreland amendment No. 26, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T12:51:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Westmoreland amendment No.24 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:05:47-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Visclosky moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:06:13-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:06:27-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2641 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:07:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6686-6695, H6695-6709" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:07:31-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:30:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westmoreland amendment No. 24, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:36:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Westmoreland amendment No.25 under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:56:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westmoreland amendment No. 25, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westmoreland demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T13:59:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sessions amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:25:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sessions amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Sessions demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:25:41-04:00">
      <text>The Committee of the Whole rose informally to receive a messsage from the President.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:26:33-04:00">
      <text>Subsequently, the Committee resumed it's sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:28:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Hensarling amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:47:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T14:53:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Lamborn amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:15:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Lamborn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Lamborn demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:17:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Campbell amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:39:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:41:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Stearns amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:55:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Stearns amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Stearns demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T15:55:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Schmidt amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:02:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Kline amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:30:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kline amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kline demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:31:30-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Visclosky moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:31:45-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:31:54-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2641 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:39:19-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Visclosky asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 2641 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 481, no further amendment to the bill will be in order except those provided on a list at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:40:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6709-6710, H6710-6715, H6715-6721" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:40:42-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:41:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Porter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:53:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Porter amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Porter demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T16:54:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Upton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T17:00:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tauscher amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T17:06:21-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T18:15:13-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Olver moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T18:15:27-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-19T18:15:34-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2641 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T12:47:13-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6757-6794" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T12:47:27-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T12:52:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Space amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:00:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:08:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foxx amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Foxx demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:09:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Matheson amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:14:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Udall (NM) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:31:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Udall(NM) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hobson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:38:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Neugebauer amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:44:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Neugebauer amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Neugebauer demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Musgrave amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:49:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schmidt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:54:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Musgrave amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T13:59:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Musgrave amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mrs. Musgrave demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:00:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wilson (NM) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:05:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Murphy(CT) amendment pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:09:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bishop (NY) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:17:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Bishop(NY) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Bishop(NY) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:18:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Jordan amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:47:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Jordan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Jordan demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:48:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Wynn amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:50:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Harman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:54:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Berkley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:57:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment pending reservation of a point of order. Subsequently, the reservation was removed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T14:59:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shadegg amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T15:08:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shadegg amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Shadegg demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T15:09:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett(NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T15:14:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Price(GA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T15:46:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Price of Georgia amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Price of Georgia demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T15:47:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Wilson of South Carolina amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T16:19:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wilson of South Carolina amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Wilson of South Carolina demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T16:20:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Hinchey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T16:50:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hinchey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-20T18:11:56-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2641 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-13">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Appropriations, H. Rept. 110-185, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T12:55:50-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Visclosky asked unanimous consent that during further consideration of H.R. 2641 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 481, no further amendment to the bill will be in order except those provided on a list at the desk. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T12:59:52-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7873-7874, H7874-7878" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:00:10-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:01:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rothman amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:07:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:16:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:21:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:28:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Flake amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Flake demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the Flake amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:28:44-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Visclosky moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:29:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:29:08-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2641 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:34:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7878-7898" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:35:01-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:35:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:47:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:47:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T13:54:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:01:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:03:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:14:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hensarling amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:22:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hensarling amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hensarling demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:22:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Campbell (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:50:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Campbell CA) amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Campbell (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T14:54:55-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:37:06-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Visclosky moved for the Committee of the Whole to rise and report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:37:18-04:00">
      <text>On motion to rise and report Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:37:23-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2641.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:38:06-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7897" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:38:15-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="641" datetime="2007-07-17T15:57:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 312 - 112 (Roll no. 641).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-07-17T15:57:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="641" datetime="2007-07-17T15:57:29-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 312 - 112 (Roll no. 641).</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="274">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 274.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="7324" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3258" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="1751" relation="companion"/>
    <bill session="110" type="hr" number="481" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lighting"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil shales"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h509"/>
    <amendment number="h508"/>
    <amendment number="h507"/>
    <amendment number="h506"/>
    <amendment number="h505"/>
    <amendment number="h504"/>
    <amendment number="h503"/>
    <amendment number="h502"/>
    <amendment number="h501"/>
    <amendment number="h500"/>
    <amendment number="h350"/>
    <amendment number="h349"/>
    <amendment number="h348"/>
    <amendment number="h347"/>
    <amendment number="h346"/>
    <amendment number="h345"/>
    <amendment number="h344"/>
    <amendment number="h343"/>
    <amendment number="h342"/>
    <amendment number="h341"/>
    <amendment number="h340"/>
    <amendment number="h339"/>
    <amendment number="h338"/>
    <amendment number="h337"/>
    <amendment number="h336"/>
    <amendment number="h335"/>
    <amendment number="h334"/>
    <amendment number="h333"/>
    <amendment number="h332"/>
    <amendment number="h331"/>
    <amendment number="h330"/>
    <amendment number="h329"/>
    <amendment number="h328"/>
    <amendment number="h327"/>
    <amendment number="h326"/>
    <amendment number="h325"/>
    <amendment number="h324"/>
    <amendment number="h323"/>
    <amendment number="h322"/>
    <amendment number="h321"/>
    <amendment number="h320"/>
    <amendment number="h319"/>
    <amendment number="h318"/>
    <amendment number="h317"/>
    <amendment number="h316"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2007-09-24T15:39:39Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2008 - Title I: Corps of Engineers-Civil - Makes FY2008 appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers for civil functions pertaining to rivers and harbors, flood and storm damage reduction, and aquatic ecosystem restoration; (2) general investigations and construction (including rescissions of funds); (3) flood damage reduction for the Mississippi River alluvial valley below Cape Girardeau, Missouri; (4) operation, maintenance, and administration of laws pertaining to regulation of navigable waters and wetlands; (5) clean up of contamination from sites resulting from work performed as part of the early atomic energy program; (6) flood control, hurricane, and natural disasters emergency operations; (7) general administration and related civil works functions in the headquarters of the Corps; and (8) the Office of Assistant Secretary of the Army (Civil Works).

(Sec. 101) Sets forth limitations upon reprogramming of funds and certain continuing contracts.

(Sec. 103) Prohibits expenditure of funds under this Act for operation and maritime maintenance of the hopper dredge McFarland.

(Sec. 104) Instructs the Secretary of the Army to reduce by 35% the full-time employees at the Sacramento District Regulatory Division office of the Corps of Engineers.

(Sec. 105) Prohibits the use of funds to conduct a public-private competition or direct conversion under the OMB Circular A-76 or any other administrative regulation, directive, or policy for any Corps of Engineers program, project or activity.

Title II: Department of the Interior - Makes FY2008 appropriations to the Department of the Interior for: (1) the Central Utah Project Completion Account; (2) the Bureau of Reclamation; (3) management, development, and restoration of water and related natural resources; (4) the Central Valley Project Restoration Fund; (5) California Bay-Delta restoration; and (6) policy and administration in the Office of the Commissioner, the Denver office, and offices in the five regions of the Bureau of Reclamation.

(Sec. 201) Prohibits the use of funds to determine the final point of discharge for the interceptor drain for the San Luis Unit until development by the Secretary of the Interior and the state of California of a plan, conforming to California water quality standards, to minimize any detrimental effect of the San Luis drainage waters.

Declares that the costs of the Kesterson Reservoir Cleanup Program and the San Joaquin Valley Drainage Program shall be classified as reimbursable or nonreimbursable and collected until fully repaid. Makes any future U.S. obligations relating to drainage for that Unit fully reimbursable by Unit beneficiaries.

Title III: Department of Energy - Makes FY2008 appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for expenses related to: (1) energy efficiency and renewable energy; (2) electricity delivery and energy reliability; and (3) nuclear energy.

Rescinds specified amounts previously designated for clean coal technology.

Makes FY2008 appropriations for: (1) fossil energy research and development; (2) naval petroleum and oil shale reserve activities, (3) the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; (4) the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve; (5) the Energy Information Administration; (6) non-defense environmental cleanup; (7) the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund; (8) science activities; and (9) nuclear waste disposal, including specified funds designated for the state of Nevada.

Makes FY2008 appropriations for: (1) DOE expenses for Environment, Safety, and Health activities; (2) the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee program; (3) salaries and expenses for departmental administration; (4) the Office of Inspector General; (5) atomic energy defense weapons activities; (6) defense nuclear nonproliferation activities; (7) naval reactors; (8) the Office of the Administrator in the National Nuclear Security Administration; (9) atomic energy defense environmental cleanup; (10) plant and capital equipment necessary for atomic energy defense, other defense, and classified activities; and (11) nuclear waste disposal activities.

Approves specified expenditures from the Bonneville Power Administration Fund for official reception and representation expenses. Prohibits new direct loan obligations from being made during FY2008.

Makes FY2008 appropriations for operation and maintenance of: (1) the Southeastern, Southwestern, and Western Area Power Administrations; (2) the Falcon and Amistad Dams; and (3) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC).

(Sec. 301) Prohibits the use of funds to award any other management and operating contract, or a significant extension or expansion to an existing management and operating contract, unless such contract is awarded using competitive procedures, or the Secretary of Energy grants a waiver (on a case-by-case basis) to allow for such a deviation. Prohibits the Secretary from delegating such waiver authority.

(Sec. 302) Prohibits the use of appropriations to prepare or initiate requests for proposals for unfunded programs.

(Sec. 304) Prohibits the use of Bonneville Power Administration funds to enter into any agreement to perform energy efficiency services outside the legally defined Bonneville service territory, with the exception of services provided internationally, including services provided on a reimbursable basis, unless the Administrator certifies in advance that such services are not available from private sector businesses.

(Sec. 305) Requires DOE: (1) when it makes a user facility available to universities or other potential users, or seeks their input on significant user facility characteristics or equipment, to ensure broad public notice of such availability or input need; and (2) employ full and open competition in selecting a university or other potential user as a formal partner in the establishment or operation of a user facility.

(Sec. 306) Deems any funds appropriated by this or any other Act, or made available by the transfer of funds in this Act, for intelligence activities to be specifically authorized by Congress for purposes of the National Security Act of 1947 during FY2008, until the enactment of the Intelligence Authorization Act for FY2008.

(Sec. 307) Authorizes the use of specified funds by: (1) government-owned, contractor-operator operated laboratories for laboratory-directed research and development; and (2) the plant manager of a covered nuclear weapons production plant or the manager of the Nevada Site Office for plant or site-directed research and development.

(Sec. 308) Prohibits implementation of a specified DOE Order modifying contractor employee pension and medical benefits policy.

(Sec. 309) Makes specified funds available until expended for the U.S. contribution to create a low-enriched uranium stockpile for an International Nuclear Fuel Bank supply of nuclear fuel for peaceful means under the International Atomic Energy Agency.

Title IV: Independent Agencies - Makes FY2008 appropriations to: (1) the Appalachian Regional Commission; (2) the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board; (3) the Delta Regional Authority; (4) the Denali Commission; (5) the Nuclear Regulatory Commission; (6) the Office of Inspector General; (7) the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board; and (8) Office of the Federal Coordinator for Alaska Natural Gas Transportation Projects.

Title V: General Provisions - (Sec. 501) Prohibits the use of funds appropriated by this Act to influence congressional action on legislation or appropriation matters pending before Congress.

(Sec. 502) Prohibits the transfer of funds made available by this Act to any federal department, agency, or instrumentality, except pursuant to a transfer made by, or transfer authority provided in, this Act or any other appropriation Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-185,Part 2</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-185</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
