<bill session="108" type="s" number="2613" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:24Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Health Preparedness Workforce Development Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a scholarship and loan repayment program for public health preparedness workforce development to eliminate critical public health preparedness workforce shortages in Federal, State, and local public health agencies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Preparedness Workforce Development Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001028"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2004-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2004-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-21T20:40:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Preparedness Workforce Development Act of 2004 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Public Health Workforce Scholarship Program to assure an adequate supply of public health professionals to eliminate critical public health preparedness workforce shortages in Federal, State, and local public health agencies by offering four-year scholarships in return for employment at such agencies.

Requires the Secretary to establish the Public Health Workforce Loan Repayment Program to provide for the repayment of loans incurred by individuals in the pursuit of the relevant public health preparedness workforce educational degree or certificate in exchange for working at such agencies for at least three years.

Requires the Secretary to award grants to public health agencies that receive public health preparedness cooperative agreements from the Department of Health and Human Services to operate State and local public health workforce loan repayment programs</summary>
</bill>
