<bill session="118" type="h" number="7932" updated="2025-08-11T18:02:32Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Our Shrimpers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Our Shrimpers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit Federal funds from being made available to international financial institutions for the purposes of financing foreign shrimp farms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001054" joined="2024-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2024-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2024-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000235" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000478" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000595" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000569" joined="2024-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2024-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2024-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2024-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2024-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2024-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-11T18:01:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Our Shrimpers Act

This bill prohibits federal funds from being made available to international financial institutions (e.g., the International Monetary Fund) for financing activities related to foreign shrimp farms. The bill also requires an annual report on compliance by U.S. leadership of international financial institutions with policies to oppose financing for certain commodities or minerals.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of the Treasury to condition any provision of federal funds to an international financial institution on the requirement that the funds not be used to finance any activity related to shrimp farming, shrimp processing, or the export of shrimp in any foreign country.

Under current law, Treasury must instruct U.S. leadership of international financial institutions to oppose providing financial assistance for the production or extraction of any commodity or mineral for export if (1) the commodity or mineral is in surplus on world markets, and (2) the export of such commodity or mineral will cause substantial injury to U.S. producers of&#160;a&#160;competing commodity or mineral (or of the same or a similar commodity or mineral). This bill requires the Government Accountability Office to investigate and annually report to Congress on the extent to which U.S. leadership at these institutions have carried out Treasury's instructions.</summary>
</bill>
