<bill session="109" type="h" number="4237" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:43Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preservation of Local Government Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that local governments can function in the case of a declared emergency or major disaster.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preservation of Local Government Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-07T22:32:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Preservation of Local Government Act - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President, acting through the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to provide an eligible local government with financial assistance to enable it to pay all or part of the expenses necessary to pay its local public employees. Allows the Director to provide such assistance for up to six months, or longer if the local government is unable to generate enough revenue to pay such expenses.

Requires a local government, to be eligible to receive assistance under this Act, to be located in an emergency or major disaster area, and certify to the Director that it is unable to generate enough revenue to pay its local public employees.</summary>
</bill>
