<bill session="108" type="s" number="821" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:12Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Energy Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accelerate the commercialization and widespread use of hydrogen energy and fuel cell technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Energy Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">George E. Brown, Jr. and Robert S. Walker Hydrogen Future Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4969-4970"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Condominium (Housing)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cooperative housing"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage"/>
    <term name="Energy transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Sustainable development"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-16T20:54:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Energy Act of 2003 - George E. Brown, Jr. and Robert S. Walker Hydrogen Future Act of 2003 - Reauthorizes through FY 2010 and revises the Spark M. Matsunaga Hydrogen Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 1990 to emphasize fuel cell research, development, and demonstration activities.



Renames the Hydrogen Technical Advisory Panel the Hydrogen and Fuel Cells Technical Advisory Panel.

Directs the President shall establish an interagency task force to coordinate Federal hydrogen and fuel cell energy activities.



Directs the Secretary of Energy to conduct a public education program designed to increase public interest in and acceptance of hydrogen energy and fuel cell technologies.

Mandates implementation of pilot projects to demonstrate the viability of: (1) fuel cells and associated hydrogen fueling infrastructure; (2) hydrogen-powered vehicles and hydrogen fueling infrastructure along major transportation routes or in entire regions; and (3) fuel cells and associated hydrogen fueling infrastructure in foreign countries. Requires a program of demonstration projects to test the technical and commercial viability of hydrogen production from renewable resources.

Amends the Energy Conservation and Production Act to direct the Secretary to revise Federal building energy efficiency performance standards to require the use of fuel cells as a primary power source in new Federal buildings.

Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to prescribe increasing percentages of zero-emission vehicles in Federal fleets from ten percent in FY 2007 up to 75 percent in FY 2013.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide as a credit against tax for: (1) acquisition of fuel cell and hydrogen motor vehicles; (2) installation of qualified hydrogen-fuel vehicle refueling property; (3) retail sale of hydrogen fuel as motor vehicle fuel; and (4) expenditures for energy-efficient building property, both business and nonbusiness.</summary>
</bill>
