<bill session="118" type="h" number="3298" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BEAD FEE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEAD FEE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband Expansion And Deployment Fee Equity and Efficiency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to require States and political subdivisions of States to streamline certain fees relating to broadband infrastructure in order to receive grant funds under the Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000372"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-17T19:16:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadband Expansion And Deployment Fee Equity and Efficiency Act of 2023 or the BEAD FEE Act of 2023

This bill restricts recipients of Broadband Equity, Access, and Deployment (BEAD) Program grants from charging fees related to the deployment of broadband infrastructure. The BEAD Program provides funds to states and territories for broadband deployment, connectivity, mapping, and adoption projects.

Generally, the bill prohibits grant recipients from charging fees for (1) considering requests for deploying broadband infrastructure; or (2) using or accessing land, or existing infrastructure on land, that is owned or managed by a state, territory, or locality (i.e., a right-of-way) to deploy broadband infrastructure.

However, the bill permits recipients to charge fees if they are nondiscriminatory, publicly disclosed, and based on actual and direct costs. Additionally, recipients must describe the fees in a manner that distinguishes between (1) recurring and nonrecurring fees, and (2) using a right-of-way with and without existing infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
