<bill session="116" type="h" number="459" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:17Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the boundary of Acadia National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2019-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="47" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="101" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-13T18:02:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Acadia National Park Boundary Clarification Act

This bill declares that the boundary of Acadia National Park in Maine is confirmed to include approximately 1,441 acres of land and interests in the Schoodic Peninsula.

The bill ratifies and approves

 the acquisition by the United States of such land and interests, effective as of September 26, 2013; and any alteration of such land or interests held or claimed by the United State that occurred after such date. The Department of the Interior may make certain technical and limited revisions to the permanent boundaries of the park.

Interior shall reestablish and appoint members to the Acadia National Park Advisory Commission.

 Certain land in the park that was conveyed by Interior to the town of Tremont, Maine, shall no longer be used exclusively for school purposes, but for public purposes, subject to specified conditions.

 Interior shall allow for the traditional taking of marine species, marine worms, and shellfish on land within the park between the mean high watermark and the mean low watermark in accordance with the laws of the State of Maine.

Interior shall convey to the town of Bar Harbor a specified parcel of land within the park to be used for a solid waste transfer facility.</summary>
</bill>
