<bill session="117" type="s" number="2827" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bankruptcy Venue Reform Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to modify venue requirements relating to bankruptcy proceedings.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Venue Reform Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4193" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-13T20:43:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bankruptcy Venue Reform Act of 2021 

This bill limits where a non-individual debtor (e.g., a corporate debtor) may file for bankruptcy.

Specifically, these debtors must file in the district court for the district in which the principal place of business or principal assets of the debtor are located. Such a debtor may also file in a district where there is a pending bankruptcy case concerning an affiliate that has a certain level of control or ownership of the debtor (e.g., if the affiliate is a controlling shareholder of the debtor), if that pending case is in a proper venue under this bill.

Under current law, these debtors may also file where they are domiciled (i.e., incorporated) or where there is a bankruptcy case pending concerning an affiliate, general partner, or partnership.

For certain debtors who are issuers of securities, their principal place of business is defined in the bill as the address of the entity's principal executive office as provided in specified Securities and Exchange Commission filings.</summary>
</bill>
