<bill session="118" type="s" number="1512" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DIRECT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DIRECT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Direct Interstate Retail Exemption for Certain Transactions Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act to allow for the interstate internet sales of certain State-inspected meat and poultry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-07T13:30:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Direct Interstate Retail Exemption for Certain Transactions Act of 2023 or the DIRECT Act of 2023

This bill allows meat and poultry products inspected by State Meat and Poultry Inspection programs to be sold by retail stores, restaurants, or similar retail-type establishments over the internet and shipped by a carrier in commerce (other than for export to a foreign country). The state-inspected meat and poultry products must be shipped directly to household consumers and in normal retail quantities (e.g., do not exceed 300 pounds for beef, 100 pounds for pork, and 27.5 pounds for lamb).

(Under the inspection programs, the Department of Agriculture Food Safety and Inspection Service allows states that meet certain requirements to inspect meat and poultry. The state-inspected products are currently limited to intrastate commerce, unless a state opts into a separate Cooperative Interstate Shipment Program.)&#160;</summary>
</bill>
