<bill session="111" type="h" number="4860" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Electric Consumer Right to Know Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to provide electric consumers the right to access certain electric energy information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">e-KNOW Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electric Consumer Right to Know Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2010-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2010-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E386-387"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5696" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3487" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-27T13:14:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Electric Consumer Right to Know Act or the e-KNOW Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to grant an electric consumer the right to access the consumer's retail electric energy information in electronic machine-readable form, in conformity with nationally recognized open standards, free of charge, and in a timely and convenient manner that provides adequate protections for information security and the consumer's privacy.

Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue guidelines identifying minimum national standards to implement such right of access, including: (1) guidance on the timeliness and granularity of retail electric energy information; (2) appropriate nationally recognized open standards for data; and (3) protection of data security and electric consumer privacy.

Empowers the attorney general, official, or agency of the state, as parens patriae, to bring a civil action against an electric utility in U.S. district court to compel compliance with such standards.

Authorizes the court to award the costs of the action and reasonable attorney's fees to the party bringing a successful civil action to enforce the standards identified by the guidelines issued under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
