<bill session="116" type="s" number="2681" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote and ensure delivery of high-quality special education and related services to students with visual disabilities or who are deaf or hard of hearing or deaf-blind through instructional methodologies meeting their unique learning needs, to enhance accountability for the provision of such services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2020-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2019-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2020-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4822" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-12T19:56:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act 

This bill expands special education and related services for students who are deaf or hard of hearing, for students with visual disabilities, and for children and youth who are deaf-blind.

The individualized education program for each child who is visually and/or hearing impaired must include specified components and must provide the child with instruction that meets the child's unique learning needs.

In addition, a state's closure of a special school serving deaf or blind children shall count as a reduction of its financial support for special education and related services.

Among other provisions, the bill authorizes support, including grants for training special education personnel, to be used in preparing individuals to become qualified teachers and early intervention specialists for children with hearing disabilities.

The bill establishes within the Department of Education the Anne Sullivan Macy Center on Visual Disability and Educational Excellence to better support students with visual disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
