<bill session="111" type="h" number="2506" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:11Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Hearing and Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to ensure the members of the Armed Forces receive mandatory hearing screenings before and after deployments and to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to mandate that tinnitus be listed as a mandatory condition for treatment by the Department of Veterans Affairs Auditory Centers of Excellence and that research on the preventing, treating, and curing of tinnitus be conducted.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Hearing and Assessment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2009-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5808"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-12T16:22:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Hearing and Assessment Act - Expresses the sense of Congress that tinnitus is one of the leading service-connected disability issues that is not being addressed.

Directs the Secretary of Defense to ensure that each member of the Armed Forces receives a hearing evaluation that includes a screening for tinnitus before the member is deployed and after the member returns from a deployment.

Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) recognize tinnitus as a mandatory condition for research and treatment by Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) Auditory Centers of Excellence; and (2) ensure that research is conducted at VA facilities on the prevention, treatment, and curing of tinnitus.</summary>
</bill>
