<bill session="108" type="s" number="239" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:08Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-23">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to add requirements regarding trauma care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2003-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2003-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2003-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000024" joined="2003-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1744-1745"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Gregg without amendment. With written report No. 108-59.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="123">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 123.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-06-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8377-8378" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8377-8378" label="text of meaure as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24T10:02:22-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-24">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health services administration"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Mortality"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced on January 29, 2003. However, because action occurred on the measure, the summary has been expanded.)Trauma Care Systems Planning and Development Act of 2003 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to collect, compile, and disseminate information regarding trauma care and emergency medical services, and, in so doing, to give special consideration to the needs of rural areas. Directs the Secretary to provide to State and local agencies technical assistance in developing, implementing, and sustaining the trauma care component of each State's plan for the provision of emergency medical services. (Current law directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to States and local agencies with respect to trauma care.)Removes provisions dealing with a National Clearinghouse on Trauma Care and Emergency Medical Services.Modifies provision pertaining to grants to improve trauma care in rural areas to allow the Secretary to make grants to entities to improve care by increasing communication and coordination with State trauma systems.Amends provisions concerning matching funds for modifications of the trauma care part of State emergency services plans, including to modify the matching requirements to not less than $1 for each $1 of Federal funds in the third year of payments and not less then $2 for each $1 of Federal funds in the fourth and fifth years. (Currently, the amount is set at not less than $1 for each $1 of Federal funding in the second year and not less than $3 for each $1 of Federal funding in the third year and subsequent years.)Amends requirements with respect to carrying out the purpose of allotments, including to require a State plan for emergency medical services to: (1) identify the number of deaths from trauma within regional trauma care systems in the State; and (2) coordinate planning for trauma systems with State disaster emergency planning and bioterrorism hospital preparedness planning. Directs the Secretary to update the model trauma care plan.Requires States in FY 2004 and in following years to submit to the Secretary the trauma care part of their emergency services plans in order to receive Federal allotments to support the modification of such part. Requires such submission to include changes and improvements made and plans to address deficiencies.Authorizes appropriations through FY 2008 for general duties of the Secretary with regard to trauma care and for formula grants with respect to modifications of State plans.Directs the Secretary to: (1) enter into a contract with the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences, or another appropriate entity, to conduct a study on the state of trauma care and trauma research; and (2) report the results to Congress. Authorizes appropriations for such study and report for FY 2004 and 2005.Authorizes appropriations through FY 2008 for residency training programs in emergency medicine.Amends provisions pertaining to the Interagency Program for Trauma Research. Directs the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in establishing and implementing a plan for carrying out the Program, to take into consideration the recommendations contained within the report of the NIH Trauma Research Task Force. Authorizes appropriations for the Program through FY 2008.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-59</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
