<bill session="117" type="h" number="2671" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to specify certain effects of guidelines, general statements of policy, and similar guidance issued by the Federal Trade Commission.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHIELD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solidifying Habitual and Institutional Explanations of Liability and Defenses Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000377"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-27T19:34:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Solidifying Habitual and Institutional Explanations of Liability and Defenses Act or the SHIELD Act

This bill provides that in any enforcement action the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) must prove a violation of law and may not base the action solely on guidelines, policy statements, or similar guidance.

The bill provides that no guidelines, general statements of policy, or similar guidance issued by the FTC shall confer any rights or bind the FTC or any person, state, or locality to the approach recommended therein. Further, the bill authorizes a defendant in an enforcement action to offer any such guidelines, policy statements, or similar guidance as evidence of compliance with a provision of law that is enforced by the FTC.</summary>
</bill>
