<bill session="117" type="h" number="6753" updated="2022-12-30T04:18:54Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide enhanced authority for the President to enter into agreements with the Government of Ukraine to lend or lease defense articles to that Government to protect civilian populations in Ukraine from Russian military invasion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2022-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3522" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-18T09:49:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Ukraine Democracy Defense Lend-Lease Act of 2022 

This bill temporarily waives certain requirements related to the President's authority to lend or lease defense articles if the defense articles are intended for Ukraine's government and necessary to protect civilians in Ukraine from Russian military invasion.

An agreement to lend or lease defense articles under this bill shall not be subject to certain requirements and provisions that typically apply to such lend-lease agreements, including (1) a requirement that prohibits a loan period from exceeding five years, (2) a requirement that the United States may recall the loaned defense article at any time, (3) a requirement that the receiving party has agreed to pay the United States all costs incurred in leasing the defense article, and (4) a provision that allows Congress to prohibit certain transfers of defense articles upon the enactment of a joint resolution.

The waivers provided by this bill shall be in effect until (1) the conflict beginning with Russia's annexation of the Crimea region of Ukraine in 2014 has ceased, and (2) Russia has reduced its military force on Ukraine's eastern border to the levels maintained prior to March 1, 2021.

The President must establish expedited procedures to ensure the timely delivery of defense articles loaned or leased under this bill.</summary>
</bill>
