<bill session="117" type="h" number="5330" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44 of the United States Code to prohibit the National Archives and Records Administration from including content warnings alongside founding documents of the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Treasures Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001120"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2021-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2021-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2862" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-31T16:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Treasures Act of 2021

This bill prohibits the National Archives and Records Administration from including content warnings alongside items associated with the founding fathers of the United States.

Content warning is defined as any message preceding or attached to the document labeling it as dangerous, harmful, anachronistic, or any other terms implying harm associated with the documents; disparaging the documents; assuming malicious intent on the part of the authors; or discouraging potential readers from reading the documents.

Founding father means any individual who signed the Declaration of Independence, served as an officer in the Revolutionary War, attended the Second Continental Congress, attended the Constitutional Convention, or was granted a charter for one of the original 13 colonies of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
