<bill session="118" type="h" number="8344" updated="2025-03-17T15:39:25Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Texas Agricultural Producers Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Texas Agricultural Producers Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to submit to Congress a report on available assistance to agricultural producers in the State of Texas that have suffered economic losses due to the failure of Mexico to deliver water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2024-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000594" joined="2024-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8467" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-17T15:38:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Texas Agricultural Producers Assistance Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to submit a report to Congress on USDA assistance available for agricultural producers in Texas related to Mexico's non-compliance with a 1944 treaty with the United States&#160;concerning water utilization.

Specifically, the USDA report must list all of the existing USDA authorities and programs that are or could be made available to provide assistance to agricultural producers in Texas that have suffered economic losses due to Mexico not delivering water to the United States in accordance with the Treaty on Utilization of Waters of the Colorado and Tijuana Rivers and of the Rio Grande, including the Supplementary Protocol.</summary>
</bill>
