<bill session="117" type="h" number="7549" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Seasonal Worker Solidarity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seasonal Worker Solidarity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the process by which temporary nonagricultural workers' visas are allocated, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2022-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000592" joined="2022-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2022-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2022-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2022-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-28T21:11:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Seasonal Worker Solidarity Act of 2022

This bill modifies the H-2B (temporary nonagricultural workers) visa program and expands protections for aliens who report workplace violations.

Changes to the H-2B program include

 requiring the Department of Labor to establish a centralized national electronic platform for U.S. workers to find and apply for positions that employers are seeking to fill with H-2B workers; requiring employers to recruit U.S. workers nationwide, including by posting the openings on the platform, before applying for H-2B visas; requiring employers to guarantee at least 40 hours of paid work per week for each H-2B worker (currently employers may guarantee fewer paid hours in certain instances); requiring employers to pay for housing for H-2B workers and transportation to and from the work site (currently employers are allowed to deduct fees for lodgings from an H-2B worker's pay); modifying the requirements for determining the minimum wage for H-2B workers; and prioritizing H-2B visas for certain employers, such as those that pay higher wages. Furthermore, an alien who has worked a certain amount of time as an H-2B worker may obtain permanent resident status, subject to various requirements.

In addition, an alien who is likely helpful in an investigation of a workplace claim (i.e., an alleged violation of law or workplace-related injury) may qualify for a U visa for victims of criminal activity. The bill also removes statutory numerical limitations on U visas.

The bill also provides protections for certain aliens who file or assist in the investigation of workplace claims.</summary>
</bill>
