<bill session="117" type="h" number="4620" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:37Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to limit the exemption provided for family offices from the definition of an investment adviser, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to limit the exemption provided for family offices from the definition of an investment adviser, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 22.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T20:30:08Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill limits the exemption for family offices from the Securities and Exchange Commission's (SEC's) regulations applicable to investment advisers. A family office is a privately held company that manages a single family's wealth. Currently, a family office is generally not considered an investment adviser for purposes of SEC regulation regardless of the amount of managed assets, and is therefore not subject to regulations relating to duties, recordkeeping, and disclosures.

The bill limits the exemption to include only family offices with less than $750 million in managed assets. Furthermore, the SEC must exclude from the exemption certain persons subject to a final order regarding fraudulent conduct, among other activities.</summary>
</bill>
