<bill session="116" type="s" number="3160" updated="2022-02-08T23:22:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable Safe Drinking Water Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Safe Drinking Water Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act and the Safe Drinking Water Act to modify the payment periods of loans from State revolving funds under those Acts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2020-01-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5513" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-18T15:43:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Affordable Safe Drinking Water Act of 2020

This bill revises the clean water state revolving fund (SRF) program and the drinking water SRF program. Both programs provide financial assistance for water infrastructure.

The bill removes the 30-year term limits for loans under the SRF programs. Thus, new loans under the programs may have terms up to the projected useful life of the projects. Loan terms for existing loans may, on agreement of the parties to the loan, be extended.

In addition, the bill allows states to use a percentage of SRF funds to replace pipes, plumbing fittings, and fixtures that carry water contaminated with lead or perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances (commonly referred to as PFAS) at certain state, municipal, or tribal facilities (e.g., schools, parks, and senior centers) that provide the public or employees with drinking water. PFAS are man-made and may have adverse human health effects.</summary>
</bill>
