<bill session="117" type="h" number="129" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No More Tulias: Drug Law Enforcement Evidentiary Standards Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the evidentiary standard required to convict a person for a drug offense, to require screening of law enforcement officers or others acting under color of law participating in drug task forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No More Tulias: Drug Law Enforcement Evidentiary Standards Improvement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4822" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-02T14:59:28Z" status="Introduced in House">No More Tulias: Drug Law Enforcement Evidentiary Standards Improvement Act of 2021 This bill establishes new requirements for states that receive funds under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program or under another law enforcement assistance program of the Department of Justice. Specifically, to be eligible for funds, states must either not fund antidrug task forces or have in effect laws that require convictions for drug offenses to be supported by evidence other than eyewitness testimony of a law enforcement officer or other individual acting on behalf of a law enforcement officer, and ensure law enforcement officers who participate in antidrug task forces are evaluated for integrity and honesty. Additionally, an eligible state that receives funds because these laws are in effect must collect and report data on criminal charges, including the racial distribution, nature, and location of such charges.</summary>
</bill>
