<bill session="111" type="hr" number="85" updated="2019-04-11T15:42:51Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Code of Official Conduct in the Rules of the House of Representatives to strengthen the reporting requirements for Members who request earmarks.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Code of Official Conduct in the Rules of the House of Representatives to strengthen the reporting requirements for Members who request earmarks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001064" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2009-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000360" joined="2009-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Ethics" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="General taxation matters"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-02T21:51:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives with respect to whether a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissiorer (Member) has a financial interest in any requested congressional earmark, limited tax benefit, or limited tariff benefit in any bill or joint resolution (or accompanying report), or in any related conference report (or accompanying joint statement of managers).

Treats as such a financial interest any campaign contribution to such individual in excess of a de minimis amount made by or on behalf of: (1) any political, for profit, or nonprofit entity; (2) any employee or person affiliated with any such entity; or (3) any political action committee (PAC) established by, administered by, or affiliated with any such entity, by or on behalf of its registered lobbyist, or by or on behalf of such PAC during the current or previous session of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
