<bill session="118" type="h" number="439" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Land Search and Rescue Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Land Search and Rescue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a grant program to allocate resources for remote search and rescue activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2023-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-08T21:40:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Land Search and Rescue Act 

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to establish a program to allocate resources to remote search and rescue activities conducted on lands under the jurisdiction of the Department of Agriculture or Interior.

Interior may award a grant under the program to a state or a political subdivision to (1) purchase equipment and gear necessary for remote search and rescue activities, (2) reimburse such an eligible recipient for the cost of maintenance and repair of remote search and rescue equipment owned or leased by the recipient, and (3) reimburse state and local agencies responsible for remote search and rescue activities.

Interior must prioritize an application from an eligible recipient who serves an area with a high ratio of visitors to residents.

The federal share of assistance under the program shall be 75% of the cost of an eligible project.</summary>
</bill>
