<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6239</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-09-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-09-29T14:08:20Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000583</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Smith, Lamar [R-TX-21]</fullName>
        <firstName>LAMAR</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>21</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Law</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence and witnesses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judicial procedure and administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor fuels</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Law</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-25T17:21:07Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Prevention of Frivolous Ethanol Lawsuits Act of 2010 - Immunizes a covered entity from suit and liability under federal and state law with respect to all claims for personal or property loss resulting from, or being aggravated by, the use of any renewable fuel containing ethanol in concentrations greater than 10% to operate an internal combustion engine.</p> <p>Defines &quot;covered entity&quot; to mean an entity engaged in the manufacture, sale, or distribution of fuel or products which use renewable fuel.</p> <p>Makes the sole exception to immunity under this Act an exclusive federal cause of action brought by an injured person or the person's representative against a covered person for death or serious physical injury proximately caused by the covered person's willful misconduct. Grants the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia exclusive jurisdiction of any such civil action.</p> <p>Excludes from the meaning of willful misconduct, however, any act or omission by a manufacturer or distributor with respect to a covered countermeasure, if the act or omission alleged to constitute willful misconduct is subject to regulation by the Clean Air Act and: (1) neither the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) nor the Attorney General has initiated an enforcement action with respect to that act or omission; or (2) an enforcement action has been initiated and the action has been terminated or finally resolved without a civil, criminal, or administrative remedy. States that any action or proceeding shall be stayed during the pendency of such an enforcement action.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Prevention of Frivolous Ethanol Lawsuits Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Prevention of Frivolous Ethanol Lawsuits Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide targeted liability protections for claims based on damages resulting from, or aggravated by, the inclusion of ethanol in certain fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Prevention of Frivolous Ethanol Lawsuits Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr6239ih/xml/BILLS-111hr6239ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
