<amendment session="112" chamber="s" number="2102" updated="2022-02-08T17:28:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2072" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-05-15">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001071"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-05-10"/>
  <description>To require the Export-Import Bank of the United States to provide financing only for transactions subsidized by export credit agencies of other countries or for which private sector financing is unavailable or prohibitively expensive and to require the Bank to maintain a ratio of capital to the outstanding principal balance of loans and loan guarantees of not less than 10 percent.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-05-15" how="roll" result="fail" roll="93">
      <text>Amendment SA 2102, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 62. Record Vote Number: 93.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Amendment SA 2102 proposed by Senator Corker. (consideration: CR S3148-3150, S3156-3157; text: CR S3148) To require the Export-Import Bank of the United States to provide financing only for transactions subsidized by export credit agencies of other countries or for which private sector financing is unavailable or prohibitively expensive and to require the Bank to maintain a ratio of capital to the outstanding principal balance of loans and loan guarantees of not less than 10 percent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2102 proposed by Senator Corker.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3148-3150, S3156-3157" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3148" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 2102, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 62. Record Vote Number: 93.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 2102, under the order of 5/14/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 36 - 62. Record Vote Number: 93.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
