<bill session="115" type="h" number="6702" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:36Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the congressional intent behind the requirements relating to immediate suspension orders and corrective action plans under the Controlled Substances Act that were added by the Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2016.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2018-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, Homeland Security, and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2493" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-21T22:04:20Z" status="Introduced in House">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2018

This bill amends the Controlled Substances Act (CSA) to modify enforcement authorities of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA).

The bill modifies the required elements of an order to show cause issued by the DEA before it denies, revokes, or suspends a registration for a CSA violation. Specifically, it eliminates the requirement for an order to show cause to notify the registrant of the opportunity to submit a corrective action plan.

Additionally, the bill modifies the standard of review for an immediate suspension order. Currently, the DEA may immediately suspend the registration of a controlled substances manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser to prevent imminent danger to the public health and safety. This bill lowers the standard for determining imminent danger to the public health and safety&#8212;from substantial likelihood of an immediate threat that harm will occur to probable cause to believe an imminent threat that harm or diversion will occur.</summary>
</bill>
