<bill session="108" type="hc" number="240" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of Congress with respect to the urgency of providing support for the "Agreement on Ceasefire and Cessation of Hostilities Between the Government of the Republic of Liberia and Liberians United for Reconciliation and Democracy and the Movement for Democracy of Liberia", and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress with respect to the urgency of providing support for the "Agreement on Ceasefire and Cessation of Hostilities Between the Government of the Republic of Liberia and Liberians United for Reconciliation and Democracy and the Movement for Democracy of Liberia", and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001238" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001241" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2003-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2003-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000191" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000537" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000602" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2003-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2003-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000070" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000284" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2003-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2003-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001148" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000159" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000057" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000794" joined="2003-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000207" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2003-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000784" joined="2003-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil War"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diamonds"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Liberia"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace treaties"/>
    <term name="Peacekeeping forces"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Sierra Leone"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-29T21:05:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Commends: (1) the Economic Community of West African States (ECOWAS) for successfully negotiating and signing in Accra, Ghana, on June 17, 2003, the "Agreement on Ceasefire and Cessation of Hostilities Between the Government of the Republic of Liberia and Liberians United for Reconciliation and Democracy and the Movement for Democracy of Liberia" (Ceasefire Agreement); (2) the Parties to the Ceasefire Agreement; and (3) the Liberian civil society and Liberian communities in exile for continuing to strive for peace and democracy in their country and for sustaining families unable to survive economically under President Taylor's corrupt regime with financial remittances and for steadfast advocacy for their country;

Calls on all parties to the Ceasefire Agreement to: (1) refrain from committing, aiding, abetting, or permitting, any acts in violation of the Agreement; and (2) facilitate the sustained delivery of humanitarian relief supplies throughout the country, ensure the safety and freedom of movement of all humanitarian workers, abide by the Ceasefire Agreement timetable, and form a transitional national government.

Calls on President Charles Taylor to implement his June 4, 2003, statement that he would seek "a national unity government immediately" and be willing to remove himself from power in the interest of transition to peace for the Liberian people.

Commends the Special Court for Sierra Leone for its work to bring justice to the people of Sierra Leone who suffered in the civil war sponsored by President Charles Taylor and fueled by the trade in "conflict diamonds".

Calls upon the U.S. Government to: (1) to assume a leadership role in the international community through its membership in the International Contact Group for Liberia to help guide the Ceasefire Agreement and subsequent peace agreement, political transition and establishment of a sustainable democracy with good governance, and economic reconstruction processes; and (2) play a strong and proactive role in supporting the Ceasefire Agreement and peace and reconciliation initiatives.

Calls upon the Secretary of State to: (1) take a lead role in collaboration with ECOWAS in negotiating the establishment of the Joint Verification Team under the Ceasefire Agreement; (2) provide leadership and participate in negotiations to establish the Joint Monitoring Committee to supervise the ceasefire; and (3) together with the United Nations, ECOWAS, and the African Union to establish and deploy an International Stabilization Force that will initially monitor the peace agreement and provide security for humanitarian relief efforts.

Calls upon the Secretary of Defense to: (1) provide military experts, personnel, logistical support, equipment and funds to support the Joint Verification Team; (2) provide financial, logistical, personnel, and technical support, and to participate in the Joint Monitoring Committee; and (3) play a lead role in creating and deploying an international stabilization force to Liberia.

Calls on the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to: (1) commit to providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Liberia; (2) focus on the most vulnerable populations, including internally displaced persons and war-affected persons in Monrovia; and (3) coordinate relief efforts with national and international nongovernmental organizations and other donors.

Calls on the international community to: (1) support humanitarian efforts to meet the urgent and dire needs of the Liberian people; (2) support efforts that advance the development of democratic civil institutions in Liberia; and (3) assist in the establishment of a government that respects the sovereignty, territorial integrity, and political independence of its neighbors.

Calls upon Liberian indigenous private and voluntary organizations active in local grassroots rehabilitation, reconstruction, and development efforts and Liberians living overseas to engage fully in the international efforts to help restore Liberia as a viable country in which present and future generations can live peacefully.

Calls upon the United Nations to: (1) provide peacekeeping troops to enforce the Ceasefire Agreement, protect humanitarian efforts, and maintain a stable transitional environment; and (2) provide adequate repatriation packages for refugees and resettlement packages for internally displaced persons.</summary>
</bill>
