<bill session="117" type="s" number="1546" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Executive Branch Comprehensive Ethics Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to provide for reform in the operations of the Office of Government Ethics, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Executive Branch Comprehensive Ethics Enforcement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-16T18:17:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Executive Branch Comprehensive Ethics Enforcement Act

This bill expands the duties and authorities of the Office of Government Ethics (OGE).

Among other things, the bill authorizes the OGE to

 issue subpoenas during investigations; and order corrective actions (e.g., divestiture) and issue administrative remedies (e.g., suspension or demotion). Additionally, the OGE shall be the central repository of all laws, rules, and regulations relating to conflicts of interest and other ethics issues, recusals, waivers, and exemptions of such laws, rules, and regulations. The OGE shall make available to the public all financial disclosure reports and records relating to conflicts of interest and other ethics issues that are determined to be public information.

The OGE must provide ethics education and training to all designated and alternate designated agency ethics officials, who must register with, and report to, the OGE and their appointing authority.</summary>
</bill>
