<bill session="116" type="s" number="3730" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Registered Traveler Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Registered Traveler Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize and modernize the registered traveler program of the Transportation Security Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2020-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2020-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2020-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2020-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-20T20:12:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Registered Traveler Act of 2020

This bill provides statutory authority for a registered traveler program of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA). (The registered traveler program authorizes an airport operator, with TSA approval, to enter into a contract with certain private entities to provide registered traveler services to program participants.)

Registered traveler services include (1) identity verification, (2) traveler vetting status authentication, (3) access to physical screening, and (4) other additional services at the airport security checkpoint as the TSA may approve.

The TSA must (1) develop policies, procedures, and capabilities that allow registered traveler services providers to provide program participants the full extent of registered traveler services; and (2) conduct audits of the performance of the providers, and allow the providers to correct any deficiencies identified during such audits.

The TSA must also provide registered traveler services providers access to technology and information that are available to airport operators, air carriers, or private screening companies, including the TSA advanced passenger prescreening system.</summary>
</bill>
