<bill session="110" type="h" number="6099" updated="2019-11-15T20:55:38Z">
  <state datetime="2008-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for extension of existing and expiring agreements under the Moving-to-Work program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for extension of existing and expiring agreements under the Moving-to-Work program of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2008-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2008-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Housing authorities"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-06-20T21:13:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, upon the request of a public housing agency (PHA) which has a Moving to Work agreement (under the demonstration program authorized by the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1996), to extend it for a 12-month period under such terms as are or were in effect upon the agreement's expiration.

Provides that, for a PHA that previously received an extension of its agreement and entered into a subsequent agreement after January 1, 2008, the Secretary shall, upon the PHA's request, invalidate such subsequent agreement and extend any agreement that was in effect as of such date also for a 12-month period under such terms as were in effect as of that date.

Prohibits the Secretary from extending a Moving to Work agreement if a PHA is noncompliant with its agreement's terms.

Expresses the sense of Congress that the maximum number of PHAs authorized to participate in the Moving to Work demonstration program should not be expanded until the demonstration program has been reformed and permanently authorized through enactment of a federal law.</summary>
</bill>
