<bill session="117" type="h" number="4355" updated="2023-03-09T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-02">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2022, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000797"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-02">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 117-81, by Ms. Wasserman Schultz.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-07-02" calendar="Union" number="56">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 56.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4502" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2604" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2471" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-07T18:44:46Z" status="Reported to House">Military Construction, Veterans Affairs, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2022

This bill provides FY2022 appropriations for military construction, the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), and related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for military construction for

 the Army; the Navy and Marine Corps; the Air Force; Defense-wide agencies and activities; the Army and Air National Guard; and the Army, Navy, and Air Force Reserves. The bill also provides appropriations to DOD for

 the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Security Investment Program; the Base Closure Account; Construction and Operation and Maintenance of Family Housing for the Army, the Navy and Marine Corps, the Air Force, and Defense-wide agencies and activities; the Family Housing Improvement Fund; and the Military Unaccompanied Housing Improvement Fund. Within the VA budget, the bill provides appropriations for

 the Veterans Benefits Administration, the Veterans Health Administration, the National Cemetery Administration, and Departmental Administration. The bill provides appropriations for related agencies and programs, including

 the American Battle Monuments Commission, the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims, Cemeterial Expenses of the Army, and the Armed Forces Retirement Home. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-81</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
