<bill session="118" type="h" number="5246" updated="2025-11-19T04:29:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Agricultural Crisis Hotline Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Agricultural Crisis Hotline Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food, Conservation, and Energy Act of 2008 to reauthorize the Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network and establish a national agricultural crisis hotline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001134"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2023-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000594" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2023-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3761" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-24T15:58:19Z" status="Introduced in House">National Agricultural Crisis Hotline Act of 2023

This bill establishes a national agricultural crisis hotline. The bill also reauthorizes the Farm and Ranch Stress Assistance Network (FRSAN) Program through FY2028. (The FRSAN Program funds projects that aim to maintain a network connecting individuals engaged in farming, ranching, and other agriculture-related occupations to stress assistance programs.)

Specifically, the Department of Agriculture&#160;(USDA) must establish, and maintain directly or by grant or contract, a national agricultural crisis hotline as part of the FRSAN. The crisis hotline must provide emotional support, information, suicide crisis intervention, mental health and substance use disorder, and agricultural support resources to farmers, farm managers, farm workers, and ranchers affected by mental health and substance use disorders and their families or household members.

Under the program, USDA or an entity receiving a grant or contract must (1) form partnerships between the crisis hotline and existing farm telephone helplines and websites; and (2) develop, and periodically update, a directory of organizations to which hotline staff can make referrals.

The bill also includes requirements for

the qualifications and training for the call responders and supervisors operating the hotline,data collection by the hotline, andconducting a public awareness campaign for the hotline.&#160;In addition, the bill expands the types of programs eligible for FRSAN grants to include mental health training for agriculture professionals (e.g., farm loan officers, extension agents, and state department of agriculture staff).&#160;</summary>
</bill>
