<bill session="111" type="h" number="1679" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:37Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-22T15:48:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-04-22T15:48:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">House Reservists Pay Adjustment Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">House Reservists Pay Adjustment Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">House Reservists Pay Adjustment Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the replacement of lost income for employees of the House of Representatives who are members of a reserve component of the Armed Forces who are on active duty for a period of more than 30 days, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001045" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000517" joined="2009-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001165" joined="2009-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-24">
      <text>Referred to House Standards of Official Conduct</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 111-85, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Standards of Official Conduct discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-04-22" calendar="Union" number="39">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 39.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T11:05:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Brady (PA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T11:05:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4595-4597" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T11:05:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1679.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T11:08:34-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T15:14:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4653-4654" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="196" datetime="2009-04-22T15:48:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 423 - 0 (Roll no. 196).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4595-4596" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22T15:49:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Ethics" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-27T21:18:43Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

House Reservists Pay Adjustment Act of 2009 - Requires the Chief Administrative Officer (CAO) of the House of Representatives to pay an eligible House employee, who is also a member of a Reserve component of the Armed Forces, for each active duty month the amount by which the employee's regular compensation from the House would have exceeded (if at all) the total monthly military compensation paid to the employee for the active duty month by the Secretary of Defense.

Limits employee eligibility for such adjusted compensation to those employed by the House each day of the 90 days ending on the day on which the employee reports for active duty under an involuntary mobilization order.

Requires the CAO to reduce the amount of any payment to such employee for an active duty month by the amount of any pay and allowances received by the individual from any other source as replacement of lost income.

Prohibits the CAO from making a required payment under this Act unless the payment, taking into account any reduction, is at least $50.

Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to declare that nothing in such Rule may be construed to prohibit the disbursement or receipt of any payment authorized under this Act.

Amends the Legislative Branch Appropriation Act, 1955 to declare that nothing in the Act may be construed to prohibit the CAO from paying a gratuity to the widow, widower, or heirs-at-law of a House employee who dies during an active duty month.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-85</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
