<bill session="118" type="hr" number="1243" updated="2025-08-23T15:10:00Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-22T14:45:36-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-22T14:45:36-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4763) to provide for a system of regulation of digital assets by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5403) to amend the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit the Federal reserve banks from offering certain products or services directly to an individual, to prohibit the use of central bank digital currency for monetary policy, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 192) to prohibit individuals who are not citizens of the United States from voting in elections in the District of Columbia.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 4763) to provide for a system of regulation of digital assets by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 5403) to amend the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit the Federal reserve banks from offering certain products or services directly to an individual, to prohibit the use of central bank digital currency for monetary policy, and for other purposes; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 192) to prohibit individuals who are not citizens of the United States from voting in elections in the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001093"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-516, by Mrs. Houchin.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-21T19:46:03-04:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each bill. H.R. 4763 and H.R. 5403 are considered under a structured rule and H.R. 192 is considered under a closed rule. The resolution provides for one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-05-21" calendar="House" number="77">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 77.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T12:15:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3414-3418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T12:20:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T13:46:58-04:00">
      <text>WORDS TAKEN DOWN - During the course of debate, exception was taken to certain words used and a demand was made to have the words taken down. After review, the Chair ruled that the words were in violation of the spirit of debate. Without objection the words were stricken from the record.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T13:47:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with further debate on H. Res. 1243.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:32:49-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 205 - 203 (Roll no. 221).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="222" datetime="2024-05-22T14:45:36-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 204 - 203 (Roll no. 222).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3414-3415" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-22T14:45:37-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5403" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4763" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="192" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-23T15:09:29Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution provides for the House of Representatives to consider

H.R. 4763, to provide for a system of regulation of digital assets by the Commodity Futures Trading Commission and the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes;&#160;H.R. 5403, to amend the Federal Reserve Act to prohibit the Federal Reserve banks from offering certain products or services directly to an individual, to prohibit the use of central bank digital currency for monetary policy, and for other purposes; and&#160;H.R. 192, to prohibit individuals who are not citizens of the United States from voting in elections in the District of Columbia.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-516</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
