<bill session="116" type="h" number="2917" updated="2022-11-01T05:47:40Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Opioid Crisis Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To hold pharmaceutical companies accountable for dubious marketing and distribution of opioid products and for their role in creating and exacerbating the opioid epidemic in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opioid Crisis Accountability Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-05-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1584" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-04T19:19:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Opioid Crisis Accountability Act of 2019

This bill establishes a series of restrictions and requirements relating to opioid marketing and distribution practices.

Specifically, the bill prohibits (1) knowingly making false advertising or marketing claims regarding the addictive nature of opioids; (2) knowingly supplying communities with quantities of opioids that are not medically reasonable; or (3) failing to report distribution orders, or patterns of orders, while knowing that the orders are not being dispensed in a medically reasonable manner. Employees of opioid manufacturers and distributors are subject to civil penalties and imprisonment for violations; corporations and executives are subject to civil penalties. Manufacturers shall also lose their period of market exclusivity.

Additionally, the Department of Health and Human Services must assess a fee against each corporation that, between January 1, 1993, and the date of enactment of this bill, manufactured or distributed opioids, if such opioids were covered under a federal health program at least once during this period. Manufacturers that fail to pay the fee shall lose associated drug approval until the fee is paid in full.

The bill authorizes collected civil penalties and fees to be used for activities that address opioid misuse and abuse, including family and educational programs.</summary>
</bill>
