<bill session="112" type="h" number="3122" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:10Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Construction Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to establish procedures to advance the use of cleaner construction equipment on Federal-aid highway and public transportation construction projects, to make the acquisition and installation of emission control technology an eligible expense in carrying out such projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Construction Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2011-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000285" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2011-11-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="972" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-01-17T18:59:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Clean Construction Act of 2011 - Requires all off-road diesel equipment and on-road diesel equipment operating for at least 80 hours over the life of a federal-aid highway construction project or public transportation construction project within a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area to have diesel emission control technology installed. Applies the same requirement to all covered equipment used on a covered public transportation construction project within a PM2.5 nonattainment or maintenance area.

Defines: (1) "off-road diesel equipment" as a vehicle (including covered equipment) that is powered by a nonroad diesel engine of at least 50 horsepower and not intended for highway use; and (2) "on-road diesel equipment" as any self-propelled vehicle that operates on diesel fuel, is designed to transport persons or property on a street or highway, and has a gross vehicle weight of at least 14,000 pounds.

Directs the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) to approve as part of the federal share of cost of a federal-aid highway construction project or public transportation construction project an amount equal to the state expenditure for acquiring and installing diesel emission control technology, if the state expenditure meets certain criteria.

Directs the Secretary and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) Administrator to establish jointly a streamlined process to ensure that states may: (1) quantify the emissions reductions achieved under this Act; and (2) include such reductions in state implementation plans for national primary and secondary ambient air quality standards under the Clean Air Act to demonstrate progress toward, attainment of, or maintenance of such standards.</summary>
</bill>
