<bill session="116" type="h" number="5502" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Removing Federal Barriers to Offering of Mobile Sports Wagers on Indian Lands Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To remove Federal barriers regarding the offering of mobile sports wagers on Indian lands when the applicable State and Indian Tribe have reached an agreement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Removing Federal Barriers to Offering of Mobile Sports Wagers on Indian Lands Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2019-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-01T23:02:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Removing Federal Barriers to Offering of Mobile Sports Wagers on Indian Lands Act

This bill establishes provisions related to the regulation of certain online sports wagers (i.e., bets) as Indian gaming.

The bill deems an online sports wager as occurring exclusively on Indian lands, and therefore subject to the jurisdictional framework that governs Indian gaming, if (1) the person placing the wager and the server that accepts the wager are located in the same state, and (2) the applicable state and Indian tribe have entered into a gaming compact that authorizes online sports wagering.

For the purposes of regulation as Indian gaming, an online sports wager is deemed to be made at the physical location of the server or other computer equipment used to accept the wager.

The bill also excludes online sports wagering platform vendors from the management contract requirements related to Indian gaming.</summary>
</bill>
