<bill session="108" type="h" number="4602" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:14Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alaska Native Allotment Subdivision Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the subdivision and dedication of restricted land owned by Alaska Natives.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Native Allotment Subdivision Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1421" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Land subdivision"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-17T20:21:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Alaska Native Allotment Subdivision Act - Authorizes an Alaskan Native owner of restricted land (land in Alaska subject to Federal restrictions against alienation and taxation), with the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, to: (1) subdivide the restricted land in accordance with State laws or applicable local platting authority; and (2) execute a certificate of ownership and dedication regarding such land with the same effect under State law as if the subdivided and dedicated land were held by unrestricted fee simple title.

Ratifies and confirms prior subdivisions and dedications as of the date of the Secretary's approval.

Provides that, except in a case in which a specific interest in such restricted land is dedicated, nothing in this Act terminates, diminishes, or otherwise affects the continued existence and applicability of Federal restrictions against alienation and taxation on restricted land or interests in restricted land (including such subdivided restricted land).</summary>
</bill>
