<bill session="119" type="h" number="6028" updated="2025-11-19T19:20:10Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Legislative Branch Agencies Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Branch Agencies Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the appointment and removal process for certain legislative branch officers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-11-19T19:19:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Legislative Branch Agencies Clarification Act

This bill revises the procedures for appointing and removing the Librarian of Congress, the Director of the Government Publishing Office (GPO), and the Register of Copyrights.

Specifically, the bill requires the Librarian and the Director of GPO to be appointed by a bipartisan congressional commission, based on procedures outlined by the bill and without regard to political&#160;affiliation. (Currently, these positions are appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate.) The Librarian and the Director of GPO may only be removed from office by a majority vote of the majority and minority leaders of the House of Representatives and the Senate.

Additionally, the bill requires the Librarian and the Director of GPO to each appoint a deputy within a set time frame and outlines related procedures.

The bill removes the Library of Congress's (LOC's) supervisory authority over the Copyright Office.&#160;LOC and other legislative agencies may provide support services to the Copyright Office.

The bill requires the Register of Copyrights to be (1) a U.S. citizen with a background and experience in copyright law, and (2) appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. (Currently, the Register is appointed by the Librarian.) The bill limits the term of office for the Register to 10 years, but the individual may be&#160;reappointed.

The bill also requires GPO to establish and maintain a human capital management system and outlines the requirements for the system.</summary>
</bill>
