<bill session="119" type="s" number="22" updated="2025-11-18T23:14:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a competitive bidding process for the relocation of the headquarters of Executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="514" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-31T20:57:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act or the SWAMP Act

This bill prohibits new construction, major renovation, leasing, or renewing a lease of certain executive agency headquarters in the District of Columbia metropolitan area and establishes a competitive bidding process for the relocation of such headquarters.

The General Services Administration (GSA) must (1) establish a process to allow an executive agency to request the GSA to issue a solicitation for the relocation of its headquarters or allow the GSA to issue such a solicitation without a request, if necessary; (2) allow any state or political subdivision of a state to respond to a solicitation with a proposal for the relocation of the agency's headquarters; and (3) in consultation with the executive agency, select a state or political subdivision of a state for the relocation of the agency's headquarters using a competitive bidding procedure based on certain considerations.</summary>
</bill>
