<bill session="117" type="s" number="2200" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to establish a research, development, demonstration, and deployment program to improve the efficiency, increase the durability, and reduce the cost of producing hydrogen using electrolyzers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing the Clean Hydrogen Future Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing the Clean Hydrogen Future Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-27T19:36:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Advancing the Clean Hydrogen Future Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a research, development, demonstration, and deployment program to improve the efficiency, increase the durability, and reduce the cost of producing hydrogen using electrolyzers. Electrolyzers are systems that produce hydrogen using electrolysis, a process that uses electricity to split water into hydrogen and oxygen. The goal of the program is to reduce the cost of hydrogen produced using electrolyzers to less than $2 per kilogram of hydrogen by 2026.

In carrying out the program, DOE must award grants for projects that DOE determines would provide the greatest progress toward achieving the goal. In addition, DOE must fund demonstration projects under the program to (1) demonstrate technologies that produce hydrogen using electrolysis; and (2) validate information on the cost, efficiency, durability, and feasibility of commercial deployment of those technologies.</summary>
</bill>
