<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1779</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T20:41:57Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T20:41:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2007-07-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
        <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Other</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2008-10-01T23:39:54Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2008-04-24T18:54:15Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2007-07-12T20:44:01Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 110-519</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-10-01</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1110.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-10-01</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-519.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-10-01</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Dorgan with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 110-519.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2008-04-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-07-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>slia00</systemCode>
            <name>Indian Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-07-12</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9143)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-07-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>T000464</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Tester, Jon [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Tester</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000432</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Dorgan, Byron L. [D-ND]</fullName>
        <firstName>BYRON</firstName>
        <lastName>DORGAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>ND</state>
        <middleName>LESLIE</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2007-07-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000243</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Baucus, Max [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>MAX</firstName>
        <lastName>BAUCUS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <middleName>SIEBEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2008-04-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2008-04-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>J000177</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Johnson, Tim [D-SD]</fullName>
        <firstName>TIM</firstName>
        <lastName>JOHNSON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>SD</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2008-04-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2008-06-26T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1779, Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/20005</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs on April 24, 2008&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2008-06-26T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1779, Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/20005</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Indian Affairs on April 24, 2008</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Native Americans</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Community health services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Epidemiology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to Indians</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian medical care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Preventive medicine</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rural health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Native Americans</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-07-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-12-20T21:20:33Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2007 - Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act or THE PATH Act - Designates the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health within the Office of Public Health and Science of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), to serve as the coordinating officer with respect to programs of tribal colleges and universities relating to health promotion and disease prevention. </p><p>Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement a memorandum of agreement with the American Indian Higher Education Consortium to establish programs to: (1) ensure that Native American communities, through tribal colleges and universities, participate equitably in employment programs, services, and resources of HHS; and (2) provide necessary technical assistance.</p><p>Establishes programs for: (1) community-based health and wellness fairs; (2) health promotion and disease prevention targeted programs and construction and renovation of community wellness centers; and (3) development and expansion of public health professional degree programs.</p><p>Establishes: (1) the Tribal College and University Rural Health Equity Endowment Fund; (2) offices of sponsored programs at tribal colleges and universities; and (3) health promotion and disease prevention research programs. </p><p>Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act or the AT TCUs Act - Establishes within the Administration on Native Americans, the Office on Tribal College and University Programs to: (1) administer the programs authorized by this Act; and (2) coordinate intra- and inter-departmental activities relating to tribal colleges and universities. </p><p>Establishes the: (1) Native Prosperity and Native American Language Vitalization and Training Programs; and (2) tribal colleges and universities native communities research program.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2008-10-01</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2008-12-19T22:20:51Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2008 - <b>Title I: Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health</b> - Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act or THE PATH Act - (Sec. 104) Designates the Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health within the Office of Public Health and Science of the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) as the coordinating officer for programs of tribal colleges and universities (tribal colleges) relating to health care workforce development and health promotion and disease prevention.</p><p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and implement a formal memorandum of agreement with the American Indian Higher Education Consortium to establish programs to ensure equitable Native American participation in HHS programs, services, and resources and to provide technical assistance to tribal colleges. </p><p>(Sec. 105) Directs the Secretary to provide for grants, or enter into cooperative agreements with, tribal colleges to: (1) carry out annual, community-based, and culturally relevant health and wellness fairs at tribal colleges; and (2) assist tribal colleges to carry out health promotion and disease prevention programs and reduce health disparities in tribal communities. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2017.</p><p>(Sec. 107) Directs the Secretary to provide grants to tribal colleges to develop and strengthen public health professional degree programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2017.</p><p>(Sec. 108) Establishes in the Treasury the Tribal College and University Rural Health Equity Endowment Fund to establish and maintain an endowment for a health professions workforce development program at tribal colleges. </p><p>(Sec. 109) Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program to establish and maintain at tribal college offices sponsored programs for research, grant management, and coordination of tribal college activities.</p><p>Requires tribal colleges to report to the Director in FY2010-FY2018 on sponsored programs. </p><p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2017.</p><p>(Sec. 110) Directs the Secretary to provide for competitive grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with, tribal colleges to conduct research on health promotion and disease prevention at the tribal colleges. Limits the term of such grants or cooperative agreements to three years and establishes the minimum amount of grants at $150,000 for a fiscal year. Provides a one-year term and a $10,000 minimum amount for undergraduate research experience program grants. Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2017. </p><p><b>Title II: Advancing Tribes through Tribal Colleges and Universities</b> - Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act or the AT TCUs Act - (Sec. 203) Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to require the Secretary of Labor to establish the TCU Native Prosperity Program to provide for grants to, or offer to enter into cooperative agreements with, eligible tribal colleges to promote economic development, entrepreneurship, community development, and sound fiscal leadership in Indian communities. Limits grant periods to five years, but allows a three-year extension on a non-competitive basis for tribal colleges that perform successfully. </p><p>Allows a tribal college to use assistance received under this Act to carry out specified activities, including: (1) microenterprise development; (2) business development and administration courses and degree programs; (3) entrepreneurship programs; (4) municipality planning and administration courses, degree programs, and in-service training; and (5) executive leadership training in economic development, planning, and emerging management issues. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a cooperative agreement with the American Indian Higher Education Consortium to provide tribal colleges with technical assistance.</p><p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2009-FY2012.</p><p>(Sec. 204) Defines &quot;tribal college or university&quot; to mean: (1) an institution that is eligible to receive funds under the Tribally Controlled College or University Assistance Act of 1978; (2) Dine College; and (3) any of the 1994 Institutions listed in the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2008</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish a program for tribal colleges and universities within the Department of Health and Human Services and to amend the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to authorize the provision of grants and cooperative agreements to tribal colleges and universities, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2008</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>THE PATH Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>AT TCUs Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Tribal Health Promotion and Tribal Colleges and Universities Advancement Act of 2008</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>AT TCUs Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Advancing Tribes Through Tribal Colleges and Universities Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>THE PATH Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Through Higher Education: Promoting the Advancement of Tribal Health Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2008-10-01T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s1779rs/xml/BILLS-110s1779rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2007-07-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s1779is/xml/BILLS-110s1779is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2008-10-01</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1110.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
