<bill session="117" type="h" number="102" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Faith in Elections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure election integrity and security and enhance Americans' access to the ballot box by establishing consistent standards and procedures for voter registration and voting in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Faith in Elections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Automatic Voter Registration Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Verifiable, Orderly, and Timely Election Results Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2021-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1130" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-20T16:55:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoring Faith in Elections Act

This bill establishes certain standards for voting, including voting by mail, in federal elections. It also establishes certain requirements for voter registration and maintenance of official lists of eligible voters.

First, the bill establishes certain requirements for voting by mail in federal elections, including by requiring mail-in ballots to be received by the time the polls close on election day.

Additionally, the bill makes it unlawful to possess or return a mail-in ballot completed by another person (commonly referred to as ballot harvesting), with exceptions. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to one year, or both.

Further, the bill establishes certain requirements for reporting results of federal elections, including by requiring states to count all eligible ballots within 24 hours after the election.

Next, the bill provides for the automatic registration of eligible voters. The Election Assistance Commission must make grants to states to implement these automatic voter registration programs.

The bill requires voters to present photo identification to vote.

It also requires states and jurisdictions to use standards that apply equally to all methods of voting used in federal elections, including standards related to signature verification.

Finally, the bill establishes the National Deconfliction Voting Database and Clearinghouse to serve as a database and clearinghouse for voter registration records and lists of eligible voters. Additionally, each state must certify that it has removed ineligible voters from the official lists of eligible voters prior to the federal election.</summary>
</bill>
