<bill session="117" type="s" number="1788" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:04Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring the IRS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide appropriations for the Internal Revenue Service to overhaul technology and strengthen enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring the IRS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-07T15:53:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring the IRS Act

This bill provides additional appropriations after FY2021 for the expenses of the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) for taxpayer services, enforcement activities, and business systems modernization.

The bill establishes new reporting requirements for certain banks or other financial institutions and increases enforcement penalties for accuracy-related underpayments of tax up to a maximum of 40% of the underpayment for taxpayers with taxable incomes greater than $5 million.

The IRS must report to Congress annually on plans to shift more of its auditing and enforcement assets toward high-income tax filers. The report must also include a tax gap analysis and a comprehensive analysis and description of whether there are any racial disparities in its enforcement activities or audits.

The bill also applies false claims rules to claims, records, or statements made by taxpayers whose gross income equals or exceeds $10 million for the taxable year, and the damages sustained by the government due to such false claims exceed $1 million.</summary>
</bill>
