<bill session="111" type="h" number="6050" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bent's Old Fort Museum Collections Facility Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior, and in cooperation with the Koshare Indian Museum, to assist in the expansion of the Museum's storage facility in La Junta, Colorado, to house the collection of Bent's Old Fort National Historic Site and collections from other National Park Service units.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bent's Old Fort Museum Collections Facility Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001172"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-19T15:04:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Bent's Old Fort Museum Collections Facility Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement with the Koshare Indian Museum (Museum) on the Otero Junior College campus in La Junta, Colorado, to: (1) assist in the construction and furnishing of an addition to the Museum for use as a curatorial center to house the Museum's collections from Bent's Old Fort, Sand Creek Massacre, and other units of the National Park System; (2) provide no more than a specified amount for the construction and furnishing of the addition; and (3) house those portions of the collections of Bent's Old Fort, Sand Creek Massacre, and Washita Battlefield National Historic Sites, and possibly collections from other System units, that the Director of the National Park Service (NPS) determines appropriate for the facility.

Requires federal funding provided for the construction and furnishing of such addition to be matched by non-federal contributions on a 1:1 basis.

Requires the curatorial addition authorized by this Act to remain part of the Museum.

Makes the Museum responsible for the maintenance and operational costs associated with the Museum, including the curatorial addition.

Authorizes the assignment of NPS staff to provide curatorial services for the NPS museum objects housed at the Museum and to assist with the curation of other objects housed there.</summary>
</bill>
