<bill session="116" type="s" number="3780" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HOME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Onshore Manufacturing Efficiencies for Drugs and Devices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOME Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage domestic advanced manufacturing of critical drugs and devices in order to address economic, health, and security concerns, combat shortages of critical drugs and devices, and promote increased domestic diversification of, and independence from foreign reliance on, pharmaceutical and medical device supply chains.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T16:09:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Help Onshore Manufacturing Efficiencies for Drugs and Devices Act or the HOME Act

This bill contains provisions related to critical drugs and medical devices.

The bill establishes within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) the Center for Domestic Advanced Manufacturing of Critical Drugs and Devices. The center shall establish and implement a program to provide grants and forgivable loans to support investment in advanced manufacturing for the domestic production of critical drugs, medical devices, and active pharmaceutical ingredients.

Furthermore, a supplemental application for a critical drug approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) may receive expedited review if, among other requirements, the applicant plans to produce the drug domestically after the approval of the supplemental application. (A supplemental application generally involves a change, such as a manufacturing change, to an existing application for FDA approval.)

The bill also authorizes HHS and the Department of Defense to enter into multiyear high-volume contracts to purchase critical drugs and medical devices.</summary>
</bill>
