<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="475" updated="2022-02-03T04:57:33Z">
  <amends type="h" number="339" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-03-10T16:25:30-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000043"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-03-10"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (preceding the amendment to the long title), insert the following new section: \   SEC. 5. ACTIONS BY YOUNG CHILDREN AGAINST SELLERS THAT MARKET TO YOUNG CHILDREN. \   Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, this Act shall not apply to an action brought by, or on behalf of, a person injured at or before the age of 8, against a seller that, as part of a chain of outlets at least 20 of which do business under the same trade name (regardless of form of ownership of any outlet), markets qualified products to minors at or under the age of 8.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in the Congressional Record to provide that the bill would not apply civil actions brought by, or on behalf of, a child or person injured at or before the age of 8, against a seller that is part of a chain with at least 20 outlets, that markets food products to minors 8 years of age or under.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-03-10T16:25:30-05:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lampson amendment (A007) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:08:54-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Lampson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H971-972" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H971" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:08:54-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Lampson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H971-972" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H971" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:25:30-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:25:30-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Lampson amendment (A007) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
