<bill session="116" type="h" number="2101" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:19Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for restrictions on recently appointed Federal employees and recently separated Federal employees with respect to lobbying activities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for restrictions on recently appointed Federal employees and recently separated Federal employees with respect to lobbying activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2019-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2019-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-21T11:33:11Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill places restrictions on certain lobbying activities by recently separated and recently appointed federal employees.

 Specifically, the bill extends to two years the ban on certain senior personnel of the executive branch and independent agencies from lobbying the department or agency in which the person served. The bill also extends to five years the ban on certain senior personnel of the executive branch and independent agencies, including the Vice President, from lobbying any officer or employee of any department or agency in which such person served.

Certain high-level employees of the executive branch are subject to a lifetime ban on knowingly representing a foreign entity before any officer or employee of any department or agency of the United States with the intent to influence a decision of such officer or employee.

During a two-year period beginning on the date an individual is appointed to a covered position, such individual is banned from participating in any matter involving specific parties that is directly related to the individual's former employer or former clients. Additionally, any individual who was a registered lobbyist or who engaged in lobbying activities during a two-year period prior to appointment is prohibited from participating in a matter on which the individual made a lobbying contact.

The Office of Management and Budget (OMB) may waive these requiremens if OMB certifies in writing to various congressional committees that it is in the public interest to grant the waiver.</summary>
</bill>
