<bill session="117" type="h" number="7939" updated="2023-09-06T16:22:05Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Auto and Education Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Veteran Emergency Relief Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Student Veteran Emergency Relief Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Veterans Auto and Education Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Sgt. Wolf Kyle Weninger Veterans Education Fairness Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Veterans Auto and Education Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Sgt. Wolf Kyle Weninger Veterans Education Fairness Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make permanent certain educational assistance benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs in the case of changes to courses of education by reason of emergency situations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2022-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2022-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2022-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-13T15:49:35-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-13T15:50:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7760-7767" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7761-7765" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-13T15:50:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-13T16:00:36-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T15:18:19-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1339, proceedings on H.R. 7939 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2022-09-14T15:18:20-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 11 of H. Res. 1339, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 1468, as amended; H.R. 5865; H.R. 5916, as amended; H.R. 7735, as amended; H.R. 7846; H.R. 7939, as amended; H.R. 8260, as amended; and S. 4205.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7814-7822" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7814-7819" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9609-9610" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2022-12-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9643-9649" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T16:50:15-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9961-9968" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T16:50:31-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 7939.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T17:02:19-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="546" datetime="2022-12-22T16:09:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 380 - 35 (Roll no. 546).</text>
      <reference ref="CR  H10037-10038" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="12/21/2022 CR H9961-9966" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-22T16:09:02-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2023-01-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-333" type="public" datetime="2023-01-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-333.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1339" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4702" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7074" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7369" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7746" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s6578"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-09-06T15:57:53Z" status="Public Law">Veterans Auto and Education Improvement Act of 2022

This act modifies provisions related to programs and benefits for veterans, including by providing permanent authority for the application of certain flexibilities to assist veterans with their educational assistance benefits during emergency situations. An emergency situation is defined as a situation that the President declares as an emergency and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) determines is an emergency for purposes of the laws it administers.

Specifically, the act extends certain program adjustments that were implemented during the COVID-19 emergency (including adjustments made in the Student Veteran Coronavirus Response Act of 2020) to other emergency situations that may arise and have an effect on veterans and their educational assistance benefits.

Among other flexibilities, the act (1) authorizes the VA to continue to provide educational assistance, including monthly housing stipends or subsistence allowances, for programs of education that have been converted to distance learning due to an emergency or health-related situation; and (2) extends the time limitation for using educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill, Post-9/11 GI Bill, or vocational rehabilitation program when institutions are closed due to an emergency situation or executive order.

Due to an emergency situation, the VA is authorized to

 extend by two months the payment of vocational rehabilitation subsistence allowances, continue paying work-study allowances and extend work-study agreements, and continue paying educational assistance and subsistence allowances for a specified amount of time for programs of education that are suspended or closed. This act also adjusts the administration of certain benefits for veterans participating in an apprenticeship or other on-job training during an emergency situation, including by proportionately reducing the 120-hour monthly training requirement to reflect an individual's period of unemployment without a reduction in training assistance.

An educational assistance payment shall not be charged against an individual's entitlement to educational assistance if an individual was unable to complete a course or program due to the temporary closure of an educational institution or the temporary termination of a program by reason of an emergency situation.

The act provides the requirements that must be met for a study-abroad course to be approved for purposes of VA educational assistance.

The act provides eligibility for Post-9/11 GI Bill educational assistance for individuals, including officers, who are discharged or released from active duty with a sole survivorship discharge following at least 30 continuous days on qualifying active duty after September 10, 2001.

The VA must partner with state approving agencies, educational institutions, and training establishments to require the use of a uniform application for the VA's course approval process. The uniform application must be developed by October 1, 2023, and be required for the approval of any new course of education proposed on or after that day.

The act provides notice requirements for VA education surveys. Specifically, the VA or a state approving agency must provide not more than one business day of notice to an educational institution before conducting a targeted risk-based survey. The VA or state approving agency must provide not more than 10 business days of notice to an educational institution or training establishment before conducting a compliance survey.

Under the act, educational institutions are excepted from the requirement to verify the enrollment of certain individuals who are receiving VA educational assistance (e.g., individuals who are enrolled in a program on at least a full-time basis before they are able to withdraw from the course without penalty).

The act expands eligibility for self-employment assistance under the Veteran Readiness and Employment Program to include certain veterans who have a service-connected disability or employment handicap in addition to those with the most severe service-connected disabilities.

The VA must report on possible definitions for student services, marketing, and classroom instruction for purposes of VA educational assistance.

The act extends through November 30, 2031, certain limitations on pension payments to veterans who have no dependents and are being furnished domiciliary care by the VA.

The act authorizes a servicemember to terminate specified contracts (e.g., contracts for commercial mobile service or internet service) that are entered into in relation to military orders for a permanent change of station if the member then receives a stop movement order in response to a local, national, or global emergency which prevents the member from using the services provided under the contract.

The act provides that a spouse of a servicemember may retain their personal residence or domicile for purposes of taxation. Under the act, a servicemember and the spouse of the member are authorized to elect to use the following locations for purposes of taxation:

 the residence or domicile of the member, the residence or domicile of the spouse, or the permanent duty station of the member. The act provides for the portability of professional licenses of servicemembers and their spouses who are relocated, because of military orders, outside of the jurisdiction that issued the license.

The act authorizes the VA to provide non-articulating trailers (adaptive equipment) to veterans with specified disabilities or diseases incurred or aggravated due to their military service.

The act authorizes the VA to provide (or assist in providing) an eligible veteran or servicemember with an additional automobile or other conveyance under the VA automobile allowance and adaptive equipment program if (1) more than 30 years have elapsed since the person last received such benefit; or (2) beginning 10 years after the date of this act, if more than 10 years have elapsed since the person last received such benefit.

Finally, the act includes certain vehicle modifications (e.g., van lifts) under the definition of medical services for VA health care purposes.</summary>
</bill>
