<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6368</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:29Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:29Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-09-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-09-29T14:24:35Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR E1857)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000147</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Del. Norton, Eleanor Holmes [D-DC-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>ELEANOR</firstName>
        <lastName>NORTON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DC</state>
        <middleName>HOLMES</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Disability assistance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-02-25T21:39:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Federal Employee Disability Insurance Act of 2010 - Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to establish and administer a program to make available insurance coverage for an injury occurring outside the workplace or for other disability otherwise not covered under federal employee worker's compensation provisions. Makes such insurance unavailable if the injury is caused by the employee's intention to bring about the injury to himself or to another individual. Requires an insurance contract under this provision to be fully insured.</p> <p>Requires the Director to contract with one or more carriers for such disability insurance policies. Authorizes the Director to prescribe reasonable minimum standards for benefit plans offered. Prohibits such a contract from providing for a preexisting condition exclusion.</p> <p> Allows an eligible employee to receive: (1) during the first 12 months that he or she qualifies, benefits equal to the lesser of 70% of his or her monthly pay at the time the injury or sickness occurs or 70% of the maximum rate of basic pay provided for grade GS-15 of the general schedule, beginning after expiration of the waiting period elected by the employee; and (2) after such 12-month period, benefits equal to 50% of monthly pay until age 67, only if such employee is totally disabled.</p> <p>Requires each eligible individual obtaining insurance coverage under this Act to be responsible for 100% of the premiums, which shall be higher for employees who elect a shorter waiting period. </p> <p>Establishes in the Employees' Life Insurance Fund a Non-Work Related Disability Insurance Administrative Account, which shall be available to OPM to defray reasonable expenses incurred in administering this Act and to which contracted carriers shall make contributions necessary to cover such expenses.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Federal Employee Disability Insurance Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Federal Employee Disability Insurance Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To provide for a voluntary, non-work related disability insurance program for Federal employees.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Federal Employee Disability Insurance Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr6368ih/xml/BILLS-111hr6368ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
