<bill session="108" type="s" number="1829" updated="2023-01-15T08:48:05Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Better Eating for Better Living Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 and the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve the nutrition and health of children in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Eating for Better Living Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1750" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Nutrition policy"/>
    <term name="Nutrition surveys"/>
    <term name="Nutritionally induced diseases"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-23T19:35:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Eating for Better Living Act of 2003 - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) and the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (NSLA) to revise school lunch programs with respect to reimbursement rates, nutrition guidelines, milk guidelines, and funds for nutrition education and training.

Amends NLSA to increase the reimbursement rate for school lunches by 20.5 cents per meal (from 10.5 to 31).

 Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) to evaluate nutrition guidelines for school meals, and issue any necessary revised guidelines, every five years.

 Revises milk guidelines. Requires schools, at a minimum, to offer students a choice of low fat or nonfat fluid milk. Allows schools, in addition, to offer any other varieties of fluid milk that are: (1) consistent with expressed preferences of the student population; and (2) reasonably equivalent in calcium, protein, vitamin A, and vitamin K content and cost.

Amends CNA to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Secretary specified amounts of funds for implementing and administering nutrition education and training programs. Requires grants to each State from such amounts to be: (1) based on a rate of 1/2 cent per average daily number of meals served; and (2) allocated among State, district, and school food service and health education authorities, as determined by the Secretary. Sets a minimum grant amount.</summary>
</bill>
