<bill session="117" type="h" number="4222" updated="2022-12-31T04:58:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to include certain overtime pay received by members of the Capitol Police in the computation of annuities for such members, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Capitol Police Retirement Reform Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Capitol Police Retirement Reform Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2021-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2021-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4346" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8237" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-26T21:37:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Capitol Police Retirement Reform Act of 2021

This bill revises the treatment of overtime pay for members of the U.S. Capitol Police for purposes of calculating certain annuity benefits, including benefits received upon a member's retirement.

Specifically, the bill categorizes overtime pay as basic pay, subject to annual statutory maximums. (Basic pay is used to calculate a member's average earnings amount upon which benefits are based.)

Overtime pay may only be treated as basic pay for purposes of a retirement annuity calculation under the Federal Employees Retirement System if the retiring member has completed at least 15 years of service. Further, such overtime pay may only be treated as basic pay if earned on or after the date of enactment, and only to the extent of the percentage allowable based upon the amount of service as set forth in this bill.

However, 100% of all amounts received as overtime pay by members of the Capitol Police earned on or after the date of enactment are treated as basic pay for purposes of computing

 a disability annuity; and a survivor annuity, if based on the service of an individual who dies before separating from service.</summary>
</bill>
