<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>430</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T22:18:43Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T22:18:43Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-02-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-02-24T22:35:10Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-09</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9027)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-15</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S11472-11473)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry. (text of measure as introduced: CR S2598-2600)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-24</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2596-2597)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-02-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000069</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Akaka, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>AKAKA</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KOHIKINA</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000123</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lautenberg, Frank R. [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <firstName>FRANK</firstName>
        <lastName>LAUTENBERG</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-11-24</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000563</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Durbin, Richard J. [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Durbin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-02-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001041</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Clinton, Hillary Rodham [D-NY]</fullName>
        <firstName>HILLARY</firstName>
        <lastName>CLINTON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>R</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-03-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Animal diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Animals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>EBB Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency Management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Livestock</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Plant diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Plant protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterinary medicine</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-02-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-11-28T17:35:40Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[Agriculture Security Preparedness Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish an agricultural disease management position in the Federal Emergency Management Agency to act as liaison between the Department and governmental and other entities in the emergency management community; (2) the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a similar animal health liaison position in the Department of Health and Human Services; (3) the Secretary of Transportation to develop guidelines for restrictions on interstate transportation of commodities or products in response to an agricultural disease; (4) the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consider potential environmental impacts of response activities in planning agricultural disease responses; (5) the Secretary of Agriculture to develop and implement agricultural risk information-sharing procedures among Federal, regional, State, and local entities; (6) the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish a task force, consisting of agricultural producers and State and local emergency response officials, to identify best practices for regional and State agricultural disease programs; (7) the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct studies on the feasibility of establishing a national plant disease laboratory, and on international agricultural disease surveillance; (8) the Secretary of Homeland Security to improve the Department of Agriculture's ability to identify agricultural commodities, products, and livestock imported from locations that have experienced agricultural terrorist activities or unusual agricultural diseases; (9) the Secretary of State to enter into mutual assistance agreements with other countries for assistance in the event of an agricultural disease, including training of U.S. veterinarians and agriculture specialists in the identification, diagnosis, and control of foreign agricultural diseases, and to provide resources and personnel to foreign governments with limited response resources; (10) the Attorney General to study the feasibility of establishing a national agroterrorism and ecoterrorism incident clearinghouse; and (11) the Secretary of Agriculture to develop a system to share information during all stages of an agroterrorism act.<p>Amends Federal criminal law to include attacks against private property, including agriculture- and livestock-related property, among terrorist acts involving weapons of mass destruction.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Agriculture Security Preparedness Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Agriculture Security Preparedness Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance agricultural biosecurity in the United States through increased prevention, preparation, and response planning.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Agriculture Security Preparedness Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-02-24T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-09-09</actionDate>
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9027)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
