<bill session="118" type="s" number="1932" updated="2025-11-18T19:47:06Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bridge Corrosion Prevention and Repair Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bridge Corrosion Prevention and Repair Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that certain aspects of bridge projects be carried out by certified contractors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4064" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-15T17:41:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bridge Corrosion Prevention and Repair Act of 2023

This bill establishes certain requirements to address corrosion control in bridge and railroad-bridge projects that receive federal assistance.

Specifically, certified contractors must employ a substantial number of individuals who are certified by a qualified training program in corrosion control, mitigation, and prevention in order to work on certain aspects of bridge project activities. A certified contractor must also provide training for any non-certified coating applicators employed by the contractor to work on certain aspects of a project.

The bill further requires bridge projects to implement a corrosion management system that utilizes industry-recognized standards and corrosion mitigation and prevention methods for construction, repair, and maintenance projects.

In addition, the bill expands the scope of the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing Program to include corrosion control work on rail bridges. (This program provides direct loans and loan guarantees for the development of railroad infrastructure.)

The bill also requires the Department of Transportation to study and report on best practices for inspecting and addressing corrosion on weathering steel bridges. This report must be made available to state and local governments, metropolitan planning organizations, and regional organizations.</summary>
</bill>
