<bill session="116" type="h" number="5503" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:14Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">The Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to direct the Director of the National Park Service to prioritize certain funds for high-commuter corridors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2019-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2020-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7095" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-11T15:24:08Z" status="Introduced in House">The Commuter Parkway Safety and Reliability Act

This bill requires the National Park Service (NPS) to prioritize the funds made available under the federal lands transportation program for high-commuter corridors. (A high-commuter corridor is a federal lands transportation facility administered by the NPS that has average annual daily traffic of not less than 20,000 vehicles.)

If the NPS determines that a high-commuter corridor requires additional investment it must submit to the state

 information on the condition of pavements and bridges; an estimate of the amounts needed to bring such corridor into a state of good repair, taking into consideration any planned future investments; and at its discretion, a request that the state transfer to the NPS a portion of the amounts necessary to address the condition of the corridor. The bill sets forth the criteria the NPS must consider when making a determination of whether a a high-commuter corridor requires additional investment.</summary>
</bill>
