<bill session="119" type="h" number="4371" updated="2025-10-24T18:26:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kayla Hamilton Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Kayla Hamilton Act</title>
    <title type="display">Kayla Hamilton Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 to enhance efforts to combat the trafficking of children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2025-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 16 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-17">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 119-345.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-17" calendar="Union" number="297">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 297.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-10T18:00:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Kayla Hamilton Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to consider additional information when it makes placement determinations for unaccompanied alien children in its custody. Under federal law, an unaccompanied alien child is a minor with no lawful immigration status and no parent or legal guardian in the United States to provide care and physical custody.

Current law&#160;requires&#160;HHS to (1) place a child in the least restrictive setting that is in the child's best interest, and (2) assess the safety and suitability of a sponsor prior to placing a child with that sponsor.&#160;

In determining the least restrictive setting, this bill requires (currently, permits) HHS to consider the child's danger to self, danger to the community, and flight risk. Additionally, the bill requires placement in a secure facility in the case of a child who is 13 years of age or older and has gang-related markings or tattoos or a history of gang-related arrests or criminal conduct.

In assessing the safety and suitability of a sponsor, this bill requires&#160;HHS to collect and provide to the Department of Homeland Security information about all adult residents of the household, including name, date of birth, Social Security number, immigration status, contact information, and the results of all background and criminal records checks. The bill also&#160;prohibits HHS from placing a child with a sponsor who is&#160;unlawfully present in the United States.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-345</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
