<bill session="116" type="s" number="3088" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACHA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACHA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Averting Crises in Housing Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance to public housing agencies that have failing properties in their inventories in order to protect the health and safety of public housing residents, to allow consortia to enter into single annual contributions contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-09T20:34:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Averting Crises in Housing Assistance Act or the ACHA Act

This bill creates a mechanism for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to identify and rehabilitate public housing agency (PHA) properties that are failing and revises requirements for contracts between PHAs and HUD.

After designating a property as failing based on its physical condition or residents' complaints, HUD must enter into an agreement with the PHA to establish an action plan to restore the property to good condition. HUD must require the PHA to notify the residents of the property of the timelines and deadlines established by the plan. HUD must also provide technical and other assistance to the PHA and must provide housing vouchers to tenants wishing to relocate during the rehabilitation process.

Residents of a failing property may sue HUD for damages if the property is not restored to good condition within one year after the PHA establishes an action plan.

Additionally, the bill allows a consortium of PHAs to enter into a single annual contributions contract (i.e., the contract under which HUD agrees to pay a PHA for housing assistance and administrative fees).</summary>
</bill>
