<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="31" updated="2024-03-18T20:09:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="21" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-01-26T18:25:26-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 89 printed in the Congressional Record to add a new subparagraph only allowing for a lease or permit if accompanied by a certification to the Secretary that it would not excessively increase the sales price of any petroleum products during a severe energy supply interruption or any period of decreased supply of petroleum products.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to only allow for a lease or permit if accompanied by a certification to the Secretary that it would not excessively increase the sales price of any petroleum products during a severe energy supply interruption or any period of decreased supply of petroleum products.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-01-26T18:25:26-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="55">
      <text>On agreeing to the DeGette amendment (A030) Failed by recorded vote: 212 - 220 (Roll no. 55).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T16:31:42-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Walberg raised a point of order against the DeGette amendment (A030). Mr. Walberg raised a point of order against the DeGette amendment. Mr. Walberg stated that the provisions of the amendment exceeds the scope of the bill and the amendment is therefore, not germane. Point of order overruled by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T16:27:06-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A030) offered by Ms. DeGette.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H380-381, H397" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T16:27:06-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A030) offered by Ms. DeGette.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H380-381, H397" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H380" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T18:25:26-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the DeGette amendment (A030) Failed by recorded vote: 212 - 220 (Roll no. 55).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T18:25:26-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26T18:25:26-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
