<bill session="108" type="s" number="2129" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:16Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Child Safety Device Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to require the provision of a child safety device in connection with the transfer of a handgun and to provide safety standards for child safety devices.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Safety Device Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1598"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Firearms injuries"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-01T20:48:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Safety Device Act of 2004 - Amends the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act to prohibit any licensed firearms importer, manufacturer, or dealer from selling, delivering, or transferring a handgun to any person other than a licensed importer, manufacturer, or dealer, unless the transferee is provided with a locking device for that handgun. Makes an exception where the transferee is a Federal, State, or local government, a law enforcement officer, or a rail police officer.

Subjects violators to license suspension or revocation or to a civil penalty of up to $15,000, or both.

Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to direct the Consumer Product Safety Commission to establish a consumer product safety standard that requires that such locking devices: (1) are sufficiently difficult for children to deactivate or remove; and (2) prevent the discharge of the handgun unless the device has been activated or removed.</summary>
</bill>
