<bill session="118" type="h" number="7391" updated="2024-08-31T08:06:20Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SUNRAY for Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing and Understanding our National Renewable Agriculture Yields for Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUNRAY for Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a study and research and demonstration on agrivoltaic systems and to issue guidance on best practices for protection of soil health and productivity during the siting, construction, operation, and decommissioning of solar energy systems on agricultural land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2024-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2024-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1778" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-17T18:03:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing and Understanding our National Renewable Agriculture Yields for Energy Act or the SUNRAY for Energy Act

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to conduct a study, research, and demonstration regarding agrivoltaic systems. The bill defines&#160;agrivoltaic system as a system under which solar energy production and agricultural production, including crop or animal production, occur in an integrated manner on the same piece of land through the duration of a project.

Specifically, the bill directs USDA to study agrivoltaic systems, which includes conducting a review of current research and identifying research gaps. USDA must also develop a five-year plan for using USDA's research, extension, outreach, conservation, and renewable energy activities to better support agrivoltaic systems that do not displace agricultural production.

USDA must also develop a definition for agrivoltaic system for the purposes of incorporating these systems into federal agriculture and energy programs, and investment tax credits.

In addition, the Agricultural Research Service must establish and maintain a network of agrivoltaic systems research and demonstration sites in multiple U.S. regions to investigate increasing agricultural productivity and profitability, enhancing agricultural resilience and the capacity to mitigate and adapt to climate change,&#160;protecting biodiversity, and increasing economic opportunities in rural communities.

Further, the Natural Resources Conservation Service must develop national and regional guidance on best practices for the protection of soil health and productivity during the siting, construction, operation, and decommissioning of solar energy systems on agricultural land. The guidance must be updated at least every two years.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
