<bill session="108" type="s" number="546" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the protection of paleontological resources on Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2003-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3265-3266"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3266-3268" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-69.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-93.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-07-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="201">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 201.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-07-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9605-9618" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9610-9612" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9608-9610" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18T09:05:05-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, USDA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fossils"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Official secrets"/>
    <term name="Paleontology"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Recidivists"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Paleontological Resources Preservation Act - Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture (the Secretaries) to: (1) manage and protect paleontological resources on Federal land using scientific principles and expertise; and (2) develop plans for inventorying, monitoring, and deriving the scientific and educational use of such resources.Directs the Secretaries to establish a program to increase public awareness about the significance of paleontological resources.Prohibits a person from collecting a paleontological resource from Federal land without a permit issued under this Act by one of the Secretaries. Authorizes the Secretaries to allow casual collecting of common invertebrate and plant paleontological resources for scientific, educational, and recreational uses, without a permit, on certain Federal lands where not inconsistent with laws governing management of such lands and this Act. Recognizes as valid permits issued before enactment of this Act.Prohibits: (1) excavating, removing, or altering a paleontological resource located on Federal lands, except in compliance with this Act; (2) exchanging or receiving such a resource, if the person knew or should have known such resource to have been illegally removed from Federal lands; (3) selling or purchasing a paleontological resource, if the person knew or should have known such resource to have been illegally removed from Federal lands; or (4) making or submitting false records, accounts, or identification of any paleontological resource excavated or removed from Federal lands. Imposes criminal penalties for violating this Act.Sets forth requirements for the assessment of civil penalties by the Secretaries for violations of any prohibitions contained in regulations or permits issued under this Act. Requires any recovered amounts to be available for use: (1) to protect or restore the paleontological resources and sites which were the subject of the action, or to acquire sites with equivalent resources and to protect, monitor, and study the resources and sites; (2) to provide educational materials to the public about paleontological resources and sites; and (3) as a reward.Requires that information on the nature and specific location of a paleontological resource that requires a permit under this Act or other Federal law be withheld from the public, including under the Freedom of Information Act, except under specified conditions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-93</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
