<bill session="119" type="h" number="1722" updated="2025-11-19T23:02:48Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Billion Dollar Boondoggle Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Billion Dollar Boondoggle Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an annual report of taxpayer-funded projects that are over budget and behind schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="766" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-07T14:02:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Billion Dollar Boondoggle Act of 2025

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to collect information from federal agencies and report to Congress regarding projects that are behind schedule or have expenditures that have exceeded the original cost estimate.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires OMB to issue guidance directing federal agencies to annually submit specified information to OMB regarding certain federally funded projects that (1) are more than five years behind schedule, or (2) have expenditures that are at least $1 billion more than the original cost estimate for the project.&#160;

Among other information, the agencies must submit to OMB

a description of each project;an explanation of any change to the original scope of the project;the original and current expected dates for the completion of the project;the original and current cost estimates adjusted for inflation;&#160;an explanation for any delays in completing the project or increases in the cost; andthe amount of and rationale for any award, incentive fee, or other type of bonus awarded for the project.The bill also requires OMB to submit an annual report to Congress containing the information submitted by the agencies&#160;and post the report on the OMB website.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
