<bill session="118" type="s" number="1272" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:34Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for examination and disclosure with respect to Presidential income tax returns, to amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require the disclosure of certain tax returns by Presidents and certain candidates for the office of the President, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-22T14:22:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Presidential Audit and Tax Transparency Act

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to conduct an examination to determine the correctness of a Presidential income tax return as rapidly as practicable after it is filed.

The IRS must disclose and make publicly available (on the internet) an initial report, periodic reports, and a final report on the examination of such tax returns. The final report must include the date on which the IRS examination of the return was completed, a list of audit materials, and a description of each proposed adjustment to a return and any controversy relating to its examination. This disclosure of tax return information is an exception to the general rule of confidentiality of taxpayer returns.

The bill defines Presidential income tax return as any relevant income tax return of (1) a president while the president is in office, (2) the spouse of a president, (3) a corporation or partnership controlled by a president or a president's spouse, and (4) the estate of a president or a president's spouse.

The bill imposes additional disclosure requirements by presidents and presidential candidates under the Ethics in Government Act of 1978.</summary>
</bill>
