<bill session="117" type="h" number="5113" updated="2023-01-01T20:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to expand and codify matters covered by diversity training in the Department of Defense.</title>
    <title type="display">REMEDI Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Realizing Efforts for Military Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REMEDI Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2021-08-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-19T15:49:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Realizing Efforts for Military Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion Act or the REMEDI Act

This bill provides statutory authority for and expands the requirements regarding diversity and inclusion training for military personnel.

The bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to ensure that each military department conducts ongoing training programs regarding human relations, diversity, equity, and inclusion for all members of the Armed Forces, civilian employees of DOD, and contractors or subcontractors providing support to DOD.

Such training must be tailored to specific leadership levels and local area requirements.

DOD must ensure that an individual preparing to enter an officer accession program, execute an original enlistment agreement, or serve as a civilian employee is (1) provided information concerning the meaning of the oath of office or oath of enlistment for service in the Armed Forces with regards to the equal protection and civil liberties guarantees of the Constitution, and (2) informed that if supporting such guarantees is not possible for that individual, the individual should decline to join the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
