<bill session="117" type="s" number="4018" updated="2022-12-29T23:48:38Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HBCU RISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HBCU RISE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable high research activity status historically Black colleges or universities to increase capacity toward achieving very high research activity status.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-04-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8140" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-06T16:00:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act or the HBCU RISE Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to establish a pilot program to increase capacity for historically Black colleges and universities (HBCUs) that are designated as high research activity status to achieve very high research activity status. High research activity status (known as R2 status) and very high research activity status (known as R1 status) are classifications by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education.

In carrying out the pilot program, DOD must award grants for key areas of scientific research to HBCUs that are classified as high research activity status institutions. DOD may expand the program to other HBCUs beyond those that are classified as high research activity status if DOD determines that the program can support such an expansion.

DOD must annually establish a list of key areas of scientific research for which grant applicants may seek funding.</summary>
</bill>
