<bill session="108" type="h" number="4324" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:59Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-21">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Thrift Savings Plan Open Elections Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, to provide for Federal employees to make elections to make, modify, and terminate contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund at any time.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to eliminate the provisions limiting certain election opportunities available to individuals participating in the Thrift Savings Plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Thrift Savings Plan Open Elections Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000597" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001151" joined="2004-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T12:53:12-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis, Tom moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T12:53:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10033-10034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T12:53:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4324.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-19T12:59:00-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10033" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T12:59:09-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T12:59:11-05:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-12-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11874" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-12-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-21" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-469" type="public" datetime="2004-12-21">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-469.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Personal budgets"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-05T23:05:47Z" status="Public Law">Thrift Savings Plan Open Elections Act of 2004 - Allows an election by a Federal employee or member to make contributions under the Thrift Savings Plan (TSP) of the Federal Employees' Retirement System to be made at any time. Provides that such an election shall take effect on the earliest date after the election that is administratively feasible and shall remain in effect until modified or terminated. Prohibits agency contributions from beginning to be made for an employee or member until the date that such contributions would have begun to be made in accordance with regulations as administered on the date preceding the enactment of this Act.

Instructs the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to: (1) periodically evaluate whether the tools available to participants provide the information needed to understand, evaluate, and compare financial products, services, and opportunities offered through the TSP; (2) use these evaluations to improve its existing program for TSP participants; and (3) annually report to the Committee on Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Government Reform of the House of Representatives on its TSP education efforts on behalf of plan participants.

Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM), as part of the retirement training offered by OPM, to: (1) develop and implement a retirement financial literacy and education strategy for Federal employees that educates Federal employees on the need for retirement savings and investment and that provides information related to how Federal employees can receive additional information on how to plan for retirement and calculate what their retirement investment should be in order to meet their retirement goals; and (2) submit a report on such strategy to such committees.</summary>
</bill>
