<bill session="112" type="h" number="4382" updated="2022-03-02T05:20:15Z">
  <state datetime="2012-05-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2012-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Leasing Certainty for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Providing Leasing Certainty for American Energy Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure Federal oil and natural gas lease sales occur, eliminate redundant leasing bureaucracy, and provide leasing certainty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001273" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2012-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000612" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000292" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2012-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000111" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000186" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000470" joined="2012-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-531.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-06-15" calendar="Union" number="379">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 379.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="4480" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-08-31T15:34:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Leasing Certainty for American Energy Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in conducting lease sales under the Mineral Leasing Act, to offer for sale at least 25% of the annual nominated acreage not previously made available for lease.

Shields such acreage from protest and the test of extraordinary circumstances. Makes it eligible, however, for certain categorical exclusions under the Energy Policy Act of 2005 in connection with review under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.

(A categorical exclusion is a category of actions which do not individually or cumulatively have a significant effect on the human environment and for which, as a consequence, neither an environmental assessment nor an environmental impact statement is required.)

Directs the Secretary to consider leasing only federal lands that are available for leasing at the time the lease sale occurs.

Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to prohibit the Secretary from: (1) withdrawing any covered energy project issued under that Act without finding a violation by the lessee of lease terms; (2) delaying indefinitely issuance of project approvals, drilling and seismic permits, and rights of way for activities under a lease; and (3) cancelling or withdrawing any lease parcel after a competitive lease sale has occurred and a winning bidder has made the last payment for the parcel.

Instructs the Secretary to: (1) make nominated areas available for lease within 18 months after an area is designated as open under a current land use plan, (2) issue all leases sold 60 days after the last payment is made, and (3) adjudicate any lease protests filed following a lease sale.

Prohibits additional lease stipulations after the parcel is sold without consultation and agreement of the lessee, unless the Secretary deems such stipulations as emergency actions to conserve national resources.

Requires federal land managers to follow existing resource management plans and continue to actively lease in areas designated as open when resource management plans are being amended or revised, until such time as a new record of decision is signed.

Declares without force or effect Bureau of Land Management Instruction Memorandum 2010-117.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-531</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
