<bill session="116" type="h" number="4478" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:52Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Simple FAFSA Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to remove barriers for students seeking Federal financial aid by reducing the complexity and length of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA) and increasing support for working students and vulnerable populations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simple FAFSA Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2019-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1196"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4674" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4787" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4478" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4216" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4240" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8748" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-17T17:37:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Simple FAFSA Act of 2019

This bill revises the application process, eligibility requirements, and certain calculations related to the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA).

Specifically, the bill

 establishes three pathways for FAFSA applicants to submit income or asset information; establishes a certification process whereby a student who submits an initial FAFSA, and who certifies in the subsequent year that their dependency status has not changed, shall not be required to submit another FAFSA to maintain aid eligibility; requires the Department of Education (ED) to make the FAFSA form available in multiple languages and in formats that are accessible to individual with disabilities; repeals provisions that make ineligible for federal student aid any individual who fails to register with selective service or has committed drug-related offenses; prohibits ED from asking questions relating to whether an applicant for federal student aid has committed any drug-related offenses; expands eligibility for federal student aid to certain students who entered the United States prior to age 16; increases support for working students; requires ED to assign an applicant an expected family contribution of zero in certain situations (e.g., if the student received a federal means-tested benefit such as Medicaid during the previous twenty-four months); and requires ED to use data from the second preceding tax year to simplify the application process and determination of financial aid eligibility.</summary>
</bill>
