<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="286" updated="2022-07-15T07:16:26Z">
  <amends type="h" number="7900" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-07-14T17:29:29-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000296"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-07-14"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 461 printed in Part A of House Report 117-405 to reauthorize the Delaware River Basin Restoration Program and increase the federal cost share for certain grant projects. The amendment also extends the program through FY2030 and increases the federal cost share of a grant project that serves a small, rural, or disadvantaged community to 90% of the total cost of the project.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment reauthorizes the Delaware River Basin Restoration Program and increase the federal cost share for certain grant projects. The amendment also extends the program through FY2030 and increases the federal cost share of a grant project that serves a small, rural, or disadvantaged community to 90% of the total cost of the project.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-07-14T17:29:29-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="347">
      <text>On agreeing to the Evans amendment (A042) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 206 (Roll no. 347).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6602-6603" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T02:19:31-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A042) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T02:11:14-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A042) offered by Mr. Evans.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6505-6507" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6505-6507" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14"/>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T02:11:14-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A042) offered by Mr. Evans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T17:29:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Evans amendment (A042) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 206 (Roll no. 347).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T17:29:29-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T17:29:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Evans amendment (A042) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 206 (Roll no. 347).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
