<bill session="111" type="s" number="1750" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">George C. Marshall National Historic Site Study Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the General of the Army George Catlett Marshall National Historic Site at Dodona Manor in Leesburg, Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">George C. Marshall National Historic Site Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">George C. Marshall National Historic Site Study Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000803"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-645.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 111-311.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="597">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 597.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3757" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-01T17:07:31Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

George C. Marshall National Historic Site Study Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a special resource study of the Dodona Manor and gardens in Leesburg, Virginia, the home of George C. Marshall during the most important period of his career.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) evaluate the national significance of the study area and the surrounding area; (2) determine the suitability and feasibility of designating the study area as an affiliated area of the National Park System; and (3) consider other alternatives for the preservation, protection, and interpretation of the study area.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the results of the study.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-311</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
