<bill session="117" type="h" number="9587" updated="2023-03-30T14:49:59Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tenants&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Right to Organize Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote the establishment of resident organizations and provide additional amounts for tenant organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tenants&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Right to Organize Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000592"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-24T16:24:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Tenants' Right to Organize Act

This bill provides for the right of tenants who receive certain rental assistance to establish, operate, and participate in a tenant organization.

Specifically, tenants who participate in Housing Choice Voucher (i.e., Section 8 tenant-based housing assistance) or Low-Income Housing Tax Credit programs administered by the Department of Housing and Urban Development have the right to engage in a tenant organization to address issues related to their living environment and participate in community development activities.

Public housing agencies and unit owners are required to recognize tenant organizations and allow tenants to conduct protected activities, including distributing leaflets, initiating tenant contact, and convening meetings in the building.

A public housing agency or building owner may not require prior permission for any of these activities. Further, these entities may not retaliate against a tenant for participating in a tenant organization.

The bill also provides grants for state and local organizations for training and outreach with respect to tenant organization capacity building and technical assistance.</summary>
</bill>
