<bill session="117" type="s" number="3296" updated="2023-02-18T07:38:36Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TRANSLATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRANSLATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TSA Reaching Across Nationalities, Societies, and Languages to Advance Traveler Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">TRANSLATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">TSA Reaching Across Nationalities, Societies, and Languages to Advance Traveler Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the TSA to develop a plan to ensure that TSA material disseminated in major airports can be better understood by more people accessing such airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with amendments. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="626">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 626.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5574" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7776" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-14T20:33:35Z" status="Reported to Senate">TSA Reaching Across Nationalities, Societies, and Languages to Advance Traveler Education Act or the TRANSLATE Act

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) to develop a plan to ensure that TSA material disseminated in major airports is better understood by people accessing such airports, including by foreign language speakers and people with vision or hearing impairments.

In developing a plan, the TSA must take into consideration data regarding international enplanement and local populations surrounding major airports.

The Government Accountability Office must also review the implementation of the plan.</summary>
</bill>
