<bill session="118" type="s" number="451" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DISRUPT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deterring Iranian Support for Russia in Ukraine and Pre-empting Terrorism Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DISRUPT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions and establish strict conditions on the termination of sanctions in response to acts of aggression by the Islamic Republic of Iran and the Russian Federation against the people of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-11T18:52:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deterring Iranian Support for Russia in Ukraine and Pre-empting Terrorism Act of 2023 or the DISRUPT Act of 2023

This bill imposes new sanctions and new conditions on the termination of existing sanctions applicable to Iranian persons and institutions that support Russian military activities, including activities against Ukraine. Specifically, the bill requires the President to impose sanctions under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act upon (1) Iranian persons who provide material, tactical, or operational support for Russian activities against Ukraine, and (2) Iranian financial institutions that facilitate transactions with Russian persons who provide material, tactical, or operational support for Russian activities against Ukraine.

The bill also requires the President to certify to Congress, before removing an Iranian person from the Department of the Treasury's Specially Designated Nationals (SDN) list, that the person did not sell defense articles to Russia for one year prior to certification. The President must also certify that Iran is no longer providing material or financial support to Russia before revoking Iran's designation as a jurisdiction of primary money laundering concern.</summary>
</bill>
