<bill session="119" type="h" number="1165" updated="2025-04-08T13:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the inspection of certain foreign cranes before use at a United States port, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000399" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2025-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2025-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-08T13:46:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2025 

This bill limits the operation of foreign cranes at U.S. ports. In general,&#160;foreign cranes are those that&#160;have information technology and operational technology components that (1) were manufactured by companies that are subject to the ownership, control, or influence of a country designated as a foreign adversary; and (2) connect to ports' cyber infrastructure.

Foreign cranes that are contracted for on or after the date of the bill's enactment may not operate at a U.S. port. Also, beginning five years after this bill is enacted, foreign cranes operating at U.S. ports may not use software or other technology manufactured by a company owned by a country designated as a foreign adversary.

Additionally, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must (1) inspect foreign cranes&#160;for potential security risks or threats before they are placed into operation, (2) assess the threat posed by security risks or threats of existing or newly constructed foreign cranes, and (3) take any crane that poses a security risk or threat offline until the crane can be certified as no longer being a risk or threat.

CISA must also report to Congress about security risks or threats posed by foreign cranes at U.S. ports.</summary>
</bill>
