<bill session="118" type="s" number="2343" updated="2025-11-18T20:36:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FAIR TARIFF Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR TARIFF Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">For Accurate Import Relief To Aid Retailers and Importers of Foreign Freights Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the liquidation or reliquidation of certain entries of products of European Union member states, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3739" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-28T17:54:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">For Accurate Import Relief To Aid Retailers and Importers of Foreign Freights Act of 2023 or the FAIR TARIFF Act of 2023

This bill provides for the liquidation or reliquidation of certain entries of products (e.g., wine, spirits, and food) of European Union countries imported into the United States during specified time periods.

A request for liquidation or reliquidation must be filed with U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP). A request must contain sufficient information for CBP to (1) locate the entry or, if the entry cannot be located, reconstruct the entry; and (2) verify the eligibility of the request.

Further, CBP must develop and make publicly available an application process for requesting these refunds.

The bill also requires the U.S. Trade Representative to provide advance notice with respect to certain increases in tariff rates.</summary>
</bill>
