<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="785" updated="2022-02-03T05:37:30Z">
  <amends type="h" number="10" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-10-07T23:59:03-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute consists of the text of the amendment contained in House Report 108-751 and printed on pages H8792-H8833 in the Congressional Record for October 7, 2004.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 1 printed in House Report 108-751 to merge two bills endorsed by the 9/11 Commission: S. 2845 and S. 2774. The amendment establishes a National Intelligence Director and makes improvements in intelligence activities, modifies laws relating to intelligence community management, establishes diplomatic means and provides foreign aid to combat terrorism, provides an integrated screening system and improves counterterrorist travel intelligence, enhances transportation security, provides resources to improve national preparedness and assist local first responders, and establishes a Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-10-07T23:59:03-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="510">
      <text>On agreeing to the Menendez amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 203 - 213 (Roll no. 510).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T21:46:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Menendez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8792-8843, H8850" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8792-8833" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T21:46:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mr. Menendez.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8792-8843, H8850" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8792-8833" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T23:59:03-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T23:59:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Menendez amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 203 - 213 (Roll no. 510).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07T23:59:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
