<bill session="117" type="s" number="4062" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HOUSES Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Open Underutilized Space to Ensure Shelter Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOUSES Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to authorize the sale of certain Federal land to States and units of local government to address housing shortages, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2022-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2022-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2022-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-02T22:13:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Open Underutilized Space to Ensure Shelter Act of 2022 or the HOUSES Act of 2022

This bill authorizes the sale of certain federal land to states and units of local government for projects to provide housing.

Specifically, the bill authorizes a state or unit of local government to nominate, for consideration for conveyance by the Department of the Interior, one or more tracts of public lands within the boundary of the state or unit of local government to carry out an eligible project to provide housing.

Interior may not offer to convey to a unit of local government such a tract until it receives from the governor of the state approval for the conveyance.

Interior may not convey to a state or unit of local government such a tract until the state or unit of local government has in effect any ordinances, statutes, or regulations that are necessary to ensure compliance with the project proposal.</summary>
</bill>
