<bill session="118" type="h" number="2613" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:47Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Communities Before Air Tourism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Communities Before Air Tourism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require that a voluntary agreement with respect to commercial air tour operations over a national park considers the well-being of communities overflown by aircraft involved in such operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001226"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2023-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-22T20:14:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Communities Before Air Tourism Act

This bill requires a voluntary agreement for commercial air tour operations over a national park to address specific management issues necessary to protect the park without compromising the well-being of communities overflown by such aircraft. Currently, the voluntary agreement must only address these issues without compromising aviation safety or the air traffic control system.

Further, the bill amends the public review requirements for a proposed voluntary agreement to require consultation with any community whose lands are, or may be, flown over by a commercial air tour operator. Currently, consultation is only required with any Indian tribe whose tribal lands are, or may be, flown over by an operator.</summary>
</bill>
