<bill session="111" type="h" number="5628" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ending Corporal Punishment in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To end the use of corporal punishment in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Corporal Punishment in Schools Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-06T19:31:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Ending Corporal Punishment in Schools Act - Amends the General Education Provisions Act to prohibit the Secretary of Education from providing education funding to any educational agency or institution that allows school personnel to inflict corporal punishment upon a student as a form of punishment or to modify undesirable behavior.

Requires each state to submit a plan to the Secretary, within 18 months of this Act's enactment and every third year thereafter, that describes how the state eliminates the use of corporal punishment in schools and makes school personnel and parents aware of its policies and procedures for doing so.

Authorizes the Secretary to award three-year grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) to assist them in improving school climate and culture by implementing school-wide positive behavior supports.

Requires grant and subgrant funds to be used for professional training, technical assistance, research, and outreach regarding positive behavior supports. Requires LEAs to ensure that private school personnel can participate, on an equitable basis, in activities supported by such funds.

Authorizes the Secretary to allocate funds to the Secretary of the Interior to carry out such activities with regard to schools operated or funded by the Department of the Interior.

 Directs the Secretary to conduct a national assessment to determine compliance with this Act's requirements and identify best practices regarding positive behavior support professional training programs.

 Gives Protection and Advocacy Systems the authority provided under the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act of 2000 to investigate, monitor, and enforce this Act's protections for students.</summary>
</bill>
