<bill session="108" type="s" number="1211" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to further the purposes of title XVI of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992, the "Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act", by directing the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a demonstration program for water reclamation in the Tularosa Basin of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further the purposes of title XVI of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992, the "Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act", by directing the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a demonstration program for water reclamation in the Tularosa Basin of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2003-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7549-7550"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7550" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-668.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-347.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-09-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="701">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 701.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-23T21:39:49Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to construct and maintain a test and evaluation facility capable of processing at least 100,000 gallons of water per day at the Tularosa Basin in Otero County, New Mexico.

Requires the facility to be used to research new desalination technologies to determine the most-technologically-efficient and cost-effective means for producing potable water from saline or other unsuitable water.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract with Sandia National Laboratory to develop a desalination technology plan; and (2) construct the facility according to recommendations of such plan.

Instructs the Secretary and the Secretary of Energy to: (1) enter into an agreement for the operation of the facility and the conduct of research under this Act; (2) establish a technical advisory panel; and (3) undertake research and development of desalination technologies in addition to the program carried out at the facility.

Requires the Secretary to dispose of all water produced by the facility under contract with at least one community in Otero County, but only after Sandia notifies the Secretary that the water is of a consistent, reliable quality. Directs that any water provided by the Secretary to such a community be provided at a cost not to exceed its fair market value. Allows the Secretary to use sums collected to assist in paying the facility's operational costs.

Authorizes appropriations, subject to specified limitations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-347</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
