<bill session="117" type="h" number="1781" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Kids Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Real Online Threats Endangering Children Today Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Kids Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2021-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-06T16:06:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Real Online Threats Endangering Children Today or the PROTECT Kids Act

This bill addresses the online collection of personal information from children.

Specifically, the bill raises the age for parental consent protections for children online from under 13 to under 16, adds geolocation and biometric information to protected personal information, and extends all protections for children online to mobile applications.

The bill also requires the operator of a website, online service, or mobile application to delete a child's personal information upon the verified request of a parent, and it prohibits such operator from terminating service to a child whose parent has refused to permit further collection or use of that child's personal information.

Additionally, the Federal Trade Commission must study and report on the appropriateness of the existing actual knowledge standard (preventing an operator from collecting personal information without meeting certain requirements when it has actual knowledge that it is collecting such information from a child) and what effects changing such standard will have on children's online privacy.</summary>
</bill>
