<bill session="118" type="h" number="1104" updated="2025-01-16T11:56:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fix Moldy Housing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix Moldy Housing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assist State and Tribal governments in assessing and remediating mold, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-24T17:10:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Fix Moldy Housing Act

This bill sets forth provisions to assess and remediate indoor mold.

Specifically, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must issue nonbinding national standards that (1) identify levels of mold that should be assessed and remediated, and (2) outline standards for properly and safely assessing and remediating mold.

The EPA must carry out a program to assist state and tribal governments in assessing and remediating mold. Under the program, the EPA must provide to state and tribal programs (1) grants for establishing licensing programs for persons engaged in assessing and remediating mold, and (2) technical assistance for assessing and remediating mold. The EPA must also administer training seminars on assessing and remediating mold.

The EPA must also award grants to state and tribal governments for (1) assessing and remediating mold in governmental buildings and private residential properties; and (2) temporary housing for individuals who are severely impacted by mold, are without insurance coverage for mold, and do not have sufficient financial resources to obtain alternative housing. Grants may not be used to assess or remediate mold in housing occupied by households that are high-income.</summary>
</bill>
