<bill session="108" type="s" number="527" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:21Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Southern Regional Commission Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Southern Regional Commission for the purpose of breading the cycle of persistent poverty among the southeastern States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southern Regional Commission Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2004-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Southern Regional Commission Act of 2003 - Establishes a Southern Regional Commission to: (1) develop plans and programs to establish priorities and approve grants aimed at breaking the cycle of persistent poverty in the area consisting of specified counties in Alabama, Florida, Georgia, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Virginia (the region) by increasing the capacity of individuals to participate in the economy and build wealth; (2) establish priorities in a targeted strategy for the region (regional development plan); (3) use the findings of Phase I of the Study on Persistent Poverty in the South, prepared by the University of Georgia, and assess any needs and capital assets of the region that are not addressed by the study based on available research, demonstration projects, assessments, and evaluations; (4) enhance the capacity of and provide support for local development districts in the region; (5) support and enhance State resources and activities designed to address persistent poverty; (6) promote multi jurisdictional efforts at the local level intended to maximize local resources; (7) support community-based efforts designed to address persistent poverty; (8) encourage private investment in industrial, commercial, and other economic development projects in the region; and (9) engage land-grant colleges and universities to provide research support for each State included in the region.Authorizes the Commission to: (1) approve grants to States and public and nonprofit entities for economic development projects; and (2) make grants to local development districts to pay administrative expenses.Requires: (1) State members to submit development plans to the Commission; and (2) the Governor of each member State to submit annually a strategy statement describing the State's program for achieving identified goals and objectives.Sets forth criteria for ranking projects to receive assistance. Requires the Commission to review State and regional and multi state subregional development plans.</summary>
</bill>
