<bill session="118" type="h" number="2936" updated="2024-07-26T14:59:10Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prohibit staged collisions with commercial motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-26T14:57:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Highway Accident Fairness Act of 2023 

This bill makes staging a collision with a commercial motor vehicle a federal crime and modifies legal procedures for suits arising from commercial motor vehicle accidents.

A person who is operating a motor vehicle and intentionally causes a collision&#160;with a commercial motor vehicle (or arranges for another person to cause such a collision) is subject to a fine, a prison term of up to 20 years, or both. If the collision results in serious bodily injury or death, the prison term may not be less than 20 years.

With respect to legal procedures, the bill requires a plaintiff, in a suit in state or federal court concerning a bodily injury or death that involves one or more commercial motor vehicles, to disclose the identity of any commercial enterprise (other than the plaintiff or the plaintiff's attorney) that has the right to receive a portion of the plaintiff's recovery (e.g., commercial enterprises that are financing the litigation in exchange for a portion of the recovery). The bill also grants federal courts jurisdiction over such actions in certain cases where damages exceed $5 million. These provisions apply to any case pending on, or commenced on or after, the date of the bill's enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
