<bill session="117" type="s" number="1470" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accessible Voting Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to increase voting accessibility for individuals with disabilities and older individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accessible Voting Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2941" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-25T21:59:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accessible Voting Act of 2021

This bill addresses voting accessibility for individuals with disabilities and older individuals.

First, the bill establishes the Office of Accessibility within the Election Assistance Commission (EAC). The office must serve as the advocate on behalf of voters with access needs, ensure state and local election officials are maintaining voting systems that meet Department of Justice accessibility standards, and make payments to states to implement the accessibility requirements outlined by the bill.

In addition, the office must establish and operate a National Resource Center on Accessible Voting to provide state and local election officials, poll workers, and volunteers with the information and technical assistance needed to provide accessible voting. The office must also work with state and local election officials to collect data and administer a public national voter accessibility website.

The bill requires each state to (1) ensure election websites are accessible and meet specified requirements, (2) designate a single office to provide information on federal elections to individuals with disabilities and older individuals, (3) notify the public of changes to voting practices, (4) expand access to absentee registration procedures and no-excuse mail-in absentee voting in federal elections, and (5) ensure all polling places and voter drop boxes are accessible.

The EAC must coordinate with specified agencies to make grants to eligible entities to study, test, and develop accessible voting options.

The bill also permanently reauthorizes and expands a Department of Health and Human Services grant program for increasing accessibility to polling places.</summary>
</bill>
