<bill session="111" type="h" number="6370" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:29Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Procurement Integrity Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Small Business Act to prevent fraud in transactions involving certain small business concerns.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Procurement Integrity Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-08T13:54:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Procurement Integrity Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Act to include as a punishable offense the misrepresentation of a business or person as a small business owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans. Includes as small business procurement fraud misrepresentation made for purposes of the award of a grant or cooperative agreement. Subjects those making such misrepresentations to federal regulations prohibiting false claims against the United States.

Includes as a punishable offense the use by a contracted small business of an ineligible business to perform a greater percentage of work under such contract.

Requires a veteran claiming service-disabled status for purposes of eligibility as a small business owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans to possess a disability rating letter issued by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) establishing a disability rating between 0% and 100%, a disability determination from the Department of Defense (DOD), or such other documentation as the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) may require.</summary>
</bill>
