<bill session="116" type="s" number="2076" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Chance at Housing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Chance at Housing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the screening and eviction policies for Federal housing assistance in order to provide fair access to housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3685" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-11T14:41:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair Chance at Housing Act of 2019

This bill limits the authority&#160;of public housing agencies (PHAs) to deny or terminate&#160;federally assisted housing based on criminal conduct by the applicant or&#160;tenant.&#160;

Specifically, PHAs may deny or terminate assistance based only on criminal conduct that threatens the health or safety of other tenants or the employees or owner of the PHA, excluding misdemeanors and certain other lesser criminal offenses. Furthermore, with respect to applicants, a denial may be based only on a&#160;felony conviction&#160;other than a conviction&#160;for&#160;a drug offense for which the&#160;individual served less than 10 years.

Before denying or terminating assistance based on criminal conduct, a PHA must conduct an individualized review and consider specified factors, including evidence of rehabilitation.&#160;PHAs must also give the household an opportunity to remove the culpable member before proceeding with the denial or termination.

Additionally, PHAs may not drug test applicants or tenants as a condition of assistance.

Under current law, PHAs must&#160;deny, and may terminate, federally assisted housing upon&#160;a determination that any household member is illegally using a controlled substance. Current law also allows PHAs to take such actions if there is reasonable cause to believe that a household member's illegal use of a controlled substance or abuse of alcohol may interfere with the health, safety, or right to peaceful enjoyment of the premises by other residents. Further, tenants evicted on the basis of drug-related criminal activity are not eligible under current law for federally assisted housing for three years, unless the tenant successfully completes a rehabilitation program.</summary>
</bill>
