<bill session="117" type="h" number="1051" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BROADBAND Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to streamline siting processes for telecommunications service facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Barriers and Regulatory Obstacles Avoids Deployment of Broadband Access and Needs Deregulatory Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BROADBAND Leadership Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001104" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3435" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-05T22:36:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Barriers and Regulatory Obstacles Avoids Deployment of Broadband Access and Needs Deregulatory Leadership Act or the BROADBAND Leadership Act

This bill limits the authority of, and places deadlines on, a state or local government over decisions regarding the placement, construction, and modification of telecommunications service facilities.

Specifically, the bill requires that the regulation of the placement, construction, or modification of a telecommunications service facility by any state or local government shall not unreasonably discriminate among providers of functionally equivalent services. Further, any decision to deny a placement, construction, or modification request must be in writing and supported by substantial evidence in a written record.

Additionally, a state or local government must grant or deny a complete request for authorization to place, construct, or modify a telecommunications service facility within 90 days of receipt of the request or within 150 days of receipt of a request to take any other action relating to such facility.

A state or local government is authorized to charge a reasonable, objective, cost-based fee for (1) review of a request, or (2) use of a right-of-way or a facility in a right-of-way that is owned or managed by the state or local government.</summary>
</bill>
