<bill session="111" type="h" number="801" updated="2022-02-03T06:07:16Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Copyright in Research Works Act</title>
    <title type="display">Fair Copyright in Research Works Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 17, United States Code, with respect to works connected to certain funding agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2009-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-27T16:50:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Copyright in Research Works Act - Prohibits any federal agency from imposing any condition, in connection with a funding agreement, that requires the transfer or license to or for a federal agency, or requires the absence or abandonment, of specified exclusive rights of a copyright owner in an extrinsic work.

Prohibits any federal agency from: (1) imposing, as a condition of a funding agreement, the waiver of, or assent to, any such prohibition; or (2) asserting any rights in material developed under any funding agreement that restrain or limit the acquisition or exercise of copyright rights in an extrinsic work.

Defines "funding agreement" as any contract, grant, or other agreement entered into between a federal agency and any person under which funds are provided by a federal agency for the performance of experimental, developmental, or research activities.

Defines "extrinsic work" as any work, other than a work of the U.S. government, that is related to a funding agreement and is also funded in substantial part by, or results from a meaningful added value contributed by, one or more nonfederal entities that are not a party to the funding agreement.</summary>
</bill>
