<bill session="116" type="h" number="5748" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jobs, On-the-Job Earn-While-You-Learn Training, and Apprenticeships for Young African-Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To rebuild the Nation's crumbling infrastructure, transportation systems, technology and computer networks, and energy distribution systems, by strongly and urgently encouraging the immediate recruitment, employment, and on-the-job "earn as you learn" training of young African Americans who throughout history experience higher unemployment rates than any other race, which is a national crisis.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs, On-the-Job Earn-While-You-Learn Training, and Apprenticeships for Young African-Americans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2020-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2020-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-23T18:02:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Jobs, On-the-Job "Earn While You Learn" Training, and Apprenticeships for Young African-Americans Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to encourage labor unions, general contractors, and businesses that will rebuild infrastructure, transportation systems, technology and computer networks, and energy distribution systems to actively recruit, hire, train, and provide apprenticeships to African Americans ages 18 to 39 through existing jobs, apprenticeships, and programs. Labor must help coordinate such recruitment.

The jobs, training, and apprenticeships must be conducted in conjunction with Labor, labor unions and associations involved in infrastructure rebuilding, and the National Joint Apprenticeship and Training Committee.

Labor unions, contractors, and businesses involved with such infrastructure or systems must recruit by seeking assistance from the African American community, churches, and civil rights organizations.</summary>
</bill>
