<bill session="112" type="h" number="6221" updated="2022-03-02T16:39:41Z">
  <state datetime="2012-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Identifying Cybersecurity Risks to Critical Infrastructure Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Identifying Cybersecurity Risks to Critical Infrastructure Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to research, identify, and evaluate cybersecurity risks to critical infrastructure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2012-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2012-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000517" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2012-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1338"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Security Technologies.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-25T19:18:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Identifying Cybersecurity Risks to Critical Infrastructure Act of 2012 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to require the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to conduct continuous, sector-by-sector research, identification, and evaluation of cybersecurity risks to critical infrastructure in coordination with: (1) the heads of sector-specific agencies, (2) owners and operators of critical infrastructure, and (3) any private sector entity engaged in ensuring the security or resilience of critical infrastructure.

Directs the Secretary to ensure that information relating to such risks is: (1) disseminated, to the maximum extent possible, in an unclassified version, to owners and operators of critical infrastructure within each such sector; or (2) if the information in whole or in part should be classified, share such information with owners and operators who possess the appropriate security clearances.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress at least semiannually on cybersecurity risks to critical infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
