<bill session="117" type="h" number="81" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Redistricting Transparency Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require States to carry out Congressional redistricting in accordance with a process under which members of the public are informed of redistricting proposals and have the opportunity to participate in the development of such proposals prior to their adoption, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Redistricting Transparency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000754"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts and representation"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-17T14:56:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Redistricting Transparency Act of 2021

This bill requires state redistricting entities to publish information regarding redistricting plans, both before and after adoption of a redistricting plan. The required information includes (1) maps of the congressional districts; (2) the composition of the districts by race, language minority group, and political party; (3) an explanation of the entity's reasoning for adopting the plan; and (4) any dissenting statements of the entity's members.

 Further, each state redistricting entity must maintain a website that provides redistricting plan information, meeting notices, and census data. The website must also allow individuals to submit comments and information.</summary>
</bill>
