<bill session="117" type="h" number="2550" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Traveling Parents Screening Consistency Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require GAO review of certain TSA screening protocols, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Traveling Parents Screening Consistency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-29T19:27:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Traveling Parents Screening Consistency Act of 2021

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office to review implementation of requirements regarding screening by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of baby formula, breast milk, purified deionized water for infants, and juice on airlines.

Specifically, the review must

 consider whether the TSA effectively manages consistency of screening protocol applications for formula, breast milk, purified deionized water for infants, and juice; evaluate the need for the TSA to update and revise procedures for such screening; assess whether the TSA effectively tracks passenger complaints related to such screening to monitor trends and identify inconsistencies; evaluate the TSA's communications and information sharing practices for passengers, air carriers, and airports relating to screening protocols for such screening; evaluate the TSA's policies regarding the screening of passengers with nursing products; and make recommendations for improving the TSA's overall screening practices relating to such screening.</summary>
</bill>
