<bill session="108" type="h" number="5300" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Servicemembers Anti-Predatory Lending Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish requirements with respect to the terms of consumer credit extended by a creditor to a servicemember or the dependent of a servicemember, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemembers Anti-Predatory Lending Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000546"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR06" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Benefits" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Usury"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-24T21:40:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Servicemembers Anti-Predatory Lending Protection Act - Amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to set forth terms for consumer credit extended to a servicemember or servicemember's dependent, including terms of interest with respect to the extension of such credit.

Prohibits a creditor from imposing an annual percentage rate greater than 36 percent with respect to the consumer credit extended.

Sets forth mandatory loan disclosures, including: (1) a statement of the annual percentage rate applicable to the extension of credit; and (2) a clear description of the payment obligations.

Prohibits a creditor from automatically renewing, repaying, refinancing, or consolidating any consumer credit with the proceeds of other credit extended to a servicemember or a servicemember's dependent by the same creditor without: (1) executing new loan documentation signed by the servicemember; and (2) providing the mandatory loan disclosures.

Preempts any State or Federal law, rule, or regulation, including any State usury law, to the extent that it is inconsistent with this Act. States that this Act does not preempt any such law, rule, or regulation that provides additional protection.

Prescribes criminal penalties for violation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
