<bill session="117" type="h" number="8821" updated="2022-12-29T12:33:50Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration to produce and make available at no cost to certain individuals in the United States an identification for the purpose of allowing such individuals to meet certain identification requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001117"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2022-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2022-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001224" joined="2022-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2022-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2022-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2022-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8227"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-19T19:12:58Z" status="Introduced in House">IDs for an Inclusive Democracy Act

This bill directs the Social Security Administration (SSA) to produce and make available at no cost to certain individuals in the United States an identification (ID) for the purpose of allowing such individuals to satisfy ID requirements.

Such ID must include a photograph and specified information, as well as security features. It shall be valid for a 10-year period. To receive an ID, an individual must be at least 14 years of age.

The SSA must develop and implement a campaign to educate the public with respect to the ID, including how an individual can receive and use it.

The U.S. Postal Service (USPS) must develop and implement a process that enables individuals to apply for the ID through the USPS, including a process for a first-time ID and renewal, modeled after the process for passport applications.

The bill establishes a Task Force on Federal Identification Cards for the purpose of determining the requirements to produce and make available the ID.

The task force shall (1) issue a report on the requirements, including a requirement that the SSA and the USPS establish procedures to prevent the unauthorized disclosure of any information obtained with respect to individuals who seek assistance in obtaining the ID; and (2) develop and publish recommendations for voluntary best practices for nonprofit organizations and entities that provide services to vulnerable populations with respect to how such organizations and entities can assist individuals to obtain the ID.</summary>
</bill>
