<bill session="109" type="s" number="2314" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:03Z">
  <state datetime="2006-02-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-02-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Royalty Relief Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to suspend the application of any provision of Federal law under which persons are relieved from the requirement to pay royalties for production of oil or natural gas from Federal lands in periods of high oil and natural gas prices, to require the Secretary to seek to renegotiate existing oil and natural gas leases to similarly limit suspension of royalty obligations under such leases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Royalty Relief Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2006-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4749" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-23T18:15:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Royalty Relief for American Consumers Act of 2006 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to suspend royalty relief from any federal requirement to pay royalty (thus requiring the payment of royalties to the federal government) for production oil or natural gas from federal lands (including submerged land) during any period in which specified prices apply to either crude oil or natural gas.

Instructs the Secretary to renegotiate certain existing leases authorizing production of oil or natural gas on federal land to conform with this Act.

Conditions eligibility for renewal of such leases or new leases for existing lessees upon compliance with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
