<bill session="116" type="h" number="4717" updated="2022-11-01T03:47:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Swap Trading Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve swap execution facility administration, swap entity compliance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Swap Trading Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2019-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-02T18:25:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Swap Trading Improvement Act 

This bill revises provisions regarding swap execution facilities (i.e., trading platforms for speculators exchanging the benefit or liability of two financial instruments).

The bill eliminates the requirement that swap execution facilities must adopt position limitations or position accountability for speculators.

The bill allows a swap execution facility to delegate certain core functions to a third party. Currently, these functions may only be delegated to other registered entities.

Additionally, the bill revises the required adequate financial resources of a swap execution facility. Currently, a facility must be able to cover the operating costs of a one year period. The bill requires the facility to cover the greater amount of the operating costs of a 90 day period, or to enable an orderly wind down of its operations.</summary>
</bill>
