<bill session="117" type="s" number="3978" updated="2023-08-08T16:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NO RUSSIA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Opportunity to Restore Uranium Supply Services In America Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NO RUSSIA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Energy to carry out a program to operate a uranium reserve consisting of uranium produced and converted in the United States and a program to ensure the availability of uranium produced, converted, and enriched in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2022-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7403" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8981" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T16:03:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Opportunity to Restore Uranium Supply Services In America Act of 2022 or the NO RUSSIA Act of 2022

This bill provides statutory authority (and reallocates funding) for the Office of Nuclear Energy to establish a strategic reserve of uranium to ensure the availability of domestic supplies of uranium. The bill also requires the office to establish another program to support domestic production, conversion, and enrichment of uranium for nuclear reactors and eliminate reliance on Russian uranium.

The office may not source uranium for the reserve or the program from companies that are controlled by, owned by, or otherwise affiliated with China or Russia.</summary>
</bill>
