<bill session="116" type="h" number="6530" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Supply Chain Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to report to Congress on certain authorities used under the Defense Production Act of 1950 and the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Supply Chain Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001101" joined="2020-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2020-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2020-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2020-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2020-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2020-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-27T14:15:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Supply Chain Transparency Act

This bill requires the President to report to Congress on certain authorities used under the Defense Production Act of 1950 and the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (Stafford Act).

Specifically, the bill requires the President or each federal agency to which the President delegates authority under the Defense Production Act, within 14 days of exercising authority provided under such Act, to report to Congress disclosing (1) the production, transport, distribution, sale, delivery, and construction of all materials, services, and facilities related to the exercise of such authority; and (2) any private entity in receipt or possession of such materials, services, and facilities.

The bill requires the President or each federal agency to which the President delegates authority under the Stafford Act's federal emergency disaster relief assistance provision, within 14 days of exercising such authority, to report to Congress disclosing all equipment, supplies, facilities, personnel, services, and other resources provided to federal agencies, private organizations, and state and local governments related to such exercise of authority.

Such reports shall be updated periodically, not less than every 14 days, while such authority is in use.</summary>
</bill>
