<bill session="118" type="h" number="4766" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clarity for Payment Stablecoins Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Clarity for Payment Stablecoins Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clarity for Payment Stablecoins Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the regulation of payment stablecoins, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2024-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 34 - 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-492.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-05-07" calendar="Union" number="408">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 408.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-01T16:02:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Clarity for Payment Stablecoins Act of 2023 

This bill establishes a regulatory framework for payment stablecoins (digital assets which an issuer must redeem for a fixed monetary value).

Only permitted issuers are allowed to issue a payment stablecoin for use by U.S. persons. Permitted issuers must be a subsidiary of an insured depository institution, a federal-qualified nonbank payment stablecoin issuer, or a state-qualified payment stablecoin issuer. In general, permitted issuers must be regulated by the appropriate federal regulator, however, state-qualified issuers must be regulated by an appropriate state regulator.

Permitted issuers must maintain reserves backing the stablecoin on a one-to-one basis using assets as outlined by the bill, such as U.S. coins and currency or other assets regulators determine appropriate. Permitted issuers must also publicly disclose their redemption policy, establish redemption procedures, and publish on their website every month the details of the issuer's reserves.

The bill sets forth requirements for (1) the rehypothecation, or reusing, of such reserves; (2) providing custodial or safekeeping services for stablecoins or private keys; and (3) supervisory, examination, and enforcement authority over non-state qualified issuers.

In addition, the bill places a two-year moratorium on new endogenously collateralized stablecoins (i.e., stablecoins that rely on the value of another digital asset created or maintained by the same originator to maintain the fixed price).

Under the bill, permitted payment stablecoins are not considered securities under securities law.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-492</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
