<bill session="119" type="h" number="1198" updated="2025-11-18T19:41:55Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Let&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Get to Work Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Let&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Get to Work Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to modify work requirements under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2025-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001317" joined="2025-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="87" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-28T17:05:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Let's Get to Work Act of 2025

This bill modifies and expands work requirements under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) and certain housing programs of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD).

Specifically, the bill expands the applicability of the work requirements for SNAP recipients who are able-bodied adults without dependents (ABAWDs). As background, SNAP recipients who are ABAWDs have work-related requirements in addition to the general SNAP work registration and employment and training requirements.

The bill applies the work requirements for ABAWDs to adults who are not over 60 years old, whereas these requirements currently apply to adults who are not over 55 years old.

Further, the&#160;ABAWD exemption for a parent or household member with responsibility for a dependent child is restricted under the bill to a dependent child under the age of&#160;six. Currently, the child must be under the age of 18.&#160;

The bill allows a member of a household with responsibility for a dependent child to participate in SNAP&#160;for up to 6 months (currently 3 months) over a 36-month period without meeting the ABAWD work requirements.

The bill also includes an exception for an individual who (1) is responsible for a dependent individual, and (2) is married to and resides with an individual who complies with the SNAP work requirements.

Additionally, the bill establishes work requirements for families residing in public housing by applying the SNAP work requirements for ABAWDs to the HUD public housing and tenant-based rental assistance (voucher) programs.</summary>
</bill>
