<bill session="117" type="h" number="5252" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to award competitive grants for the purpose of developing, offering, improving, and providing educational or career pathway programs for workers, to direct the Secretary of Education to establish a program that awards grants to State coalitions that build or expand career pathways programs in schools within the State, and to establish a program that awards grants to eligible agencies to carry out career pathways programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Connecting Students to Great Jobs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting Students to Great Jobs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-05T16:12:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Connecting Students to Great Jobs Act

This bill directs the Department of Labor and the Department of Education (ED) to award career pathway grants and provide assistance for career pathway programs.

Labor must award competitive grants to eligible institutions of higher education and vocational institutions to develop, offer, improve, and provide educational or career pathway programs for workers. Grant funds must be used for specified purposes, including for career pathway programs that provide relevant job training to meet the needs of employers in high-skill, high-wage, or in demand sectors or occupations and that may include registered apprenticeship programs.

 The bill requires ED to carry out a program to award START federal Pell Grants to students in short-term programs that prepare participants for employment opportunities in high-skill, high-wage, or in demand sectors or occupations in a geographic area in which the programs are offered.

 The bill also directs ED to (1) award grants to states to establish statewide career pathways coalitions, (2) establish a career pathways innovation grant program to support career pathways in high school and career exploration in the middle grades, and (3) provide technical assistance.</summary>
</bill>
