<bill session="115" type="s" number="2936" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:28Z">
  <state datetime="2018-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improved Soil Moisture and Precipitation Monitoring Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve soil moisture and precipitation monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Soil Moisture and Precipitation Monitoring Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-05T18:28:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improved Soil Moisture and Precipitation Monitoring Act of 2018

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to implement a strategy for improving the accuracy of the U.S. Drought Monitor by increasing the geographic resolution of rural in-situ soil moisture profile observation or other soil moisture profile measuring devices.

USDA must prioritize adding in-situ soil moisture profile monitoring stations in states that have experienced D3 (extreme drought) or D4 (exceptional drought) within any six month period from 2016 to the present.

USDA shall develop standards for:

 the integration of data that is derived from citizen science (open collaborations through which individuals or organizations participate voluntarily in the scientific process) into the Drought Monitor models, including data from the Cooperative Observer Program of the National Weather Service; and the collection of soil moisture data that is based on readily available equipment. USDA shall direct the Farm Service Agency and the Risk Management Agency of USDA to use the Drought Monitor in the profile monitoring stations added by this bill, data from the Cooperative Observer Program, and any other applicable data in establishing loss assistance and grazing rates.</summary>
</bill>
