<bill session="117" type="s" number="2290" updated="2022-12-31T05:25:53Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for requirements for data brokers with respect to the acquisition, use, and protection of brokered personal information and to require that data brokers annually register with the Federal Trade Commission.</title>
    <title type="display">Data Broker List Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Broker List Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-12T17:08:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Data Broker List Act of 2021 This bill establishes requirements for data brokers that obtain personal information about consumers for the sale to other businesses.

Specifically, data brokers are prohibited from (1) acquiring such information by fraud, (2) using such information for a specified prohibited purpose such as fraud or identity theft, or (3) selling such information to a third party that the broker should reasonably know intends to use the information for a specified prohibited purpose. Data brokers also must implement safeguards to prevent security breaches that result in the improper disclosure of such personal information. Additionally, they must register with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) on an annual basis and the FTC must publish the registry. Violations of these requirements are enforceable by the FTC as unfair or deceptive business practices.</summary>
</bill>
