<bill session="108" type="s" number="2540" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Educational Radio Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect educational FM radio stations providing public service broadcasting from commercial encroachment.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Radio Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/18/2004 S7009-7010"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-05T19:03:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Educational Radio Protection Act - States that a qualifying educational FM radio station is entitled, upon application by the station's licensee, to: (1) have its license be subject to the same license terms and renewal standards (other than fees) as licenses for full-power class A FM radio stations; and (2) have its licensee accorded primary status as a radio broadcaster so long as the station remains a qualifying FM radio station.

Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to provide written notice of the provisions of this Act to specified licensees of Class D FM radio stations.

Prohibits the FCC from awarding or assigning to commercial FM radio stations any portion of the radio spectrum assigned to qualifying educational FM radio stations for which an application is submitted within one year of enactment of this Act and approved.

Requires the FCC to restore to educational stations whose applications are successful and not subject to appeal any portion of educational station spectrum previously awarded to commercial stations if the previous award occurred after April 30, 2004, and before the educational station's application was approved.</summary>
</bill>
