<bill session="108" type="s" number="1952" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mexican Agricultural Trade Compliance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the United States Trade Representative to enforce United States rights, under certain trade agreements with respect to Mexico, pursuant to title III of the Trade Act of 1974.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mexican Agricultural Trade Compliance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15977-15978"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-14T15:16:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mexican Agricultural Trade Compliance Act - Determines that U.S. rights under the Uruguay Round Agreements are being denied by Mexico in connection with Mexico's imposition of a 20 percent tax on soft drinks containing high fructose corn syrup, an extension of Mexico's unjustified antidumping order on high fructose corn syrup from the United States. Directs the U.S. Trade Representative, unless certifying to Congress within 30 days after the enactment of this Act that Mexico has eliminated such tax and is otherwise preserving all U.S. trade agreement rights with respect to high fructose corn syrup, to either: (1) suspend, withdraw, or prevent the application of benefits of trade agreement concessions to carry out a trade agreement with Mexico; or (2) impose duties or other import restrictions on the goods of Mexico, and fees or restrictions on the services of Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
