<bill session="116" type="s" number="2700" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Roadside First Responders Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Roadside First Responders Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to provide for efforts relating to Move Over laws, to amend title 49, United States Code, to require crash avoidance technology on motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2019-10-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6158-6159" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4871" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-08T21:31:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Roadside First Responders Act

This bill addresses transportation matters relating to Move Over laws and crash avoidance technology. (Move Over laws are intended to ensure first responder and motorist safety by requiring motorists to change lanes or slow down when approaching an authorized emergency vehicle that is parked or otherwise stopped on a roadway.)

Specifically, the bill requires

 the Department of Transportation (DOT) to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to produce research findings on the efficacy of Move Over laws and related public awareness campaigns; DOT to award grants to states to prevent death and injury from crashes involving vehicles striking vehicles and individuals stopped at the roadside; DOT to implement rules to establish minimum performance standards with respect to crash avoidance technology and to require mandating crash avoidance technology on all new motor vehicles; and all federal fleet vehicles to have crash avoidance technology and, if such vehicles are used for emergency response activities, be equipped with digital alert technology.</summary>
</bill>
