<bill session="117" type="h" number="6762" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2022-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2022-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2022-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-28T13:02:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement Act

This bill establishes the Office of the Special Inspector General for Law Enforcement. The bill sets forth the duties of the office, including investigating

 racial profiling, officer misconduct, use of force, use of deadly force, or pattern or practice of unconstitutional misconduct involving federal law enforcement agencies or officers; and use-of-deadly-force cases referred by state and local law enforcement agencies. The bill requires a state or local government that receives funding under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant program or the Community Oriented Policing Services grant program to have in effect a law establishing a process by which use-of-deadly-force cases can be referred to the office for investigation.</summary>
</bill>
