<bill session="119" type="h" number="2002" updated="2025-05-30T08:05:49Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MATCH IT Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MATCH IT Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Matching And Transparency in Certified Health IT Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXX of the Public Health Service Act to establish standards and protocols to improve patient matching.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2025-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2025-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-27T17:07:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Patient Matching And Transparency in Certified Health IT Act of 2025 or the MATCH IT Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a definition and standards for patient matching (i.e., the process of&#160;accurately matching patients with their medical records, including when records are exchanged between health care providers). It also requires the development of&#160;(1)&#160;a minimum data set for technology standards&#160;to increase patient matching, and (2) incentives for patient matching under Medicare.

Specifically, the bill requires HHS to develop a uniform definition and standards for patient matching to track patient match rates and document improvement over time. The definition and standards must account for certain situations, including duplicate records and multiple matches.

The bill also requires the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information Technology (ONC) to adopt a minimum data set to help health care providers or health information systems achieve&#160;a patient match rate of 99.9%. The&#160;minimum data set and related standards must be incorporated&#160;into the U.S. Core Data for Interoperability and the Medicare Promoting Interoperability Program&#160;for&#160;health information technology.

Additionally, the Centers for Medicare &amp;&#160;Medicaid Services (CMS) must&#160;establish a voluntary bonus measure within the Medicare Promoting Interoperability Program to allow&#160;health care providers who have a patient match rate over a certain percentage to receive a payment adjustment.&#160;The ONC and CMS&#160;must develop a voluntary reporting program for providers to anonymously submit patient matching data to HHS.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
