<bill session="111" type="s" number="3355" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:00Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans One Source Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for an Internet website for information on benefits, resource, services, and opportunities for veterans and their families and caregivers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans One Source Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2010-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2010-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-19">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-623.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-02T16:34:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans One Source Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish and maintain an Internet website that provides information on the benefits, resources, services, and opportunities available for veterans and their families and caregivers, including veterans' benefits provided through the VA and the Department of Labor, tax benefits, social security benefits, state and local resources, and small business assistance. Requires the website to: (1) consolidate, expand on, and improve information and links from other existing websites relating to such benefits, resources, services, and opportunities; and (2) integrate dynamic Internet features and virtual interface tools to provide a personalized, interactive, and user-centered Internet experience. Requires the Secretary to consult with specified federal officials in providing information on benefits and services.

Directs the Secretary to include, in a currently-required biennial plan on VA outreach activities, the VA's plans for improving and enhancing the website.</summary>
</bill>
