<bill session="112" type="h" number="6341" updated="2019-11-15T21:46:57Z">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a partial exclusion under section 911 for foreign earned income of employees of United States Government contractors who do not fulfill their foreign country residency requirements by reason of an Armed Forces troop reduction or similar cause beyond the employer's control.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a partial exclusion under section 911 for foreign earned income of employees of United States Government contractors who do not fulfill their foreign country residency requirements by reason of an Armed Forces troop reduction or similar cause beyond the employer's control.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000601"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-14T20:46:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow employees of a U.S. contractor working in a foreign country to claim the exclusion from gross income for their income earned in such country even if they are required to depart from such country prior to meeting the foreign country residency requirement for such tax exclusion if their departure was a direct result of: (1) a reduction in the number of personnel serving in a combat zone in such country, (2) a termination of the contract under which the U.S. contractor is performing services in such combat zone, or (3) the termination of their employment with the contractor on account of the reduction of personnel or the termination of the contract.</summary>
</bill>
