<bill session="109" type="h" number="661" updated="2019-11-15T21:34:37Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for naturalization through service in a combat zone designated in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-02T21:11:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2005 - Authorizes naturalization without regard to specified Immigration and Nationality Act requirements for an alien or noncitizen national of the United States who: (1) served honorably in a combat zone designated in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom; and (2) if separated from such service, was not separated except under honorable conditions. Prohibits imposition of any Federal or State naturalization fee. Provides for overseas naturalization proceedings.

Retains immediate relative status for the alien wife, child, or parent of a U.S. citizen who died from injury or disease incurred while serving honorably in such combat zone.

States that an application for status adjustment by the alien wife, child, or parent of an alien member of the Armed Forces who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship based upon service in such zone may be adjudicated as if the death had not occurred.

Treats the spouse, child, or parent of a lawful permanent resident who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship based upon service in such zone as a valid petitioner for immediate relative status.

Permits such aliens to apply for adjustment to lawful permanent resident status.

Waives specified grounds of inadmissibility for surviving spouses, children, and parents granted posthumous benefits under this Act.

Authorizes the naturalization of surviving spouses, children, or parents of U.S. citizens who die in Operation Iraqi Freedom and states that no prior residence or specified physical presence in the United States shall be required.

Gives priority to the naturalization applications referenced in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
