<bill session="119" type="h" number="1774" updated="2025-06-18T20:12:28Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to withhold certain apportionment funds from the District of Columbia unless the Mayor of the District of Columbia removes the phrase Black Lives Matter from the street symbolically designated as Black Lives Matter Plaza, redesignates such street as Liberty Plaza, and removes such phrase from each website, document, and other material under the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend title 23, United States Code, to withhold certain apportionment funds from the District of Columbia unless the Mayor of the District of Columbia removes the phrase Black Lives Matter from the street symbolically designated as Black Lives Matter Plaza, redesignates such street as Liberty Plaza, and removes such phrase from each website, document, and other material under the jurisdiction of the District of Columbia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-18T20:11:15Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill withholds certain highway funds from the District of Columbia (DC) unless DC removes the phrase Black Lives Matter from the portion of&#160;16th Street NW that is between H Street NW and K Street NW&#160;(currently designated as Black Lives Matter Plaza) and redesignates the street as Liberty Plaza. In addition, DC must remove the phrase from&#160;websites, documents, and other materials which are under its jurisdiction.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Transportation to withhold 50% of the annual&#160;Highway Trust Fund apportionment for&#160;DC on the first day of each fiscal year in which DC has not complied with these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
