<bill session="117" type="s" number="3567" updated="2023-08-17T18:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No PLA LOOPHOLES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No People&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Liberation Army in Logistical Operations and Other Pertinent Humanitarian Operations Leading to Endangered Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No PLA LOOPHOLES Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the limitation on military-to-military exchanges and contacts with the People's Liberation Army to cover all logistical operations and remove the exception for search-and-rescue and humanitarian operations and exercises.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2022-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2022-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2022-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2022-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-17T18:38:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No People's Liberation Army in Logistical Operations and Other Pertinent Humanitarian Operations Leading to Endangered Security Act or the No PLA LOOPHOLES Act

This bill increases restrictions on military-to-military exchanges or contacts between the U.S. Armed Forces and the Chinese military. Specifically, the bill expands an existing prohibition on exchanges or contacts that include inappropriate exposure to advanced logistical operations to cover logistical operations instead.

Additionally, the bill eliminates an exception to the prohibited exchanges or contacts in the case of search and rescue or humanitarian operations or exercises.</summary>
</bill>
