<bill session="118" type="s" number="2428" updated="2025-11-18T20:34:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PATHS to Tutor Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Partnering Aspiring Teachers with High-need Schools to Tutor Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PATHS to Tutor Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a grant program for innovative partnerships among teacher preparation programs, local educational agencies, and community-based organizations to expand access to high-quality tutoring in hard-to-staff schools and high-need schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7016" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-29T16:02:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Partnering Aspiring Teachers with High-need Schools to Tutor Act of 2023 or the PATHS to Tutor Act of 2023

This bill expands access to tutoring in hard-to-staff and high-need schools by establishing a grant program.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Education (ED) to award competitive grants to local consortia to carry out high-quality tutoring programs. Local consortia refers to partnerships between teacher preparation programs, local educational agencies or individual schools, and community-based organizations.

Grant recipients may use these funds for certain activities, including matching and placing tutors, purchasing instructional materials and connectivity resources, and providing transportation and meals to students who attend the tutoring program.

ED must also enter into an interagency agreement with the Corporation for National and Community Service to include tutor positions as approved national service positions.</summary>
</bill>
