<bill session="117" type="h" number="9496" updated="2023-08-28T13:00:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alaska Land Conveyances and Trails Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alaska Land Conveyances and Trails Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance to the University of Alaska of certain public land in the State of Alaska, to amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to exclude certain payments to aged, blind, or disabled Alaska Natives or descendants of Alaska Natives from being used to determine eligibility for certain programs, to amend the National Trails System Act to designate the Chilkoot National Historic Trail and to provide for a study of the Alaska Long Trail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2546" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9269" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1128" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1354" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2524" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T12:45:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Alaska Land Conveyances and Trails Act

This bill addresses issues involving Alaska lands and trails and Alaska Natives.

Specifically, the bill establishes within the Bureau of Land Management a program to (1) identify and convey available state-selected land to the University of Alaska to support higher education in the state; and (2) acquire, by purchase or exchange, University of Alaska-owned inholdings (certain interests in land owned by the university) in the state.

The bill provides for exclusion of certain settlement trust payments to Alaska natives for purposes of determining eligibility for certain federal programs.

The bill (1) designates the Chilkoot National Historic Trail, and (2) provides for a study of the feasibility and desirability of designating the Alaska Long Trail as a national scenic trail.</summary>
</bill>
