<bill session="117" type="s" number="2557" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain transportation projects to include a value-for-money analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to require certain transportation projects to include a value-for-money analysis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-16T14:50:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires a value-for-money analysis as part of certain applications for financial assistance for transportation projects.

An applicant for assistance through the Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act program and the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing program must include the analysis if the project (1) has an estimated cost that exceeds $750 million, and (2) is carried out in a state that authorizes the use of public-private partnerships for transportation projects. The analysis must address, among other matters, the cost of using public funding versus private financing.

Additionally, the Department of Transportation must (1) report to Congress about the use of private financing for such transportation projects and the benefits of value-for-money analysis; and (2) issue guidance on performance benchmarks, risk premiums, and expected rates of return on private financing for transportation.</summary>
</bill>
