<bill session="119" type="h" number="56" updated="2025-07-01T14:53:33Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Secret Service Prioritization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secret Service Prioritization Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To transfer certain responsibilities of the United States Secret Service to the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001132" joined="2025-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-01T14:52:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Secret Service Prioritization Act of 2025

This bill transfers most investigative authorities of the U.S. Secret Service to the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI).&#160;

Specifically, the bill transfers to the FBI the Secret Service's authority to investigate federal criminal offenses involving (1) certain misconduct in connection with government transportation requests, federal farm loans, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation; (2) coins, obligations, and securities of the United States and foreign governments, including counterfeiting of U.S. currency; and (3) financial and computer-based crimes, including identity theft, electronic access fraud, computer fraud, and electronic benefits transfer fraud.&#160;

Under the bill, the Secret Service retains the authority to investigate two categories of federal criminal offenses: (1) threats against the President, President-elect, Vice President, or Vice President-elect; and (2) threats against former Presidents and certain other persons.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
