<bill session="118" type="h" number="928" updated="2025-01-16T11:56:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To repeal the High-Efficiency Electric Home Rebate Program and transfer funds under such program to the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the High-Efficiency Electric Home Rebate Program and transfer funds under such program to the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-05T11:35:19Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill repeals the High-Efficiency Electric Home Rebate Program and transfers unobligated funds under such program to the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program.

The High-Efficiency Electric Home Rebate Program provides rebates to low- or moderate-income households for qualified electrification projects (e.g., installing certain efficient appliances). The Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program provides funding to states, tribes, and local governments to support a range of programs, such as law enforcement and crime prevention programs.</summary>
</bill>
