<bill session="116" type="s" number="2718" updated="2022-11-01T04:32:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Western Water Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Water Security Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conduct of certain water security measures in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-375.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4891" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural practices and innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-03T19:18:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Western Water Security Act of 2019

This bill addresses water management infrastructure and improvement, groundwater management, and water conservation and environmental restoration in certain western states.

Specifically, the bill increases the authorization of appropriations to fund research agreements between the Bureau of Reclamation and eligible entities for water management improvement. The bill expands eligibility for such agreements to include nonprofit conservation organizations.

The bill also reauthorizes through FY2024 a program through which Interior is authorized to assist eligible desalination projects. The bill lowers cost-sharing requirements under the program for rural desalination projects.

Further, the bill allows certain financial assistance made available under an existing drought relief program to be used to assist state and tribal governments in addressing drought-related impacts to water supplies or any other immediate water-related crises. The bill reauthorizes the program through FY2030.

Additionally, the bill increases the maximum federal share of costs for certain infrastructure improvements and activities for groundwater management that provide benefits to consumptive water users (i.e., users of water that is not returned to a stream, river, or water treatment plant) and nonconsumptive ecological or recreational values.

The bill also requires Reclamation to carry out a water acquisition program in specified river basins. Further, Interior must analyze the extent to which changes in water supply will affect native biodiversity and must produce strategies for sustaining native biodiversity during periods of drought.</summary>
</bill>
