<bill session="108" type="s" number="2782" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:47Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Security Personal Savings Guarantee and Prosperity Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform social security by establishing a Personal Social Security Savings Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Personal Savings Guarantee and Prosperity Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2004-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4851" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget resolutions"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Gross national product"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-30T14:33:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Security Personal Savings Guarantee and Prosperity Act of 2004 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to provide for the establishment of a voluntary, personal Social Security investment program under a new part B (Personal Social Security Savings Program) where a participating individual is able to invest in tax free personal accounts in a way that is similar to the way Federal employees invest in the Thrift Savings Program.

Establishes in the Treasury the Social Security Personal Savings Fund, with personal Social Security savings accounts for deposit of the redirected Social Security contributions of participating individuals as mechanisms for crediting to such individuals amounts held in the Tier I Investment Fund, the Tier II Investment Fund, and Tier III Investment Options, also hereby established. Prescribes rules for personal Social Security savings annuity and other distributions.

Establishes in the executive branch of the Government a Personal Social Security Savings Account Board to administer the new part B program.

Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to provide for adjustment of primary insurance amounts in relation to deposits made to personal Social Security accounts.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund amounts equal to the recapture of corporate tax on account yields and of Government savings over baseline.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt the Social Security Personal Savings Fund and each Tier III Investment Option from income taxation. Subjects a personal Social Security savings account to taxes imposed on unrelated business income of charitable, etc. organizations. Excludes from a distributee's gross income any qualified distribution from amounts credited to a personal Social Security savings account from the Social Security Personal Savings Fund or held in a Tier III Investment Option.

Creates in the Treasury the Self-Liquidating Social Security Transition Fund for the deposit of OASDI trust fund surplus for the preceding year.

Amends SSA to provide for accounting for the OASDI program and the individual Social Security investment program.

Amends SSA title VII to prescribe the budgetary treatment of the Social Security trust funds, the Social Security Personal Savings Fund, and taxes on self-employment income and FICA (Federal Insurance Contributions) taxes.</summary>
</bill>
