<bill session="117" type="h" number="6374" updated="2023-08-04T16:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Supply Chains for Servicemembers and Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Supply Chains for Servicemembers and Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement the recommendations of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense with respect to mitigation of foreign suppliers in the pharmaceutical supply chain of the Department of Defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001085"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001186" joined="2022-01-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3174" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4543" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-04T16:09:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Supply Chains for Servicemembers and Security Act

This bill addresses Department of Defense (DOD) supply chain risk management, specifically risk management related to pharmaceuticals.

The bill requires the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment within DOD to develop and issue implementing guidance for risk management for DOD supply chains for materiel (e.g., pharmaceuticals) and identify supply chain information gaps regarding reliance on foreign suppliers of drugs.

After such guidance is issued, the Defense Health Agency must develop and publish implementing guidance for risk management for DOD's supply chain for pharmaceuticals and establish a working group to assess risks to the pharmaceutical supply chain, identify the pharmaceuticals most critical to beneficiary care at military treatment facilities, and establish policies for allocating scarce pharmaceutical resources.

Finally, the Defense Logistics Agency must modify Defense Logistics Agency Instructions 5025.03 and 3110.01 to require Defense Logistics Agency Troop Support to coordinate annually with customers in the military departments to test responsiveness of the agency's contingency contracts for pharmaceuticals and to include the results of the testing in the annual Warstopper Program reports.</summary>
</bill>
