<bill session="108" type="h" number="1807" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:03Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trade Adjustment Assistance for Self-Employment Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the trade adjustment assistance program under the Trade Act of 1974 to establish a demonstration project to provide self-employment training and assistance to eligible adversely affected workers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trade Adjustment Assistance for Self-Employment Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000210" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000280" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000545" joined="2003-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2003-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-11-18T19:28:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Trade Adjustment Assistance for Self-Employment Act of 2003 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish an alternative trade adjustment assistance program for workers that provides for self-employment training and funds to pay, in whole or in part, the start up costs attributable to the individual's business enterprise.

Requires the Secretary to provide the opportunity for one or more workers in a group of workers on whose behalf a petition is filed for a trade adjustment assistance application eligibility to request that the individual workers be certified for the alternative trade adjustment assistance program.

Requires a worker covered by an group trade adjustment assistance eligibility certification who elects to receive alternative trade adjustment assistance program benefits to: (1) submit a self-employment business plan to the appropriate State agency for approval; (2) be likely to obtain self-employment in accordance with such plan within 26 weeks after separation from the adversely affected employment; (3) be likely to engage in self-employment on a full-time basis; and (4) be likely not to return to the employment from which the worker was separated.

Limits the total amount of payments made on behalf of a worker during the two-year eligibility period to: (1) $2,500 per worker for training costs; and (2) $10,000 per worker for start-up costs. Prohibits any other trade adjustment assistance benefits for a worker accepting alternative benefits under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
