<bill session="119" type="sr" number="31" updated="2025-11-18T20:04:48Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution calling on the Government of Panama to expel officials and interests of the People's Republic of China and terminate Chinese management of key Panamanian ports.</title>
    <title type="display">A resolution calling on the Government of Panama to expel officials and interests of the People's Republic of China and terminate Chinese management of key Panamanian ports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001227"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2025-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S338-339" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="hr" number="232" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-04T15:38:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution expresses concern about the presence and influence of China in Panamanian ports and infrastructure, particularly in facilities with strategic significance such as the ports of Balboa and Cristobal. &#160;

The resolution calls on the Panamanian government to reaffirm its commitment to the permanent neutrality of the Panama Canal as defined by the Neutrality Treaty (i.e., the Treaty Concerning the Permanent Neutrality and Operation of the Panama Canal, signed in 1977) and terminate agreements allowing Chinese state-owned enterprises or private entities based in China to manage such strategic infrastructure. The resolution also urges the U.S. government to (1) leverage provisions of the Neutrality Treaty to address threats to the neutrality of the Panama Canal, and (2)&#160;develop a U.S.-Panama task force to oversee canal security and operations.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
