<bill session="111" type="s" number="1555" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:12Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Office of the National Alzheimer's Project Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of the National Alzheimer's Project.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of the National Alzheimer's Project Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001162"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2009-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4689" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3036" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-17T18:42:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Office of the National Alzheimer's Project Act - Establishes in the Office of the President the Office of the National Alzheimer's Project to: (1) accelerate the development of treatments that would prevent, halt, or reverse the course of Alzheimer's; (2) create and maintain an integrated national plan to overcome Alzheimer's; (3) help to coordinate the health care and treatment of citizen's with Alzheimer's; (4) ensure the inclusion of ethnic and racial populations that are at higher risk for Alzheimer's or that are least likely to receive care in clinical, research, and service efforts with the purpose of decreasing health disparities; and (5) coordinate with international bodies to integrate and inform the fight against Alzheimer's globally.

Sets forth the duties of the Director of the Office, including to use discretionary authority to evaluate all federal programs around Alzheimer's.

Establishes in the Office an Advisory Council on Alzheimer's Research and Treatment.</summary>
</bill>
