<bill session="111" type="s" number="1523" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:13Z">
  <state datetime="2009-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Services for Ending Long-Term Homelessness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a grant program to provide supportive services in permanent supportive housing for chronically homeless individuals and families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Services for Ending Long-Term Homelessness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2009-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2009-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2009-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3636" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-04T21:47:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Services for Ending Long-Term Homelessness Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Administrator of Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, to design national strategies for providing services in supportive housing that will assist in ending chronic homelessness and to implement programs that address chronic homelessness.

Requires the Secretary to make matching grants to eligible entities to provide services that promote recovery and self-sufficiency and that address barriers to housing stability to chronically homeless individuals and families in, or who are scheduled to become residents of, permanent supportive housing and to other individuals and families who have voluntarily chosen to seek other housing opportunities after a period of tenancy in supportive housing.

Directs the Secretary to require grantees to report data regarding the performance outcomes of projects carried out under this Act, which shall include measuring and reporting specific performance outcomes related to the long-term goals of: (1) increasing stability within the community for individuals and families who have been chronically homeless; and (2) decreasing recurrence of periods of homelessness.</summary>
</bill>
