<bill session="111" type="h" number="1165" updated="2020-02-10T16:51:51Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mentoring for All Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Mentoring for All Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To develop capacity and infrastructure for mentoring programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2010-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001045" joined="2009-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2010-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2009-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2009-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E401"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Healthy Families and Communities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED04" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Healthy Families and Communities" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-03T22:19:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Mentoring for All Act of 2009 - Amends the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to direct the Corporation for National and Community Service to award competitive, matching, three-year grants to nonpartisan, collaborative, public-private partnerships at the state and local level for efforts to grow and strengthen direct-service youth mentoring programs in all forms and settings in their service areas.

Requires partnership grantees to use at least 80% of their grant for competitive subgrants to mentoring programs: (1) operated by or being created by, nonprofit organizations, schools, or local governments; or (2) operated by local collaboratives that each include at least two experienced youth mentoring organizations and at least one entity that provides volunteer mentors. Allows partnership grantees to give subgrant priority to collaboratives.

Requires each partnership grantee to participate in a collaborative national network of mentoring partnerships.

Directs the Corporation to award competitive, matching, three-year grants to entities or collaboratives of entities enabling the entities or collaboratives to: (1) build the necessary infrastructure to create a state mentoring partnership; or (2) implement national mentoring projects.

Requires the Corporation to evaluate this Act's programs and provide training and technical assistance to grant fund recipients that is based on support from the national network of mentoring partnerships.</summary>
</bill>
