<bill session="111" type="h" number="4546" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:43Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Truth in Tuition Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require certain institutions of higher education to commit to, and provide notice of, tuition levels for students.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Tuition Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2010-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-03T16:43:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Truth in Tuition Act of 2010 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education (IHEs) to provide each admitted student considering an undergraduate or graduate program: (1) a multi-year tuition and fee schedule; or (2) a single-year tuition and fee schedule, and a nonbinding, multi-year estimate of net costs after all financial aid is awarded.

Requires IHEs that choose the second option to include with each multi-year estimate the average deviation, in percentage terms, between previous year estimates and actual net costs for their students.

Directs the Secretary of Education to waive the application of these requirements to IHEs for which the requirements are not practicable due to events that cause them severe economic distress, a dramatic reduction in state or federal aid, or any other circumstance the Secretary deems valid.</summary>
</bill>
