<bill session="116" type="h" number="3677" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:43Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Opportunity for Lead Exposure Accountability and Deterrence Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to improve transparency under the national primary drinking water regulations for lead and copper, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Opportunity for Lead Exposure Accountability and Deterrence Act of 2017</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000380"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2020-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2086" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-01T15:45:58Z" status="Introduced in House">National Opportunity for Lead Exposure Accountability and Deterrence Act of 2017 [sic]

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to revise the national primary drinking water regulations for lead and copper. The rule must direct

 public water systems (the systems) to meet certain reporting requirements; the EPA to develop a sampling protocol and develop instructions for compliance with the protocol; the EPA, or the state exercising primary enforcement responsibility, to require on-site investigations for identifying the source of lead in all residential or nonresidential facilities when their individual samples have concentrations of lead or copper contamination exceeding specified levels; the systems to meet certain notification and reporting requirements when lead or copper concentration levels are exceeded; the systems to develop and make publicly available an inventory of the material composition of the service lines at residential and nonresidential facilities; the systems to collect and make publicly available information about the ownership of those service lines; and the systems to replace an entire lead service line (instead of partially replacing them) when they are replaced. The EPA must also revise the rule to lower the allowable level of lead that may be contained in drinking water.</summary>
</bill>
