<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1062" updated="2022-02-03T05:20:43Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5658" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-05-22T21:15:37-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001032"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the videotaping or electronic recording of detainee interrogations in the custody of or under the effective control of the Department of Defense. The amendment also directs the Judge Advocates General of the respective military services to develop uniform guidelines for such videotaping or electronic recording and for said guidelines to be provided to Congress.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 32 printed in House Report 110-666 to require the videotaping or electronic recording of detainee interrogations in the custody of or under the effective control of the Department of Defense. Directs the Judge Advocates General of the respective military services to develop uniform guidelines for such videotaping or electronic recording, and for said guidelines to be provided to Congress.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-05-22T21:15:37-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="362">
      <text>On agreeing to the Holt amendment (A017) Agreed to by recorded vote: 218 - 192 (Roll no. 362).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T19:00:03-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Holt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/23/2008 H4796-4797, H4810-4811" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 5/23/2008 H4796" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T21:15:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T21:15:37-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T19:00:03-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A017) offered by Mr. Holt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/23/2008 H4796-4797, H4810-4811" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 5/23/2008 H4796" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T21:15:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Holt amendment (A017) Agreed to by recorded vote: 218 - 192 (Roll no. 362).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
