<bill session="112" type="h" number="1520" updated="2019-11-15T21:29:37Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Drilling Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Offshore Drilling Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to require that oil and gas drilling and production operations on the outer Continental Shelf must have in place the best available technology for blowout preventers and emergency shutoff equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2011-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2011-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2011-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000031" joined="2011-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E710"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-14T14:44:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Offshore Drilling Safety Improvement Act - Amends the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to direct the Secretary of the Interior to issue regulations requiring: (1) that all oil and gas drilling and production operations on the outer Continental Shelf have safety and environmental management systems in place, including blowout preventers and additional backup emergency shutoff equipment such as acoustic shut-off technology; and (2) that such equipment use the best available and safest technologies. Requires consideration of the need for different technology requirements in different environments and depths.

Applies such regulations to: (1) all new oil and gas drilling and production operations, and (2) all existing drilling and production operations six months after the issuance of the regulations.

Requires the Secretary, every five years thereafter, to review blowout preventer and emergency shutoff equipment technology and revise the regulations as necessary to require use of the best available technology.

Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to require the Department of Energy (DOE) Assistant Secretaries to identify the best available and safest technology for offshore oil and gas exploration and production.</summary>
</bill>
