<bill session="116" type="s" number="4062" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:09Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stopping Big Tech's Censorship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Big Tech's Censorship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 to require that providers and users of an interactive computer service meet certain standards to qualify for liability protections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000594"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-20T15:46:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Big Tech's Censorship Act

This bill modifies the requirements that providers and users of interactive computer services (e.g., social media companies) must meet in order to qualify for certain liability protections.

Specifically, in order to be exempt from being treated as the publisher or speaker of any information published by a third-party information content provider, a provider or user of an interactive computer service must take reasonable steps to prevent or address the unlawful use of such service or unlawful publication of information on the service.

Further, the bill removes the protection against civil liability for a provider or user of an interactive computer service that voluntarily takes action in good faith to restrict access to or availability of certain offensive material, unless such action meets specified First Amendment requirements.

Lastly, to be eligible for protection from liability for information published by a third-party information content provider, a provider or user of an interactive computer service must meet certain notice requirements.</summary>
</bill>
