<bill session="117" type="h" number="5513" updated="2023-01-01T23:51:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to ensure that the process for an individual obtaining a security clearance includes vetting the individual for ties to domestic terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Clearance for Terrorists Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Clearance for Terrorists Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001109" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2021-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-11T23:24:24Z" status="Introduced in House">No Clearance for Terrorists Act

This bill requires processes for vetting an individual for a security clearance to take into consideration whether that individual has been involved in terrorism.

The Special Security Directorate of the National Counterintelligence and Security Center must ensure that the guidelines for adjudicating security clearances, when determining what conditions could raise a security concern or disqualify an applicant, include whether the applicant has been involved in or advocated domestic or international terrorism.

The directorate must also ensure that guidelines and instructions to federal agencies relating to security clearances include screening an individual for possible involvement with domestic terrorism.

The directorate and the Office of Personnel Management must ensure that certain forms related to public trust and national security positions include questions regarding whether the individual submitting the form has been involved in domestic terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
