<bill session="117" type="h" number="4259" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, to direct the Institute to establish a robust program focusing on driving improvements in America's cybersecurity posture by creating more robust digital identity management standards and guidelines.</title>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000454"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2021-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-07T16:47:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening Digital Identity Act of 2021

This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to take into account strengthening identity proofing under the program to support the development of voluntary and cost-effective technical standards, metrology, test beds, and conformance criteria for identity management.

NIST shall develop and implement a technical roadmap for identity management research and the development of standards and guidelines focused on enabling the use and adoption of modern digital identity solutions.

 NIST shall develop and periodically update a framework of standards, methodologies, procedures, and processes as a guide for federal, state, and local governments to follow when providing services related to digital identity verification.</summary>
</bill>
