<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>896</number>
    <updateDate>2025-01-14T18:51:33Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-01-14T18:51:33Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-03-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2023-03-21T20:43:28Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-03-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000577</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lee, Mike [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Lee</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        <updateDate>2023-04-12T16:45:17Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-03-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-05-12T18:34:15Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stopping Harmful Incidents to Enforce Lawful Drone Use Act or the SHIELD U Act &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This bill authorizes and expands counter-drone activities by state, local, and airport law enforcement, and federal agencies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Specifically, the bill authorizes state, local, and airport law enforcement to carry out Counter-Unmanned Aircraft System (Counter-UAS) activities on commercial service airport property to detect, identify, and mitigate threats posed by unmanned aircraft (i.e., drones). The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) is also authorized to carry out these activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further, the bill authorizes state and local law enforcement to carry out Counter-UAS activities off commercial airport property; the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must establish a process that allows for collaboration and coordination with these entities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In addition, each commercial airport must convene a task force that includes federal agencies, air carriers, and telecommunications service providers to establish or modify the airport's tactical response plan to drone threats. The FAA and Transportation Security Administration must also publish best practices guidance on Counter-UAS activities at commercial service airports. This guidance must be updated annually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The bill also allows DHS and the Departments of Defense, Justice, and Energy to contract with other entities to carry out authorized Counter-UAS activities.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Further, the bill amends restrictions on the use of radio frequency jamming technology to allow state, local, and airport law enforcement to use the technology to mitigate a drone threat.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Finally, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Center must expand its curriculum to include training on the use of Counter-UAS activities. The training must be available to state, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement, as well as private sector security agencies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>SHIELD U Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>SHIELD U Act</title>
        <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:23:14Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>SHIELD U Act</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:41:33Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Stopping Harmful Incidents to Enforce Lawful Drone Use Act</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:41:33Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to authorize Counter-UAS activities on and off commercial service airport property, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-04-07T02:28:43Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-03-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s896is/xml/BILLS-118s896is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-03-21</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
