<bill session="117" type="s" number="1127" updated="2023-03-08T19:57:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LEGEND Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to make certain operational models available to the public, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Learning Excellence and Good Examples from New Developers Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">LEGEND Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Learning Excellence and Good Examples from New Developers Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LEGEND Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2021-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1942-1943" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="211">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 211.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>By Senator Cantwell from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 117-160.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-06T12:35:29Z" status="Reported to Senate">Learning Excellence and Good Examples from New Developers Act of 2021 or the LEGEND Act of 2021

This bill requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to develop and implement a plan to make certain operational models available to the public and periodically review innovations and improvements made to such models in order to improve the accuracy and timeliness of NOAA forecasts.

In developing and implementing the plan, NOAA may make accommodations to ensure the public release of any model, information, documentation, or data does not jeopardize

 national security; intellectual property or redistribution rights; certain trade secrets, commercial information, or financial information; any models or data that are otherwise restricted by contract or other written agreement; or its mission to protect lives and property. NOAA must prioritize making available to the public operational models that it developed.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-160</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
