<bill session="115" type="h" number="4017" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:27Z">
  <state datetime="2017-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States-Israel Common Defense Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Israel Common Defense Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the President to take actions to ensure Israel is prepared for all contingencies if Iran seeks to develop a nuclear weapon after expiration of certain provisions of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2017-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-27T13:15:20Z" status="Introduced in House">United States-Israel Common Defense Authorization Act

This bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should: (1) seek to extend certain provisions of the Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action (JCPA) without abrogating the JCPA, (2) ensure that Israel and other allies are prepared for all contingencies should Iran pursue development of a nuclear weapon after expiration of JCPA provisions, and (3) send a clear signal to Iran that development of a nuclear weapon will never be tolerated.

The Department of Defense shall: (1) conduct a study with the government of Israel on Israel's military requirements to defend itself against Iran's pursuit of a nuclear weapon, including the extent to which the post-JCPA transfer of U.S. ordnance to Israel would advance the national interests of both countries, and (2) submit the results of such study to Congress.

The President may, upon Israel's request, provide for the construction of infrastructure in Israel to accommodate ordnance systems designed to destroy underground nuclear infrastructure and store related munitions for U.S. use, or for transfer to Israel's custody under specified circumstances. The President must certify to Congress that such actions are consistent with the results of the study of Israel's military requirements and vital to U.S. national security interests.

The Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action was agreed to at Vienna on July 14, 2015, by Iran and China, France, Germany, the Russian Federation, the United Kingdom, and the United States, with the High Representative of the European Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy, and all related implementing materials and agreements.</summary>
</bill>
