<bill session="117" type="s" number="2583" updated="2023-03-08T19:57:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for rules for the use of retirement funds in connection with federally declared disasters.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for rules for the use of retirement funds in connection with federally declared disasters.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6241" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4808" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-01T16:17:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill allows penalty-free distributions from tax-exempt retirement plans for a federally declared disaster (i.e., a qualified disaster recovery distribution). The bill defines qualified disaster recovery distribution as any distribution within a 180 day period after a disaster declaration that is made to an individual whose principal residence is located in a qualified disaster area (an area for which a major disaster has been declared) and who has sustained an economic loss due to the disaster.

The bill sets forth rules for the recontribution of withdrawals from a plan for first-time home purchases or for purchases or construction of a principal residence in a disaster area, and increases the limit on loans from a qualified employer plan that an individual may take in lieu of a distribution.</summary>
</bill>
