<bill session="108" type="s" number="2084" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet Tax Ban Extension and Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revive and extend the Internet Tax Freedom Act for 2 years, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Tax Ban Extension and Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000352" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000725" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2004-02-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2004-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1294-1295" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-31T19:54:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Internet Tax Ban Extension and Improvement Act - Amends the Internet Tax Freedom Act to extend the ban on State taxation of Internet access and on multiple or discriminatory taxes on electronic commerce until November 1, 2005.

Makes such tax ban inapplicable to a tax on Internet access that was generally imposed and enforced prior to October 1, 1998, if, before that date, the tax was authorized by statute and either: (1) a provider of Internet access services had a reasonable opportunity to know that an agency has interpreted and applied such tax to Internet access services; or (2) a State or political subdivision generally collected such tax on charges for Internet access. Applies the same rule for a tax on Internet access that was generally imposed and enforced as of November 1, 2003.

Changes the definition of "Internet access service" to exclude telecommunications services (current law), except to the extent such services are purchased, used, or sold by an Internet access provider to connect a purchaser of Internet access to the Internet access provider. Changes the definition of "tax on Internet access" to: (1) mean a tax on Internet access regardless of whether such tax is imposed on a provider of Internet access or a buyer of Internet access and regardless of the terminology used to describe the tax; and (2) exclude a tax levied upon or measured by net income, capital stock, net worth, or property value.

Permits subjecting Internet access charges to taxation if they are aggregated with telecommunications service charges and the provider cannot identify them from regular business records.</summary>
</bill>
