<bill session="110" type="h" number="2743" updated="2023-01-12T17:53:00Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Affiliate Radio System Emergency Communication Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continuance of volunteer communications capability within the United States and its territories.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Affiliate Radio System Emergency Communication Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2007-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2007-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2007-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2007-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000573" joined="2007-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antennas"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military communications"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio spectrum allocation"/>
    <term name="Radio stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-31T21:18:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Affiliate Radio System Emergency Communication Act of 2007 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) require that high frequency (short-wave) transmitters, receivers, and related data and interface equipment that meet standards of service established for the Amateur Radio Service by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) in the frequency range of 2-30 megahertz are also approved for routine training functions and emergency communication service on any federal government Military Affiliate Radio System (MARS) or National Communication System Shared Resources High Frequency Radio Program (SHARES) channel within that frequency range; and (2) encourage and utilize MARS personnel, facilities, capabilities, and radio equipment to connect to the Internet in their emergency communication planning..

Prohibits the Secretary from: (1) requiring the discontinuance of the use in the radio service bands assigned to MARS or SHARES of any communications equipment that has been approved by the FCC for operation within the Amateur Radio Service; or (2) adding, or permitting any agency of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to add, any technical requirements for MARS stations.

Authorizes the Secretary to add new transmitters and receivers to the MARS and SHARES networks provided the equipment meets FCC standards for operation in the Amateur Radio Service and is equipped with frequency stabilization modules.</summary>
</bill>
