<bill session="111" type="h" number="1847" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:37Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Coal-Derived Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the inclusion of coal-derived fuel at certain volumes in aviation fuel, motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Coal-Derived Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000712" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2009-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2009-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-15T14:23:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Clean Coal-Derived Fuels for Energy Security Act of 2009 - Directs the President to promulgate regulations to ensure that aviation fuel, motor vehicle fuel, home heating oil, and boiler fuel sold or introduced into commerce in the United States, on an annual average basis, contains the applicable volume of clean coal-derived fuel, determined in accordance with this Act.

Exempts small refineries from compliance with such regulations until calendar 2018.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to study and report to the President and Congress on whether compliance with the requirements of this Act would impose a disproportionate economic hardship on small refineries. Requires the President to extend such exemption if it would.

Allows a small refinery to: (1) petition the President for an exemption at any time for the reason of disproportionate economic hardship; and (2) opt-in and be subject to such regulations if it notifies the President that it waives the exemption.</summary>
</bill>
