<bill session="116" type="s" number="3805" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:37Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paycheck Protection Program Flexibility Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paycheck Protection Program Flexibility Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act and the CARES Act to modify certain provisions related to the forgiveness of loans under the paycheck protection program, to allow recipients of loan forgiveness under the paycheck protection program to defer payroll taxes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2020-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2020-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2020-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2020-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7010" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-29T16:56:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Paycheck Protection Program Flexibility Act of 2020

This bill modifies provisions related to the forgiveness of loans made to small businesses under the Paycheck Protection Program implemented in response to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill establishes a minimum maturity of five years for a paycheck protection loan that has a remaining balance after the application of forgiveness. The bill also extends the covered period during which the recipient of a paycheck protection loan may use such funds for certain expenses while remaining eligible for forgiveness of the loan.

Further, the bill prohibits the Small Business Administration from limiting the non-payroll portion of a forgivable covered loan amount. Currently, only 25% of a paycheck protection loan may be allocated to non-payroll expenses such as rent and utilities.

The bill extends the period of time in which an employer may rehire or eliminate a reduction in employment, salary, or wages that would otherwise reduce the forgivable amount of a paycheck protection loan. However, the forgivable amount must be determined without regard to a reduction in the number of employees if the recipient is (1) unable to rehire an employee, (2) able to demonstrate an inability to hire a similarly qualified employee, or (3) able to demonstrate an inability to return to the same level of business activity.

Lastly, the bill eliminates a provision that makes a paycheck protection loan recipient who has such indebtedness forgiven ineligible to defer payroll tax payments.</summary>
</bill>
