<bill session="117" type="h" number="4339" updated="2022-12-31T05:08:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to publicly disclose the results of Department of Defense perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Military PFAS Testing Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military PFAS Testing Disclosure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2021-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2792" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-19T19:08:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Military PFAS Testing Disclosure Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to immediately publicly disclose the results of any testing for perfluoroalkyl or polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFAS, conducted on or at specified sites (i.e., areas surrounding DOD military installations in the United States, formerly used defense sites, and state-owned facilities of the National Guard).

DOD must also disclose the expected timing and location of any planned testing for PFAS conducted at the specified sites.

DOD may satisfy the disclosure requirements by publishing the information, data sets, and results relating to the testing on a publicly available DOD website or in the Federal Register.

Prior to conducting any testing for PFAS, DOD must provide notice in writing to (1) the managers of the public water system and the publicly owned treatment works serving the areas located immediately adjacent to the military installation being tested, (2) the municipal government serving the areas located immediately adjacent to the military installation being tested, and (3) all Restoration Advisory Board members for the military installation where the testing is to occur.

DOD must test for any PFAS for which a method of measurement in drinking water has been validated by the Environmental Protection Agency.</summary>
</bill>
