<bill session="109" type="sr" number="419" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:48Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the new United Nations Human Rights Council fails to adequately reform the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, thus preventing that body from becoming an effective monitor of human rights throughout the world.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the new United Nations Human Rights Council fails to adequately reform the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, thus preventing that body from becoming an effective monitor of human rights throughout the world.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000439"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2006-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2006-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2693"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2692-2693" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations delegations"/>
    <term name="United Nations structure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-04T21:06:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Affirms that the United Nations Rights Council should uphold the ideals contained in the U.N. Charter and the Universal Declaration on Human Rights.

 Believes that countries charged with protecting human rights throughout the world should be required to hold democratic elections, allow for freedom of expression, and have a credible civil society.

 Finds that the creation of the Council fails to adequately reform the U.N. Commission on Human Rights, and prevent the worst human rights abusers from attaining Council membership.

Applauds the Administration for opposing the creation of the new council, and believes that the United States should seek membership on such council.

Urges the Administration to not support the Council, and to advocate in favor of withdrawing financial support until meaningful reforms are undertaken.

 Believes the United States should strengthen the work of the international community of democracies by establishing an effective human rights oversight body outside the U.N. system.</summary>
</bill>
