<bill session="117" type="s" number="2773" updated="2023-11-09T22:28:57Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act to address satellite offices of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2022-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6589" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-01">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Durbin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-01" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="571">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 571.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7006-7007" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07T14:04:58-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07T14:19:56-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8697" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-09T20:54:19Z" status="Passed Senate">Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022 

This bill modifies the responsibilities of U.S. Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) satellite offices and addresses related issues.

The bill increases the discount on patent-related fees for small and micro entities. An entity that falsely claims such a discount shall be subject to a fine, in addition to any other existing penalties.

The bill also modifies the statutory purpose of PTO satellite offices to include (1) outreach activities targeting certain groups, such as low-income populations, veterans, and geographic groups that are underrepresented in patent filings; and (2) targeting patent examiners and administrative patent judges from economically, geographically, and demographically diverse backgrounds in the PTO's retention activities.

For each satellite office established after January 1, 2023, the PTO must consider the office's proximity to anchor institutions (e.g., hospitals primarily serving veterans and institutions of higher education) and certain groups, such as low-income populations, veterans, and geographic groups that are underrepresented in patent filings.

The PTO must establish (1) a satellite office in the southeastern United States within three years of this bill's enactment, (2) at least four community outreach offices throughout the United States within five years of this bill's enactment, and (3) a pilot program to help prospective first-time patent applicants assess the strengths and weaknesses of a potential patent application.

The PTO must also (1) conduct and report to Congress a study on patent pro bono programs, including whether such programs are sufficiently serving prospective and existing participants; and (2) use the study's findings to update such pro bono programs.</summary>
</bill>
