<bill session="109" type="s" number="2561" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:38Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bureau of Reclamation Water Conservation, Efficiency, and Management Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make available cost-shared grants and enter into cooperative agreements to further the goals of the Water 2025 Program by improving water conservation, efficiency, and management in the Reclamation States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bureau of Reclamation Water Conservation, Efficiency, and Management Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3218"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3218-3219" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held in Albuquerque, NM. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-477.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5192" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-01T14:38:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bureau of Reclamation Water Conservation, Efficiency, and Management Improvement Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to provide grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, nonfederal entities with water delivery authority to pay the federal share of the cost of a project to conserve water, increase water use efficiency, facilitate water markets, enhance water management, or implement other actions to prevent water-related crises or conflicts in watersheds that have a nexus to federal water projects within reclamation states (Arizona, California, Colorado, Idaho, Kansas, Montana, Nebraska, Nevada, New Mexico, North Dakota, Oklahoma, Oregon, South Dakota, Texas, Utah, Washington, and Wyoming). Directs the Secretary to publish assistance eligibility and priority criteria. Limits the federal cost share of the project to 50%. Sets the nonfederal cost share for project operation and maintenance at 100%.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with institutions of higher education, nonprofit research institutions, or organizations with water or power delivery authority to fund research to conserve water, increase water use efficiency, or enhance water management.</summary>
</bill>
