<bill session="118" type="h" number="1305" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:32Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SUPER BUGS Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Us from Pandemic Era Resistance by Building a Unified Global Strategy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUPER BUGS Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to formulate a strategy for the Federal Government to secure support from foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities to facilitate the development and commercialization of qualified pandemic or epidemic products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000465" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000266" joined="2023-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2024-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T15:08:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Saving Us from Pandemic Era Resistance by Building a Unified Global Strategy Act of 2023 or the SUPER BUGS Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to seek to enter into arrangements with foreign countries, multilateral organizations, and other appropriate entities to facilitate the development and commercialization of qualified pandemic or epidemic products, which include drugs, biological products, and medical devices. HHS shall report to Congress a strategy for achieving this goal.</summary>
</bill>
