<bill session="118" type="h" number="189" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Action Versus No Action Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Action Versus No Action Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that only two alternatives be considered with respect to certain proposed collaborative forest management activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000668" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-01T23:54:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Action Versus No Action Act

This bill limits the scope of certain environmental assessments or impact statements related to forest management activities on National Forest System lands or public lands suitable for timber production to a consideration only of the effects of the forest management activity and the alternative of no action.

Specifically, the bill applies to assessments or impact statements prepared by the Department of Agriculture (USDA), with respect to National Forest System lands, or the Department of the Interior, with respect to public lands, for forest management activities that meet at least one of the criteria specified.

In the case of the alternative of no action, USDA or Interior shall consider whether to evaluate

 the effect of no action on, among other things, forest health, wildfire potential, insect and disease potential, and timber production; and the implications of a resulting decline in forest health, loss of habitat diversity, wildfire, or insect or disease infestation on potential losses of life and property, domestic water supply in the project area, and wildlife habitat loss.</summary>
</bill>
