<bill session="116" type="h" number="2697" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Corporal Ronil Singh and Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase Federal Pell Grants for the children of fallen public safety officers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Corporal Ronil Singh and Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2020-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T20:21:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Corporal Ronil Singh and Fallen Heroes Scholarship Act

This bill eliminates the expected family contribution (EFC) used to determine financial need in the case of a Pell Grant-eligible student whose spouse died as a result of performing military service in Iraq or Afghanistan after September 11, 2001, or while in the line of duty as a police officer, firefighter, or other public safety officer. Such a student is eligible to receive an automatic zero EFC and qualifies for the maximum Pell Grant award if the student was younger than 24 years old or enrolled at an institution of higher education at the time of the spouse's death. Currently, the automatic zero EFC provision applies only to a Pell Grant-eligible student whose parent or guardian died in the line of duty.

The bill also modifies the calculation of the increased Pell Grant award for these students.</summary>
</bill>
