<bill session="118" type="h" number="4408" updated="2025-11-19T02:32:10Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promising Pathway Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promising Pathway Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to establish a time-limited provisional approval pathway, subject to specific obligations, for certain drugs and biological products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000632" joined="2023-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2023-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000061" joined="2024-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2023-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1906" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-06T19:19:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Promising Pathway Act

This bill provides for expedited, provisional approval of drugs for serious or life-threatening diseases or conditions.

Specifically, the bill allows for provisional approval of drugs that are used to treat, prevent, or diagnose a serious or life-threatening disease or condition for which premature death is likely without early medical intervention. The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) must evaluate applications within 90 days of receipt. The FDA may approve applications if there is early evidence, including real-world and real-time evidence, of the drug's efficacy, as well as substantial evidence of the drug's safety. Provisional approval is valid for two years and may be renewed for up to eight years. The FDA may withdraw provisional approval in the event of serious adverse health effects.&#160;

Drug sponsors that receive provisional approval must require all patients receiving the drug to participate in an observational registry, through which the drug sponsor may collect and submit data relating to the drug until it is fully approved. Registries may be operated by the drug sponsor or another entity. The FDA must annually review these registries; sponsors of registries that fail to meet the bill's requirements are subject to civil penalties.&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
