<bill session="117" type="s" number="2878" updated="2023-01-02T00:29:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to codify in statute the establishment of the Office of Global Women's Issues and the Women's Global Development and Prosperity Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to codify in statute the establishment of the Office of Global Women's Issues and the Women's Global Development and Prosperity Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000601"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-07T19:32:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides funding through FY2026 and provides statutory authority for an office and related initiatives within the Department of State to advance U.S. foreign policy concerning the status of women and girls.

Specifically, the bill provides statutory authority for an Office of Global Women's Issues. The office, headed by an Ambassador-at-Large for Global Women's Issues, must advise on foreign policy and international programs relating to equal opportunities for and the advancement of women and girls. Additionally, the bill provides statutory authority for the Women's Global Development and Prosperity Initiative, which promotes women in the workforce and otherwise supports economic advancement for women internationally.

The bill prohibits the office, ambassador, or initiative from using funding to lobby other countries to change their abortion laws or policies or include abortion as a programmatic requirement.

The State Department must report annually on the program, including compliance with the abortion-related funding restrictions.</summary>
</bill>
