<bill session="108" type="s" number="190" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Intelligence Community Leadership Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Director of National Intelligence as head of the intelligence community, to modify and enhance authorities and responsibilities relating to the administration of intelligence and the intelligence community, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Community Leadership Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000352" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2004-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1081-1082"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Intelligence Community Leadership Act of 2003 - Amends the National Security Act of 1947 to establish the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to be composed of: (1) a Director and Deputy Director of National Intelligence; (2) a Deputy Director of National Intelligence for Community Management; (3) a National Intelligence Council; (4) three Assistant Directors for National Intelligence for Collection, Analysis and Production, and Administration; (5) a General Counsel to the Director; (6) an Inspector General of the Intelligence Community; and (7) the Office of the National Counterintelligence Executive. Includes among the Director's responsibilities: (1) providing national intelligence to the President, the heads of Federal departments and agencies, the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff and senior military commanders, and, where appropriate, Congress; (2) developing an annual budget for intelligence and intelligence-related activities; and (3) establishing requirements and priorities to govern the collection of national intelligence by elements of the intelligence community.Recodifies provisions establishing the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), designating as its lead official the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency (currently, the Director of Central Intelligence) and removing provisions which established specified CIA deputy and assistant director positions. Prohibits an individual from serving simultaneously as Director of National Intelligence and Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.Expresses the sense of Congress that the Director should be a cabinet-level official.Provides Executive Schedule pay levels for the newly-established Director, Deputy Director, and Assistant Director positions.</summary>
</bill>
