<bill session="108" type="h" number="3745" updated="2023-01-15T09:32:50Z">
  <state datetime="2004-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal and Local Communities Relationship Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to require State legislature approval of new gambling facilities, to provide for minimum requirements for Federal regulation of Indian gaming, to set up a commission to report to Congress on current living and health standards in Indian country, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal and Local Communities Relationship Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001144"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2004-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2004-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2004-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Standard of living"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-17T18:11:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal and Local Communities Relationship Improvement Act - Amends the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act to make invalid any tribal-State compact entered into after the enactment of this Act unless it is approved by the Governor and legislature of the State with which the compact was negotiated (with an exception for compact renewals that do not expand covered gambling operations). Requires approval by a State legislature (as well as by the State Governor, as under current law) of Indian gaming as regulated under such Act on lands acquired in trust by the Secretary of the Interior after October 17, 1988.

Prohibits the conduct of class III gaming on more than one parcel of land of an Indian tribe (unless under valid existing Tribal-State compacts, but on no more parcels than those on which gaming is conducted on the date of enactment of this Act). Directs the President to establish the Advisory Committee on Minimum Regulatory Requirements and Licensing Standards for Indian Gaming. Requires Committee recommendations to be submitted to specified congressional committees, the National Indian Gaming Commission, and each federally recognized Indian tribe. Establishes the Commission on Native American Policy to study and report to Congress on living standards in Indian country, including health, infrastructure, economic development, educational opportunities, housing, crime control on Indian reservations, the influence of organized crime on Indian gaming, and other specified matters.</summary>
</bill>
