<bill session="116" type="h" number="5440" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:55Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Remembering the Life of Kyle Poteat Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide financial assistance to eligible entities to provide and coordinate the provision of post-traumatic stress disorder prevention services for veterans through the award of grants to such entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remembering the Life of Kyle Poteat Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-21T19:45:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Remembering the Life of Kyle Poteat Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to award grants for a period of three years to eligible entities for the provision of post-traumatic stress disorder prevention services to veterans. Under the bill, eligible entities include tribally designated housing entities, community-based organizations, and other private entities that meet certain requirements.

Entities must submit an application to receive financial assistance that includes a description of the services they propose to provide, among other elements.

The bill requires the VA to equitably distribute grants across geographic regions and areas with the most need. Additionally, the VA shall give preference to entities that are experienced in providing post-traumatic stress disorder prevention services.

Entities receiving funding must notify service recipients that funding is wholly or partially from the VA.

The bill also expands VA patient advocate responsibilities by requiring them to share specified information with a family member who is a caregiver of a veteran.</summary>
</bill>
