<bill session="119" type="s" number="239" updated="2025-11-19T04:07:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Crow Revenue Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crow Revenue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to take certain mineral interests into trust for the benefit of the Crow Tribe of Montana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="725" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-02T14:13:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crow Revenue Act

This bill addresses the exchange of mineral interests in Montana involving the federal government, the Crow Tribe of Montana, and a private party.

Specifically, the bill requires&#160;

the Department of the Interior to accept the relinquishment of a specified federal coal lease associated with the Bull Mountains Mine near Roundup, Montana (the current operator of the mine is Signal Peak Energy);&#160;the Joe and Barbara Hope Mineral Trust (Hope Family Trust) to convey approximately 4,660 acres of subsurface mineral interests located within the boundaries of the Crow Indian Reservation in Big Horn County, Montana, to the tribe; and&#160;Interior to convey approximately 4,530 acres of subsurface mineral interests and 940 acres of surface interests located in Musselshell County, Montana, to the Hope Family Trust.&#160;Prior to these conveyances, the tribe must notify Interior that the tribe and the Hope Family Trust have agreed on a revenue-sharing formula for the development of the mineral and surface interests in&#160;Musselshell County, Montana.

The mineral interests conveyed by the Hope Family Trust to the tribe shall be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the tribe, upon the tribe's request. These mineral interests shall not be subject to state or local taxation.</summary>
</bill>
