<bill session="118" type="h" number="3711" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Schools Not Shelters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Schools Not Shelters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of elementary, secondary, and post-secondary school facilities to provide shelter for unlawfully present aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000632" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2023-05-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-02T15:25:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Schools Not Shelters Act

This bill prohibits schools that receive certain federal financial assistance from using their facilities to shelter certain non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) unless the individual pays for such shelter.

Specifically, this prohibition shall apply to sheltering individuals who are (1) unlawfully present, or (2) subject to removal proceedings or a removal order and are not being detained by the Department of Homeland Security.

Under this bill, if an elementary school, secondary school, or institution of higher education receives financial assistance from a program administered by the Department of Education, that school or institution may not use its facilities to provide shelter to such individuals unless the individual is housed in a dormitory and pays the amount normally assessed to residents of that dormitory.</summary>
</bill>
