<bill session="116" type="h" number="7683" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACCESS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to make projects that directly or indirectly increase the accessibility of affordable, quality child care eligible for certain grants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACCESS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Child Care for Economic Strategies and Success Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001088" joined="2020-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4383" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8326" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-29T18:44:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable Child Care for Economic Strategies and Success Act or the ACCESS Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Commerce to provide grants for public works and economic development projects that will directly or indirectly increase the accessibility of affordable, quality child care, including grants for planning, and training, research, and technical assistance related to such projects.

Commerce must issue regulations to establish criteria for whether a project directly or indirectly increases the accessibility of affordable, quality child care. Such criteria shall consider (1) the availability, validity, and accessibility of timely data, (2) the extent to which a project contributes to a family's financial security, and (3) the extent to which a project addresses child care needs in child care deserts or areas otherwise recognized as being in shortage. A child care desert is an area in which the number of children who are under age five is more than three times the number of slots provided by child care providers who are licensed or registered by the state involved, or a community that the state or tribal entity involved determines has a low supply of quality, affordable child care.

Commerce must also issue guidance on how to include the accessibility of affordable, quality child care in a comprehensive economic development strategy.</summary>
</bill>
