<bill session="117" type="s" number="5230" updated="2023-10-20T19:00:19Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Billy&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Help Find the Missing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Billy's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Help Find the Missing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Billy's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Billy&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Help Find the Missing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Help Find the Missing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Billy's Law</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Help Find the Missing Act</title>
    <title type="display">Billy's Law</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase accessibility to the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System, to facilitate data sharing between such system and the National Crime Information Center database of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7080-7081" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7080-7081" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12T14:12:05-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12T14:24:59-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:30:49-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Nadler moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:30:58-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9828-9831" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:31:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 5230.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T18:40:35-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T20:33:51-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9842" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="526" datetime="2022-12-14T20:44:57-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 422 - 4 (Roll no. 526).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9828-9829" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T20:44:58-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2022-12-27" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-327" type="public" datetime="2022-12-27">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-327.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5029" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9491" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-20T18:58:31Z" status="Passed House">Billy's Law or the Help Find the Missing Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Department of Justice (DOJ) to maintain the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs) consistent with its existing purpose and structure.

NamUs is a national information clearinghouse and resource center for cases involving missing persons and unidentified or unclaimed remains. NamUs is administered by the National Institute of Justice within DOJ.

The bill also establishes new requirements.

First, it requires a law enforcement agency that submits a missing child report to the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) to also submit the missing child report to NamUs. The NCIC is a computerized index of criminal justice data and files for reports of missing and unidentified persons. Current law requires law enforcement agencies to submit missing child reports to the NCIC database but not to the NamUs databases.

Second, the bill establishes requirements to facilitate data sharing between the NCIC database and the NamUs databases with respect to missing and unidentified persons.

Specifically, the bill requires DOJ to give the National Institute of Justice access to the NCIC missing person and unidentified person records for the purpose of validating cases and reconciling data with NamUs.

Additionally, the bill requires DOJ to assess the NCIC and NamUs systems and governing statutes, policies, and procedures and create a plan for NCIC to automatically transmit certain records to NamUs.

Third, the bill requires DOJ to report to forensic medicine service providers and law enforcement agencies on best practices for collecting, reporting, and analyzing data and information on missing persons and unidentified human remains.

DOJ must also report to Congress biennially on the status of the NCIC database and the NamUs databases. The report must describe the process of information sharing between the NCIC database and NamUs databases.</summary>
</bill>
