<bill session="118" type="h" number="9530" updated="2025-08-05T13:12:46Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COLUMBIA Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">College Oversight and Legal Updates Mandating Bias Investigations and Accountability Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COLUMBIA Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Education to establish a program to provide for antisemitism monitors at institutions of higher education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-05T13:12:34Z" status="Introduced in House">College Oversight and Legal Updates Mandating Bias Investigations and Accountability Act of 2024 or the COLUMBIA Act of 2024

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to establish a program to appoint third-party anti-Semitism monitors at certain institutions of higher education (IHEs). Specifically, ED must establish this program to appoint a monitor at an IHE that (1) has a high incidence of anti-Semitic activity (based on data received from ED's Office for Civil Rights), and (2) receives federal funds for higher education.&#160;

ED must develop an anti-Semitism monitorship agreement that (1) designates the terms and conditions of the monitorship, and (2) requires the&#160;IHE to provide for the monitor's reasonable expenses.&#160;

The bill requires the monitor to

operate under the monitorship agreement developed by ED and entered into with the IHE;&#160;provide publicly available quarterly reports that evaluate the IHE's progress in combating&#160;anti-Semitism on campus; andprovide annual reports to Congress, ED, state and local governments (as needed), and the IHE that include recommendations for actions, policies, and sanctions to prevent and reduce anti-Semitism at the IHE.</summary>
</bill>
