<bill session="118" type="s" number="3222" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to ensure the security of office space rented by Senators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure the security of office space rented by Senators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2023-11-02" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T17:57:09-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06T18:01:38-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18T17:28:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H229-230" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18T17:28:26-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Steil asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2024-01-18T17:28:44-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H229-230" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-01-18T17:28:46-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-01-24">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-01-26" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-36" type="public" datetime="2024-01-26">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-36.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2302" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-02T20:20:46Z" status="Public Law">This act establishes certain security-related exceptions to limitations on&#160;the size and cost of Senators' home state office space. (The size and cost limitations vary based on the population of the Senator's home state.)

The act specifies that any portion of home state office space that is used for building security or safety measures is not included in calculating the total amount of office space subject to applicable maximum size. The building safety and security measures must be (1) of a kind authorized by the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration and (2) approved by the&#160;Senate Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.

The act also specifies that an information technology security closet and a secure lobby or reception area are&#160;security or safety enhancements that are of a kind authorized by the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration.

The act also excludes the cost of building security and safety measures&#160;from the limitation on the cost of renting office space in the home state. Such costs must be (1) of a kind authorized by the Senate Committee on Rules and Administration, (2)&#160;approved by the Senate Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate,&#160;and (3)&#160;itemized separately in a manner approved by the Senate Sergeant at Arms and Doorkeeper of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
