<bill session="109" type="h" number="5627" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:48Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Steel Financing Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Overseas Private Investment Corporation from providing insurance or financing to countries that subsidize their steel industries and for projects producing goods subject to antidumping duties, to require the United States to oppose the provision by the International Monetary Fund of assistance to countries which subsidize their steel industries, and to ban assistance by the Export-Import Bank of the United States to countries that subsidize their steel industries.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Steel Financing Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2006-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1162-1163"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on International Relations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA19" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Investment guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-11T15:35:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Steel Financing Fairness Act - Prohibits the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) from providing insurance or financing for a project: (1) in any country that grants a subsidy to its steel industry until three months after such subsidy is eliminated; or (2) that produces, outside of the United States, any product subject to antidumping duties.

Amends the Bretton Woods Agreements Act to require the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) instruct the U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to oppose any assistance from the IMF to any foreign government that subsidizes its steel industry until three months after such subsidy is eliminated; and (2) reduce the U.S. contribution to the IMF if it provides assistance to any such government during such period.

Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the Export-Import Bank from guaranteeing, insuring, or extending credit for exports to any foreign government that subsidizes its steel industry until three months after such subsidy is eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
