<bill session="117" type="s" number="1303" updated="2023-08-03T16:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Build America, Buy America Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that certain Federal infrastructure programs require the use of materials produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build America, Buy America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Build America, Buy America Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-268.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="667">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 667.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2810" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5059" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-03T15:48:52Z" status="Reported to Senate">Build America, Buy America Act

This bill requires federal infrastructure programs to provide for the use of materials produced in the United States.

Each federal agency must submit to the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and to Congress a report that identifies each federal financial assistance program for infrastructure administered by the agency and (1) identify domestic content procurement preferences applicable to the assistance, (2) assess the applicability of such requirements, (3) provide details on any applicable domestic content procurement preference requirement, and (4) include a description of the type of infrastructure projects that receive funding under the program.

Each agency shall ensure that none of the funds made available for such a program may be used for a project unless all of the iron, steel, and manufactured products used in the project are produced in the United States, subject to waivers under specified circumstances.

The Department of Transportation must enter into a technical assistance partnership with the National Institute of Standards and Technology to ensure the development of a domestic supply base to support intermodal transportation in the United States.

The Office for Federal Procurement Policy shall promulgate final regulations or other policy or management guidance to standardize and simplify how federal agencies comply with, report on, and enforce the Buy American Act.

The OMB must establish a Made in America Office to undertake specified activities, including to maximize and enforce compliance with domestic preference statutes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-268</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
