<bill session="116" type="s" number="4969" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Fairness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Fairness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize funds to prevent housing discrimination through the use of nationwide testing, to increase funds for the Fair Housing Initiatives Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-24T15:16:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housing Fairness Act of 2020 

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 the Fair Housing Initiatives Program and revises program reporting requirements and organization eligibility requirements. The bill also allows the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to enter into agreements with certain organizations to test and investigate differential treatment and discriminatory housing practices based on race, color, sex, religion, national origin, disability, and familial status. The results of these tests and investigations may be used as the basis for an enforcement action under specified fair housing laws.

Additionally, HUD must establish a grant program for public and private nonprofit organizations to study housing discrimination and implement pilot projects to test solutions.</summary>
</bill>
