<bill session="117" type="h" number="7097" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:50Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">3T Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">3T Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telehealth Treatment and Technology Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the provision of telehealth services through interstate recognition of health care professionals' licenses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001104"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2022-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-06T19:37:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Telehealth Treatment and Technology Act of 2022 or the 3T Act of 2022

This bill allows a health care professional to provide, subject to scope of practice and other requirements, health services in any U.S. jurisdiction based on that individual's authorization to practice in any one state or territory.

Additionally, the bill provides certain related powers to health care professional regulatory bodies, such as medical boards. Specifically, a regulatory body may investigate and take disciplinary actions against a professional who provides services pursuant to this bill to a patient in that body's jurisdiction. The bill also requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to revise applicable privacy regulations to allow providers to use any nonpublic-facing communication product to provide telehealth services after the COVID-19 emergency ends. (Typically, communication products used to provide telehealth services must comply with federal privacy standards for personal health information. However, during the COVID-19 emergency HHS exercised enforcement discretion to allow for the use of noncompliant communication products, including applications such as Apple FaceTime, Zoom, or Skype.)</summary>
</bill>
