<bill session="116" type="h" number="7450" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prevent Harmful Algal Blooms Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to designate organizations as National Centers of Excellence in Harmful Algal Bloom Research, Prevention, Response, and Mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Harmful Algal Blooms Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2020-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2020-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2020-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2020-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2020-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8632" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="5056" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-12T20:30:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Harmful Algal Blooms Act

This bill directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to designate organizations as National Centers of Excellence in Harmful Algal Bloom Research, Prevention, Response, and Mitigation. An algal bloom is a rapid growth of algae that may create toxic or hypoxic (severely low-oxygen) conditions that are harmful to humans, animals, aquatic ecosystems, and the economy.

To be eligible for designation, an organization must

 be an institution of higher education, a government research agency, a nonprofit laboratory or other research entity, or a consortium of such institutions; have demonstrated expertise and success in harmful algal bloom research, monitoring, forecasting, prevention, or response efforts; have demonstrated ability to collaborate with local, state, territorial, and tribal governments and federal agencies on harmful algal blooms; and be located in an area that is economically and environmentally impacted by harmful algal blooms. In designating National Centers of Excellence, NOAA must (1) consult with the Inter-Agency Task Force on Harmful Algal Blooms and Hypoxia; (2) ensure regional balance by designating centers in a variety of locations throughout the United States, including the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, American Samoa, and other territories and possessions of the United States; and (3) avoid duplication of other harmful algal bloom research.

Each designation shall be effective for five years and reviewed by NOAA in the fourth year of such effective period. The designation may be renewed for an additional five-year period.</summary>
</bill>
