<bill session="117" type="h" number="579" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century Energy Workforce Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a pilot competitive grant program for the development of a skilled energy workforce, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Energy Workforce Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2021-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-01T14:52:40Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Energy Workforce Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a National Center for Excellence for the 21st Century Workforce Advisory Board to foster strategic vision, guidance, and networks for the energy industry.

 The purpose of the board is to (1) support and develop training and science education programs, (2) align apprenticeship programs and industry certifications to further develop succession planning in the energy sector, (3) integrate educational standards to develop foundational skills for elementary and secondary education and postsecondary education to create a pipeline between education and career, and (4) support the replication of existing model energy curricula.

 DOE shall also establish a pilot program to award grants to eligible entities for job training programs that lead to an industry-recognized credential.</summary>
</bill>
