<bill session="117" type="h" number="1529" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VOTER ID Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to conduct post-election audits for elections for Federal office and to provide attestations of the integrity and security of voter identification and voter registration list maintenance procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verification and Oversight for Transparent Elections, Registration, and Identifications Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VOTER ID Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000821"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2021-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2021-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-06T16:36:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Verification and Oversight for Transparent Elections, Registration, and Identifications Act or the VOTER ID Act

This bill requires states to conduct post-election audits of federal elections and attest to the integrity and security of voting procedures in those elections.

Specifically, states must conduct a post-election audit after each federal election. The audit must include the accuracy of voting systems used in the election and an assessment of state compliance with applicable election laws and procedures, including those governing the requirements for voter identification and use of mail-in voting.

The Election Assistance Commission (EAC) must develop best practices for conducting post-election audits, including recommendations to (1) conduct an audit using a bipartisan entity, and (2) complete an audit within 30 days after the state certifies the results of a congressional election.

Additionally, states must attest to the integrity and security of their voter identification procedures and maintenance of voter registration lists.

States must submit to the EAC, and make publicly available on their websites, these audit results and attestations.</summary>
</bill>
