<bill session="116" type="s" number="1808" updated="2022-11-01T07:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hack Your State Department Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hack Your State Department Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of State to design and establish a Vulnerability Disclosure Process to improve the Department of State cybersecurity and a bug bounty program to identify and report vulnerabilities of Internet-facing information technology of the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="328" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-06T14:56:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hack Your State Department Act

This bill requires the Department of State to design, establish, and make publicly known a Vulnerability Disclosure Process to improve cybersecurity. In establishing the process, the State Department must identify which information technology should be included, determine whether the process should differentiate among and specify the types of security vulnerabilities that may be targeted, and provide a readily available form and means of reporting, amongst other requirements.

The bill requires the State Department to establish a bug bounty pilot program, where an approved individual, organization, or company is temporarily authorized to identify and report vulnerabilities of internet-facing information technology of the State Department in exchange for compensation.</summary>
</bill>
