<bill session="111" type="h" number="3678" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:02Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 49, United States Code, to modify the authority of the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to issue regulations and security directives using emergency procedures.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to modify the authority of the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration) to issue regulations and security directives using emergency procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000689"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000716" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-06">
      <text>Provisions of measure incorporated into H.R. 2200 as an amendment during House consideration on and adopted by a recorded vote of 219 yeas and 211 noes (Roll Call Vote No. 304)..</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-18T15:25:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Revises the authority of the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]) to immediately issue, rescind, and revise regulations and security directives to protect transportation security during an emergency. Requires the Assistant Secretary to issue such emergency regulations and directives, instead, in cases of imminent threat of finite duration.

Declares that review of emergency regulations and directives by the Transportation Security Oversight Board (authorized by existing law) shall determine, specifically, if a regulation or security directive is needed to respond to an imminent threat of finite duration.

Revises factors the Assistant Secretary must consider in issuing, rescinding, or revising a regulation or security directive. Requires the Assistant Secretary to consider whether a regulation or security directive will remain in force for more than a 90-day period, and whether it will require revision in the subsequent 90-day period.

Authorizes the Assistant Secretary, if it is not feasible to make such an estimate, to waive requirements for an analysis of whether the estimated costs of such regulations and directives are excessive in contrast to the number of lives save by the regulations or directives.</summary>
</bill>
