<bill session="118" type="h" number="2463" updated="2025-11-19T03:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Junk Fee Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Junk Fee Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit and eliminate excessive, hidden, and unnecessary fees imposed on consumers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2024-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2024-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2023-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000585" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000308" joined="2023-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2024-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001223" joined="2024-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001223" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="916" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-06T11:44:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Junk Fee Prevention Act

This bill establishes requirements related to the fees charged by specified covered businesses, including those providing short-term lodging, ticketing services, internet service, mobile service, or video programming. It also requires air carriers to seat each young child next to an accompany adult during flights.

Specifically, businesses providing short-term lodging or ticketing services must display the total price (including mandatory fees) of the offered good or service in each advertisement and when the price is first shown to the consumer. Further, ticketing services must (1) disclose any guarantee or refund policy for an event before the transaction is completed, and (2) disclose when they do not possess the ticket for an event at the time of sale. The bill also prohibits excessive or deceptive mandatory fees and provides the Federal Trade Commission and state attorneys general authority to enforce these requirements.

Additionally, the bill prohibits internet service, mobile service, or video programming providers from charging excessive or unreasonable termination fees. The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) also must conduct a rulemaking to consider requiring such providers to disclose mandatory fees or prohibiting the services from imposing mandatory fees. The bill provides the FCC authority to enforce these requirements.

Finally, the bill establishes requirements for air carriers to seat each child who is age 13 or younger next to an accompanying adult, subject to limited exceptions. The bill also requires air carriers to provide specified alternatives or a full refund in the event that such seating is not available.</summary>
</bill>
