<bill session="118" type="s" number="1734" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SARFA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SARFA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing American Research from Foreign Adversaries Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the research security protocols of the Department of Energy for the purpose of preventing theft of government research by nationals of foreign countries of concern, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-27T17:56:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing American Research from Foreign Adversaries Act or the SARFA Act

This bill requires the Department of Energy to administer polygraphs to foreign nationals of countries of concern as a condition of their employment at or internal access to the department's national laboratories. Covered countries include China, North Korea, Russia, Iran, and any other country designated by the Department of State.

The bill also specifically applies provisions that require the department to assess the security risks of certain research activities, and that prohibit entities of concern from participating in these activities, to all programs and activities of the department, including the department's national laboratories.</summary>
</bill>
