<bill session="118" type="s" number="1743" updated="2025-11-19T02:58:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forest Data Modernization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Data Modernization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Research Act of 1978 to modify the forest inventory and analysis program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8467" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3990" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-15T15:46:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forest Data Modernization Act of 2023

This bill modifies the Forest Inventory and Analysis (FIA) program of the Forest Service.

Specifically, FIA must include forest carbon in its inventory. Further, FIA must carry out, as a data collection method, a timber products output study and a national woodland owner survey.

FIA must include a clear definition of forest when reporting data.

FIA's strategic plan must describe in detail the organization and procedures necessary to

 understand and report on changes in land cover and use, and evaluate carbon-related data variables. FIA must update the strategic plan not later than 180 days after this bill's enactment to include, among other things

 a plan to implement nationally consistent data collection protocols and procedures to improve the statistical precision of base program estimates; pathways to integrate and report on changes in forest carbon, including below-ground carbon; plans to collaborate with other federal agencies, nonfederal partners, and the private sector to integrate existing nationally available data sets and best available commercial technologies; and a plan to increase transparency and clarity in reporting. FIA (1) must establish an office, a data platform, or both to process and respond to complex data requests submitted by external organizations; and (2) may impose fees on the organizations submitting the requests.</summary>
</bill>
