<bill session="117" type="h" number="1061" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CABLE Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to preserve cable franchising authority, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CABLE Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Connecting And Building Lines for Expedited Expansion Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3435" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-07T17:05:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Connecting And Building Lines for Expedited Expansion Act or the CABLE Expansion Act

This bill modifies the requirements governing decisions about the placement, construction, or modification of a facility that provides cable service to subscribers using an easement or public right-of-way.

A franchise authority (i.e., a state or local entity that regulates certain aspects of cable operators) may not regulate the placement, construction, or modification of such facilities in a manner that effectively prohibits a cable operator from providing or enhancing its service under a franchise granted by the authority. Additionally, a franchise authority must approve or deny a complete request to place, construct, or modify a facility within specified time frames. The denial of a request must be in writing, supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record, and publicly released at the same time as the decision is made.</summary>
</bill>
