<bill session="117" type="h" number="5316" updated="2023-03-15T14:00:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent allocations of Special Drawing Rights at the International Monetary Fund for countries that are perpetrators of genocide or state sponsors of terrorism, and to prevent United States tax dollars from directly going to the Taliban or other terrorists or terrorist-harboring nations.</title>
    <title type="display">No Support for Terror Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Support for Terror Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2021-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2021-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-25T20:35:29Z" status="Introduced in House">No Support for Terror Act

This bill establishes measures to prevent the allocation or use of certain funds to support genocide or terrorism.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director at the International Monetary Fund (IMF) to oppose the allocation of Special Drawing Rights (a currency support tool) to any country that is a perpetrator of genocide or a state sponsor of terrorism and to advocate that the IMF adopt a rule prohibiting such allocation.

Further, the bill requires Treasury, the Department of State, and the U.S. Agency for International Development to jointly review and report on assistance provided to nongovernmental organizations and international organization to ensure such assistance is not being provided to the Taliban or other terrorist organizations. Each prime awardee of this assistance must provide evidence that all subawardees are complying with U.S. anti-terrorism financing laws.</summary>
</bill>
