<bill session="108" type="h" number="1350" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Education Results for Children With Disabilities Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Improving Education Results for Children With Disabilities Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Improving Education Results for Children With Disabilities Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report">Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000104" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001241" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001232" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000210" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000439" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000174" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000361" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000358" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000553" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000508" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2003-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000462" joined="2003-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2003-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E527"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Education Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 29 - 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 108-77.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-04-29" calendar="Union" number="44">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 44.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29T19:58:07-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 206 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1350 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order. Makes in order only those amendments printed in H. Rept. 108-79 and provides that they shall be considered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, considered as read, debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponen...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:50:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 206 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:51:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 206.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3466-3531" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:51:36-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1350 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. The rule waives all points of order against consideration of the bill and provides that the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Education and the Workforce now printed in the bill shall be considered as an original bill for the purpose of amendment and shall be considered as read. Makes in order only those amendments printed in H. Rept. 108-79 and provides that they shall be considered only in the order printed in the report, may be offered only by a Member designated in the report, considered as read, debatable for the time specified in the report equally divided and controlled by the proponent andan opponent, shall not be subject to amendment, not be subject toa...</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:51:53-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 206 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:51:55-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable John Linder to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T11:52:07-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 1350.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:06:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castle amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:22:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Vitter amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:22:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Vitter amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Vitter demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the rule, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:25:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bradley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:27:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Woolsey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:28:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the DeMint amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:53:45-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeMint amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded a recorded vote and made a point of no quorum. Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment and the point of no quorum was considered as withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T13:54:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Musgrave amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T14:07:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Musgrave amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T14:08:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Shadegg amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T14:24:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to provisions of H. Res. 206 the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tancredo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T14:35:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tancredo amendment, the Chair put the question on the adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Woolsey demanded a recorded vote and pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T14:35:48-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:23:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kirk amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:30:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McKeon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:39:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nethercutt amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:47:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davis (CA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:56:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wu amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T15:58:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 206, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett (NJ) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T16:01:54-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 1350.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T16:02:45-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T16:02:56-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3480-3510" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="154" datetime="2003-04-30T16:24:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 251 - 171 (Roll no. 154).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T16:24:13-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-30T16:24:14-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 1350.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Senate Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5411" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.1248 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="94" datetime="2004-05-13" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate H.R. 1350 in lieu of S.1248 with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 95 - 3. Record Vote Number: 94.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5411-5451" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-21">
      <text>Senate ordered measure printed as passed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:20-04:00">
      <text>Mr. McKeon asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9020" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:41-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Education and the Workforce for consideration of the House bill and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Boehner, Castle, Ehlers, Keller, Wilson (SC), Miller, George, Woolsey, and Owens.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:42-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Energy and Commerce for consideration of sec. 101 and title V of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Barton (TX), Bilirakis, and Dingell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:57-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on the Judiciary for consideration of sec. 205 of the House bill, and sec. 101 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Sensenbrenner, Smith (TX), and Conyers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08T22:52:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-09">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, agrees to request for a conference, appoints conferees Gregg; Frist; Enzi; Alexander; Bond; DeWine; Roberts; Sessions; Ensign; Graham SC; Warner; Kennedy; Dodd; Harkin; Mikulski; Jeffords; Bingaman; Murray; Reed; Edwards; Clinton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T17:12:58-05:00">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17">
      <text>Mr. Boehner asked unanimous consent that managers on the part of the House have until midnight on Nov. 17 to file a conference report on H.R. 1350. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-17T19:37:59-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-779 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9895-9959" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-18T22:14:08-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 858 Reported to House. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T10:14:58-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 858 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T10:15:29-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Boehner brought up conference report H. Rept. 108-779 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 858.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10010-10022" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T10:15:38-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 1350.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T11:25:01-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10021" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="537" datetime="2004-11-19T11:46:17-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE">
      <text>Conference report agreed to in House: On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 397 - 3 (Roll no. 537).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T11:46:17-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="537" datetime="2004-11-19T11:46:17-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 397 - 3 (Roll no. 537).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="conference" datetime="2004-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Unanimous Consent Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11653-11660" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19T20:23:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Con. Res. 524, enrollment corrections on H.R. 1350 have been made.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-11-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-03" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-446" type="public" datetime="2004-12-03">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-446.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1248" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hc" number="524" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="206" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="858" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Attention deficit disorders"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child development"/>
    <term name="Class size"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational planning"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic mail systems"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian children"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Occupational therapy"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Physical therapy"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Problem children"/>
    <term name="Reading"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="School discipline"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="School security"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Self-help devices for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h99"/>
    <amendment number="h98"/>
    <amendment number="h97"/>
    <amendment number="h96"/>
    <amendment number="h95"/>
    <amendment number="h94"/>
    <amendment number="h93"/>
    <amendment number="h92"/>
    <amendment number="h91"/>
    <amendment number="h90"/>
    <amendment number="h89"/>
    <amendment number="h88"/>
    <amendment number="h87"/>
    <amendment number="h100"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed House amended">Improving Education Results for Children With Disabilities Act of 2003 - Amends the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA) to revise its programs and to reauthorize appropriations permanently for its part B programs and through FY 2009 for its other programs.Title I: General Provisions - (Sec. 101) Revises definitions. Requires a free appropriate public education to be reasonably calculated to provide educational benefit to enable the child with a disability to access the general curriculum. Provides that the term highly qualified, as it relates to teachers, has the same meaning as under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (ESEA), as amended by the No Child Left Behind Act of 2001 (NCLBA).(Sec. 102) Revises requirements relating to employment of qualified individuals with disabilities in IDEA programs to emphasize employment as teachers, related services personnel, early intervention providers, and administrators.Revises requirements for prescribing regulations, including policy letters, statements, and correspondence. Limits the Secretary of Education's authority to prescribe regulations to those that are reasonably necessary to ensure compliance with specific requirements of IDEA. Reduces the minimum required public comment period for part B or C regulations from 90 to 60 days.(Sec. 103) Requires States receiving IDEA funds to: (1) ensure that relevant State rules, regulations, and policies conform to IDEA purposes, as well as support and facilitate local educational agency (LEA) and school-level systemic reform designed to enable children with disabilities to meet challenging State student academic achievement standards; and (2) minimize the number of rules, regulations, and policies to which LEAs and schools are subject under IDEA.(Sec. 104) Directs the Comptroller General (GAO Review) to review and report on IDEA-related matters concerning: (1) Federal, State, and local paperwork requirements, with recommendations to reduce or eliminate excessive paperwork burdens; (2) biennially on disability definitions and evaluation processes, including variations among States and conformance with scientific, peer-reviewed research; (3) distance learning professional development programs for special education personnel; and (4) services for limited English proficient children with disabilities.Title II: Assistance for Education of All Children With Disabilities - Amends IDEA part B to revise requirements and permanently reauthorize funds for assistance for education of all children with disabilities (programs for those aged three through five and those aged six through 21).(Sec. 201) Reauthorizes appropriations for part B programs in specified amounts for FY 2004 through 2010 and in necessary amounts for FY 2011 and each subsequent fiscal year. (Thus providing for permanent authorization of funds for part B of IDEA.)Revises requirements for grants for States, outlying areas, and Indian schools.Increases the part B set-aside funding cap to $7,500,000.Sets the maximum amount which a State may use for cost or risk sharing funds, consortia, or cooperatives to assist LEAs in providing high cost special education and related services at 40 percent of the funds the State may retain for administration and other State-level activities.Requires States to allocate increases in their IDEA funding above FY 2003 levels to LEAs, with specified exceptions.(Sec. 202) Revises State eligibility requirements. Requires a State to reasonably demonstrate to the Secretary (currently, demonstrate to the satisfaction of the Secretary) that it has in effect policies and procedures to ensure that it meets certain conditions. Conforms IDEA with NCLBA requirements relating to State personnel standards, performance goals and indicators, and LEA permitted uses of funds for additional expenses for providing supplemental educational services for children with disabilities who are being educated in a school identified for school improvement.Revises requirements relating to children with disabilities in private schools. Requires completion of the child find process for children in private schools in a time period comparable to that for public school students. Prohibits reimbursement from being reduced or denied to parents of children with disabilities in private schools on the basis of their noncompliance with a specified notice requirement if: (1) the school prevented the parent from providing a required notice, (2) the parents had not received notice from the LEA; (3) compliance would likely result in physical harm to the child; or (4) in the discretion of a court or a hearing officer, if the parent is illiterate or cannot write in English or compliance would likely result in serious emotional harm to the child.Requires for State eligibility for IDEA: (1) State adoption of a national instructional materials accessibility standard in providing such materials to blind persons or other persons with print disabilities and a State purchase requirement for publishers of instructional materials to prepare and supply electronic files with such materials' contents using such standard; (2) State policies and procedures to prevent overidentification or disproportionate representation by race and ethnicity of children as children with disabilities, including identification of children as children with a particular impairment; and (3) State educational agency (SEA) development and implementation of policies and procedures prohibiting school personnel from requiring a child, as a condition of attending school or receiving services, to obtain a prescription for a controlled substance in schedule II under specified requirements of the Controlled Substances Act (thus prohibiting school personnel from coercing children to receive, or their parents to administer, psychotropic medication).(Sec. 203) Revises LEA eligibility requirements for part B assistance, including a reasonable demonstration to the State (rather than a demonstration to the satisfaction of the State) that LEA policies, procedures, and programs are consistent with State policies and procedures. Revises requirements for supplementing and not supplanting other special education funds, and for maintenance of effort. Requires (currently permits) an SEA, if authorized by State law and if it determines that an LEA is unable to establish and maintain programs of free appropriate public education, to prohibit the LEA from counting a portion of the increase in its IDEA grants from one year to the next as meeting such requirements. Allows other LEAs to use their own increased IDEA funds for ESEA programs.Requires LEAs to: (1) serve children with disabilities attending public charter schools in the same manner as they do in their other public schools, including providing supplemental and related services on site if they have such a policy or practice; and (2) provide part B funds to public charter schools on the same basis as they do to their other public schools (including, at LEA option, proportional distribution based on relative enrollment of children with disabilities) and at the same time as they distribute other Federal funds to those schools, consistent with the State's charter law.Includes among permissible uses of part B funds by LEAs: (1) prereferral educational support services; (2) cost or risk sharing funds, consortia, or cooperatives to assist them in providing high cost special education and related services; (3) case management and administration technology; and (4) supplemental educational services for children with disabilities in schools designated for improvement. Allows LEAs to use up to 15 percent of a part B grant for prereferral educational support services for students who have not been identified as needing special education or related services but who need additional academic and behavioral support to succeed in a general education environment. Provides for such services from kindergarten to 12th grade, with emphasis on kindergarten through third grade.(Sec. 204) Revises requirements for evaluations, assessments, and Individualized Education Programs (IEPs), and educational placements.Allows LEAs to pursue an initial evaluation if the parent does not provide consent or respond to an LEA request for such consent. Provides that, if the parent does not provide consent for IDEA services or fails to respond to an LEA request for such consent, the LEA shall not: (1) provide special education and related services to the child through specified procedures; (2) be obligated to hold an IEP meeting or prepare an IEP; or (3) be considered to be in violation of any part B requirement (including the requirement to make available a free appropriate public education).Revise requirements for IEPs to eliminate, as of the beginning of the 2005-2006 school year, a requirement for benchmarks and short-term objectives. Limits certain IEP information to what is specifically required. Allows regular education teachers to be excused from attendance at IEP team meetings under certain circumstances. Allows the parents and the LEA to agree to: (1) excuse any IEP team member from attending a meeting when such member's attendance is not necessary; (2) not reconvene the IEP team and instead develop a written document to amend or modify the current IEP; and (3) use alternate means of meeting participation, such as video conference and conference calls. Authorizes LEAs to offer parents the option of developing a comprehensive multi-year IEP, of not more than three years, designed to cover natural transition points for the child.Requires an LEA to ensure that certain assessments of a child are provided and administered in the language and form most likely to yield accurate academic and developmental data, unless it is clearly not feasible to do so. (Current law requires that this be done to the extent practicable).Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) students who have not been diagnosed by a physician or other person certified by a State health board as having a disability (as defined under IDEA) should not be classified as children with disabilities for purposes of receiving services under IDEA; and (2) students with behavioral problems who have not been diagnosed by a physician or other person certified by a State health board as having a disability should be subject to the regular school disciplinary code.(Sec. 205) Revises requirements for procedural safeguards, including those for notices.Establishes a statute of limitations on complaints, allowing a complaint only with respect to violations that occurred within one year before the complaint's filing.Requires mediation procedures to be available for matters arising prior to, as well as after, the filing of a complaint. Requires alternative voluntary binding arbitration procedures to be available when a due process hearing is requested.Allows due process hearings to be requested by either parents or LEAs (currently by the parents only). Requires such hearings to be conducted by the SEA. (Currently the SEA or the LEA, as State law provides, may conduct such a hearing, with a right of appeal to the SEA if the LEA conducts it.) Requires the LEA, prior to the due process hearing, to convene a resolution session, meeting with the parents and a team of qualified professionals, to which certain procedural safeguards would not apply. Prohibits, unless both parties agree otherwise, allowing any party to raise issues at the due process hearing that were not raised in the complaint, discussed in the resolution session meeting, or properly disclosed under requirements for evaluations and recommendations.Directs the State Governor or other appropriate State official to set, and publish annually, the attorneys' fees that may be awarded in actions or proceedings under IDEA (currently such fees are set by the court that hears the case).Authorizes school personnel to change the placement of a child with a disability who violates a code of student conduct to an appropriate interim alternative educational setting selected so as to enable the child to continue to participate in the general education curriculum and to progress toward IEP goals. Allows such change for: (1) not more than 45 school days, to the extent such alternative and such duration would be applied to children without disabilities, and with authorized discretion to include consideration of unique circumstances on a case-by-case basis; or (2) more than 45 days, if required by State law or regulation for the violation in question, to ensure the safety and appropriate educational atmosphere in the schools. Eliminates requirements: (1) requiring a determination be made concerning whether a child's action was a manifestation of the child's disability; and (2) if the child's behavior was not a manifestation of such disability, allowing application to that child of relevant disciplinary procedures applicable to children without disabilities in the same manner in which they would be applied to such children, but with no cessation of educational services to the child with disabilities.(Sec. 206) Adds requirements for monitoring and enforcement to requirements for withholding and judicial review. Sets forth requirements for Federal monitoring, including required indicators for States' progress on improving educational results for children with disabilities, permitted indicators and priorities for part B and for part C, setting of additional priorities, standards for compliance, and penalties for noncompliance.(Sec. 207) Authorizes the Secretary to carry out a demonstration program of granting waivers of IDEA paperwork requirements for up to four years for up to ten States, based on State proposals for addressing reduction of paperwork and non-instructional time spent fulfilling statutory and regulatory requirements. Requires the annual report of the Department of Education to Congress to include information on the efficacy and promise of such waivers.Directs the Secretary to publish and disseminate to States, LEAs, and parent training and information centers model forms for IEPs, procedural safeguards notices, and prior written notices.(Sec. 208) Revises requirements for State program information to include data: (1) by race, ethnicity, and disability category, in information on the number of children with disabilities who are subject to long-term suspensions or expulsions; and (2) on disproportionality with regard to the incidence, duration, and type of disciplinary actions, including suspensions and expulsions, in information on whether significant disproportionality based on race is occurring with regard to identification and placement.(Sec. 209) Reauthorizes appropriations in a specified amount for FY 2004 and in necessary amounts for each subsequent fiscal year for the part B preschool grants program for special education and related services for preschool children with disabilities. (Thus provides for permanent authorization of funds for such program.)Title III: Infants and Toddlers With Disabilities - Amends IDEA part C to revise requirements, and reauthorize funds through FY 2009, for programs for infants and toddlers with disabilities (from birth through age two).(Sec. 301) Includes certain children with disabilities ages three to five in the definition of an infant or toddler with a disability.Provides that the parents and the individualized family service plan team may determine the most appropriate setting for early intervention services for an infant or toddler.(Sec. 302) Reauthorizes appropriations for part C programs in a specified amount for FY 2004 and necessary amounts for FY 2005 through 2009.Title IV: National Activities to Improve Education of Children with Disabilities - Amends IDEA part D to revise and reauthorize requirements for national activities to improve the education of children with disabilities.(Sec. 401) Revises subpart 1 as State professional development grants. Authorizes the Secretary, in making such grants, to give priority to applications: (1) on the basis of need; and (2) that provide for establishing professional development programs regarding methods of early and appropriate identification of children with disabilities. Requires that at least 90 percent of such grant funds be used for specified professional development activities. Allows up to ten percent to be used for certain State activities. Reauthorizes appropriations for subpart 1 in a specified amount for FY 2004 and necessary amounts for FY 2005 through 2009.Revises subpart 2 requirements for scientifically-based research, technical assistance, model demonstration programs, and personnel preparation programs.Establishes a National Center for Special Education Research to conduct research on improving special education and related services for children with disabilities. Places the Center in the Institute of Education Sciences, with the Center's Commissioner to be appointed by the Institute's Director. Authorizes the Institute's Director to make competitive grants for research to improve educational results for children with disabilities. Requires the Center to propose and implement a research plan.Revises personnel preparation programs with respect to activities for: (1) regular and special education teachers, related services personnel, and early intervention services; (2) teachers of children with low-incidence disabilities; and (3) leadership preparation. Includes among personnel preparation programs training for: (1) school safety personnel and first responders working at qualified educational facilities; and (2) service providers for children with low-incidence disabilities with limited English proficiency.Reauthorizes appropriations for certain subpart 2 programs in specified amounts for FY 2004 and necessary amounts for FY 2005 through 2009.Reauthorizes appropriations, in specified amounts for FY 2004 and necessary amounts for FY 2005 through 2009, for: (1) grant, contract, and technical assistance for parent training and information centers and community parent resource centers; and (2) grants and contracts with eligible entities to support technology development, demonstration, and implementation, and media services. (Transfers such requirements to a new subpart 3, Supports to Improve Results for Children with Disabilities.)Title V: Miscellaneous Provisions - (Sec. 501) Expresses the sense of Congress that safe and drug-free schools are essential for the learning and development of children with disabilities.(Sec. 502) Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on costs to States to comply with the requirements of IDEA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-779</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-77</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
