<bill session="118" type="s" number="662" updated="2025-11-19T03:29:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STEM RESTART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM RESTART Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM Restoring Employment Skills through Targeted Assistance, Re-entry, and Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to create a new national program to support mid-career workers, including workers from underrepresented populations, in reentering the STEM workforce, by providing funding to small- and medium-sized STEM businesses so the businesses can offer paid internships or other returnships that lead to positions above entry level.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1403" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-03T14:04:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">STEM Restoring Employment Skills through Targeted Assistance, Re-entry, and Training Act or the STEM RESTART Act

This bill establishes a new national program to support mid-career workers, including workers from underrepresented or rural populations, in reentering or transitioning to the STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics) workforce by awarding grants to certain small- and medium-sized businesses to assist such workers in reentering or transitioning to the workforce at positions above entry level.</summary>
</bill>
