<bill session="117" type="hr" number="681" updated="2022-12-31T05:35:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the ongoing crackdown on freedom of expression and human rights in Belarus a year after the 2020 election, calling for an end to Alyaksandr Lukashenka's continued campaign of repression against peaceful protesters, journalists, cultural workers, human rights defenders, trade union activists, political activists, and government critics, and expressing solidarity with the Belarusian people.</title>
    <title type="display">Recognizing the ongoing crackdown on freedom of expression and human rights in Belarus a year after the 2020 election, calling for an end to Alyaksandr Lukashenka's continued campaign of repression against peaceful protesters, journalists, cultural workers, human rights defenders, trade union activists, political activists, and government critics, and expressing solidarity with the Belarusian people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2021-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2021-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2021-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2021-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Europe, Energy, the Environment and Cyber.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA14" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Europe" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T12:10:12Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution condemns Belarusian authorities' assault on freedom of expression and human rights in Belarus since the August 2020 presidential election.

The resolution also calls for the immediate release of journalists, cultural figures, and dissidents currently held as political prisoners in Belarus.

Furthermore, the resolution calls on the Biden Administration to

 support initiatives to assist survivors of torture and other human rights violations from Belarus, including by working with allies in the region to grant them protection and providing avenues for them and their families to access safety in the United States; examine all available accountability options for violators of human rights and fundamental freedoms; and demand that Belarus cooperate fully with international partners and organizations, including the United Nations High Commissioner for Human Rights. Finally, the resolution supports the aspirations of the Belarusian people in their struggle for freedom and human rights.</summary>
</bill>
