<bill session="118" type="s" number="2365" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SNAP Next Step Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Next Step Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to authorize funds for certain employment and training activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-06T15:21:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SNAP Next Step Act of 2023

This bill allows a state agency to use Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) administrative funding for certain&#160;Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (WIOA) programs.

Specifically, a state agency may recruit eligible SNAP participants for, and carry out employment and training activities under, WIOA programs. Participants must (1) be in a household that is receiving SNAP assistance, (2) meet SNAP participation requirements (e.g., work requirements)&#160;or be exempt from those requirements, (3) be unemployed or underemployed, (4) be in a family that is not receiving assistance under a Temporary Assistance for Needy Families (TANF) block grant, and (5) not be enrolled in a&#160;state program that is identified as an Employment First program by a state workforce agency.&#160;

Further, a state agency may develop a publicly available employment calculator for the state agency's website to assist SNAP recipients in calculating whether the amount of benefits received would be greater or lesser than income from future employment. Developing the calculator must be considered an administrative cost, which is shared by a state agency and the Department of Agriculture.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
