<bill session="110" type="h" number="2423" updated="2023-01-11T16:03:24Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ballast Water Management Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the management and treatment of ballast water to prevent the introduction of nonindigenous aquatic species into coastal and inland waters of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ballast Water Management Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000180" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2007-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2007-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="1578" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Aquatic pests"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sediment control"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-24T17:00:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Ballast Water Management Act of 2007 - Amends the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to direct the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue regulations to prevent the introduction and spread of nonindigenous aquatic species in waters of the United States (under current law, of aquatic nuisance species into the Great Lakes).

Directs the Secretary to: (1) issue regulations to establish national ballast water discharge standards that limit the number of living organisms contained in ballast water discharged from vessels into waters of the United States; and (2) determine whether one or more alternative ballast water management methods are available to achieve those standards.

 Requires vessel operators to conduct all ballast water management operations in accordance with a ballast water management plan designed to minimize the discharge of aquatic nuisance species.

Regulates ballast tank sediment management.

Removes provisions allowing, except in the Great Lakes, a vessel to exchange ballast water in a harbor if it has, because of safety, not done so at sea.

Replaces a ballast water management demonstration program with a shipboard technology evaluation and demonstration program to evaluate alternative ballast water management methods aboard vessels to prevent aquatic nuisance species from being introduced into and spread through discharges of ballast water in waters of the United States.

Requires a program to demonstrate and verify technologies and practices to monitor and control the introduction of aquatic invasive species by ship pathways other than the release of ballast water.</summary>
</bill>
