<bill session="117" type="h" number="8741" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Firearm Industry Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firearm Industry Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on the total revenue of manufacturers and importers of semi-automatic assault weapons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-08-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-30T20:01:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Firearm Industry Fairness Act 

This bill imposes a 20% surtax on the total revenue of each semi-automatic assault weapon manufacturer or importer. The bill defines semi-automatic assault weapon to include a semiautomatic rifle that has a fixed ammunition feeding device with the capacity to accept more than 15 rounds, semiautomatic pistols and shotguns, and other identified assault weapons.

The bill establishes the Community Violence Intervention and Prevention Trust Fund to hold tax revenues generated by this bill to carry out the Bureau of Justice Assistance Community Violence Intervention and Prevention Initiative to prevent and reduce violent crime in communities.</summary>
</bill>
