<bill session="117" type="h" number="7508" updated="2022-12-29T23:03:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Specialty Care for Women Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Specialty Care for Women Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a program for the recruitment, retention, and training of providers of specialty care for women veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-20T22:15:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Specialty Care for Women Veterans Act

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a program for the recruitment, retention, and training of specialty care providers for former members of the Armed Forces who are women. Individuals serving in a medical internship or residency program or nurses and physicians who are covered providers (i.e., employees of the VA or persons providing care under the Veterans Community Care Program) may participate in the program.

The VA may target individuals with expertise in certain specialty care areas for recruitment. Additionally, the VA may offer targeted individuals appropriate incentives (e.g., monetary incentives).

The VA must provide individuals participating in the program with training and support related to the unique needs of women veterans.

Finally, the VA must (1) provide veterans enrolled in the VA health care system with information that indicates whether a provider has participated in the program, and (2) improve the timeliness of appointments scheduled with such providers.</summary>
</bill>
