<bill session="118" type="h" number="5208" updated="2025-08-27T13:06:18Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Care Provider Shortage Minimization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Provider Shortage Minimization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to clarify the treatment of locum tenens physicians and advanced care practitioners as independent contractors to help alleviate physician shortages, including in underserved areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2024-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2024-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2024-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2023-08-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2024-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2024-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2024-07-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-27T12:26:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Care Provider Shortage Minimization Act of 2023

This bill provides statutory authority to classify qualified locum tenens physicians and advanced care practitioners as independent contractors for federal tax purposes. (Locum tenens generally refers to an individual who temporarily fulfills the duties of another individual and is commonly used to refer to temporary staffing in the healthcare industry.)

Under current law, independent contractors are considered self-employed for federal tax purposes and, thus, are required to make quarterly estimated income tax payments and pay self-employment taxes (Social Security and Medicare taxes). (Other federal tax reporting requirements and obligations apply.)

The bill defines a qualified locum tenens physician or advanced care practitioner as an individual who provides temporary services for not more than one continuous year at a site of service as (1) a doctor of medicine, osteopathy, dentistry, optometry, or podiatry (authorized to provide such services by the state, U.S. possession, or U.S. territory in which such services are performed); or (2) a nurse practitioner, physician&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s assistant, or certified registered nurse anesthetist. The term also includes an individual who provides such temporary services and is otherwise considered a physician under the Social Security Act (e.g., certain chiropractors).</summary>
</bill>
