<bill session="116" type="h" number="6196" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:05Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trademark Act of 1946 to provide for third-party submission of evidence relating to a trademark application, to establish expungement and ex parte proceedings relating to the validity of marks, to provide for a rebuttal presumption of irreparable harm in certain proceedings, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">TM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Trademark Modernization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TM Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trademark Modernization Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001093" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000610" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000020" joined="2020-11-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000591" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2020-11-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 116-645.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-14" calendar="Union" number="530">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 530.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3449" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-23T14:39:17Z" status="Reported to House">Trademark Modernization Act of 2020 or the TM Act of 2020

This bill makes several changes to trademark law, such as by providing new mechanisms for opposing and canceling trademark registrations at the Patent and Trademark Office (PTO) and by making it easier to secure an injunction.

The bill authorizes a third party to submit evidence to the PTO to oppose an application for a federal trademark registration.

The bill establishes a procedure for any party to petition the PTO to expunge a registration for a trademark that has not been used in commerce. The bill also establishes a procedure for any party to petition the PTO to reexamine any trademark registration on such nonuse grounds.

The PTO may also initiate such an expungement or reexamination proceeding.

If a plaintiff has prevailed in court in asserting certain trademark rights, that plaintiff shall be entitled to a presumption that the plaintiff will suffer irreparable harm for purposes of determining whether the plaintiff is entitled to a permanent injunction. If a trademark plaintiff is seeking a preliminary injunction, that plaintiff is entitled to this presumption upon a court finding that the plaintiff is likely to succeed on the merits of the case. Under current law, a plaintiff must establish irreparable harm to secure an injunction.

In addition, the PTO Director shall have the authority to reconsider, modify, or set aside certain decisions made by the Trademark Trial and Appeal Board.

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress on PTO efforts to address false and inaccurate claims in trademark registrations and applications.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-645</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
