<bill session="117" type="h" number="5250" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend the commitment of the United States to the International Space Station, to develop advanced space suits, and to authorize a stepping stone approach to exploration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000587"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2021-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Space and Aeronautics.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY16" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Space and Aeronautics" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1756" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="International scientific cooperation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Space flight and exploration"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-21T14:04:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Human Spaceflight Act of 2021

This bill establishes programs and policies pertaining to human presence in space.

The National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) shall

 establish a program to develop next-generation space suits and associated technologies, establish an outpost in orbit around the Moon as described in this bill, and submit a plan for achieving a power supply on the Moon. The bill declares that it is U.S. policy to continuously maintain the capability for a continuous human presence in low-Earth orbit through and beyond the useful life of the International Space Station (ISS) and that such capability shall

 maintain U.S. global leadership and relations with partners and allies, contribute to the general welfare of the United States, and leverage commercial capabilities to promote affordability so as not to preclude a robust portfolio of other human space exploration activities. NASA shall ensure that the ISS remains a viable and productive facility capable of potential U.S. use through at least FY2030.

NASA must submit a strategy that includes how it will transition to a successor platform to the ISS.

The Office of Science and Technology Policy shall conduct a study on the manner in which NASA funds missions of national need.</summary>
</bill>
