<bill session="111" type="s" number="721" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand the Alpine Lakes Wilderness in the State of Washington, to designate the Middle Fork Snoqualmie River and Pratt River as wild and scenic rivers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and  Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection  Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3920" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-223.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-132.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="282">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 282.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1769" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-19T14:52:45Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions and Pratt and Middle Fork Snoqualmie Rivers Protection Act - Designates as wilderness and as a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System and considers as part of the Alpine Lakes Wilderness certain federal land in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest in the state of Washington that is within the proposed Alpine Lakes Wilderness Additions Boundary.

Makes any land or interests within the proposed boundary acquired by the United States part of the Wilderness.

Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the Middle Fork Snoqualmie and Pratt Rivers in the state of Washington as scenic and/or wild rivers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-132</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
