<bill session="117" type="s" number="3252" updated="2022-12-30T02:48:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Surpassing Temporary Obstructions at Ports and Guaranteeing Resources to Increase the Nation's Commercial Health Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP the GRINCH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Surpassing Temporary Obstructions at Ports and Guaranteeing Resources to Increase the Nation's Commercial Health Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the supply chain backlog in the freight network at United States ports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6028" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3807" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7456" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-30T20:45:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Surpassing Temporary Obstructions at Ports and Guaranteeing Resources to Increase the Nation's Commercial Health Act or the STOP the GRINCH Act

This bill temporarily waives various requirements and makes other changes to address congestion at U.S. ports.

The Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) must waive the hours of service limits (i.e., the number of hours a driver may operate a truck or motor carrier in a set period of time) and minimum age requirements that apply to commercial driver's licenses for individuals transporting cargo directly to or from a U.S. port.

Additionally, the Coast Guard may temporarily allow foreign-built, -owned, and -crewed vessels to transport cargo between U.S. ports and engage in certain ship-to-ship transfers of cargo. (Current coastwise law, commonly known as the Jones Act, generally requires that vessels transporting cargo domestically be U.S.-built, -owned, and -crewed.)

The FMCSA and the Coast Guard must also prioritize the completion of security screenings and credentialing of maritime workers.

The Department of Defense must (1) inventory its intermodal equipment (e.g., trailers and chassis used to transport shipping containers) to identify equipment available for loan to trucking companies to relieve congestion at U.S. ports, and (2) establish a process to allow trucking companies to request the loan of such equipment.

The bill also requires the identification and designation of federal land located near U.S. ports for use as overflow areas for empty cargo containers.</summary>
</bill>
