<bill session="117" type="s" number="4371" updated="2023-01-21T05:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">C&#195;&#169;sar E. Ch&#195;&#161;vez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">C&#195;&#169;sar E. Ch&#195;&#161;vez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Cesar E. Chavez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park in the States of California and Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2895-2896" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8046" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-02T19:12:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park Act

This bill establishes, as a unit of the National Park System, the C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez and the Farmworker Movement National Historical Park in California and Arizona. It also establishes the Farmworker Peregrinaci&#243;n National Historic Trail in California.

The boundary of the historical park shall include

 The Forty Acres in Delano, California; the C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez National Monument, including Nuestra Se&#241;ora Reina de la Paz, in Keene, California; and the Santa Rita Center in Phoenix, Arizona. The Department of the Interior may acquire land and interests in land that are within the boundary of the park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or exchange.

 The C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez National Monument shall continue to be administered as a distinct and identifiable unit of the National Park System.

Interior may provide public interpretation of historic sites, museums, and resources on land not administered by Interior related to the life of C&#233;sar E. Ch&#225;vez and the history of the farmworker movement.

Interior must prepare a general management plan for the park.

The Farmworker Peregrinaci&#243;n National Historic Trail is added to the National Trails System.

The federal government shall not acquire for the trail any land or interest in land outside the exterior boundary of any federally managed area without the owner's consent.</summary>
</bill>
