<bill session="119" type="s" number="719" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Forest Protection Act Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Forest Protection Act Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Tribal Forest Protection Act Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tribal Forest Protection Act of 2004 to improve that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2025-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 119-23.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-05-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="76">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 76.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-23T16:10:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Forest Protection Act Amendments Act of 2025

This bill reauthorizes through FY2031 the Tribal Forest Protection Act (TFPA) and expands the lands and activities eligible for inclusion in the TFPA.

Currently under the TFPA, the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA) may enter into contracts and agreements with Indian tribes for tribes to carry out land management projects on federal lands. These projects are designed to protect Indian forest lands and rangelands from wildfire, disease, and other threats coming from federal lands. However, the&#160;TFPA is currently limited to projects on federal lands that border or are adjacent to Indian forest lands and rangelands under the jurisdiction of the tribe.

This bill removes certain limitations of the TFPA, first by expanding the definition of Indian forest land or rangeland to include land in Alaska&#160;that is held by Alaska Native corporations, thereby allowing these corporations to participate in TFPA projects.

Additionally, the bill removes the requirement that&#160;TFPA projects must occur on federal lands that border or are adjacent to Indian forest lands or rangelands. The bill instead requires the federal land involved&#160;to have a special geographic, historical, or cultural significance to the tribe.

The bill allows TFPA projects to be carried out directly on Indian forest lands and rangelands. (Currently, the TFPA only applies to work conducted on federal lands and not on tribal&#160;lands.)

The bill also updates a requirement for Interior and USDA to report to Congress on TFPA activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-23</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
