<bill session="118" type="s" number="1950" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Temporary Emergency Scheduling and Testing of Fentanyl Analogues Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the temporary order for fentanyl-related substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2024-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2024-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2024-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-24T19:39:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Temporary Emergency Scheduling and Testing of Fentanyl Analogues Act of 2023 or the TEST Act&#160;

This bill provides for the rescheduling or removal from scheduling of certain fentanyl-related substances under the Controlled Substances Act.

Specifically, the bill requires the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) to schedule, reschedule, or remove from scheduling fentanyl-related substances it has identified but not yet permanently scheduled within one year of the bill's enactment. The DEA must schedule, reschedule, or remove from scheduling any new fentanyl-related substances that it identifies after the bill's enactment within three years of identification. The DEA may temporarily schedule newly identified fentanyl-related substances under schedule I for up to three years.&#160; The bill provides for the rescheduling of fentanyl-related substances to lower schedules, or for their removal from scheduling altogether, based on appropriate scientific and medical evaluations from the Department of Health and Human Services.&#160;

The bill also provides for expedited registrations to research schedule I controlled substances, including by allowing for the continuation and consolidation of research under a single registration.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
