<bill session="116" type="h" number="5475" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:16Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROSPECT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish competitive Federal grants that will empower community colleges and minority-serving institutions to become incubators for infant and toddler child care talent, training, and access on their campuses and in their communities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preparing and Resourcing Our Student Parents and Early Childhood Teachers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROSPECT Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2020-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2019-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3168" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-09T17:15:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Preparing and Resourcing Our Student Parents and Early Childhood Teachers Act or the PROSPECT Act

This bill establishes various grant programs to increase the supply of, and access to, high-quality, early-childhood care. Specifically, grants are established for

 planning and developing expanded access to free infant and toddler child care for student parents attending community college or minority-serving institutions; providing free infant and toddler child care to such student parents, including developing on-campus child care centers that meet specified requirements; training, mentorships, and technical support to community child care agencies and the professional development of licensed and unlicensed child care professionals; and increasing the workforce pipeline of high-quality infant and toddler child care providers, particularly in locations with a low supply of affordable care. The bill also revises the formula for providing federal matching funds to states providing child care assistance.

Further, the bill requires the Department of Education&#8217;s college cost calculator to include information about the dependent care allowance with respect to the cost of attendance and financial aid.</summary>
</bill>
