<bill session="116" type="h" number="8492" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Count Every Vote Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Count Every Vote Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 3, United States Code, to extend the date provided for the meeting of electors of the President and Vice President in the States and the date provided for the joint session of Congress held for the counting of electoral votes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2020-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2020-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2020-10-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-30T16:31:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Count Every Vote Act of 2020

This bill revises the electoral college's time frame for presidential elections, particularly with regard to the meeting of electors and the counting of electoral votes.

First, the bill requires states to make final determinations of controversies or contests as to the appointment of electors within three (instead of six) days before the electors meet in their respective states to cast their votes for President and Vice President.

Further, it extends the date for state electors to meet and vote from the first Monday after the second Wednesday in December following their appointment to the first day after January 1 following their appointment.

In addition, it requires states to deliver certificates of electoral votes in the most expeditious method available, including by overnight delivery or a secure form of electronic transmission. Currently, states may transmit these certificates only by registered mail.

Finally, the bill changes the date for the joint session of Congress to count electoral votes from the sixth day of January succeeding the meeting of the state electors to the second day following the extended deadline for the receipt of certificates and votes by the President of the Senate or the Archivist of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
