<bill session="117" type="h" number="3347" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GREEN Buses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a program relating to the acquisition or leasing of zero emission buses or bus facility improvements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generating Reduced Emissions by Electrifying New Buses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GREEN Buses Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2021-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-30T18:00:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Generating Reduced Emissions by Electrifying New Buses Act or the GREEN Buses Act

This bill limits eligibility for certain grants that support projects to reduce emissions of public transportation vehicles.

Current law permits the use of the grants for (1) projects related to both low- and zero-emission vehicles, and (2) constructing new and improving existing public transportation facilities to accommodate such vehicles. This bill limits the use of the grants to (1) projects related to no-emission vehicles, and (2) improving existing public transportation facilities.

The bill also sets out additional criteria that apply to the grants. For example, the bill specifies the minimum number of buses that must be procured through a grant. Furthermore, at least 10% of grant funds must be distributed to projects that predominately serve low-income communities.</summary>
</bill>
