<bill session="116" type="h" number="8251" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit preventing access to lifesaving medical procedures and treatments, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit preventing access to lifesaving medical procedures and treatments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000812"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-14T21:04:00Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill establishes a new criminal offense for preventing or otherwise interfering with the ability of any individual or class of individuals from obtaining or providing a lifesaving medical procedure or treatment. However, the parent or legal guardian of a minor shall not be subject to any penalties under this bill with respect to medical decisions directed exclusively at that minor.

An individual who engages in this conduct is subject to a fine, a prison term, or both. The amount of the fine and duration of the prison term depends on whether it is a first or subsequent offense and whether the obstruction is nonviolent or results in bodily injury or death.

In addition, an aggrieved individual may bring a civil action against an individual whose conduct prevented access to, or the provision of, a lifesaving medical procedure or treatment, and the Department of Justice and the Attorney General of a state or territory may also commence civil actions for violations of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
