<bill session="111" type="h" number="809" updated="2019-11-15T21:41:14Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, to reduce from age 57 to age 55 the age after which the remarriage of the surviving spouse of a deceased veteran shall not result in termination of dependency and indemnity compensation otherwise payable to that surviving spouse.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to reduce from age 57 to age 55 the age after which the remarriage of the surviving spouse of a deceased veteran shall not result in termination of dependency and indemnity compensation otherwise payable to that surviving spouse.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-10T17:31:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Reduces from age 57 to age 55 the age after which the remarriage of the surviving spouse of a deceased veteran shall not result in termination of dependency and indemnity compensation otherwise payable to that surviving spouse. Prohibits payment of retroactive benefits. Permits eligibility for such benefits by an individual who but for having remarried would be eligible for such benefits by reason such age reduction and whose remarriage was before the date of the enactment of this Act and after the individual had attained age 57 only if the individual submits an application for such benefits within one year of enactment.</summary>
</bill>
