<bill session="118" type="h" number="1596" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stabilizing Vulnerable Banks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stabilizing Vulnerable Banks Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act to repeal the exemption from enhanced supervision and prudential standards applicable to bank holding companies with total consolidated assets between $50,000,000,000 and $250,000,000,000.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001196"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1602" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="817" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-14T14:32:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Stabilizing Vulnerable Banks Act 

This bill increases the oversight of certain nonbank financial companies and bank holding companies by repealing Title IV of the Economic Growth, Regulatory Relief, and Consumer Protection Act (P.L. 115-174). (A nonbank financial company is a financial institution without a banking license that may be subject to supervision due to the company's size or risk profile. A bank holding company owns a controlling interest in one or more banks.)

Specifically, the bill decreases from $250 billion to $50 billion the asset threshold at which enhanced prudential standards become mandatory, thereby requiring more companies to comply with these standards. These standards include stress testing, leverage limits, liquidity requirements, and resolution plan requirements (i.e., living will requirements). Under current law, the Federal Reserve has the discretion to determine the applicability of these standards to bank holding companies with assets between $100 billion and $250 billion.

The bill also expands stress testing by

 increasing the number of board-run stress test scenarios from two to three; decreasing the asset threshold at which company-run stress tests are required from $250 billion to $10 billion; and requiring company-run stress tests to be performed annually or semiannually, depending on the amount of assets held. The bill also decreases from $50 billion to $10 billion the asset threshold for mandatory risk committees.</summary>
</bill>
