<bill session="111" type="h" number="314" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Criminal Immigration Courts Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the number of Federal judgeships in certain judicial districts with heavy caseloads of criminal immigration cases.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Criminal Immigration Courts Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2009-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-14T22:08:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Criminal Immigration Courts Act of 2009 - Directs the President to appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the following permanent judgeships: (1) four additional district judges for the district of Arizona; (2) one additional district judge for the district of New Mexico; (3) two additional district judges for the southern district of Texas; and (4) one additional district judge for the western district of Texas.

Directs the President to appoint, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, the following temporary judgeships: (1) one additional district judge for the district of Arizona; and (2) one additional district judge for the district of New Mexico.

Provides that, for each of the judicial districts named in this Act, the first vacancy arising on the district court 10 years or more after a judge is first confirmed to fill the temporary district judgeship created by this Act shall not be filled.</summary>
</bill>
