<bill session="108" type="hc" number="440" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:09Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States should resume normal diplomatic relations with the Republic of China on Taiwan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of Congress that the United States should resume normal diplomatic relations with the Republic of China on Taiwan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000458"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2004-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2004-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-16T19:17:05Z" status="Introduced in House">States that the United States commends the people of the Republic of China on Taiwan for having established a democracy and for repeatedly reaffirming their dedication to democratic ideals and human rights.

Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the President should recognize the Republic of China on Taiwan as a sovereign government, separate from the communist regime in Beijing, and immediately resume normal diplomatic relations with the Republic of China on Taiwan; (2) the United States should enter into a bilateral agreement with the Republic of China on Taiwan acknowledging a sense of unity between the Republic of China on Taiwan and the United States and a common determination to maintain Western Pacific regional security; and (3) the Republic of China on Taiwan should be permitted to participate fully in all international organizations for which statehood is a requirement for membership, including the United Nations.</summary>
</bill>
