<bill session="118" type="s" number="545" updated="2025-11-18T20:45:10Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the rights of passengers with disabilities in air transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1267" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T19:14:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Air Carrier Access Amendments Act of 2023

This bill expands protections for airline passengers with disabilities and requires air carriers to meet certain minimum accessibility standards.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) must prescribe regulations setting minimum accessibility standards for new and existing aircraft, airport facilities, websites, and kiosks. The accessibility standards must address topics including

 boarding and deplaning equipment, including ensuring individuals can board and deplane an aircraft from their personal assistive devices (e.g., wheelchairs); seating accommodations; lavatories; visually accessible announcements; and proper stowage of assistive devices in the cargo hold to prevent damage. Existing aircraft have five years from the effective date of the regulations to comply with the standards. DOT must assess civil penalties against an air carrier for violations of these provisions and refer patterns of discrimination to the Department of Justice (DOJ).

DOT must also ensure that passengers with disabilities may (1) file a complaint with the agency in response to disability-related discrimination, and (2) receive assistance through a toll-free hotline or other electronic method.

Further, the bill authorizes DOJ and aggrieved passengers to bring civil actions for discrimination against an air carrier.</summary>
</bill>
