<bill session="118" type="h" number="1067" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to clarify the effect of a pending civil action on the processing of an application for a permit to drill, to require courts to remand lease sale Environmental Impact Statements to agencies to remedy when necessary, and to establish a term limit for permits to drill.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000825"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000377" joined="2023-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000604" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001212" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2023-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2023-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1335" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="947" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-23T14:59:35Z" status="Introduced in House">American Energy Act

This bill sets forth requirements to extend terms for energy drilling permits and to limit the effect of civil actions concerning such permits. Specifically, the bill extends the terms for permits to drill issued under Section 17 of the Mineral Leasing Act from two years to four years.

The bill also requires the Department of the Interior to process an application for an oil or gas drilling permit or other authorizations under a valid existing lease regardless of any pending civil actions affecting the application or related lease.

It also addresses litigation concerning the environmental review of certain oil and gas lease sales held under the Mineral Leasing Act or the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act. A court may not vacate a lease sale nor otherwise limit, delay, or enjoin related lease activities unless the court concludes that (1) the lease will pose a risk of an imminent and substantial environmental harm, and (2) there is no other equitable remedy available.

In addition, no court may enjoin or issue any order preventing the award of leases to a bidder in a lease sale if Interior has previously opened bids for such leases or disclosed the high bidder for any tract that was included in such lease sale.</summary>
</bill>
