<bill session="109" type="h" number="5824" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:37Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Manchester Bidwell Center for Arts and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Labor to award a grant to the Manchester Bidwell Corporation to improve, expand, and replicate the arts and technology education centers operated by such corporation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manchester Bidwell Center for Arts and Technology Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2006-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on 21st Century Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-21T18:57:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Manchester Bidwell Center for Arts and Technology Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to award a grant to the Manchester Bidwell Corporation in Pennsylvania to improve, expand, and replicate the arts and technology education centers operated by such Corporation.

Permits the Manchester Bidwell Corporation to use the grant awarded under this Act to conduct any of the following activities: (1) the development of a business plan to replicate at other locations in the United States the arts and technology education centers modeled after the Corporation in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; (2) the implementation of such business plan at locations in the United States where there is an interest in establishing arts and technology education centers similar to those operated by the Corporation in Pittsburgh; or (3) any other activities the Secretary determines to be appropriate.

Requires Manchester Bidwell Corporation, in order to be eligible to receive such grant, to provide matching funds from non-federal sources (in cash or in kind) in an amount equal to or greater than the federal funds received in accordance with the grant to carry out the activities supported by it.</summary>
</bill>
