<bill session="118" type="s" number="1426" updated="2025-11-19T03:46:30Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RISE from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resilience Investment, Support, and Expansion from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RISE from Trauma Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the identification and support of children and families who experience trauma.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2024-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1507-1510" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4541" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-18T19:08:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Resilience Investment, Support, and Expansion from Trauma Act or the RISE from Trauma Act

This bill reauthorizes, establishes, and extends programs to support youth and families who have experienced, or may experience, trauma.

The bill reauthorizes through FY2028

 the National Child Traumatic Stress Network, school-based grants to increase access to trauma-support and mental health services, public health data collection about adverse childhood experiences, and a task force on trauma-informed care. It also establishes grants for

 multi-sector demonstration projects to mitigate trauma and toxic stress; improving outcomes for hospital patients who experience drug overdoses, suicide attempts, or violent injury; and clinical training in infant and early childhood mental health. Additionally, the bill authorizes (1) federal agencies to use specified discretionary funds for pilot projects to address traumatic exposures among children, and (2) Department of Justice (DOJ) grants to prevent trauma in children by reducing their exposure to violence and trauma.

Further, the Department of Health and Human Services must provide resources for training frontline service providers and certain community members about trauma, toxic stress, and resilience. In addition, DOJ must establish a national center to disseminate resources to law enforcement agencies to improve interactions with youth and families who are exposed to violence and trauma.

The bill also incorporates trauma-informed practices in programs for health care professional education, health care access, and educators.</summary>
</bill>
