<bill session="116" type="h" number="8126" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Communities Serving Schools Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Communities Serving Schools Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to establish a program to assist certain schools with respect to the implementation of wraparound services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-31T17:42:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Communities Serving Schools Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Education to award four-year competitive grants to state and local educational agencies for implementing wraparound services in public elementary and secondary schools. Wraparound service refers to a school-based service that targets academic and non-academic barriers to student achievement, including assistance with academics and physical and mental health, provision of basic needs (e.g., food, housing, and clothing), and college and career preparation.

A state educational agency that receives a grant must award subgrants to local educational agencies. A local educational agency that receives a grant or subgrant must use these funds for certain activities, such as hiring an on-site coordinator to ensure wraparound services are aligned with student needs and to connect students with those services.</summary>
</bill>
