<bill session="117" type="s" number="904" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-18">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing Access to Our Public Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works to digitize and make publicly available geographic information system mapping data relating to public access to Federal land and waters for outdoor recreation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAPLand Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Access to our Public Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Modernizing Access to Our Public Land Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000584"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2021-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2022-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-83.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-02-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="284">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 284.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3113" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T16:35:30Z" status="Reported to Senate">Modernizing Access to our Public Land Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to jointly develop and adopt interagency standards to ensure compatibility and interoperability among federal databases for the collection and dissemination of certain data.

Specifically, these requirements shall apply to outdoor recreation data related to federal lands and used to depict locations at which recreation uses are available to the public.

Each such department shall digitize and make publicly available on their websites, as applicable, geographic information system mapping data that specifies, with respect to the relevant department, all federal interests in private land, including easements, reservations, and rights-of-way

 to which the federal government does not have a fee title interest, and that may be used to provide recreational access to the federal land. Interior, the Forest Service, and the Corps of Engineers must digitize and publish geographic information system mapping data that includes

 status information as to whether roads and trails are open or closed, the dates on which roads and trails are seasonally opened and closed, the types of vehicles that are allowed on each segment of roads and trails, and the boundaries of areas where hunting or recreational shooting is regulated or closed.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-83</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
