<bill session="117" type="s" number="560" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oral Health for Moms Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve coverage of maternal oral health care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oral Health for Moms Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-02T18:22:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Oral Health for Moms Act

This bill expands access to oral health care during pregnancy and the postpartum period.

Specifically, Medicaid, the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP), and health insurance plans in the individual and small-group markets must provide coverage for oral health services for pregnant and postpartum individuals.

The federal government must cover, subject to certain exceptions, the costs of oral health services provided through Medicaid and CHIP, and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must publish measures to assess the quality of oral health services provided through those public insurance programs.

In addition, HHS must consult with tribal nations and organizations to improve the oral health of pregnant individuals, postpartum individuals, and infants in tribal populations.

The bill also establishes grants and programs for purposes related to maternal oral health, including

 to promote good oral health practices among, and share information about oral health benefits with, pregnant and postpartum individuals in public insurance programs; to expand access to oral health services through federally qualified health centers; and to train maternal health providers about oral health during the pregnancy and postpartum period. Furthermore, the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission must report on issues related to maternal oral health.</summary>
</bill>
