<bill session="116" type="h" number="5682" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Care for Veterans Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to furnish hospital care and medical services to veterans, members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, and dependents who were stationed at Wurtsmith Air Force Base in Oscoda, Michigan, and were exposed to volatile organic compounds, to provide for a presumption of service connection for those veterans and members of the reserve components, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Care for Veterans Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000380"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1024" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-31T14:59:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Care for Veterans Act of 2020

This bill requires hospital care and medical services to be furnished to veterans and reservists who were exposed to volatile organic compounds, including trichloroethylene and benzene, while serving at Wurtsmith Air Force Base in Oscoda, Michigan. Family members of veterans and reservists who resided at Wurtsmith Air Force Base are also eligible for hospital care and medical services under this bill.

The bill also provides a presumption of service connection for veterans and reservists who were exposed to volatile organic compounds while serving at Wurtsmith Air Force Base. Under a presumption of service connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.</summary>
</bill>
