<bill session="111" type="h" number="1758" updated="2021-09-28T20:40:26Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Opportunity and Equity Commission Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Educational Opportunity and Equity Commission Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of a commission to stimulate and engage in an informed, national, and public dialogue about how to ensure that each student in the United States receives an equitable education that enables the student to achieve his or her maximum academic potential.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001173" joined="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-22T15:41:17Z" status="Introduced in House">The Educational Opportunity and Equity Commission Act of 2009 - Establishes the Educational Opportunity and Equity Commission, composed of the Secretary of Education and 14 individuals appointed by the Secretary who are educational stakeholders or have relevant experience or knowledge.

Tasks the Commission with conducting a study and reporting to Congress on ways to enable all students to achieve their academic potential, with particular emphasis on: (1) ensuring that schools receive adequate resources; (2) developing methods for assessing students' educational needs; and (3) creating innovative strategies for state and local educational agencies to follow to enable students to achieve their academic potential, and to enable such agencies to participate in school funding reform efforts that result in educational equity.

Directs the Commission to conduct outreach programs with communities throughout the nation to engage them in a public dialogue on how to ensure that their schools enable all students to achieve their academic potential.</summary>
</bill>
