<bill session="117" type="s" number="2298" updated="2022-12-31T05:25:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 1977 of the Revised Statutes to protect equal rights under law.</title>
    <title type="display">Economic Inclusion Civil Rights Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Inclusion Civil Rights Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-04-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4157" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-29T15:17:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Economic Inclusion Civil Rights Act of 2021

This bill modifies the prohibition against intentional racial discrimination in the context of economic activity such as employment, contracts, or other commercial transactions.

Specifically, the bill makes an action that has a discriminatory effect a violation of section 1977 of the Revised Statutes. It also states that all non-White persons within U.S. jurisdiction shall have the same right in every state and territory as is enjoyed by White citizens in certain respects.

No person shall use a criterion, method of administration, practice, or policy that has a disparate impact in violation of that provision.

Further, a plaintiff may prove intentional discrimination by showing only that the discriminatory intent was a motivating factor in the alleged violation. Under current law, a plaintiff must prove that the harm would not have occurred but for the defendant's unlawful conduct.

Additionally, standing shall not be limited to victims who were parties to, or third-party beneficiaries of, a contract with the defendant.

The bill provides for a right to jury trial and no joint-action waiver or pre-dispute arbitration agreement shall be enforceable with respect to any alleged violation.

The bill provides for a four-year statute of limitations.</summary>
</bill>
