<bill session="111" type="h" number="4338" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Responders Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide adequate benefits for public safety officers injured or killed in the line of duty, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responders Support Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001161"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2441" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1037" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2885" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-06T15:45:47Z" status="Introduced in House">First Responders Support Act of 2009 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to: (1) increase death and disability benefits for public safety officers; (2) expand educational benefits for dependents of public safety officers killed or disabled in the line of duty; and (3) require the Bureau of Justice Assistance of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to adopt and apply a system for prioritizing claims for public safety officers' benefits based on the severity of a claim and the likelihood of its approval (grants automatic priority to a claim for death benefits or 100% disability).

Authorizes the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to organizations for reduced cost mental health services or counseling to public safety officers seriously injured in the line of duty and their families.

Requires the Director to structure, design, and implement a performance measure for the Public Safety Officers Benefits program to monitor the claims process and payment of benefits to public safety officers and their beneficiaries and to report to Congress annually on the performance of the program and its activities.</summary>
</bill>
