<bill session="118" type="s" number="169" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Parental Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parental Rights Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain COVID-19 vaccination mandates for minors, and to require parental consent for COVID-19 vaccination of minors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-14T22:55:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Parental Rights Protection Act

This bill restricts government entities from requiring that individuals age 18 or younger receive certain COVID-19 vaccines that were authorized through emergency use and related procedures.

Specifically, a federal, state, tribal, territorial, or local government entity (including a local educational agency) that receives funding from either the Department of Education or the Department of Health and Human Services may not require such COVID-19 vaccinations for individuals age 18 or younger. In particular, a local educational agency that mandates COVID-19 vaccinations for students loses its eligibility for federal education funding.

The bill also requires the prior, informed, written consent of a parent or guardian before administration of such COVID-19 vaccines to an individual age 18 or younger.</summary>
</bill>
