<bill session="118" type="hr" number="590" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:35Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding calling on the President to direct the United States Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to immediately promote the establishment of an appropriate regional or international justice mechanism through the United Nations and United Nations General Assembly to investigate and prosecute possible war crimes, crimes against humanity, and violations of internationally recognized human rights stemming from the conflict in Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the House of Representatives regarding calling on the President to direct the United States Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to immediately promote the establishment of an appropriate regional or international justice mechanism through the United Nations and United Nations General Assembly to investigate and prosecute possible war crimes, crimes against humanity, and violations of internationally recognized human rights stemming from the conflict in Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2023-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-20T20:04:05Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution expresses that the President should direct the U.S. Representative to the United Nations to promote the establishment of an international justice mechanism that will investigate and prosecute war crimes, crimes against humanity, and violations of internationally recognized human rights that occurred during the period of conflict in Syria. The resolution states that the United States should urge all interested countries to apprehend and deliver persons indicted for international crimes to that justice mechanism.</summary>
</bill>
