<bill session="116" type="s" number="4722" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:41Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to establish a standard of care for the selection by certain entities of motor carries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2020-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-18T18:58:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transportation and Logistics Hiring Reform Act of 2020

This bill establishes a standard of care for the selection of motor carriers by specified entities (e.g., shippers, brokers, freight carriers).

Before tendering a shipment, but not more than 45 days before the pickup of a shipment by the hired motor carrier, an entity shall verify that the carrier

 is registered with and authorized by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) to operate as a motor carrier, does not have an unsatisfactory safety fitness rating, and has not otherwise been ordered to discontinue operations by the FMCSA. In any civil action in federal or state court for damages in which it is asserted or alleged that an entity acted negligently in the selection or retention of a motor carrier, such entity shall be considered to have acted reasonably and prudently in the selection if it establishes that it verified information relating to the motor carrier through the FMCS.</summary>
</bill>
