<bill session="112" type="s" number="1702" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:59Z">
  <state datetime="2011-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide that the rules of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled "National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants for Reciprocating Internal Combustion Engines" have no force or effect with respect to existing stationary compression and spark ignition reciprocating internal combustion engines operated by certain persons and entities for the purpose of generating electricity or operating a water pump.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that the rules of the Environmental Protection Agency entitled "National Emission Standards for Hazardous Air Pollutants for Reciprocating Internal Combustion Engines" have no force or effect with respect to existing stationary compression and spark ignition reciprocating internal combustion engines operated by certain persons and entities for the purpose of generating electricity or operating a water pump.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2011-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2011-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2011-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3616" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3185" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Agricultural equipment and machinery"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-10T12:38:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farmers Undertake Environmental Land Stewardship Act or the FUELS Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in implementing the Spill Prevention, Control, and Countermeasure rule, with respect to any farm, to require certification of compliance with such rule by: (1) a professional engineer for a farm with an individual tank with a storage capacity greater than 10,000 gallons, an aggregate storage capacity of at least 42,000 gallons, or a history that includes a spill; or (2) the owner or operator of the farm (via self-certification) for a farm with an aggregate storage capacity greater than 10,000 gallons but less than 42,000 gallons and no history of spills. Exempts from all requirements of such rule any farm with an aggregate storage capacity of at least 10,000 gallons and no history of spills.

Excludes all containers on separate parcels that have a capacity that is less than 1,320 gallons from the aggregate storage capacity of a farm.</summary>
</bill>
