<bill session="116" type="s" number="4386" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Substance Regulation and Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Substance Regulation and Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to decriminalize and reschedule cannabis, to provide for the regulation of cannabis and cannabis products to protect public health and safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-16T13:18:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Substance Regulation and Safety Act of 2020

This bill decriminalizes cannabis and contains other related provisions.

Specifically, the bill removes marijuana and tetrahydrocannabinols, commonly known as THC, from the schedule of controlled substances and removes references to such substances from various criminal provisions. Such changes related to decriminalization shall be retroactive to apply to cases from before this bill's enactment.

The Food and Drug Administration (FDA) shall regulate cannabis products in the same manner as the FDA's regulation of tobacco, including prohibiting any retailer from selling cannabis products to an individual younger than 21 years of age. The bill also requires the Department of Agriculture to promulgate regulations relating to the production and quality control of cannabis, and U.S. Customs and Border Protection to prescribe regulations relating to the import and export of cannabis.

The bill also requires each national research institute and national center to (1) evaluate each application for medical research related to cannabis on the same basis as it would any other application for medical research, and (2) not deny an application for financial assistance solely due to the fact that the research relates to cannabis.

In addition, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to develop a national strategy to prevent youth use and abuse of cannabis. The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration shall research and publicly report on methods for detecting cannabis-impaired driving. Both the strategy and the research shall address whether any proposed strategies or methods would have racially disparate impacts.</summary>
</bill>
