<bill session="119" type="h" number="2883" updated="2025-11-19T04:23:19Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NO TIME TO Waste Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Opportunities for Technological Innovation, Mitigation, and Education To Overcome Waste Act,</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NO TIME TO Waste Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out activities to reduce food loss and waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1395" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-23T14:09:11Z" status="Introduced in House">New Opportunities for Technological Innovation, Mitigation, and Education To Overcome Waste Act or the NO TIME TO Waste Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to reduce U.S. food loss and waste (FLW) through federal coordination,&#160;grants, and education.

Under the bill, food loss means the food that does not reach a consumer as a result of an issue in the production, storage, processing, or distribution phase. Food waste means that food intended for human consumption is unconsumed for any reason at the retail or consumption phase.

The bill requires USDA to collaborate with the Food and Drug Administration and the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out&#160;a December, 17, 2020, agreement to coordinate federal efforts to cut FLW.

Further,&#160;USDA must establish an Office of Food Loss and Waste to support the existing role of the Food Loss and Waste Liaison. The office must also, among other things, establish

a grant program to support collecting data on existing state and local FLW policies (and the office must use the data to establish model policies for state and local governments);a block grant program for states and Indian tribes to develop and support food recovery infrastructure and innovative food distribution models; anda grant program to incentivize state, municipal, local, and tribal governments to establish public-private partnerships that commit to reducing FLW by 50% by 2030.The Office of Food Loss and Waste must also initiate a national FLW education and public awareness campaign.</summary>
</bill>
