<bill session="116" type="h" number="5328" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:05Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Funding Accountability for Sexual Harassers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain information be reported with respect to principal investigators who have discriminated, including harassed, on the basis of sex (including gender identity, sexual orientation, pregnancy, childbirth, medical conditions related to pregnancy and childbirth, parental status, and sex stereotype), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Funding Accountability for Sexual Harassers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2019-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2019-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2019-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Reform, and Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-17T17:50:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Funding Accountability for Sexual Harassers Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that receive federal funding to report certain instances of discrimination on the basis of sex.

Such IHEs must report, to all federal agencies that awarded competitive research and development grants over the previous 10 years and to the Federal Audit Clearinghouse, substantiated findings of discrimination (including harassment) on the basis of sex by a principal investigator or program director.

A principal investigator or program director is an individual designated to direct or lead a project, program, or activity supported by a federal grant and who is responsible and accountable for the proper conduct of the project, program, or activity.

In addition, each federal department or agency that is authorized to award competitive research and development grants must take into consideration any such reports when making the final decision of whether to award a grant to an IHE. The department or agency may condition the grant award on the prohibition of an individual for whom a report has been filed from using the grant award or carrying out activities under the grant.

The National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine must study and report on the implementation and effectiveness of strategies employed to address and prevent sexual harassment.</summary>
</bill>
