<bill session="117" type="h" number="3059" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:53Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Quality Care for Our Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into a contract or other agreement with a third party to review appointees in the Veterans Health Administration who had a license terminated for cause by a State licensing board for care or services rendered at a non-Veterans Health Administration facility and to provide individuals treated by such an appointee with notice if it is determined that an episode of care or services that they received was below the standard of care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Quality Care for Our Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="372" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-09T10:15:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Quality Care for Our Veterans Act

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to contract with a nonfederal organization to conduct a quality management review of hospital care or medical services furnished by each Veterans Health Administration (VHA) provider whose license was terminated by a state licensing board based upon care or services provided in a non-VHA facility.

If a review determines that the standard of care was not met, the VA shall notify the individual who received such care or services.</summary>
</bill>
