<bill session="108" type="s" number="999" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Highlands Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Highlands Stewardship Area in the States of Connecticut, New Jersey, New York, and Pennsylvania, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highlands Stewardship Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2003-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5775-5776"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5776-5777" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1964" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Greenways"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-08-22T14:14:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Highlands Stewardship Act - Directs the Secretaries of Agriculture and the Interior to establish the Highlands Stewardship Area in the Highlands region (an area encompassing nearly 2,000,000 acres extending from eastern Pennsylvania through New Jersey and New York to northwestern Connecticut (the Highlands States)).

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish: (1) within the Department of Agriculture the Office of Highlands Stewardship to advise the Secretaries and the Governors of the Highlands States on priorities for projects carried out with financial or technical assistance under this Act, land conservation partnership projects, Highlands region research, policy and education initiatives necessary to implement the findings of the Highlands Regional Study (conducted by the Forest Service in 1990) and the New York-New Jersey Highlands Regional Assessment Update (conducted by the Service in 2001), and to implement the strategies of the study, the update, and other studies in consultation with the Highlands States; and (2) the Highlands Stewardship Area Work Group to assist with such implementation. Authorizes the Office to provide financial and technical assistance to an eligible entity to carry out a project to protect, restore, preserve, promote, or interpret natural, agricultural, historical, cultural, or recreational resources of the Area.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior, from among proposed land conservation partnership projects submitted by the Governors of the Highlands States, to annually designate those projects that are eligible to receive financial assistance under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
