<bill session="112" type="h" number="4409" updated="2019-11-15T21:08:55Z">
  <state datetime="2012-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Government Agency Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Government Agency Reform Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for reforming and consolidating agencies of the Federal Government to improve efficiency and save money, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001252"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2129" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-10T15:51:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Government Agency Reform Act of 2012 - Defines "efficiency-enhancing plan," for purposes of executive authority to reorganize federal executive agencies, as a reorganization plan that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) determines will or is likely to result in a decrease in the number of agencies and cost savings in performing the functions that are the subject of the plan.

Expands executive authority to reorganize agencies by allowing: (1) the renaming of an existing executive department, (2) the abolition or transfer of an executive department or independent regulatory agency, or (3) the consolidation of two or more executive departments or two or more independent regulatory agencies.

Allows a provision in a reorganization plan to take effect only if such plan is transmitted to Congress within two years of the enactment of this Act and is an efficiency-enhancing plan.</summary>
</bill>
