<bill session="117" type="h" number="742" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLEX Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require short-term limited duration insurance issuers to renew or continue in force such insurance coverage at the option of the enrollees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLEX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flexibility Through Lower Expenses Health Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2021-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="896" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8588" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-25T19:49:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Flexibility Through Lower Expenses Health Care Act or the FLEX Act

This bill provides statutory authority for certain short-term, limited-duration health insurance plans and association health plans.

The bill permits short-term, limited-duration plans to provide coverage for a period of less than 12 months, not including extensions. Under current law, such plans are exempt from certain market requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, such as coverage of individuals with preexisting conditions.

The bill further permits groups or associations of employers to sponsor fully insured group health plans as if they were employers. Such plans may not discriminate based on the health factors of any prospective plan participant for the purpose of granting an employer's membership in the association or determining a participant's eligibility for benefits or premium amounts.</summary>
</bill>
