<bill session="117" type="s" number="951" updated="2023-02-14T14:35:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAWS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to make grants to eligible organizations to provide service dogs to veterans with severe post-traumatic stress disorder, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAWS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puppies Assisting Wounded Servicemembers Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2021-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2021-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-231.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-03T18:42:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Puppies Assisting Wounded Servicemembers Act of 2021 or the PAWS Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a grant program for the purpose of pairing service dogs with eligible veterans. Organizations that receive grants shall provide veterinary health insurance coverage, hardware, and travel expenses for each service dog and veteran participating in the program.

Eligible veterans are those who (1) are enrolled in the VA health care system, (2) have been evaluated and treated for post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) but remain diagnosed with PTSD, (3) may benefit from a service dog, and (4) agree to successfully complete training provided by an eligible organization. Veterans are required to see a VA health care provider at least once every 180 days to determine whether the veteran continues to benefit from a service dog.

Eligible organizations are nonprofit organizations that

 are accredited by a widely recognized accreditation organization, meet publicly available standards set forth by the Association of Service Dog Providers for Military Veterans, have expertise in the needs of veterans with PTSD, agree to cover all costs in excess of the grant amount to guarantee the benefits of the program, agree to reaccept or replace a service dog provided to a veteran, and submit an application to the VA. Any improvement in PTSD symptoms as a result of the provision of a service dog shall not affect the veteran's eligibility for any other VA benefits.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the grant program.</summary>
</bill>
