<bill session="116" type="s" number="3182" updated="2022-02-09T00:41:44Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Helping Expand and Launch Transitional Health for Women Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Expand and Launch Transitional Health for Women Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out the Women's Health Transition Training pilot program through at least fiscal year 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-05">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Moran with an amendment and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-02-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="415">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 415.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2752" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2942" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T16:37:34Z" status="Reported to Senate">Helping Expand and Launch Transitional Health for Women Veterans Act or the HEALTH Act

This bill updates programs and provisions related to the health of women veterans.

(Sec. 2) Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to continue through at least FY2020 and report on the Women's Health Transition Training pilot program. Among other elements, the report should include the number of female participants by military department, the number of courses held under the program, and the locations where the courses were held.

(Sec. 3) The VA is authorized to furnish transportation in connection with the receipt of covered health care services for a newborn child of a woman veteran (and the child's parents). The bill expands covered health care services to include services furnished at health care facilities other than the facility where the child was delivered.

Under the bill, the VA may furnish more than seven days of health care services and transportation to such services if a child is in need of additional care.

Expenses incurred for transportation furnished in order for a newborn child of a veteran to receive health care services between May 5, 2010, and the enactment of this bill may be waived or reimbursed to the veteran by the VA.</summary>
</bill>
