<bill session="116" type="h" number="7102" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FARM to TABLE Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Motor Carrier Safety Improvement Act of 1999 with respect to exemptions from certain motor carrier regulations, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations related to agricultural commodities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FARM to TABLE Delivery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fixing America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Regulatory Mess To Facilitate Agricultural Byproducts and Livestock Expedited Delivery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="General agriculture matters"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-01T16:56:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Fixing America's Regulatory Mess To Facilitate Agricultural Byproducts and Livestock Expedited Delivery Act or the FARM to TABLE Delivery Act

This bill revises exemptions with respect to commercial motor vehicle safety regulations involving the transportation of agricultural commodities and farm supplies.

 The bill allows the federal hours-of-service rules exemption regarding maximum driving and on-duty time for drivers transporting agricultural commodities and farm supplies to apply year-round. Current law provides an exception from the federal hours-of-service rules for the transportation of agricultural commodities within a 150 air-mile radius of the normal work reporting location only during planting and harvest periods which are determined by each state.

Additionally, the Department of Transportation must issue regulations to amend the definition of agricultural commodity to include specific commodities that are covered by the federal hours-of-service rules exception.</summary>
</bill>
