<bill session="109" type="h" number="2779" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:00Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Species Rescue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to enable Federal agencies responsible for the preservation of threatened species and endangered species to rescue and relocate members of any of those species that would be taken in the course of certain reconstruction, maintenance, or repair of Federal or non-Federal manmade flood control levees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Species Rescue Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000528"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-07-09T15:58:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Species Rescue Act - Amends the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to provide for expedited consultation and conferencing (within 60 days of the date on which initiated) with respect to impacts on endangered or threatened species of federal agency flood control actions. Directs the Secretary of the Interior or of Commerce, as appropriate, acting through the Fish and Wildlife Service, any other federal land management agency, the National Marine Fisheries Service, or a state conservation agency, to relocate from the flood control levee: (1) any threatened or endangered species of plant or animal that would be taken in the course of the agency action; and (2) any plant or other natural material that the Secretary considers to be suitable habitat, or a component of suitable habitat, for such species and that the Secretary determines would be damaged, destroyed, or removed in the course of the action. Bars the Secretary from requiring a non-federal person (other than a state conservation agency) to carry out any measures to minimize or mitigate impacts of agency flood control actions.</summary>
</bill>
