<bill session="116" type="s" number="886" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:06Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Public Land Management Act of 2009 to make the Reclamation Water Settlements Fund permanent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Hoeven with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-189.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-12-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="397">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 397.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2743-2745" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>The committee substitute withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2745"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-06-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-06-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15T15:04:20-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15T15:15:30-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1904" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3292" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="895" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="644" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4153" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1207" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1875" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1592"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-02-05T22:00:32Z" status="Passed Senate">Indian Water Rights Settlement Extension Act

This bill ratifies and modifies various agreements related to tribal water rights and contains other related provisions.

The bill ratifies an agreement relating to the settlement of the Aamodt litigation, which resolved claims concerning Pueblo water resources. The bill also reauthorizes through FY2028 activities to construct a regional water system as part of that settlement. Specifically, the bill ratifies an agreement between the United States, New Mexico, the city of Santa Fe, and the Pueblos of Nambe, Pojoaque, San Ildefonso, and Tesuque relating to the litigation. (This agreement is in addition to previously ratified agreements settling the litigation.)

The bill also ratifies and modifies the Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Agreement negotiated between the Navajo Nation, the United States, and Utah. That agreement gives the Navajo Nation the right to use water from sources located within Utah and adjacent to or encompassed within the boundaries of the Navajo Reservation, resulting in depletions not to exceed a specified amount annually.

The Department of the Interior shall establish and manage the Navajo Utah Settlement Trust Fund, with amounts available for withdrawal by the Navajo Nation for Navajo water development projects.

The bill specifies waivers and releases that must be executed in order for the Navajo settlement to be binding and effective.

The bill also authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense to enter arrangements for the sharing of medical facilities and services with urban Indian organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-189</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
