<bill session="118" type="h" number="9906" updated="2025-08-19T16:19:05Z">
  <state datetime="2024-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Safety Notification System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Safety Notification System Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require local educational agencies to develop emergency response and parental notification procedures for certain threats and emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2024-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2024-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-10-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-19T16:18:39Z" status="Introduced in House">School Safety Notification System Act

This bill requires each local educational agency (LEA), as a condition of receiving federal elementary and secondary education funds, to establish procedures for responding to school emergencies and for timely notifying parents of school emergencies.

Specifically, the bill requires each LEA to (1) develop and implement emergency response procedures covering all students, faculty, and staff at public schools under the jurisdiction of the LEA; and (2) ensure that parents and guardians receive timely notification of covered threats and emergencies (e.g., active shooter situations, bomb threats, and natural disasters) that occur on school grounds, during school transportation, or during school-sponsored activities. These emergency response procedures must meet specified criteria, including by requiring&#160;commonly used alarm system responses for specific types of emergencies.</summary>
</bill>
