<amendment session="109" chamber="s" number="1550" updated="2022-02-03T05:35:42Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1042" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-11-09">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-07-25"/>
  <description>To improve national security through the establishment of a Civilian Linguist Reserve Corps Pilot Project within the Department of Defense comprised of citizens fluent in foreign languages who would be available to provide translation services and related duties, as needed.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Amendment SA 1550, previously agreed to, was modified further by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12672-12675" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S12672" label="text as further modified"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2005-11-09" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 1550 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12590-12591" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Amendment SA 1550 proposed by Senator Warner for Senator Feingold. (consideration: CR S12589-12595) To improve national security through the establishment of a Civilian Linguist Reserve Corps Pilot Project within the Department of Defense comprised of citizens fluent in foreign languages who would be available to provide translation services and related duties, as needed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 1550 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12590-12591" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1550 proposed by Senator Warner for Senator Feingold.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12589-12595" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
