<bill session="118" type="h" number="3278" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WARRIOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WARRIOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working to Address Recruiting and Retention to Improve Our Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the use of military personnel for certain purposes, to direct the Secretary of Defense to appoint a Director of COVID Policy of the Department of Defense, and to limit environmental projects of such Department.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000823"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2023-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-20T19:33:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Working to Address Recruiting and Retention to Improve Our Readiness Act or the WARRIOR Act

This bill addresses the funding of certain Department of Defense (DOD) activities as well as certain personnel and training matters.

The bill prohibits the use of federal funds to (1) take into consideration race, ethnicity, color, national origin, or gender of an individual when making a determination regarding a military accession, assignment, selection, or promotion; (2) promote at the service academies, in military training, or in professional military education the theory that individuals, by virtue of race, ethnicity, color, or national origin, bear collective responsibility for actions committed in the past by individuals of such race, ethnicity, color, or national origin; or (3) investigate extremism in the Armed Forces or DOD.

The bill also requires the military departments to establish gender-neutral physical readiness standards.

DOD must freeze the number of civilian employees who perform tasks related to diversity, equity, and inclusion (DEI). DOD may hire only one DEI employee for every 2,000 members who join the Armed Forces.

The service academies may not employ as instructors individuals who are not members of the Armed Forces or civilian DOD employees unless no member or DOD employee may be adequately trained for such purpose.

DOD must appoint a Director of COVID Policy to determine and implement actions regarding members of the Armed Forces who are involuntarily separated solely on the basis of refusing to receive a COVID-19 vaccination.

DOD must submit a cost-benefit analysis and certain certifications to Congress in order to use federal funds for environmental projects.</summary>
</bill>
