<bill session="117" type="h" number="5380" updated="2022-12-31T05:36:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require institutions of higher education to notify students of the impact of private scholarships and grants on eligibility for institutional financial aid, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Helping Students Plan for College Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Students Plan for College Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2021-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2021-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-04T17:24:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Students Plan for College Act of 2021

This bill requires certain statements related to the impact of nonfederal financial assistance (e.g., private scholarships, grants, and loans) on financial-aid awards from an institution of higher education (IHE).

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE that participates in federal student-aid programs and adjusts its financial-aid awards based on students receiving such other financial assistance to provide enrolled and prospective students with a statement about (1) its policies on adjusting awards, and (2) how receipt of such other financial assistance may impact student eligibility for and the amount of financial-aid awards from the IHE.

 The Government Accountability Office must study and report on the relationship between such other financial assistance and eligibility for and the amount of financial-aid awards from IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
