<bill session="111" type="h" number="2685" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate and Ocean Research and Coordination Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and a National Climate Enterprise, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate and Ocean Research and Coordination Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Climate Enterprise Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000611" joined="2010-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2009-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1304"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-24T18:39:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Climate and Ocean Research and Coordination Act of 2009 - Reestablishes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) and its leadership. (NOAA was created by the Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970.) Includes in NOAA the National Weather Service and the Science Advisory Board.

National Climate Enterprise Act of 2009 - Directs the President to establish a National Climate Enterprise to coordinate international, federal, and nonfederal activity to provide scientifically based climate and climate impact data, information, products, and services to better forecast climate, climate change, and climate variability and to understand climate impacts at regional and local scales. Requires that the Enterprise consist of an Interdepartmental Oversight Board, an Interagency Coordinating Committee, and a Climate Operations Office established by this Act, and nonfederal contributors.

Requires the Office, subject to appropriations, to develop and implement a quality assurance program to certify climate products and services that satisfy this Act's standards. Defines "climate product and service" as any publicly or commercially available product or service produced by a nonfederal contributor that includes or displays climate data, meta-data, or information. Allows the Enterprise to authorize the use of the emblem or any trademark of the Enterprise on a certified climate product or service. Establishes in the Treasury the Climate Products And Services Account.

Requires the Enterprise Advisory Board to provide advice to the Interagency Coordinating Committee on policy implementation by the Climate Operations Office, the effectiveness of data, meta-data, information, products, and services delivered to end-users, priorities for climate research and information needs, the performance of non-federal contributors, and critical climate research needs.</summary>
</bill>
