<bill session="111" type="h" number="2564" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:09Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paid Vacation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act to require that employers provide a minimum of 1 week of paid annual leave to employees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paid Vacation Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2009-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-09T21:13:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Paid Vacation Act of 2009 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act to require: (1) upon enactment of this Act, each employer who employs 100 or more employees to provide each employee one week of paid vacation during each 12-month period; and (2) beginning three years after enactment of this Act, each employer who employs 50 or more employees to provide each employee one week of paid vacation during each 12-month period, and each employer that employs 100 or more employees to provide each employee two weeks paid vacation during each 12-month period, beginning on the employee's first anniversary of employment.

Requires an employee to provide the employer not less than 30 days' prior notice of his or her intent to take paid vacation, including the date the paid vacation will begin.

Requires the Secretary of Labor to conduct: (1) a public awareness campaign, through the Internet and other media, to inform the public of the entitlement to paid leave under the Act; and (2) a study on workplace productivity and the effect of paid leave on such productivity.</summary>
</bill>
