<bill session="116" type="h" number="8316" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coronavirus E-BD Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coronavirus E-BD Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coronavirus Emergency Borrower Defense Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Education to provide relief to borrowers of student loans for whom the Department of Education found misrepresentation by the institution of higher education or a State attorney general has asserted a right to borrower defense discharge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3745" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-22T21:35:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Coronavirus Emergency Borrower Defense Act of 2020 or the Coronavirus E-BD Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to discharge, within 30 days, the federal student loan debt of three categories of borrowers.

Specifically, ED must discharge the federal student loan debt of a borrower (1) who is covered by ED findings against an institution of higher education (IHE) for job placement rate misrepresentation; (2) for whom a state attorney general has asserted a right to borrower defense discharge; or (3) who was subject to a misrepresentation made by the IHE related to guaranteed employment or transferability of credits, and who has asserted such misrepresentation in a borrower defense application.

ED must reimburse a borrower for amounts paid toward the federal student loan.

The bill also requires ED to (1) notify borrowers of loan relief and eligibility for financial aid, and (2) report loan discharge to consumer reporting agencies.

Finally, ED must initiate a proceeding to require the IHE whose act or omission resulted in loan discharge to repay ED for such amounts.</summary>
</bill>
