<bill session="117" type="s" number="2237" updated="2022-12-31T05:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Education to establish and carry out two grant programs to make grants to eligible institutions to plan and implement programs that provide comprehensive support services and resources designed to increase graduation rates and transfer rates to 4-year institutions at community colleges, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community College Student Success Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community College Student Success Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T19:48:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community College Student Success Act of 2021

This bill establishes two grant programs for public two-year institutions of higher education (IHEs) to plan and implement programs that are designed to increase the rate at which their students graduate, the rate at which their students transfer to a four-year IHE, and the number of credits that students apply to a degree in their major.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Education to establish (1) a community college student success grant program, and (2) a part-time community college student success grant program. Under both programs, grant recipients may use grant funds for certain activities, including to establish career development services, expand tutoring and academic support services, and provide financial support for students.

The Institute of Education Sciences must enter into a contract with an independent evaluator to evaluate these grant programs.</summary>
</bill>
