<bill session="117" type="s" number="161" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SECURE Small Business Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to establish a program to assist small business concerns with purchasing cybersecurity products and services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SECURE Small Business Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening and Enhancing Cybersecurity Usage to Reach Every Small Business Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2021-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-01T13:49:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening and Enhancing Cybersecurity Usage to Reach Every Small Business Act or the SECURE Small Business Act

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to help small businesses purchase cybersecurity products and services.

Specifically, the SBA must establish a website that provides a marketplace for facilitating agreements under which small businesses may cooperatively purchase cybersecurity products and services. Such website shall be free to use for small businesses and cybersecurity vendors. The SBA must also take steps to educate small businesses about the types of cybersecurity products and services that are specific to each industry sector and provide outreach to encourage use of the cooperative marketplace.

The Government Accountability Office must study and report on potential improvements to existing federal initiatives that train small businesses on how to avoid cybersecurity threats.</summary>
</bill>
