<bill session="118" type="h" number="6836" updated="2025-02-03T17:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PHONE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PHONE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Home and Office Numbers in Emergencies Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for a moratorium on number reassignment after a disaster declaration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2023-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-03T17:00:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Preserving Home and Office Numbers in Emergencies Act of 2023 or the PHONE Act of 2023

This bill restricts the reassignment of wireline&#160;(or landline) telephone numbers following the declaration of a major disaster in a given geographic area.&#160;

Specifically, for up to two years after&#160;a major disaster has been declared, wireline telephone&#160;numbers may not be reassigned except at the request of the subscriber. Further, where a subscriber demonstrates that&#160;the residence associated with a telephone number is inaccessible or uninhabitable following a disaster, the subscriber may generally cancel their telephone service and resubscribe with the same number at the same address or at a new address. Such cancellations and resubscriptions may not be subject to cancellation or connection fees.

The Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must publish a list of areas affected by declared disasters, as determined by states, on its website. The bill takes effect 180 days after the FCC determines it is&#160;able to&#160;publish lists of&#160;affected areas in accordance with the bill's requirements.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
