<bill session="117" type="s" number="1335" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish a Global Climate Change Resilience Strategy, to authorize the admission of climate-displaced persons, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Global Climate Change Resilience Strategy, to authorize the admission of climate-displaced persons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2826" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-15T14:38:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill generally addresses the adverse effects of climate change with a particular focus on immigration.

Specifically, the bill establishes an immigration pathway to admit climate-displaced persons into the United States. These are individuals (1) who need durable resettlement because of an environmental change that adversely affects their living conditions, and (2) whose government cannot or will not provide a resettlement solution. Persons admitted to the United States under this pathway are entitled to the same resettlement assistance and benefits available to refugees.

Additionally, the bill authorizes the President to provide foreign assistance for promoting resilience and reducing vulnerability among communities facing adverse effects of climate change. It also creates the position of Coordinator of Climate Change Resiliency in the Department of State.

Moreover, the State Department must implement, and periodically report on, a strategy to mitigate the impact of climate change on displacement and humanitarian emergencies. The State Department must also provide (1) training on climate displacement to foreign service officers assigned to countries from which climate-displaced persons originated, and (2) guidance on the humanitarian impacts associated with climate change to all U.S. diplomatic missions.

The bill also requires the President to report on displacement caused by climate change.</summary>
</bill>
