<bill session="115" type="s" number="3182" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:05Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for the responsibility of the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center to maintain capabilities to identify threats to industrial control systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5733" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-08-23T14:14:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DHS Industrial Control Systems Capabilities Enhancement Act of 2018

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to expand the responsibilities of the National Cybersecurity and Communications Integration Center. The center must address the security of both information and operational technology, including industrial control systems and must identify and address threats and vulnerabilities to products and technologies intended for use in the automated control of critical infrastructure processes by: (1) leading efforts to identify and mitigate cybersecurity threats to industrial control systems; (2) maintaining cross-sector incident response capabilities to respond to cybersecurity incidents; (3) providing cybersecurity technical assistance to stakeholders; and (4) collecting, coordinating, and providing vulnerability information to the industrial control systems community.</summary>
</bill>
