<bill session="117" type="sr" number="693" updated="2023-08-15T14:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing the contributions of African Americans to the musical heritage of the United States and the need for greater access to music education for African-American students and designating June 2022 as African-American Music Appreciation Month.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the contributions of African Americans to the musical heritage of the United States and the need for greater access to music education for African-American students and designating June 2022 as African-American Music Appreciation Month.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3166" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="sr" number="305" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="1215" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T14:38:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution designates June 2022 as African-American Music Appreciation Month.

Further, the resolution recognizes

 the contributions of African Americans to the musical heritage of the United States; the wide array of talented and popular African-American musical artists, composers, songwriters, and musicians who are underrecognized for contributions to music; the achievements, talent, and hard work of African-American pioneer artists and the obstacles that those artists overcame to gain recognition; and the need for African-American students to have greater access to, and participation in, music education in schools across the United States. The resolution also recognizes Black History Month and African-American Music Appreciation Month as an important time to celebrate the impact of the African-American musical heritage on the musical heritage of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
