<bill session="118" type="h" number="1187" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Civil Aviation Security and Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil Aviation Security and Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the requirements for the registration of certain aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-02T20:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Civil Aviation Security and Safety Act of 2023

This bill revises and sets forth new requirements for the registration of civilian aircraft.

For example, the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must conduct a comprehensive review of the process under which it reviews and approves aircraft registration applications and dealer certificates.

The bill revises application requirements for aircraft registration to include name, address, date of birth, driver's license or pilot's license (or both if applicable), and applicant photos in the submission of an application.

Additionally, the FAA must

 review Office of Foreign Assets Control sanctions data on applicants; ensure that all eligibility and registration information in an application is true and correct before issuing a registration or dealer certificate; increase the fees for registration to a level sufficient to cover the costs to collect and verify applicant data and the costs of inflation; provide to the Drug Enforcement Administration declarations of its international operations to maximize the ability of federal national security and law enforcement agencies in preventing use of the Civil Aviation Registry for illicit purposes and detecting trade-based money laundering and other cross-border schemes; implement an enforcement mechanism for suspending and revoking dealer certificates; and establish an Aircraft Registry Task Force to examine national security, law enforcement, and public safety issues related to civil aircraft registration and develop solutions to mitigate security and safety risks and increase interagency cooperation.</summary>
</bill>
