<bill session="110" type="h" number="1795" updated="2023-01-11T19:49:47Z">
  <state datetime="2007-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="1478" relation="text similarities"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="952" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-11T22:44:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Morris K.Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental and Native American Public Policy Act of 1992 to: (1) require the Morris K. Udall Scholarship and Excellence in National Environmental Policy Foundation to award grants to the Udall Center for Studies in Public Policy at the University of Arizona to develop resources to train Native American and Alaska Native professionals in health care and public policy; (2) revise requirements regarding limitations on program priorities and require that at least 50% of the funds provided to the Center be spent for Native American education and policy activities; (3) provide for the Foundation to pay a limited amount for official reception and representation expenses; (4) prohibit any committee or group organized by the U.S. Institute for Environmental Conflict Resolution in connection with the services it provides pursuant to the Act from being subject to the provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act, provided that the committee or group is neither established nor controlled by another agency of the executive branch; and (5) instruct the Foundation to carry out the Act's provisions without regard to federal law governing appointments in the competitive service.</summary>
</bill>
