<bill session="117" type="h" number="3840" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening MSI Competitiveness in Research and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the National Science Foundation to establish a capacity-building program for developing universities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening MSI Competitiveness in Research and Innovation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2021-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-20T23:48:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Strengthening MSI Competitiveness in Research and Innovation Act

This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish a program to make competitive awards to eligible institutions to support the mission of the NSF and to build institutional research capacity at eligible institutions.

To be eligible to receive an award, an institution shall be

 a historically Black college or university; a Tribal College or University; a minority-serving institution; or an institution of higher education with an established science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM) capacity building program focused on traditionally underrepresented populations in STEM, including Native Hawaiians, Alaska Natives, and Indians. Each eligible institution shall have not more than $50 million in annual federally-financed research and development expenditures for science and engineering as reported through the National Science Foundation Higher Education Research and Development Survey.</summary>
</bill>
