<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>849</number>
    <updateDate>2020-02-10T16:51:51Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2020-02-10T16:51:51Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-02-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
        <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed10</systemCode>
            <name>Workforce Protections Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2009-03-23T18:47:06Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-02-04T15:04:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed10</systemCode>
            <name>Workforce Protections Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsed00</systemCode>
            <name>Education and the Workforce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000725</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Miller, George [D-CA-7]</fullName>
        <firstName>GEORGE</firstName>
        <lastName>MILLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>7</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001252</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Barrow, John [D-GA-12]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Barrow</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>GA</state>
        <district>12</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000738</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Woolsey, Lynn C. [D-CA-6]</fullName>
        <firstName>LYNN</firstName>
        <lastName>WOOLSEY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <district>6</district>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-02-04</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Labor</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor standards</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Worker safety and health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Labor and Employment</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-02-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-03-02T22:48:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate an interim final standard regulating combustible dusts, which shall apply to manufacturing, processing, blending, conveying, repackaging, and handling of combustible particulate solids and their dusts (including organic dusts, plastics, sulfur, wood, rubber, furniture, textiles, pesticides, pharmaceuticals, fibers, dyes, coal, metals, and fossil fuels), but shall not apply to processes already covered by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration's (OSHA) standard on grain facilities.</p><p>Requires such standard to provide requirements for: (1) a hazard assessment to identify, evaluate, and control combustible dust hazards; (2) a written program that includes provisions for hazardous dust inspection, testing, hot work, ignition control, and housekeeping; (3) engineering controls, administrative controls, and operating procedures; (4) housekeeping to prevent accumulation of combustible dust in places of employment in depths that can present explosion, deflagration, or other fire hazards, including safe methods of dust removal; (5) employee participation in hazard assessment, development of and compliance with the written program, and other elements of hazard management; and (6) providing safety and health information and annual training to employees.</p><p>Provides an exemption from otherwise applicable rulemaking requirements for the interim standard but not for the final standard.</p><p>Provides that such interim standard shall have the legal effect of an occupational safety and health standard and shall apply until a final standard becomes effective.</p><p>Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate a final occupational safety and health standard regulating combustible dust explosions that has the same scope and worker protection provisions as the interim rule and provides requirements for: (1) managing change of dust producing materials, technology, equipment, staffing, and procedures; (2) building design, such as explosion venting, ducting, and sprinklers; and (3) explosion protection, including separation and segregation of the hazard. Requires the final rule to include relevant and appropriate provisions of the National Fire Protection Association combustible dust standards.</p><p>Requires the Secretary to revise the hazard communications standard to amend the definition of &quot;physical hazard&quot; to include &quot;a combustible dust&quot; as an additional example of such a hazard. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Worker Protection Against Combustible Dust Explosions and Fires Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To require the Secretary of Labor to issue interim and final occupational safety and health standards regarding worker exposure to combustible dust, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2009-02-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr849ih/xml/BILLS-111hr849ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-03-23</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
