<bill session="117" type="s" number="5107" updated="2023-07-31T19:00:30Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Data on Interactions and Accountability for Law Enforcement with Individuals with Disabilities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data on Interactions and Accountability for Law Enforcement with Individuals with Disabilities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the collection of data regarding interactions between law enforcement officers and individuals with disabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-31T18:50:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Data on Interactions and Accountability for Law Enforcement with Individuals with Disabilities Act

This bill expands activities to collect data about interactions between law enforcement officers and individuals with disabilities.

In particular, the bill establishes a temporary advisory council within the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a methodology for collecting and reporting data on interactions between law enforcement officers and individuals with disabilities. HHS must award a grant to an independent research organization or institution of higher education to test the validity and reliability of the council's methodology. The council must also provide the Department of Justice with best practices to collect disability status in cases where a death or injury occurred because of an interaction with law enforcement.

The bill also requires certain federal initiatives that collect information about interactions with law enforcement (e.g., the National Use-of-Force Data Collection) to include disability status.

Further, the Bureau of Justice must award a grant to an independent third-party organization (e.g., an institution of higher education) for identifying trends using certain survey data in violence committed by law enforcement officers against individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
