<bill session="117" type="s" number="3612" updated="2023-03-30T14:50:00Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOCK Act 2.0</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOCK Act 2.0</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 and the STOCK Act to require certain senior officials to report payments received from the Federal Government, to improve the filing and disclosure of financial disclosures by Members of Congress, congressional staff, very senior employees, and others, and to ban stock trading for certain senior Government officials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6694" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-27T15:52:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">STOCK Act 2.0

This bill expands restrictions on investment practices and requirements for financial disclosures that apply to specified high-level government officials.

In particular, the bill bars individual stock trading by (1) Members of Congress, (2) the President and Vice President, (3) Supreme Court Justices, (4) governors of the Federal Reserve Board, and (5) presidents and vice presidents of Federal Reserve banks.

Additionally, the bill requires financial disclosures to include loans, contracts, and other benefits (excluding salaries, compensation, or tax refunds) from the federal government. It also requires additional officials, namely judges and senior leaders of Federal Reserve banks, to make the disclosures.

Further, the bill directs supervising ethics agencies to make the disclosures publicly available in formats that are easily searchable, sortable, and downloadable.</summary>
</bill>
