<bill session="117" type="s" number="2361" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the budget-neutral demonstration program for energy and water conservation at multifamily residential units, to establish a green retrofit program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Green Retrofits Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Green Retrofits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4929" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-23T20:25:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Green Retrofits Act

This bill reauthorizes a Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) water and energy conservation demonstration program through FY2027. Prior to its FY2019 expiration, the program allowed HUD to execute agreements with specified entities to reduce utility costs through improvements at multifamily subsidized housing projects.

The reauthorization makes a number of changes to the original program, including increasing the cap on eligible residential units from 20,000 to 35,000 and extending the cap on agreement terms from 12 to 15 years.

The bill also creates a green retrofit program that allows HUD to provide grants or loans to owners of multifamily subsidized housing projects. The grants or loans must be used to perform in-home health and green retrofits to the property.</summary>
</bill>
