<bill session="116" type="s" number="1748" updated="2022-11-01T06:32:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Furthering Access and Networks for Sports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Furthering Access and Networks for Sports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to decrease the frequency of sports blackouts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-17T18:02:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Furthering Access and Networks for Sports Act 

This bill&#160;makes the antitrust laws&#160;applicable to joint agreements among professional football, baseball, basketball, or hockey teams covering the telecasting of sports contests to the extent that a league of clubs does not (1) expressly prohibit sponsored telecast licensees and any video licensee from intentionally removing the live content of such league from a multichannel video programming distributor during, or related to a negotiation regarding, carriage of the league's games by such distributor; or (2) make a sponsored telecast of a game that is played in the home territory of a member club available to consumers over the internet in any territory in which the game is not available for private viewing through a local television broadcast station or a such a distributor.

The bill repeals the exception that allows the antitrust exemption for such a joint agreement that prohibits televising games within the home territory of a member club on a day when such club is playing at home.</summary>
</bill>
