<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="709" updated="2022-02-03T06:02:28Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2551" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-07-21T21:30:08-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-07-21"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC. 211. None of the funds made available in this Act for Members' representational allowances or for official mail for committees and leadership offices of the House of Representatives may be used for any mailing that does not bear the official letterhead of the Member, committee, or office involved, other than a publication or document produced by another office of the Government or by an office of a State or local government that is included with such a mailing.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 112-173 to require all mail funded by the Members' representational allowance and from funds for official mail for committees and leadership offices of the House bear the official letterhead of the Member, committee, or office involved.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-07-21T21:30:08-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="fail">
      <text>On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A013) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21T21:22:14-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5370-5371" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5370" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21T21:30:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A013) Failed by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21T21:30:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21T21:22:14-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A013) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5370-5371" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5370" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-21">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
