<bill session="111" type="h" number="6064" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commuter Bill of Rights Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide certain rights to commuters who ride public transportation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commuter Bill of Rights Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2010-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-03T16:14:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Commuter Bill of Rights Act of 2010 - Establishes the Commuter Transit Rights Commission.

Requires the Commission to make recommendations to the Secretary of Transportation in the form of a Commuter Bill of Rights which includes: (1) a list of situations in which a provider of public transportation will implement its contingency plan during an emergency; (2) recommendations for minimum standards that a plan must meet, including the provision of food, water, restrooms, ventilation, and medical services, as well as the distribution of certain critical information to commuters on a disabled or delayed train or other transit vehicle; and (3) recommendations for federal regulations on commuter safety during emergencies.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide competitive grants to providers of public transportation to develop and implement contingency plans that fulfill the Bill of Rights.

Requires the Secretary to review the Bill of Rights and issue regulations to require providers of public transportation to comply with the Bill's recommended standards.

Requires the Secretary to use the Bill of Rights to develop related federal policies.

Authorizes the Secretary to assess penalties or sanctions against providers of public transportation who fail to submit, obtain approval of, or adhere to its contingency plan.

Requires the Secretary to establish a consumer hotline telephone number for public transportation complaints.</summary>
</bill>
