<bill session="108" type="s" number="1516" updated="2023-01-15T10:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to further the purposes of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 by directing the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to carry out an assessment and demonstration program to control salt cedar and Russian olive, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further the purposes of the Reclamation Projects Authorization and Adjustment Act of 1992 by directing the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the commissioner of Reclamation, to carry out an assessment and demonstration program to assess potential increases in water availability for Bureau of Reclamation projects and other uses through control of salt cedar and Russian olive.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Salt Cedar Control Demonstration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000109" joined="2004-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2004-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2004-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10638"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10638-10639" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-211.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-235.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-03-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="445">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 445.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-05-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5844-5845" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5844-5845" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20T10:04:31-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20T18:44:41-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2707" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Aquatic pests"/>
    <term name="Aquatic plants"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fibers"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revegetation"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-19T18:30:19Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Salt Cedar and Russian Olive Control Demonstration Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) , acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation and in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Defense to carry out a salt cedar (Tamarix spp) and Russian olive (Elaeagnus angustifolia) assessment and demonstration program to: (1) assess the extent of the infestation by salt cedar and Russian olive trees in the western United States; (2) to demonstrate strategic solutions for the long-term management of such trees and the reestablishment of native vegetation; and (3) assess economic means to dispose of biomass created as a result of removal of those trees.

Requires the Secretary to complete an assessment of the extent of the infestation on public and private land. Provides that, in addition to describing the acreage of and severity of infestation, the assessment shall: (1) consider existing research on methods to control salt cedar and Russian olive trees; (2) consider the feasibility of reducing water consumption by such trees; (3) consider methods of and challenges associated with the revegetation or restoration of infested land; and (4) estimate the costs of destruction of such trees, related biomass removal, and revegetation or restoration and maintenance of the infested land.

Instructs the Secretary to identify and document long-term management and funding strategies that: (1) could be implemented by Federal, State, and private land managers in addressing the infestation; and (2) should be tested as components of the five demonstration projects specified below.

Directs the Secretary to establish a program that selects and funds at least five demonstration projects proposed by and implemented in collaboration with Federal agencies, units of State and local government, national laboratories, Indian tribes, institutions of higher education, individuals, organizations, or soil and water conservation districts to demonstrate and evaluate the most effective methods of controlling salt cedar and Russian olive trees. Limits the Federal cost share of such projects not carried out on Federal land to: (1) 75 percent for each of the first five years of the project; and (2) for the purpose of long-term monitoring, 100 percent for each of such five-year extensions as the Secretary may grant. Permits the non-Federal share of the costs of such a project to be provided as in-kind contributions, including services provided by a State agency or any other public or private partner. Lists project requirements.

Directs the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture, to complete an analysis of economic means to use or dispose of biomass created as a result of removal of salt cedar and Russian olive trees. Requires such analysis to: (1) determine conditions under which removal of biomass is economically viable; (2) consider and build upon existing research by the Department of Agriculture and other agencies on beneficial uses of salt cedar and Russian olive tree fiber; and (3) consider economic development opportunities, including manufacture of wood products using biomass resulting from the demonstration projects under this Act as a means of defraying costs of control.

Sets monetary limits on costs under this Act and provides that activities under this Act, and any of the five demonstration projects that are carried out on Federal land, shall be at full Federal expense.

Directs the Secretary to subject the assessment, the identification and documentation of long-term management strategies, the projects, and the analysis to independent review.

Requires the Secretary to submit to Congress annual reports describing the results of carrying out this Act, including a synopsis of any such review and details of the manner and purposes for which funds are expended.

Instructs the Secretary to facilitate public access to all information that results from carrying out this Act.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-235</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
