<bill session="108" type="s" number="1133" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Programs Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the authorities of the Department of Veterans Affairs relating to compensation, dependency and indemnity compensation, pension, education benefits, life insurance benefits, and memorial benefits, to improve the administration of benefits for veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Programs Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7031"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S7031-7033" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government life insurance"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-09T18:41:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Programs Improvement Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to increase, as of December 1, 2003, the rates of veterans' disability compensation, additional compensation for dependents, the clothing allowance for certain disabled adult children, and dependency and indemnity compensation for surviving spouses and children.

Makes the effective date for the award of death pension the same as that for the award of death compensation or dependency and indemnity compensation.

Excludes lump-sum insurance proceeds from income for purposes of eligibility for veterans' pensions.

Prohibits the payment of veterans' disability compensation for an alcohol- or drug-abuse related disability even if the the alcohol or drug abuse is secondary to a service-connected disability.

Provides alternative beneficiaries for National Service Life Insurance and United States Government Life Insurance proceeds when the first beneficiary does not make a claim.

Provides burial benefit eligibility for a veteran's surviving spouse who remarries following the veteran's death.

Makes permanent the authority for the State cemetery grants program.

Repeals the Department of Veterans Affairs Education Loan program.

Includes self-employment training under the Montgomery GI Bill.</summary>
</bill>
