<bill session="118" type="h" number="4367" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:42Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28T23:17:47-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-28T23:17:47-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000295"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-27">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-123, by Mr. Joyce (OH).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-27" calendar="Union" number="95">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 95.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26T10:29:47-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 723 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:56:56-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 723.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4628-4649" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4633-4644" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:57:01-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:59:04-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 723 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:59:09-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Russ Fulcher to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T14:59:20-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4367.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T15:47:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Joyce (OH) amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:05:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:12:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:20:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Arrington amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:30:07-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Joyce (OH) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:30:28-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T16:30:56-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4367 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:32:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4669-4711" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:32:20-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:33:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Correa amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:39:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Correa amendment No. 13, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Correa demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:45:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:46:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Wasserman Schultz amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:55:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Wasserman Shultz amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Wasserman Schultz demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:56:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 24.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T18:59:43-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 24, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Burchett demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:00:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:07:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Escobar amendment No. 25, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Ms. Escobar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:08:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tony Gonzales (TX) amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:12:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:20:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Clyde demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:21:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:30:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:39:25-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 39, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Biggs demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:40:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 40.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:46:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 40, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Biggs demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:48:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:55:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 41, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T19:56:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:04:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 42, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Biggs demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:05:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:12:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 43, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Biggs demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:13:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:33:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:37:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:41:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:50:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:58:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 48, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T20:59:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:04:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 49, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:05:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:14:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 50, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:15:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Castro (TX) amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:27:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Castro (TX) amendment No. 51, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the noes had prevailed. Mr. Castro (TX) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:28:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:37:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:45:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T21:55:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:01:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:06:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:09:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:16:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:23:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 64, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Nehls demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:24:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:28:17-04:00">
      <text>VACATING DEMAND FOR A RECORDED VOTE - Mr. Joyce (OH) asked unanimous consent that the request for a recorded vote on the Burchett amendment No. 24 be vacated to the end that the amendment be withdrawn. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T22:29:37-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on agreeing to the amendments to H.R. 4367, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:46:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:51:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 66, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:52:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:54:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 67, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:55:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 69.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:57:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 69, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cuellar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27T23:57:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:02:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:04:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pfluger amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:10:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:14:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:21:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 74, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Joyce (OH) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:22:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:27:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 76.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:33:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 77.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:37:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:38:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 79.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:42:33-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 730 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5692, H.R. 4365 and H.R. 4367. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5692, under a closed rule. The resolution provides for 30 minutes of general debate on the bill H.R. 5692 and one motion to recommit. The resolution provides that further consideration of H.R. 4365, the further amendments specified in section 3 shall be considered as adopted and the resolution provides for further consideration of H.R. 4367, the further amendment specified in section 5 shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:42:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malliotakis amendment No. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:47:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Joyce (OH) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:47:44-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T00:48:14-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4367 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:33:45-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 730 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:33:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4799-4802" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:34:11-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:50:01-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4367.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:50:58-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:51:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 4367 would be postponed</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:05:09-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the House resumed consideration of H.R. 4367.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:05:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:05:39-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:06:19-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Escobar moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:06:29-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:12:16-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 218 (Roll no. 504).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="505" datetime="2023-09-28T23:17:47-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 220 - 208 (Roll no. 505).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:17:49-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:30:18-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4367.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2625" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="723" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="730" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h435"/>
    <amendment number="h434"/>
    <amendment number="h433"/>
    <amendment number="h432"/>
    <amendment number="h431"/>
    <amendment number="h430"/>
    <amendment number="h429"/>
    <amendment number="h428"/>
    <amendment number="h427"/>
    <amendment number="h426"/>
    <amendment number="h425"/>
    <amendment number="h424"/>
    <amendment number="h423"/>
    <amendment number="h422"/>
    <amendment number="h421"/>
    <amendment number="h420"/>
    <amendment number="h419"/>
    <amendment number="h418"/>
    <amendment number="h417"/>
    <amendment number="h416"/>
    <amendment number="h415"/>
    <amendment number="h414"/>
    <amendment number="h413"/>
    <amendment number="h412"/>
    <amendment number="h411"/>
    <amendment number="h410"/>
    <amendment number="h409"/>
    <amendment number="h408"/>
    <amendment number="h407"/>
    <amendment number="h406"/>
    <amendment number="h405"/>
    <amendment number="h404"/>
    <amendment number="h403"/>
    <amendment number="h402"/>
    <amendment number="h401"/>
    <amendment number="h400"/>
    <amendment number="h399"/>
    <amendment number="h398"/>
    <amendment number="h397"/>
    <amendment number="h396"/>
    <amendment number="h395"/>
    <amendment number="h394"/>
    <amendment number="h393"/>
    <amendment number="h392"/>
    <amendment number="h391"/>
    <amendment number="h390"/>
    <amendment number="h389"/>
    <amendment number="h388"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-10-05T16:43:20Z" status="Passed House">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations to DHS for Departmental Management, Intelligence, Situational Awareness, and Oversight, including

 the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management; the Management Directorate; Intelligence, Analysis, and Situational Awareness; and the Office of the Inspector General. In addition, the bill provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations, including

 U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, the Transportation Security Administration, the U.S. Coast Guard, and the U.S. Secret Service. The bill provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery, including

 the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA). The bill provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services, including

 U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers, the Science and Technology Directorate, and the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-123</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
