<bill session="117" type="h" number="6378" updated="2022-12-30T03:33:58Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Control Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to notify the Governor of a State prior to the date on which any alien without lawful status under the immigration laws is transported to, housed in, or resettled in such State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000103" joined="2022-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-02T16:37:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Control Act

This bill imposes requirements on the placement in a state of a non-U.S. national (alien under federal law) without lawful immigration status.

Specifically, before such an individual may be settled in, housed in, or transported to a state or political subdivision within a state, the Department of Homeland Security must notify the office of the governor of that state and the office of the chief executive of the political subdivision. No federal funds may be used for the proposed settling, housing, or transporting if (1) the state governor's office does not approve of the action, or (2) the political subdivision in question has a law or resolution prohibiting or disapproving of such an action.

These requirements shall not apply to the use of federal funds to transport or detain such an individual for civil or criminal law enforcement purposes.</summary>
</bill>
