<bill session="116" type="h" number="6880" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Medical Manufacturing Library Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to coordinate the development of plans, designs, and guidance relating to the production, in accordance with other applicable law, of certain homeland security-critical supplies to address potential national emergencies and disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Medical Manufacturing Library Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001123" joined="2020-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2020-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2020-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2020-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response, and Recovery.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-17T14:42:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Medical Manufacturing Library Act of 2020

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to coordinate the development of plans, designs, and guidance relating to the production of certain homeland security-critical supplies to address potential national emergencies and disasters.

Specifically, FEMA shall coordinate with other relevant federal departments and agencies

 to identify categories of homeland security-critical supplies that would be needed to address potential national emergencies or disasters, including any such public health emergency, terrorist incident, armed attack, or cyber attack; to develop plans, designs, and guidance relating to the production of the categories of homeland security-critical supplies identified to address the respective national emergencies and disasters, including such production by nontraditional manufacturers; and based on such final plans, designs, and guidance, to enter into such contingent arrangements with governmental and private entities to expedite the production of homeland security-critical supplies in the event of a national emergency or disaster. FEMA shall (1) publish each final plan, design, or guidance that is developed on a public website, except for protected information; and (2) at least every two years, coordinate the review and revision of each plan, design, and guidance in effect.</summary>
</bill>
