<bill session="117" type="h" number="2945" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VR&amp;E NEED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for an extension of the period of eligibility under the Department of Veterans Affairs training and rehabilitation program for veterans with service-connected disabilities by reason of school closures due to emergency and other situations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Readiness and Employment National Emergency Extended Deadline Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VR&amp;E NEED Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2167" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1935" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1936" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-07T19:14:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Veteran Readiness and Employment National Emergency Extended Deadline Act or the VR&amp;E NEED Act

This bill extends a veteran's eligibility for the Veteran Readiness and Employment program when educational institutions are temporarily or permanently closed due to an emergency situation, or there is another reason that prevents a veteran from participating.

Specifically, the period of eligibility must not run during the period the veteran is prevented from participating in the program. The period must resume on a date, determined by the Department of Veterans Affairs, that is not earlier than the first day after the veteran is able to resume participation and not later than 90 days after that day.</summary>
</bill>
