<bill session="117" type="hr" number="1333" updated="2023-02-02T04:45:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ride-Along Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ride-Along Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Requiring Members of the House of Representatives to serve one shift in a passenger seat of a law enforcement vehicle observing the work day of a local law enforcement officer once during the first term of a Member in the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001119"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-02T00:27:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Ride-Along Resolution

This resolution requires any Member of the House of Representatives serving a first term as a Member of the House to participate in one shift in a passenger seat of a law enforcement vehicle observing the work day of a local law enforcement officer in the respective congressional district of the Member not later than one year after the date such Member is sworn in.

The Committee on House Administration shall promulgate regulations to carry out this resolution.

If the Committee on Ethics determines that a Member has not satisfied the requirement to participate in such a ride-along by the deadline, the committee must

 publish the name of the Member on a readily available, public list on the committee's website; and cause to be published in the Congressional Record information with respect to the failure of the Member to satisfy such requirement.</summary>
</bill>
