<bill session="111" type="h" number="4229" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Borrowers' Right to Inspect Closing Documents Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to ensure that borrowers under federally related mortgage loans have an opportunity to inspect closing documents.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Borrowers' Right to Inspect Closing Documents Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001253"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001234" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2009-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001077" joined="2010-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2010-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000568" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2010-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001140" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2010-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2010-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2010-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000801" joined="2010-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-12T16:29:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Borrowers' Right to Inspect Closing Documents Act of 2009 - Amends the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 (RESPA) to revise procedures governing the furnishing of closing documents to borrowers.

Requires the lender to furnish to the settlement agent, at least four business days before the scheduled date of a real estate settlement, the completed promissory note, the mortgage instrument, and all other items needed to complete the uniform settlement statement, the final Truth-in-Lending Act disclosure, and the final closing instructions.

Requires the settlement agent to furnish the borrower, at least three business days before the scheduled settlement date, with the completed documents and the completed uniform settlement statement, as long as the lender has timely provided the agent with those items.

Shields the settlement agent from liability for the lender's noncompliance with this Act. Cites circumstances under which the settlement agent may correct the uniform settlement statement and related documents prior to the scheduled settlement date.

Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to exempt settlements from the requirements of this Act in certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
