<bill session="111" type="s" number="1519" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:13Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the eradication and control of nutria in Maryland, Louisiana, and other coastal States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2009-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2009-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-03">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Water and Wildlife. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 111-182.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-05-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="367">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 367.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEV15" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="Fisheries, Water, and Wildlife" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3850" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Chesapeake Bay"/>
    <term name="Delaware"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-08T13:59:27Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Nutria Eradication and Control Act of 2009 - (Sec. 4) Establishes a nutria eradication program under which the Secretary of the Interior may provide financial assistance on a cost-sharing basis to Maryland, Louisiana, and the "coastal states" (Delaware, Oregon, Virginia, and Washington) to eradicate or control nutria and restore nutria-damaged wetland. (States that the program goal in Maryland is nutria eradication.)

Requires the Maryland program to consist of management, research, and public education activities carried out in accordance with the United States Fish and Wildlife Service's document "Eradication Strategies for Nutria in the Chesapeake and Delaware Bay Watersheds."

(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary and the National Invasive Species Council to: (1) give consideration to the report of the Louisiana Department of Wildlife and Fisheries entitled "Nutria in Louisiana," and the updated version of the "Eradication Strategies for the Nutria in the Chesapeake and Delaware Bay Watersheds" document; (2) continue, in cooperation with the Louisiana Department of Wildlife and Fisheries and the Maryland Department of Natural Resources, a long-term nutria control or eradication program; and (3) develop, in cooperation with the Delaware Department of Natural Resources and Environmental Control, the Virginia Department of Game and Inland Fisheries, the Oregon Department of Fish and Wildlife, and the Washington Department of Fish and Wildlife, long-term nutria control or eradication programs.

(Sec. 6) Authorizes specified FY2010-FY2014 appropriations for: (1) Maryland and Louisiana; and (2) the coastal states.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-182</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
