<bill session="111" type="h" number="5792" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:55Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Manufacture Renewable Energy Systems: Make it in America Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require 100 percent domestic content in green technologies purchased by Federal agencies or by States with Federal funds and in property eligible for the renewable energy production or investment tax credits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacture Renewable Energy Systems: Make it in America Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000099" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000600" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001178" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-30T23:01:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Manufacture Renewable Energy Systems: Make it in America Act of 2010 - Authorizes federal acquisition of, or the provision of federal funds to states for purchase of, only green technologies that are 100% manufactured in the United States from articles, materials, or supplies that are 100% grown, produced, or manufactured in the United States beginning in the fourth fiscal year after enactment of this Act. Provides that such percentage shall be 30% in the first fiscal year after enactment, 50% in the second fiscal year, and 80% in the third fiscal year.

Defines "green technologies" to mean renewable energy and energy efficiency products and services that: (1) reduce dependence on unreliable sources of energy by encouraging the use of sustainable biomass, wind, small-scale hydroelectric, solar, geothermal, and other renewable energy and energy efficiency products and services; and (2) use hybrid fossil-renewable energy systems.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to prohibit treating any facility originally placed in service after December 31, 2013, as a qualified facility for purposes of the renewable energy production and investment tax credits unless such facility is 100% manufactured in the United States from articles, materials, or supplies that are 100% grown, produced, or manufactured in the United States. Provides that such percentage shall be 30% for a facility placed in service during 2011, 50% for a facility placed in service during 2012, and 80% for a facility placed in service during 2013.</summary>
</bill>
