<bill session="119" type="h" number="582" updated="2025-05-07T20:12:03Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Protection and Wildfire Resilience Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Protection and Wildfire Resilience Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a community protection and wildfire resilience grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001241" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-07T20:02:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Protection and Wildfire Resilience Act

This bill establishes a wildfire resilience grant program within the U.S. Fire Administration (USFA), expands an existing U.S. Forest Service (USFS) wildfire risk reduction grant program, and requires the USFA and Government Accountability Office (GAO) to produce various reports and resources relating to wildfire resilience.

Specifically, the bill requires the USFA to award grants to state or local governments, tribes, volunteer fire departments, or groups thereof for developing a community protection and wildfire resilience plan or carrying out projects that support strategies described in such a plan.&#160;

Also, under current law, the USFS&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Community Wildfire Defense Grant program provides grants to at-risk communities for implementing wildfire risk reduction, including reducing hazardous fuels and restoring fire-adapted ecosystems, but excluding activities such as construction and home hardening (e.g., roof upgrades, fire-resistant siding). The bill expands the eligible project types to include construction or modification of a structure to increase fire-resistance and modification of a structure or the adjacent area to reduce exposure to contact with wildfire.&#160;

Additionally, the bill requires the USFA to develop and publish a map depicting communities at risk from wildfire. The&#160;USFA must also provide a report evaluating and ensuring public entities have radio communication capabilities adequate for wildfire management. The bill also requires the GAO to publish a study on potential certification for community protection and wildfire resilience plans, and a report assessing impediments for federal wildfire resilience programs.</summary>
</bill>
