<bill session="119" type="h" number="1538" updated="2025-11-08T09:06:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Delivering for Rural Seniors Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delivering for Rural Seniors Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agriculture and Consumer Protection Act of 1973 to establish a pilot grant program to award grants to facilitate home delivery of commodities under the commodity supplemental food program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001327" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2025-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2025-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2025-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2025-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2025-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2025-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000136" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-08-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-27T15:25:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Delivering for Rural Seniors Act of 2025

This bill directs the Food and Nutrition Service (FNS) to award competitive grants to state agencies under a home delivery pilot program for participants in the Commodity Supplemental Food Program (CSFP).&#160;

As background,&#160;the&#160;CSFP works to improve the health of low-income persons at least 60 years of age by supplementing their diets with nutritious Department of Agriculture foods.

Under the pilot program, a state agency must distribute grant funds to an eligible entity (i.e., a local agency or subdistributing agency) to operate projects that facilitate home delivery of commodities to CSFP participants. Grant funds may be used for costs associated with

transportation and distribution of commodities to CSFP participants,staffing required to operate home delivery services, andhome delivery outreach to CSFP participants or potential participants.A state agency must prioritize eligible entities that serve CSFP participants who reside in rural areas.

A state agency must also submit an annual report to FNS about the project, including best practices regarding the use of home delivery to improve the effectiveness of the CSFP.</summary>
</bill>
