<bill session="118" type="s" number="10" updated="2025-01-14T17:02:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Clinician Appreciation, Recruitment, Education, Expansion, and Retention Support (CAREERS) Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Clinician Appreciation, Recruitment, Education, Expansion, and Retention Support (CAREERS) Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the workforce of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="693" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="55" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-02T16:22:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">VA Clinician Appreciation, Recruitment, Education, Expansion, and Retention Support (CAREERS) Act of 2023

This bill addresses Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) personnel matters and the training, recruitment, and retention of VA health care employees.

Among other requirements, the VA must

 expand various staff training efforts and programs; comply with certain notification and staffing requirements when a VA medical center director is on detail; prescribe a system of pay for individuals appointed as directors of medical centers and directors of Veterans Integrated Service Networks; and establish a consolidated annual leave account for certain VA employees with restored leave during 2020, 2021, and 2022. The bill also

 authorizes the VA to waive pay limitations for employees of the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) who are performing mission critical work; increases the maximum amount of incentive pay for pharmacist executives; modifies the special pay authority for nurse executives and the administration of pay for VA physicians, podiatrists, optometrists, and dentists; authorizes a waiver of certain licensure requirements for psychologists and mental health counselors in certain circumstances; requires the Inspector General of the VA to study and report on the use of direct hire authority, the contributions made by the use of such authority, and any vulnerabilities or inconsistencies with respect to the use of such authority; includes VA police officers as law enforcement officers for purposes of the federal retirement system; and requires the Government Accountability Office to report on human resources modernization conducted by the VHA.</summary>
</bill>
