<bill session="116" type="s" number="3901" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AI Scholarship-for-Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AI Scholarship-for-Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal artificial intelligence scholarship-for-service program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2020-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-10T15:23:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">AI Scholarship-for-Service Act

This bill establishes a federal artificial intelligence (AI) scholarship-for-service program to recruit and train AI professionals to lead and support AI in federal, state, local, and tribal governments.

Specifically, the National Science Foundation must establish criteria to designate qualified institutions of higher education (IHEs) as eligible to participate in the program. Such criteria must include (1) measures of an IHE's demonstrated excellence in the education of students in AI; and (2) measures of an IHE's ability to attract and retain a diverse and nontraditional student population in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.

Further, the program must (1) provide scholarships through qualified IHEs to students who are enrolled in programs of study related to AI, (2) provide scholarship recipients with internship opportunities, (3) prioritize the employment placement of scholarship recipients in executive agencies, (4) identify opportunities to promote multidisciplinary programs of study that integrate basic or advanced AI training with other fields of study, and (5) support education research programs to train AI researchers and practitioners.

Additionally, the post-award employment obligations of a scholarship recipient must include three years of work for an executive agency; Congress; an interstate agency; a state, local, or tribal government; or a government-affiliated nonprofit that is considered to be critical infrastructure. A scholarship recipient who completes less than the required three years of service must repay the scholarship, or the scholarship must&#160;be treated as a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan that is subject to repayment.</summary>
</bill>
