<bill session="111" type="h" number="5816" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:54Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commercial Real Estate Stabilization Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a commercial real estate credit guarantee program to empower community banks and other lenders to make loans while stabilizing the value of small denomination commercial real estate assets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Real Estate Stabilization Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000370" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000553" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001146" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2010-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-04T20:48:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Commercial Real Estate Stabilization Act of 2010 - Establishes an Oversight Board to: (1) advise the Secretary of the Treasury on the Commercial Real Estate Credit Guarantee Program (established by this Act); and (2) report quarterly to Congress on the Program and on the current state of the credit system in the United States with respect to commercial lending, small business, and commercial real estate lending.

Directs the Secretary to establish the Commercial Real Estate Credit Guarantee Program, under which the Secretary shall guarantee payments of interest and principal on an approved credit instrument.

Requires 50% of the Program to be used for small- and mid-sized institutions.

Permits loans for either owner-occupied or nonowner-occupied commercial real estate.

States that guarantees issued under this Act constitute general obligations of the United States, for which the full faith and credit of the United States is pledged.

Expresses the intent of Congress that the Program be utilized when such utilization proves beneficial, and not be unduly inhibited by concerns related to potential unfavorable regulatory accounting treatment.</summary>
</bill>
