<bill session="118" type="h" number="1021" updated="2025-11-18T18:23:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to remove or permanently conceal the name of Francis Newlands on the grounds of the memorial fountain located at Chevy Chase Circle in the District of Columbia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E123"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="417" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-28T20:56:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Francis G. Newlands Memorial Removal Act 

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to remove or permanently conceal the name of Francis Newlands on the grounds of the memorial fountain located at Chevy Chase Circle in the District of Columbia and take other specified actions.

Specifically, Interior must

 remove the brass plaque bearing the name Senator Francis G. Newlands from the grounds of the memorial fountain located at Chevy Chase Circle in the District; remove from the south end of the memorial fountain's face, the stone, tablet-like projection bearing the name of Francis Griffith Newlands and a related inscription; remove or permanently conceal the name Newlands Memorial Fountain carved into the upper face of the memorial fountain's coping stones; and offer the items removed to the descendants of Francis Griffith Newlands for a 60-day period, and if not claimed within that period, direct the removed items to be maintained by the National Park Service as federal property and accessioned into the Rock Creek Park museum collection.</summary>
</bill>
