<bill session="117" type="h" number="7509" updated="2023-09-06T19:30:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wild Rogue Conservation and Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wild Rogue Conservation and Recreation Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand certain land administered by the Bureau of Land Management and Forest Service in the State of Oregon as wilderness and a national recreation area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1589" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-19T14:30:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Wild Rogue Conservation and Recreation Enhancement Act

This bill designates specified Bureau of Land Management land in Oregon as the Rogue Canyon National Recreation Area and adds approximately 59,512 acres of federal land to the Wild Rogue Wilderness.

The Department of the Interior, for public land, and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), for National Forest System land, must conduct a wildfire risk assessment that covers the recreation area, the Wild Rogue Wilderness, and any adjacent federal land. Interior and USDA must develop plans to mitigate wildfire risk to communities located near the land.

No new permanent or temporary roads shall be constructed within the recreation areas except as necessary for public safety or to implement the wildfire mitigation plan.

 Interior or USDA, as appropriate, may take measures within such wilderness additions as are necessary to control fire, insects, and disease.

All federal surface and subsurface land within the recreation area or the wilderness additions is withdrawn from

 entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral leasing, geothermal leasing, or mineral materials.</summary>
</bill>
