<bill session="115" type="h" number="6271" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:16Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fulfilling Obligations to Families of the Fallen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require notarized acknowledgment by the spouse of a member of the Armed Forces who is eligible for insurance under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance Program before the member may elect not to be insured under such Program, to be insured under the Program for an amount less than the maximum amount, or to designate a beneficiary other than the member's spouse or child.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fulfilling Obligations to Families of the Fallen Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-03T19:39:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Fulfilling Obligations to Families of the Fallen Act

This bill requires a notarized acknowledgement from a service member and the service member's spouse before certain elections or designations can go into effect under the Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance Program. Specifically, such an acknowledgement is required if a service member declines life insurance, elects less coverage than the maximum amount provided, or the service member chooses a beneficiary other than the spouse or child or the member.</summary>
</bill>
