<bill session="118" type="h" number="6276" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-12T17:13:39-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-12T17:13:39-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">USE IT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">USE IT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Utilizing Space Efficiently and Improving Technologies Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">USE IT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Utilizing Space Efficiently and Improving Technologies Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USE IT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utilizing Space Efficiently and Improving Technologies Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">USE IT Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Utilizing Space Efficiently and Improving Technologies Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize the Administrator of General Services and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to identify the utilization rate of certain public buildings and federally-leased space, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of General Services and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to identify the utilization rate of certain public buildings and federally-leased space, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 35 - 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-384.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-02-13" calendar="Union" number="314">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 314.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-11T19:27:05-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1071 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6276 and H. Res. 1065. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6276 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit. Resolution provides for consideration of H. Res. 1065 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:16:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1071.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1116-1127" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1121-1122" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:16:15-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6276 and H. Res. 1065. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6276 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit. Resolution provides for consideration of H. Res. 1065 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:16:44-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1071 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:16:46-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jennifer A. Kiggans to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:16:56-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 6276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:44:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Edwards amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:52:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T14:58:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:03:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:07:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:11:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:14:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rose amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:21:47-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 6276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:22:14-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:23:16-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T15:24:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - The Chair announced that pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, further proceedings on H.R. 6276 are postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T16:30:11-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the House resumed consideration of H.R. 6276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T16:30:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1131-1133" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T16:30:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Beyer moved to recommit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1132" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T16:30:57-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T17:06:36-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 206 - 213 (Roll no. 83).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="84" datetime="2024-03-12T17:13:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 217 - 203 (Roll no. 84).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T17:13:42-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T17:13:46-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12T17:21:54-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 6276.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1071" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h866"/>
    <amendment number="h865"/>
    <amendment number="h864"/>
    <amendment number="h863"/>
    <amendment number="h862"/>
    <amendment number="h861"/>
    <amendment number="h860"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-03-18T20:55:08Z" status="Passed House">Utilizing Space Efficiently and Improving Technologies Act of 2023 or USE IT Act of 2023

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) and the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish standard methodologies and identify technologies to measure federal building utilization and to use both to evaluate and consolidate public buildings and federally leased space. Federal agencies must (1) work with GSA to use sensors and other technologies in public buildings to measure occupancy, and (2) report on actual space utilization.

OMB and GSA must annually ensure building utilization averages at least 60% in each public building and federally leased space over each 1-year period. The bill also requires OMB and GSA to submit a plan to Congress and the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to consolidate federal agency headquarters buildings in the National Capital region so that building utilization exceeds 60%.

Occupancy agreements between federal tenants and the GSA shall stipulate annual reporting to GSA on space utilization and occupancy. Federal tenants must return office space to GSA if the occupancy of the tenant falls below a 60% space utilization rate for six months within any 1-year period. Agencies with independent leasing authorities must report space utilization and occupancy annually to Congress.

The GAO shall report on agency costs and occupancy rates for public or federally leased buildings.

Agencies must report certain buildings with utilization rates below 20% to the agency's inspector general for investigation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-384</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
