<bill session="109" type="s" number="1484" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:23Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Fallon Paiute Shoshone Indian Tribes Water Rights Settlement Act of 1990.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fallon Paiute Shoshone Indian Tribes Water Rights Settlement Act of 1990.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2005-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2005-07-26" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9053-9055" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="S9054-9055" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27T10:33:18-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-02T20:15:52Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Amends the Fallon Paiute Shoshone Indian Tribes Water Rights Settlement Act of 1990 to revise Settlement Fund requirements. Specifies a formula for determining the amount of Fund income that may be expended or obligated for certain purposes. Adds to such purposes any fees and expenses incurred in connection with the investment of the Fund, for investment management, investment consulting, custodianship, and other transactional services or matters.

Provides that no monies from the Fund other than certain amounts authorized may be expended or obligated for any purpose.

Authorizes the expenditure or obligation for per capita distributions to tribal members, in addition to certain already authorized Fund amounts, of any unexpended or unobligated portion of the Annual 1.2% Amount from any of the three immediately preceding Fund fiscal years subsequent to Fund FY 2005 (minus any accrued negative income).

Directs the Fallon Business Council to amend promptly the original Fund plan for purposes of conforming it to the Fallon Paiute Shoshone Tribal Settlement Act, and making certain nonsubstantive updates, improvements, or corrections.</summary>
</bill>
