<bill session="117" type="h" number="8964" updated="2022-12-29T12:33:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">EAT for Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">EAT for Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education And Training for Health Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue to Federal agencies guidelines for developing procedures and requirements relating to certain primary care Federal health professionals completing continuing medical education on nutrition and to require Federal agencies to submit annual reports relating to such guidelines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-04T19:06:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Education and Training for Health Act of 2022 or the EAT for Health Act of 2022

This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services to issue guidelines to federal agencies to ensure that federal, full time primary care health professionals have continuing education relating to nutrition. Agencies must annually report information including the extent to which they have adopted and encouraged the guidelines.

The continuing education must: (1) include content on the role of nutrition in the prevention, management, and reversal of obesity, cardiovascular disease, diabetes, or cancer; and (2) meet requirements for continuing medical education or continuing education by medical or nurse practitioner professional organizations or certified accrediting bodies.</summary>
</bill>
