<bill session="116" type="s" number="4307" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Benefits for Elderly Refugees and Refugees with Disabilities During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Benefits for Elderly Refugees and Refugees with Disabilities During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 402 of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to extend the eligibility period for supplemental security income benefits for refugees, asylees, and certain other humanitarian immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-08T14:46:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Benefits for Elderly Refugees and Refugees with Disabilities During COVID-19 Act of 2020

This bill extends the eligibility period for certain aliens to receive Supplemental Security Income (SSI) benefits. The bill also waives naturalization fees for SSI recipients.

Currently, certain aliens, such as refugees and victims of trafficking, are eligible to receive SSI benefits for a seven-year period. For such an alien whose eligibility expired after January 31, 2020, this bill extends that alien's eligibility to September 30, 2021.

Furthermore, during the period from January 31, 2020, to September 30, 2021, such a qualifying alien's eligibility for SSI benefits shall not expire while the alien has (1) a pending naturalization application, (2) an application on appeal, or (3) an accepted application but the alien has not yet sworn in as a U.S. citizen.</summary>
</bill>
