<bill session="118" type="s" number="816" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seeing Objects at Altitude Regularly Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOAR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to establish an Aviation Rulemaking Committee to make recommendations regarding continuous aircraft tracking and transmission of identity, altitude, and location data for high altitude balloons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-31T15:34:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Seeing Objects at Altitude Regularly Act or the SOAR Act

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to establish a rulemaking committee and propose rules on the continuous tracking of high altitude balloons (i.e., manned or unmanned free balloons operating at least 10,000 feet above sea level).

Specifically, the committee must develop findings and recommendations regarding a standard requiring high altitude balloons to be equipped with a system for continuous aircraft tracking and transmit, at a minimum, the altitude, location, and identity of the balloon in a manner that is accessible to air traffic controllers, aircraft, and other users of the U.S. national airspace system (NAS).

Further, the FAA must, in accordance with the recommendations of the committee, issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to require a continuous aircraft tracking and transmission system for high altitude balloons and coordinate with foreign authorities to develop such standards for any balloons operating outside of NAS.

If the FAA does not issue a notice of proposed rulemaking within two years of the bill's enactment, the bill prescribes certain interim standards for the operation of high altitude balloons, which stay in place until the FAA issues a notice of proposed rulemaking.</summary>
</bill>
