<bill session="111" type="h" number="5716" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:57Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-21T12:44:57-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-21T12:44:57-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for enhancement of existing efforts in support of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities to advance technologies for the safe and environmentally responsible exploration, development, and production of oil and natural gas resources.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Science and Technology</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 111-554, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Natural Resources discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-07-21" calendar="Union" number="317">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 317.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T12:28:36-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Gordon (TN) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T12:28:37-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5874-5878" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T12:28:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5716.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2010-07-21T12:44:57-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5875-5876" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-07-21T12:44:58-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="517">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 517.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3509" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-15T20:04:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to direct the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to implement a deepwater (in lieu of ultra-deepwater) technologies research and development program, which shall: (1) address technology challenges for well control and accident prevention; and (2) implement research supportive of such activities through DOE and the Office of Fossil Energy. Revises the petroleum resources research and development program to replace ultra-deepwater activities with deepwater architecture, well control and accident prevention, and deepwater technology. Extends the program to drilling in all waters greater than 1,000 feet (currently, limited to only those waters greater than 15,000 feet).

Directs the Secretary to advance safe and environmentally responsible exploration, development, and production of natural gas and petroleum resources.

Modifies the focus areas for awards to include: (1) specified aspects of deepwater resources; (2) expanded unconventional onshore resources; (3) consortia of small producers; and (4) safety, accident prevention, and mitigation research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities.

Renames the Ultra-Deepwater Advisory Committee as the Program Advisory Committee.

Renames the Ultra-Deepwater and Unconventional Natural Gas and Other Petroleum Research Fund as the Safer Oil and Natural Gas Drilling Technology Research and Development Fund. Revises the formula for Fund allocations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-554</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
