<bill session="118" type="h" number="8674" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:40Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Milestones for Advanced Nuclear Fuel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Milestones for Advanced Nuclear Fuel Act</title>
    <title type="display">Milestones for Advanced Nuclear Fuel Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish milestone-based development and demonstration projects relating to nuclear fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000828"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001225" joined="2024-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 118-686.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-09-18" calendar="Union" number="580">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 580.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-25T17:58:30Z" status="Reported to House">Milestones for Advanced Nuclear Fuel Act

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish certain milestone-based development and demonstration projects that support the domestic supply chain for nuclear fuel, including high-assay low-enriched uranium (HALEU). Milestone-based demonstration projects require particular technical and financial milestones to be met before a project participant is provided an award through a competitive process.

Specifically, DOE must carry out milestone-based demonstration projects under its Fuel Cycle Research and Development program. DOE must also complete and make publicly available a study that analyzes the practicability, potential benefits, and estimated lifecycle costs of recycling certain spent nuclear fuel into usable fuel for nuclear reactors.

In carrying out the Nuclear Fuel Security Program and the HALEU for Advanced Nuclear Reactor Demonstration Projects Program, DOE must award funding for milestone-based advanced fuel cycle technologies development and demonstration projects, including uranium production, conversion, enrichment, deconversion, and waste reduction for advanced fuels. As part of its annual budget request, DOE must provide to specified congressional committees a briefing on the milestone-based projects, including information about the benefits and drawbacks of milestone-based projects as compared to traditional project structure funding models.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-686</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
