<bill session="109" type="h" number="650" updated="2022-02-03T05:25:26Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vaccine Accessibility for Children and Seniors Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VACS Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">VACS Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish reasonable legal reforms that will facilitate the manufacture of vital, life-saving vaccines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2005-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2005-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2005-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2005-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Frivolous lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Lawyers"/>
    <term name="Legal ethics"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-14T20:44:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Vaccine Accessibility for Children and Seniors Act of 2005 or the VACS Act of 2005 - Establishes an exclusive Federal cause of action for claims arising from a vaccine-related injury or death associated with the administration of a vaccine after October 1, 1988, except for a compensation proceeding under the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program (the Program). Preempts all State actions for damages arising from such an injury or death.

Defines "vaccine" to include any preservative, ingredient, or component of a vaccine.

Requires a district court to suspend an attorney from the practice of law in such court for one year if the attorney has violated the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure requiring the attorney to certify the validity of claims filed in connection with a vaccine suit three times during that attorney's career. Allows the court to suspend the attorney for any additional period that the court considers appropriate.

Amends Federal vaccine civil trial procedures to insert a new first stage to determine whether competent and reliable scientific evidence demonstrates that the plaintiff's alleged vaccine-related injury or death was caused in fact by the vaccine.

Requires the dismissal with prejudice or removal to a Federal court of all pending State vaccine cases.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General to jointly submit a report to Congress concerning recommendations to ensure that injured patients with legitimate claims are rapidly and appropriately compensated through the Program in a less adversarial manner.</summary>
</bill>
