<bill session="116" type="s" number="752" updated="2022-11-01T17:32:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PREP Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREP Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preparing and Retaining Education Professionals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for teacher and school leader quality enhancement and to enhance institutional aid.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2019-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1795" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="468" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-11T21:22:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preparing and Retaining Education Professionals Act of 2019 or the PREP Act of 2019

This bill reauthorizes and revises certain grant programs to address shortages of teachers and school leaders (e.g., principals) in elementary and secondary schools, including shortages in rural areas and related to specific positions (e.g., special education and English language instruction).

First, the bill makes permanent and otherwise revises the Teacher Quality Partnership program (which provides grants to improve the quality of teachers and enhance professional development activities). It revises the program to, among other things (1) expand the purpose of grants to include the recruitment of well-prepared individuals, including individuals from underrepresented populations, into the teacher and school leadership force; (2) include training and professional development opportunities for school leaders; and (3) establish a grant program to address workforce shortages or increase workforce diversity.

Next, the bill makes permanent and otherwise revises the Augustus F. Hawkins Centers of Excellence program (which provides grants to establish teacher preparation programs at minority-serving institutions). It allows grants to be used for school leader preparation programs.

Additionally, it aligns activities within teacher preparation programs at predominantly Black institutions and Native American-serving nontribal institutions with certain changes made to the Teacher Quality Partnership program.

It permanently reauthorizes the Minority Science and Engineering Improvement program (which provides grants to improve science and engineering education at predominantly minority institutions).

Finally, it provides annual funding beginning in FY2020&#160;to historically Black colleges and universities and other minority-serving institutions for grant programs (e.g., teacher preparation).</summary>
</bill>
