<bill session="116" type="s" number="2684" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing, Opportunity, Mobility, and Equity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing, Opportunity, Mobility, and Equity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Community Development Block Grant and Surface Transportation Block Grant recipients to develop a strategy to support inclusive zoning policies, to allow for a credit to support housing affordability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4808" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-03T15:06:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Housing, Opportunity, Mobility, and Equity Act of 2019

This bill addresses zoning policies, housing affordability, and economic security.

Specifically, the bill requires each state or local government that receives a Community Development Block Grant from the Department of Housing and Urban Development or a Surface Transportation Block Grant from the Department of Transportation to develop and implement a strategy to support zoning policies or regulatory initiatives that create a more affordable, elastic, and diverse housing supply.

Additionally, the bill establishes a tax credit for individuals who spend more than 30% of their adjusted gross income on rent and requires the Department of the Treasury to make advance payments of this credit to eligible taxpayers who elect that option.

The bill also requires Treasury to establish a Rainy Day Savings Program to allow an eligible taxpayer to defer 20% of the amount that would otherwise be refunded to the taxpayer. Treasury must invest the deferred amount and later disburse that amount, along with any interest, to the taxpayer.</summary>
</bill>
