<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1452" updated="2022-02-03T05:59:31Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4078" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-07-26T11:23:58-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000207"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-07-25"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to exempt regulatory actions by the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office that streamline the application process for patents and trademarks, including rules implementing the micro entity provision of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act, from Title I of the bill and exempts midnight rules implementing such provisions from Title II of the bill. The amendment also sought to exempt consent decrees and settlement agreements in an action to compel agency action by the PTO to help streamline the application process for patents and trademarks from Title III of the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in Part B of House Report 112-616 to exempt regulatory actions by the U.S. Patent and Trademark Office that streamline the application process for patents and trademarks, including rules implementing the micro entity provision of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act, from Title I of the bill and exempts midnight rules implementing such provisions from Title II of the bill. The amendment also would exempt consent decrees and settlement agreements in an action to compel agency action by the PTO to help streamline the application process for patents and trademarks from Title III of the bill.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-07-26T11:23:58-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="520">
      <text>On agreeing to the Watt amendment (A006) Failed by recorded vote: 177 - 244 (Roll no. 520).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5308" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T19:00:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Watt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5265" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5265" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26T11:23:58-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26T11:23:58-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-26T11:23:58-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Watt amendment (A006) Failed by recorded vote: 177 - 244 (Roll no. 520).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5308" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25T19:00:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Watt.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5265" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5265" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
