<bill session="117" type="h" number="7029" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:13Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Injection Sites for Illegal Drugs Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Injection Sites for Illegal Drugs Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain Federal funds to be provided to any State, local, Tribal, or private entity that operates an unlawful injection center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6159" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-29T16:18:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Injection Sites for Illegal Drugs Act of 2022

This bill generally prohibits federal funds from being made available to a state, local, tribal, or other entity that operates or controls an injection center (i.e., a medically supervised injection site) in violation of the federal statute commonly known as the Crack House Statute. The statute generally prohibits making facilities available for the purpose of unlawfully using a controlled substance.

The bill provides an exception for federal funds awarded through the Community Oriented Policing Services (COPS) grant program or the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant (JAG) program. Specifically, federal funds awarded through the COPS grant program or the JAG grant program shall remain available to a state, local, tribal, or other entity that operates or controls an injection center in violation of the Crack House Statute.</summary>
</bill>
