<bill session="108" type="h" number="1248" updated="2023-01-15T22:33:38Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safer Truck Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, relating to motor vehicle weight and width limitations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Truck Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Weights and measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer Truck Act - Amends Federal highway law to authorize a State to allow a single unit truck or bus without a trailer to operate on the Interstate System while carrying up to 20 metric tons (44,080 pounds) of cargo, packaging, and load securement materials regardless of the overall weight of the vehicle, its axle weights, or weight of its safety and energy conservation devices if: (1) the cargo is evenly distributed in a compartment or combined compartments at least 40 feet long; (2) the overall height of the vehicle and cargo does not exceed the width of the wheelbase; (3) the axles are positioned at the extreme ends of the vehicle; and (4) the gross weight and certified empty weight of the vehicle (including detachable cargo compartments) are marked conspicuously on the front of the vehicle in contrasting three-inch or taller letters and numbers.Amends Federal transportation law to revise certain commercial motor vehicle width limitations on vehicles operating on the Interstate System and on Federal-aid highways to exclude from width calculations with respect to such limitations any safety devices that reduce the possibility of death and injury, if such devices fit entirely within the legal travel lanes of all roads upon which the vehicle operates.</summary>
</bill>
