<bill session="116" type="h" number="4151" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:11Z">
  <state datetime="2019-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Undocumented Taxpayers Opportunity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve agricultural job opportunities, benefits, and security for aliens in the United States and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Undocumented Taxpayers Opportunity Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="175" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="641" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T14:41:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Undocumented Taxpayers Opportunity Act of 2019 

This bill allows qualified alien taxpayers to obtain provisional immigrant status and establishes procedures for provisional immigrants to obtain permanent resident status.

An alien shall qualify if he or she has been assessed and paid taxes for each of the previous five years before applying for such status. The Department of Homeland Security may grant provisional immigrant status to qualified individuals who pass security checks and are not disqualified for various reasons, such as an aggravated felony conviction. DHS may waive certain disqualifications for humanitarian or public interest reasons.

Provisional immigrants shall be authorized for employment in the United States and travel outside the United States. Such individuals shall be ineligible for various federal benefits, including the&#160;healthcare premium assistance tax credit.

Individuals going through deportation or removal proceedings shall be given a chance to apply for provisional immigrant status if they qualify.

Provisional immigrants may apply for permanent resident status, subject to various requirements, including payment of federal taxes for the each of the previous three years. An alien may not hold provisional immigrant status for more than eight years.</summary>
</bill>
