<bill session="117" type="h" number="1514" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">POWER ON Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Power Act to increase transmission capacity for clean energy, reduce congestion, and increase grid resilience.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POWER ON Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevent Outages With Energy Resilient Options Nationwide Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2021-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-17T18:03:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Prevent Outages With Energy Resilient Options Nationwide Act or the POWER ON Act

This bill revises requirements governing the designation of a national interest electric transmission corridor. Currently, the Department of Energy (DOE) may designate any geographic area experiencing electric energy transmission capacity constraints or congestion that adversely affects consumers.

The bill expands the list of considerations DOE may use to select and designate a corridor. Specifically, DOE may consider whether the designation would (1) enhance the ability of facilities that generate or transmit renewable energy, low-emission energy, or emission-free energy to connect to the electric grid; (2) promote electrification of other sectors, including the transportation sector; or (3) facilitate other public policies to decarbonize the grid. DOE may also consider whether the designation maximizes existing rights-of-way, avoids sensitive environmental areas and cultural heritage sites, and would lower the cost of electricity for consumers.

The bill also revises the authority (i.e., backstop authority) of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to issue a permit for interstate transmission projects in such corridors when states and local governments fail to do so, including by specifying the timing for when FERC may issue such permits. In addition, the bill requires permit holders to make good faith efforts to engage landowners and other stakeholders early before exercising the right of eminent domain to purchase property needed to complete permit projects.

Finally, the bill requires DOE to provide technical assistance to regional transmission siting agencies.</summary>
</bill>
