<bill session="116" type="s" number="3961" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:15Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic Democracy for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic Democracy for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require States and local jurisdictions to allow absentee voting in the November 2020 general election for Federal office for individuals impacted by coronavirus disease 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-13T20:27:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic Democracy for All Act

This bill requires states and local jurisdictions to allow absentee voting during the November 2020 general election for individuals impacted by COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019). It also establishes grants to implement online registration systems and to increase absentee voting.

Specifically, states and local jurisdictions must allow an individual to use absentee registration procedures and to vote by absentee ballot if the individual has a reasonable concern that voting in person on the date of the election may expose them to contracting COVID-19 or if&#160;they are otherwise impacted by COVID-19. The Department of Justice may bring a civil action against a state or local jurisdiction for violations.

In addition, the bill authorizes the Election Assistance Commission to award grants to states and local jurisdictions to (1) implement online absentee registration systems for the November 2020 general election, and (2) facilitate an increase in absentee voting during such election (e.g., the costs associated with the purchase of materials and educational outreach).</summary>
</bill>
