<bill session="116" type="h" number="2067" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Aid for Trade Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the coordination of programs to provide trade capacity building assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aid for Trade Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000591"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001210" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-29T17:10:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Aid for Trade Act of 2019

This bill establishes a body to coordinate the use of U.S. foreign aid to build trade capacity in recipient countries and contains other related provisions.

The President shall establish an interagency task force to improve effectiveness of trade-capacity-building assistance programs. The task force shall have members from relevant executive branch agencies including the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency.

The task force shall (1) review executive branch agency expenditures on trade-capacity-building assistance, and (2) make recommendations to the President as to the appropriate allocations of such funds.

The State Department shall (1) have primary responsibility for overseeing and carrying out such assistance programs, (2) prioritize assistance to certain countries such as those that have consistently supported policies that promote the development of private enterprise, and (3) ensure that the programs are not duplicative.

The bill also establishes that one goal of each mission to a foreign country shall be to&#160;(1) identify local barriers to international trade and investment, (2) advise the State Department on trade-capacity-building assistance, and (3) coordinate and supervise trade-capacity-building assistance programs.

The Government Accountability Office shall periodically review the impact of the trade-capacity-assistance programs.</summary>
</bill>
