<bill session="119" type="h" number="334" updated="2025-02-19T19:43:45Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to establish technical and procedural standards for artificial or prerecorded voice systems created through generative artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to establish technical and procedural standards for artificial or prerecorded voice systems created through generative artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000372"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-19T19:40:53Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides statutory authority for the application of certain technical and procedural standards to systems that transmit artificial or prerecorded telephone messages generated using artificial intelligence.

Specifically, the standards require (1) that such messages clearly identify and state the telephone number or address of the individual or entity initiating the call, and (2) that any system making such phone calls release a recipient&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s telephone line within five seconds of notification that the recipient has ended the call. Such standards are prescribed and implemented by the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) and apply under current law to any system used to transmit an artificial or prerecorded voice message by telephone.&#160;

The bill also permits the FCC to apply the standards to other technologies used to transmit artificial and prerecorded telephone messages as it deems appropriate.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
