<bill session="118" type="h" number="6891" updated="2025-11-19T03:56:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MORE USDA Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from USDA Grants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MORE USDA Grants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the Department of Agriculture to certain counties in which the majority of land is owned or managed by the Federal Government and to other units of local government and Tribal governments in those counties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001228"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-08-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3595" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1580" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-23T19:56:33Z" status="Introduced in House">More Opportunities for Rural Economies from USDA Grants Act or the MORE USDA Grants Act 

This bill revises the process for awarding grants under certain programs of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to high-density public land counties and any units of tribal or local governments within such counties. A high-density public land county is a county that has a population of not more than 100,000 people and in which more than 50% of the land is owned or managed by the federal government.

Any requirement for local matching funds under a qualifying grant program must be reduced by 50% with respect to such jurisdictions.

On request, USDA must provide additional technical assistance to such jurisdictions before and during the annual application period for each qualifying grant program.

USDA must also prioritize grant applications from such jurisdictions that have not received support under the qualifying grant program during the 10-year period preceding the date of the application.</summary>
</bill>
