<bill session="118" type="s" number="1194" updated="2025-11-19T04:20:44Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-12">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recycling and Composting Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out certain activities to improve recycling and composting programs in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Committee consideration held. Business Meeting printed. S. Hrg. 118-708.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Carper without amendment. With written report No. 118-42.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="105">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 105.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2368-2370" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-03-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2369-2370" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-15T11:03:31-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-15T11:07:36-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4040" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1692"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-04-02T13:41:09Z" status="Passed Senate">Recycling and Composting Accountability Act

This bill establishes data collection and reporting requirements concerning composting and recycling programs.

Specifically, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must issue several reports related to composting and recycling, including a report on the capability of the United States to implement a national composting strategy in order to reduce contamination rates for recycling.

The EPA must also

 inventory certain facilities that recycle residential materials and describe the materials that the facilities can process; collect data related to curbside and drop-off recycling and composting programs in order to establish a comprehensive baseline of data for the U.S. recycling system; and develop and disseminate best practices that states, local governments, and Indian tribes may use to enhance recycling and composting. The EPA must also develop a metric for determining the proportion of recyclable materials in commercial and municipal waste streams that is being diverted from circular markets, which are markets that utilize industrial processes and economic activities to enable post-industrial and post-consumer materials used in those processes and activities to maintain their highest values for as long as possible. After developing the metric, the EPA must then study the proportion of recyclable materials in such waste streams that were diverted from those markets in the prior ten years.

Finally, the Government Accountability Office must report on the recycling practices of federal agencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-42</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
