<bill session="108" type="h" number="420" updated="2023-01-15T21:19:38Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Forest Organizational Camp Fee Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a user fee system that provides for an equitable return to the Federal Government for the occupancy and use of National Forest System lands and facilities by organizational camps that serve the youth and disabled adults of America, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Forest Organizational Camp Fee Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Camping"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Forest Organizational Camp Fee Improvement Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to charge an annual acreage and market value-based fee for the occupancy and use of National Forest System lands (land use fees) and facilities (facility fees) by organizational camps (nonprofit or governmental entity-run camps for youth or persons with disabilities). Provides for annual land use fee adjustments.Reduces the land-use fee, but not below a minimum amount to be determined by the Secretary, for: (1) use by persons with disabilities and at-risk children; and (2) youth programs through organized social, citizenship, character-building, or faith-based activities oriented to outdoor recreation. Prohibits facility use fee reductions.Provides for an additional fee if an organizational camp derives revenue from such lands' or facilities' use for purposes other than to introduce young people or people with disabilities to natural resource education or other appropriate experiences.</summary>
</bill>
