<bill session="116" type="h" number="5322" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:05Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-21T16:15:36-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-21T16:15:36-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish or modify requirements relating to minority depository institutions, community development financial institutions, and impact banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001137"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2020-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2019-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 52 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T16:01:12-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sherman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T16:01:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4597-4602" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T16:01:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5322.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-09-21T16:15:36-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4597-4600" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-09-21T16:15:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6379" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6321" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4818" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="5065" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-06T19:26:42Z" status="Passed House">Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act 

This bill establishes and revises provisions related to minority depository institutions, community development financial institutions, and impact banks.

(Sec. 4) The bill expands the definition of minority depository institutions to include women-owned banks. It also establishes impact banks as depository institutions with total assets less than $10 billion and where a certain total dollar value of loans are extended to low-income borrowers.

(Sec. 6) The bill creates Minority Depository Institutions Advisory Committees at the Federal Reserve Board, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration. The committees must provide advice to their respective entities regarding preservation of the number and character of minority-owned institutions and the creation of new institutions.

(Sec. 8) The bill establishes the Minority Bank Deposit Program to prioritize the use of minority depository institutions to hold the deposits of federal departments and agencies.

(Sec. 10) The bill sets forth the threshold of controlling shares with respect to minority depository institutions and impact banks. It also allows new minority depository institutions and impact banks to take three years to meet initial capital requirements.

(Sec. 12) The bill establishes a program allowing minority depository institutions and impact banks to apply to receive deposits from certain Treasury accounts.

 (Sec. 13) The Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation must evaluate certain applications for deposit insurance for eligibility as a community development financial institution.

(Sec. 14) The Small Business Administration must establish a task force on lending to small business concerns by improving relationships with community development financial institutions, minority depository institutions, and impact banks.

(Sec. 15) The bill also decreases, beginning September 30, 2030, the cap on the surplus funds of the Federal Reserve banks. (Amounts exceeding this cap are deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.)</summary>
</bill>
