<bill session="118" type="h" number="4204" updated="2025-05-27T14:11:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shielding Community Banks from Systemic Risk Assessments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shielding Community Banks from Systemic Risk Assessments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to exempt community banks from any special assessment of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation caused by the use of the systemic risk authority under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-11-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-03T14:06:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Shielding Community Banks from Systemic Risk Assessments Act 

This bill directs the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) to exempt small insured depository institutions and depository institution holding companies from special assessments related to the use of FDIC's systemic risk authority. (In the event of a bank failure, FDIC may provide monetary assistance for the purpose of winding up the insured depository institution. FDIC then recovers any resulting loss through a special assessment on insured depository institutions, depository institution holding companies, or both.)

Further, FDIC must graduate the amount of the special assessment so that, of the remaining institutions and companies that must pay the assessment, smaller institutions and companies pay a significantly smaller proportion than the largest.</summary>
</bill>
