<bill session="118" type="s" number="2355" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Crypto-Asset National Security Enhancement and Enforcement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crypto-Asset National Security Enhancement and Enforcement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the applicability of sanctions and antimoney laundering compliance obligations to United States persons in the decentralized finance technology sector and virtual currency kiosk operators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2990-2991" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-26">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-31T14:31:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crypto-Asset National Security Enhancement and Enforcement Act of 2023

This bill applies sanctions compliance requirements and&#160;anti-money laundering requirements to decentralized finance services. Decentralized finance services are applications that facilitate peer-to-peer digital asset financial transactions using distributed ledger (i.e., blockchain) technology.

Specifically, the bill requires certain U.S. persons to comply with sanctions obligations if a violation of sanctions is committed through the use of a digital asset protocol. U.S. persons subject to these requirements are digital transaction facilitators and, in certain circumstances, digital asset protocol backers.

Further, digital asset transaction facilitators and digital asset protocol backers are subject to reporting requirements designed to prevent money laundering, including suspicious transaction reporting.&#160;

Finally, virtual currency kiosks (i.e., digital asset kiosks) must verify and record the identities of the counterparties to a transfer.&#160;&#160; &#160;</summary>
</bill>
