<bill session="116" type="h" number="8183" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ADAPT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ADAPT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Development of AI Processes and Talent Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to enhance public-private talent exchange programs in the Department of Defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-21T15:13:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Development of AI Processes and Talent Act or the ADAPT Act

This bill modifies the Department of Defense (DOD) public-private talent exchange program under which DOD and private sector employees exchange duties. It requires that an agreement under such program must specify that DOD employees may not improperly use information that relates to a DOD acquisition or procurement for the benefit or advantage of the private-sector organization.

DOD must ensure that the authority for operating a public-private talent exchange program is used to exchange personnel working on artificial intelligence applications. DOD must brief the congressional armed services committees on efforts to expand existing DOD public-private exchange programs and to ensure that such programs seek opportunities for exchanges with private sector entities working on artificial intelligence applications.</summary>
</bill>
