<bill session="116" type="h" number="8902" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Bankruptcy Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Bankruptcy Reform Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 11, United States Code, to add a bankruptcy chapter relating to the debt of individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2020-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4991" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-09T14:12:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Consumer Bankruptcy Reform Act of 2020

This bill generally revises consumer bankruptcy law by establishing a new Chapter 10 for individual debtors with not more than $7.5 million in debt. The bill eliminates the ability of individual debtors to file for bankruptcy under Chapter 7 liquidation bankruptcy and repeals Chapter 13, which requires individual debtors to comply with a repayment plan to receive a discharge of debt.

Under Chapter 10, debtors may receive a discharge of debt through making minimum payment obligations based on the debtor's assets and income which may result in immediate discharge for individuals with no minimum payment obligation. The bill also provides for residential protections for debtors and revises what type of debt is dischargeable in bankruptcy. An individual may obtain a discharge under Chapter 10 once every six years.

Individuals may seek limited bankruptcy proceedings on certain debts, such as a home mortgage.

The bill also establishes consumer bankruptcy protections, including by creating a Consumer Bankruptcy Ombuds at the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau.</summary>
</bill>
