<bill session="117" type="h" number="8152" updated="2023-08-30T13:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Data Privacy and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Data Privacy and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">American Data Privacy and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide consumers with foundational data privacy rights, create strong oversight mechanisms, and establish meaningful enforcement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2022-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 53 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-30">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 117-669.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-30" calendar="Union" number="488">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 488.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-01T17:55:57Z" status="Reported to House">American Data Privacy and Protection Act

This bill establishes requirements for how companies, including nonprofits and common carriers, handle personal data, which includes information that identifies or is reasonably linkable to an individual.

Specifically, the bill requires most companies to limit the collection, processing, and transfer of personal data to that which is reasonably necessary to provide a requested product or service and to other specified circumstances. It also generally prohibits companies from transferring individuals' personal data without their affirmative express consent.

The bill establishes consumer data protections, including the right to access, correct, and delete personal data. Prior to engaging in targeted advertising, the bill requires companies to provide individuals with a means to opt out of such advertising. The bill also provides additional protections with respect to personal data of individuals under the age of 17. It further prohibits companies from using personal data to discriminate based on specified protected characteristics.

Additionally, companies must implement security practices to protect and secure personal data against unauthorized access, and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) may issue regulations for complying with this requirement.

The bill provides for enforcement of these requirements by the FTC and state attorneys general. Beginning two years after the bill takes effect, individuals may, subject to certain notification requirements, bring civil actions for violations of the bill.

Finally, the bill preempts state laws that are covered by the provisions of the bill except for certain categories of state laws and specified laws in Illinois and California.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-669</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
