<bill session="116" type="h" number="8131" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hemp Opportunity Zone Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hemp Opportunity Zone Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish Hemp Opportunity Zones.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Horticulture and plants"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-14T16:30:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Hemp Opportunity Zone Act of 2020

The bill permits the designation of up to 25% of the low-income communities as Hemp Opportunity Zones. Hemp, or industrial hemp, is a variety of the cannabis sativa plant species grown specifically for certain industrial uses, such as making rope, strong fabrics, fiberboard, and paper.

 In designating such zones, preference must be given to areas that are facing obstacles to economic development, are the focus of governmental or private economic development initiatives, are poised for economic growth requiring access to a larger hemp market, and represent the areas of a state where hemp production would result in the highest return on investment.

The bill also allows

 deferral of tax on gain from investment in Hemp Opportunity Zones, immediate expensing off qualified zone business property, an increased business income tax deduction for hemp producers, a start-up tax credit for hemp farmers, and a 30% investment tax credit for the farming property of certain small hemp farmers. The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to study certain issues relating to hemp production, including the potential opportunities for hemp seed to be used as animal feed and for the use of hemp to create personal protective equipment for health care workers and first responders.</summary>
</bill>
