<bill session="111" type="h" number="6420" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:19Z">
  <state datetime="2010-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Red Flag Program Clarification Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act with respect to the applicability of identity theft guidelines to creditors.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Red Flag Program Clarification Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3987" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-06T22:23:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Red Flag Program Clarification Act of 2010 - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act, with respect to federal agency (red flag) guidelines regarding identity theft and the users of consumer reports, to define creditor to mean one that regularly and in the ordinary course of business: (1) obtains or uses consumer reports, directly or indirectly, in connection with a credit transaction; (2) furnishes information to certain consumer reporting agencies in connection with a credit transaction; or (3) advances funds to or on behalf of a person, based on the person's obligation to repay the funds or on repayment from specific property pledged by or on the person's behalf.

Includes in the definition any other type of creditor as the federal agency (banking agency, National Credit Union Administration, or the Federal Trade Commission [FTC]) having authority over that creditor may determine appropriate, if the creditor offers or maintains accounts subject to a reasonably foreseeable risk of identity theft.

Excludes from the definition of creditor, however, any creditor that advances funds on behalf of a person for expenses incidental to a service the creditor provides to that person.</summary>
</bill>
