<bill session="116" type="s" number="2419" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of Coconino National Forest land in the State of Arizona.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of a small parcel of Coconino National Forest land in the State of Arizona.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2020-12-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-18T15:23:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the conveyance of a land exchange involving Coconino National Forest in Arizona.

Specifically, the bill requires the independent appraisal of 13.3 acres of land within the Coconino National Forest, 43 acres of nonfederal land in Arizona, and an easement for the full maintenance and use of Forest Service Road 9201D from its junction with Forest Service Road 0618 (commonly known as Beaver Creek). Based on the appraisal of such lands and easement, the Arizona Board of Regents (ABOR), on behalf of the University of Arizona Experiment Station, may identify a portion of the nonfederal land that (1) is equal in value to the federal land, and (2) shall be offered in exchange for the federal land.

Upon identification of the portion of the nonfederal land to be offered in the exchange, the ABOR may submit an offer to the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to convey all right, title, and interest of the ABOR in and to the offered portion. On receiving an offer, USDA shall accept it and convey to the ABOR all U.S. interest in and to the federal land and easement.</summary>
</bill>
