<bill session="112" type="h" number="3896" updated="2020-02-10T16:50:30Z">
  <state datetime="2012-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend section 8007 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to extend eligibility for emergency and modernization grants to local educational agencies in which at least 10 percent of the property in each such agency is nontaxable due to the presence of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 8007 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to extend eligibility for emergency and modernization grants to local educational agencies in which at least 10 percent of the property in each such agency is nontaxable due to the presence of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000329"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3990" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="595" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-08T22:08:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Impact Aid program (which compensates local educational agencies [LEAs] for the financial burden of federal activities affecting their areas) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to make certain LEAs eligible for emergency school repair grants and school modernization grants if they serve areas where at least 10% of the property is nontaxable due to the federal government's presence.

Prohibits the Secretary of Education from requiring: (1) those LEAs to serve areas where more than 10% of the property is nontaxable due to the federal government's presence, or (2) other LEAs (those currently eligible for such grants by reason of having a student enrollment at least 40% of which resides on Indian lands) to have a student enrollment more than 40% of which resides on Indian lands before being deemed eligible for such grants.</summary>
</bill>
