<bill session="118" type="h" number="3370" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reclamation of War Powers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation of War Powers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit funds available for the United States Armed Forces to be obligated or expended for introduction of United States Armed Forces into hostilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001047"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Armed Services, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T23:54:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Reclamation of War Powers Act

This bill prohibits Armed Forces funding from being obligated or expended for the introduction of the Armed Forces into hostilities, or into situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances, in the absence of a declaration of war, specific statutory authorization, or a national emergency created by an attack or imminent threat of attack upon the United States, its territories or possessions, or the Armed Forces.

In the case of a national emergency created by an attack (or threat of attack), funds may be used for only 60 days.

The House of Representatives or the Senate may not consider a bill or joint resolution that makes funds available in violation of these provisions.

The President shall, in the case of such introduction of the Armed Forces, submit to Congress a report that includes

 an analysis of the threat to be countered by the use of the Armed Forces; the specific objectives and justification for those objectives; and a description of the scope, duration, cost, and likelihood of success.</summary>
</bill>
