<bill session="108" type="s" number="482" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:41Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fisheries Science and Management Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize and amend the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fisheries Science and Management Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2940-2941"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Overfishing"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Sustainable fisheries"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fisheries Science and Management Improvement Act of 2003 - Amends the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act to permit each Regional Fishery Management Council under the National Fishery Management Program to establish one or more scientific review committees to conduct peer review of all stock assessments prepared for fisheries under the Council's jurisdiction.Requires the Secretary of Commerce or his designee to conduct an independent and confidential peer review of any stock assessment by a scientific review committee before the assessment is used to further the purposes, policy, and provisions of this Act.Requires the Council of jurisdiction to establish a set of goals, objectives, an implementation schedule, and a statistically reliable method of achieving such goals and objectives for Fishery Management Observer programs that utilize observers deployed on U.S. fishing vessels or to U.S. fish processors.Requires the Secretary to issue national criteria for designating a habitat as a habitat area of particular concern.Revises requirements for: (1) fishery management plans; (2) fish habitat guidelines and recommendations; and (3) the determination and rebuilding of overfished fisheries.Requires fishery conservation and management measures to take into account the importance of fishery resources to fishing communities and the cumulative impact of fishery conservation and management measures on those fishing communities.Requires fishery management plans to comply with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969.</summary>
</bill>
