<bill session="108" type="h" number="2728" updated="2023-01-15T05:32:37Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-18T15:19:41-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-05-18T15:19:41-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for adjudicative flexibility with regard to an employer filing of a notice of contest following the issuance of a citation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; to provide for greater efficiency at the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission; to provide for an independent review of citations issued by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; to provide for the award of attorney's fees and costs to very small employers when they prevail in litigation prompted by the issuance of citations by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration; and to amend the Paperwork Reduction Act and titles 5 and 31, United States Code, to reform Federal paperwork and regulatory processes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for adjudicative flexibility with regard to an employer filing of a notice of contest following the issuance of a citation by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Occupational Safety and Health Independent Review of OSHA Citations Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission Efficiency Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Occupational Safety and Health Small Employer Access to Justice Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000358" joined="2003-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000104" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001239" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001240" joined="2003-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001232" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001052" joined="2003-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2003-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2004-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000549" joined="2003-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000676" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000174" joined="2004-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000361" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001138" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000508" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2003-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000166" joined="2004-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001151" joined="2003-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2003-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001155" joined="2003-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2003-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2004-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1483"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 24 - 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 108-487.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-13" calendar="Union" number="276">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 276.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-05-17T22:24:31-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 645 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2728, H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731 and H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T12:23:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 645.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3107-3115, H3130, H3161" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3107-3108" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T12:23:29-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2728, H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731 and H.R. 2432.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T12:24:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to House Resolution 645, the House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 2728.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T13:25:43-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T13:26:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.R. 2728, the Chair put the question on adoption of the bill and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Owens demanded the Yeas and Nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the bill until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T15:19:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3130, H3161" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="183" datetime="2004-05-18T15:19:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 251 - 177 (Roll No. 183).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T15:40:51-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18T19:36:46-04:00">
      <text>ENGROSSMENT OF H.R. 2728 - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 645, the texts of H.R. 2729, H.R. 2730, H.R. 2731, and H.R. 2432 will be appended to the engrossment of H.R. 2728.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="535">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 535.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2432" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2729" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2730" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2731" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="645" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Apples"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity Credit Corporation"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal education"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h529"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-05-28T20:05:20Z" status="Passed House amended">Title I: Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act - Occupational Safety and Health Small Business Day in Court Act of 2004 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSH Act) to exempt employers from a 15-day deadline for notifying the Secretary of Labor of their intent to contest citations, notices of uncorrected violations, and proposed penalties issued by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA), if their failure to meet such deadline results from mistake, inadvertence, surprise, or excusable neglect.

Title II: Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission Efficiency Act - Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission Efficiency Act of 2004 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSH Act) to increase the membership of the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission (OSHRC) from three to five. Requires the presence of three of such five members to constitute a quorum.

Includes an individual's legal training among possible qualifications for OSHRC membership.

Authorizes the President to extend for up to 365 days the term of an OSHRC member until a nominated successor is confirmed to serve by the Senate.

Title III: Occupational Safety and Health Independent Review of OSHA Citations Act - Occupational Safety and Health Independent Review of OSHA Citations Act of 2004 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSH Act) to revise judicial review provisions to require deference to be given to reasonable conclusions of the Occupational Safety and Health Review Commission (OSHRC), with respect to all questions of law that are subject to agency deference under governing court precedent relating to citations issued by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) against businesses for violations of the OSH Act.

Title IV: Occupational Safety and Health Small Employer Access to Justice Act - Occupational Safety and Health Small Employer Access to Justice Act of 2004 - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSH Act) to provide for the award of attorney's fees and costs to certain small employers when they prevail in specified administrative or court proceedings.

Requires such awards to prevailing employers if they had not more than 100 employees and a net worth of not more than $7 million at the time of: (1) the initiation of the administrative proceedings (in the case of an adversary adjudication); or (2) the filing of the action addressed in the court proceedings (in the case of judicial review of an administrative action).

Provides for such awards without regard to whether the position of the Secretary of Labor or the Federal Government was substantially justified or whether special circumstances make an award unjust.

Title V: Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act - Paperwork and Regulatory Improvements Act of 2004 - Amends the Paperwork Reduction Act to require the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to review information collection conducted by the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to identify actions IRS can take to reduce the information collection burden imposed on small business concerns, and to include the results of such review in a specified annual report.

Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to repeal specified exemptions from Paperwork Reduction Act requirements and certain other rulemaking requirements.

Amends the Truth in Regulating Act of 2000 to make permanent the authority of a chairman or ranking member of a congressional committee to request the Comptroller General to perform a regulatory analysis of an economically significant rule upon agency publication.

Amends the Treasury and General Government Appropriations Act, 2001 to instruct the Director of OMB to require each agency annually to submit an estimate of the total annual costs and benefits of Federal rules and paperwork for the agency and each agency program.

Requires the Director to designate at least three agencies to participate in a study on regulatory budgeting for FY 2006 and 2007. Includes the regulatory budgets of the designated agencies as an alternative budget presentation. Requires a report on the study to be included in a certain report to Congress, as well as submitted directly to specified congressional committees.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-487</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
