<bill session="118" type="h" number="4608" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:02Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation Megaprojects Accountability and Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation Megaprojects Accountability and Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to establish additional requirements for certain transportation projects with estimated costs of $2,500,000,000 or more, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-29T13:00:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Transportation Megaprojects Accountability and Oversight Act

This bill sets forth additional requirements for certain recipients of National Highway System&#160;assistance for a megaproject. (A megaproject is a project that has an estimated total cost of $2.5 billion or more.)

Specifically, the bill requires a recipient of federal financial assistance for a megaproject&#160;to&#160;

submit to the Department of Transportation (DOT) a comprehensive risk management plan that contains, among other things, a description of the process for identifying, quantifying, and monitoring the risks that might result in cost overruns, delays, reduced construction quality, or reduced megaproject benefits;establish a peer review group that consists of at least five individuals to give expert advice on the scientific, technical, and project management aspects of the megaproject; andpublish specific information online, including the name, license number, and license type of each engineer supervising an aspect of the megaproject.DOT must make arrangements with the Transportation Research Board of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine under which the board must convene a transportation megaprojects committee.

These requirements apply to projects that are authorized for construction beginning at least one year after the bill's enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
