<bill session="116" type="s" number="63" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bipartisan Budget and Appropriations Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan Budget and Appropriations Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Joint Select Committee on Budget and Appropriations Process Reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2019-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2019-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2019-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2019-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBU" name="Senate Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="House Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate Committee on the Budget"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-05T20:00:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bipartisan Budget and Appropriations Reform Act of 2019 

This bill modifies the federal budget process to require biennial congressional budget resolutions, instead of the annual budget resolutions required under current law. The bill retains the existing annual process for budget reconciliation and appropriations bills.

The bill also modifies the budget process to

 allow budget resolutions that have bipartisan support, establish a target for the ratio of the public debt to the gross domestic product, and meet other specified requirements to be considered in the Senate using expedited procedures; require the congressional budget committees to hold joint hearings to hear testimony from the Comptroller General regarding the audited financial statements of the executive branch and the financial position and condition of the federal government; allow budget resolutions to include the total combined outlays and revenues for tax expenditures; and require the chairmen and ranking members of the Senate Appropriations Committee and the Senate Finance Committee to serve on the Senate Budget Committee.</summary>
</bill>
