<bill session="108" type="s" number="1737" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gasoline Free Market Competition Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clayton Act to enhance the authority of the Federal Trade Commission or the Attorney General to prevent anticompetitive practices in tightly concentrated gasoline markets.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gasoline Free Market Competition Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2004-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12621"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2836-2839"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3317"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-09T19:01:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gasoline Free Market Competition Act of 2003 - Amends the Clayton Act to prohibit any person engaging in commerce from: (1) imposing any condition, agreement, or understanding between a crude oil refiner and a motor fuel distributor that limits or prevents the distributor from supplying branded gasoline to independent motor fuel retailers in a highly concentrated market, unless the limitation can be proven not to injure, destroy, or limit competition; (2) selling the same brand of gasoline (if that person is a refiner) to retailers owned or controlled by that refiner in a highly concentrated market at different prices than the refiner charges to its independent dealers, or selling to independent dealers in the same relevant geographic market at different prices if those dealers are located in a highly concentrated market; or (3) engaging in any other practice that the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) determines would be likely to reduce supply or increase the price of gasoline in a highly concentrated market.

Directs the FTC or the Attorney General to provide notice to each refiner, distributor, and retailer doing business in a highly concentrated market that such market is a "consumer watch zone" subject to specified conditions.

Prohibits the FTC or the Attorney General from approving any combination that would create a highly concentrated market that would injure, destroy, or limit competition.

Authorizes State attorneys general to bring civil actions in U.S. district court.</summary>
</bill>
