<bill session="119" type="h" number="1108" updated="2025-06-16T11:33:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Diagnostics Testing Preparedness Plan Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diagnostics Testing Preparedness Plan Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a plan to improve the development and distribution of diagnostic tests during a public health emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2025-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2025-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="891" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1768" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-25T20:11:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Diagnostics Testing Preparedness Plan Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and publish a plan for the rapid development and distribution of diagnostic tests in response to a chemical, biological, radiological, or nuclear&#160;threat, including an emerging infectious disease, that causes or has significant potential to cause a declared public health emergency.

Specifically, HHS must coordinate with any relevant public and private entities, such as government entities&#160;and device manufacturers, in creating the plan and facilitating its collaborative implementation. The plan must take into consideration certain factors specified in the bill, including domestic testing capacity, novel technologies, and medical supply needs. HHS must publish the plan within one year after enactment of the bill and then update the plan every three years.</summary>
</bill>
