<bill session="109" type="s" number="694" updated="2020-02-10T17:00:21Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide for a job training grant pilot program.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to provide for a job training grant pilot program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3156" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-14">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-152.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-11T21:45:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Workforce Investment Act of 1998 to establish a job training grant pilot program.

Directs the Secretary of Labor to make such grants to qualified training programs in the following forms: (1) placement grants, upon placement of a qualified graduate in qualifying employment; and (2) retention grants, in an additional amount, upon retention of a qualified graduate in qualifying employment for one year.Requires the Secretary, in determining the amount of such grants, to consider the economic benefit received by the Government from the employment of the qualified graduate, including increased tax revenue and decreased unemployment benefits or other support obligations. Sets forth criteria for qualified job training programs, qualified graduates, and qualifying employment.</summary>
</bill>
