<bill session="119" type="h" number="2458" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-28T15:58:42-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-04-28T15:58:42-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Space Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Secure Space Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Secure Space Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Secure Space Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Secure Space Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission from granting a license or United States market access for a geostationary orbit satellite system or a nongeostationary orbit satellite system, or an authorization to use an individually licensed earth station or a blanket-licensed earth station, if the license, grant of market access, or authorization would be held or controlled by an entity that produces or provides any covered communications equipment or service or an affiliate of such an entity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000558" joined="2025-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 52 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-24">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 119-65.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-04-24" calendar="Union" number="42">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 42.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T15:52:27-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Bilirakis moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T15:53:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1652-1653: 1" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T15:53:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2458.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-04-28T15:58:42-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1652" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28T15:58:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1768" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-23T17:43:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure Space Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from granting satellite licenses or earth station authorizations, including U.S. market access for foreign-licensed satellites, to specified foreign entities of concern and their affiliates. (Earth stations, also commonly known as ground stations, are earth-based radio stations that communicate with satellites. A grant of U.S. market access permits one or more foreign-licensed satellites to communicate with one or more U.S.-licensed earth stations.)

Specifically, the FCC may not grant a satellite license, an earth station authorization, or market access to any entity, or an affiliate thereof, that produces or provides communications equipment or services deemed to pose an unacceptable risk to the national security of the United States. (The FCC maintains a list of such equipment and services, known as the Covered List. Providers of such equipment and services include, for example, Huawei Technologies Company and ZTE Corporation.)&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-65</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
