<bill session="110" type="s" number="1213" updated="2023-01-11T19:40:45Z">
  <state datetime="2007-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to give States the flexibility to reduce bureaucracy by streamlining enrollment processes for the Medicaid and State Children's Health Insurance Programs through better linkages with programs providing nutrition and related assistance to low-income families.</title>
    <title type="display">Children's Express Lane to Health Coverage Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Children's Express Lane to Health Coverage Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2007-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000055" joined="2007-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2007-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2007-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2007-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-10-03T23:05:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Children's Express Lane to Health Coverage Act of 2007 - Amends titles XIX (Medicaid) and XXI (State Children's Health Insurance) (SCHIP) of the Social Security Act to give states the option of providing for simplified determinations of a child's or pregnant woman's financial eligibility for Medicaid or SCHIP that are made by a non-health federal or state agency administering a program providing nutrition or other public assistance.

Allows state mechanized claims processing and information retrieval systems, for which Medicaid payments may be made, to include technology that enables inter-program connections and other technology that: (1) reduces the number of individuals inaccurately granted eligibility; (2) increases the number of individuals accurately granted eligibility; or (3) improves the efficiency of eligibility determinations.

Authorizes relevant federal, state, local, and private entities to convey information about an individual to a person directly connected with the administration of a state Medicaid plan or SCHIP, if such information is used solely for the purposes of identifying, verifying, and enrolling individuals who are eligible.</summary>
</bill>
