<bill session="118" type="h" number="1171" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:35Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop CCP Fentanyl Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop CCP Fentanyl Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the imposition of sanctions on the Government of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001135" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001086" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000399" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001222" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T19:11:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop CCP Fentanyl Act

This bill imposes sanctions on various Chinese government officials and entities. It also establishes a cause of action against China&#8217;s government or Chinese government officials for certain harms stemming a fentanyl-related overdose.

Specifically, the bill requires the President to impose visa- and property-blocking sanctions on (1) the president of China, (2) the chairman of the Chinese Communist Party (CCP), (3) China&#8217;s State Council, and (4) China&#8217;s Politburo Standing Committee.

The President may waive the sanctions upon certifying that (1) China&#8217;s government and the CCP have taken all reasonable measures to prevent the flow of fentanyl produced in China into the United States, and (2) the intelligence community has determined that amount of fentanyl from China and the deaths resulting from overdoses of such fentanyl has dropped 98%.

This bill also authorizes a U.S. national or lawful permanent resident to sue certain Chinese government officials or the Chinese government for the death of an immediate family member caused by an overdose by fentanyl (or fentanyl analogue) manufactured using fentanyl precursors from China. Property blocked pursuant to sanctions under this bill may be used to satisfy a judgment from such a lawsuit.</summary>
</bill>
