<bill session="108" type="sc" number="13" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A concurrent resolution condemning the selection of Libya to chair the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution condemning the selection of Libya to chair the United Nations Commission on Human Rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2003-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate and ordered held at desk.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3199-3200" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3338-3339" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-03-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3338-3339" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10T12:03:19-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10T12:07:07-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="hc" number="27" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Bombings"/>
    <term name="Bush (George W.) Administration"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commercial aircraft"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International claims"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Scotland"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s257"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Condemns the selection of Libya to chair the United Nations Commission on Human Rights.Commends the President for the principled position of the United States in objecting to and calling for a vote on Libya's chairmanship of the Commission.Commends countries that joined the United States in objecting to Libya's selection as chair of the Commission.Expresses the dismay of Congress at the European Union countries' common position of abstention on the critical vote over Libya's chairmanship.Expresses its shock and dismay over the support provided to Libya in its efforts to lead the Commission.Highlights its grave concern over the continuing efforts of countries violating human rights and terrorist countries to use international fora to legitimize their regimes and to continue to act with impunity.Calls on the President to raise U.S. objections to such efforts during bilateral and multilateral discussions and to direct pertinent members of the President's Cabinet to do the same.Calls on countries at various stages of democratization to: (1) demonstrate their commitment to human rights, democracy, peace and security; and (2) support efforts to reform the Commission.Calls on the President to instruct the Secretary of State to consult with the appropriate congressional committees regarding U.S. priorities and strategy for the 59th session of the Commission on Human Rights and its strategy and proposals for reform of the Commission.Objects to the continued suspension of UN sanctions against Libya until the Government of Libya: (1) publicly accepts responsibility for the bombing of Pan American World Airways Flight 103; (2) provides appropriate compensation to the victims of the bombing; and (3) fully complies with all of the other requirements of the UN sanctions imposed as a result of Libya's orchestration of the terrorist attack on Pan American World Airways Flight 103.Calls on the Secretary of State to engage UN Member States to support efforts to ensure that states that are gross violators of human rights, sponsors of terrorist activities, or subjects of United Nations sanctions are not elected to: (1) leadership positions in the UN General Assembly; or (2) membership or leadership positions on the UN Commission on Human Rights, the UN Security Council, or any other UN entity or affiliate.</summary>
</bill>
