<bill session="108" type="h" number="3356" updated="2023-01-15T07:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Joint Administrative Procedures Committee Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to establish the Joint Administrative Procedures Committee.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">JAPC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Joint Administrative Procedures Committee Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001247"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2003-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2003-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000293" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2004-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2454"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-29T21:09:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Joint Administrative Procedures Committee Act of 2003 (JAPC Act) - Establishes a Joint Administrative Procedures Committee to selectively review existing major rules of Federal agencies and recommend amendment or repeal of such rules. Directs the Committee to periodically review the regulatory plan of each agency of its most important significant regulatory actions that the agency reasonably expects to issue in proposed or final form in the fiscal year in which the plan is submitted.

Makes it in order for any Member of the House, after the third legislative day after the date on which the committee to which a joint resolution is referred has reported, to move to proceed to consideration of a joint resolution. Waives all points of order against the motion to proceed and against consideration of that motion. Makes the motion privileged in the House and not debatable. Provides that: (1) the motion is not subject to amendment, to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business; and (2) debate in the House shall not exceed one hour.

Provides that: (1) before a rule can take effect, the Federal agency promulgating the rule shall submit to each house of Congress and to the Comptroller General a report to the Committee; and (2) within a specified time frame, the Committee may report a committee resolution recommending that each standing committee with jurisdiction to which copies of the applicable report were provided report a joint resolution disapproving the applicable rule.</summary>
</bill>
