<bill session="112" type="hc" number="2" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:05Z">
  <state datetime="2011-01-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Commission on the European Union Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Establishing the Congressional Commission on the European Union, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Commission on the European Union Resolution</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-01-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional Budget Office (CBO)"/>
    <term name="Congressional Research Service (CRS)"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-13T17:07:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Commission on the European Union Resolution - Establishes the Congressional Commission on the European Union (Commission), which shall be composed of 18 Members of the House of Representatives and Senate, to work with the European Parliament of the European Union (EU) and the European Commission in order to: (1) enable Members, officers, and employees of Congress to provide expert advice to members and staff of the EU and the European Commission and to permit members and staff of such entities to obtain the services of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO), the Congressional Research Service (CRS), and the Government Accountability Office (GAO); (2) enable members and staff of the EU and the European Commission visiting Congress and its support agencies to learn first-hand about their corresponding operations; and (3) provide information and recommendations to committees of the House of Representatives and Senate regarding legislation, regulatory standards, and activities being proposed by the EU and the European Commission.

Directs the Commission to conduct an annual study on the impact on U.S. interests of legislation recently passed by the European Parliament and regulations issued by the European Commission.</summary>
</bill>
