<bill session="108" type="h" number="3661" updated="2023-01-15T09:17:39Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Illegal Transshipments Enforcement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide for the seizure, forfeiture, and destruction of textile and apparel articles imported in violation of certain laws of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Illegal Transshipments Enforcement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001029"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000104" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000280" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000981" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001146" joined="2004-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2004-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Clothing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-02-19T22:50:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Illegal Transshipments Enforcement Act of 2003 - Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize the appropriate customs officer to destroy textile or apparel products that have been forfeited by reason of a violation of the customs laws.

Revises the authority of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection of the Department of Homeland Security to seize merchandise introduced or attempted to be introduced into the United States contrary to law if the importer has received written notices that previous importations of merchandise from the same supplier were found to have been marked in violation of country-of-origin marking requirements. (Current law limits such condition to identical merchandise from the same supplier marked in violation of such requirements.)

Changes the monetary penalties for specified violations by customs brokers from $30,000 in total for a violation or violations to $100,000 for each violation.

Amends the Federal criminal code to repeal the requirement of specific intent to convert to personal use from the prohibition against theft or fraudulent acquisition of goods or chattels in an interstate or foreign shipment of cargo. Adds to the list of vehicles or facilities involved any trailer, air cargo container, intermodal container, trailer, container freight station, warehouse, or freight consolidation facility. Increases from one to three years the prison term for any such felony involving less than $1,000. States that goods and chattel shall be construed to be moving as an interstate or foreign shipment at all points between the point of origin and the final destination (as evidenced by the waybill or other shipping document of the shipment), regardless of any temporary stop while awaiting transshipment or otherwise.

Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review the Federal Sentencing Guidelines for such felonies and promulgate any appropriate amendments.</summary>
</bill>
