<bill session="117" type="h" number="9029" updated="2023-04-24T13:45:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to identify and develop campsites and related facilities for public use in the Ouachita National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000821"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-14T23:05:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Ouachita National Forest Overnight Camping Act

This bill requires the identification and development of campsites and related facilities in the Ouachita National Forest in Arkansas.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall (1) identify areas within Albert Pike Recreation Area that may be suitable for overnight camping; (2) review each area identified; and (3) from the areas identified, select and establish campsites and related facilities within the recreation area for public use.

USDA must ensure (1) that at least 54 campsites are available, of which not less than 8 shall have electric and water hookups; and (2) that each campsite and related facility identified or established is located outside of the 1% annual exceedance probability flood elevation.

Not later than 30 days after the enactment of this bill, USDA shall open each campsite within the recreation area that (1) exists on the enactment of this bill, and (2) is located outside of the 1% annual exceedance probability flood elevation.</summary>
</bill>
