<bill session="108" type="s" number="458" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Southwest Regional Border Authority Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Southwest Regional Border Authority.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southwest Regional Border Authority Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2003-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2849-2850"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2850-2855" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1071" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Entrepreneurs"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Southwest Regional Border Authority Act - Establishes the Southwest Regional Border Authority to: (1) develop plans and programs for the economic development of the Southwest border region (specified counties in California, New Mexico, and Texas); (2) conduct and sponsor investigations, research, and studies of the resources of the region; (3) sponsor up to ten authorized demonstration projects; (4) enhance the capacity of and support for local development districts or, if there is no such district for a portion of the region, foster the creation of one; (5) review, study, and recommend appropriate modifications to Federal, State, and local development programs for the region; (6) formulate and recommend interstate compacts and other forms of interstate and international cooperation; (7) encourage private investment in the region; (8) provide a forum for the consideration of problems of the region; (9) establish and use citizens, special advisory counsels, and public conferences; and (10) provide for the avoidance of duplication of efforts among the border programs of Federal agencies and the programs established under the North American Free Trade Agreement.Authorizes the Authority to approve grants for regional infrastructure development and improvement, technology development and deployment, community development and entrepreneurship, and education and workforce development. Provides funding. Requires the Authority to allocate at least 60 percent of the amounts authorized under this Act for programs and projects to serve the needs of distressed counties and isolated areas of distress within counties along the international border between the United States and Mexico. Authorizes the Authority to increase the Federal share to up to 90 percent of a project's total cost (to aid communities that could not otherwise meet matching funds requirements). Requires the Authority to make grants to local development districts for administrative expenses.Directs the Authority, for purposes of grant assistance, to designate within the region distressed counties, economically strong counties, attainment counties, competitive counties, and isolated areas of distress.Requires each affected State to submit to the Authority an annual development plan for the appropriate State area within the region.</summary>
</bill>
