<bill session="117" type="h" number="5885" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To establish an interagency task force to address the backlog of cargo ships at the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach and in the coastal waters of Orange County, California, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an interagency task force to address the backlog of cargo ships at the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach and in the coastal waters of Orange County, California, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-27T15:46:13Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Coast Guard to establish an interagency task force to address the vessel backlogs at the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach and in the coastal waters of Orange County, California.

Specifically, the task force must

 evaluate and quantify the impact of the vessel backlogs at the Port of Los Angeles and the Port of Long Beach, evaluate and quantify the costs incurred by other federal, state, and local governments due to such vessel backlogs, evaluate the responses of federal agencies to such vessel backlogs, investigate the cause of the oil spill that occurred in October 2021 in the coastal waters of Orange County, and develop and report on a plan to solve the vessel backlog and oil spill crises along the coast of southern California.</summary>
</bill>
