<bill session="110" type="s" number="1989" updated="2023-01-11T20:36:02Z">
  <state datetime="2007-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a mechanism for the determination on the merits of the claims of claimants who met the class criteria in a civil action relating to racial discrimination by the Department of Agriculture but who were denied that determination.</title>
    <title type="display">Pigford Claims Remedy Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pigford Claims Remedy Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000167"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3073" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-01-23T22:17:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pigford Claims Remedy Act of 2007 - Declares that any Pigford claimant (relating to a racial discrimination action against the Department of Agriculture) who has not previously obtained a determination on the merits of a Pigford claim may, in a civil action, obtain that determination.

Asserts that it is Congress's intent that this Act be liberally construed so as to effectuate its remedial purpose of giving a full determination on the merits for each denied Pigford claim.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide a claimant with a report on farm credit loans made within the claimant's county or adjacent county during a specified period which shall contain information on all accepted applicants (but without any personally identifiable information), including: (1) the applicant's race; (2) the application and loan decision dates; and (3) the location of the office making the loan decision.

Sets forth provisions respecting: (1) expedited claim resolution; and (2) foreclosure limitation.

Defines: (1) "Pigford claimant" as an individual who previously submitted a late-filing request under the consent decree in the case of Pigford v. Glickman (1999); and (2) "Pigford claim" as a discrimination complaint as defined and documented by such consent decree.</summary>
</bill>
