<bill session="115" type="h" number="5727" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:34Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the San Rafael Swell Western Heritage and Historic Mining National Conservation Area in the State of Utah, to designate wilderness areas in the State, to provide for certain land conveyances, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001050" joined="2018-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-12-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1071.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-12-10" calendar="Union" number="832">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 832.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2809" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3803" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-04T14:51:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Emery County Public Land Management Act of 2018

This bill establishes the San Rafael Swell Western Heritage and Historic Mining National Conservation Area, consisting of 336,467 acres in Utah. The bill also amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate a 54-mile segment of Green River, which is located in the area, as a component of the national wild and scenic rivers system.

Over 500,000 acres in Utah are designated as national wilderness areas, including Candland Mountain, Crack Canyon, Desolation Canyon, Devil's Canyon, Horseshoe Canyon (North), Mexican Mountain, Muddy Creek, Nelson Mountain, San Rafael Reef, and Sid's Mountain.

With respect to the newly established conservation area and wilderness areas, the bill:

 allows for commercial services to the extent necessary to fulfill the areas' recreational or other purposes; allows the grazing of livestock, if already established, to continue; allows for the "casual collection" (for noncommercial use) of plants, rocks, and minerals; and otherwise provides for management by the Department of the Interior. In addition, with respect to other land in Utah, the bill provides for:

 the cooperative (state and federal) management of the Temple Mountain Cooperative Management Area (7,792 acres); the management of the Goblin Valley State Park Expansion as a state park; the establishment and management of the Jurassic National Monument (2,534 acres); and public purpose conveyances, by Interior to the applicable local government entity, of the Huntington Airport (1,400 acres), the Emery City Recreation Area (640 acres), the State Road 6 Emery Sheriff's Office substation site (640 acres), and the Buckhorn Information Center (65 acres).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1071</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
