<bill session="110" type="s" number="1933" updated="2023-01-11T20:36:28Z">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to provide grants to small public drinking water systems.</title>
    <title type="display">Small Community Drinking Water Funding Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Small Community Drinking Water Funding Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Community Drinking Water Funding Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000705" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2007-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2007-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10623-10624"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10624-10627" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 110-475. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1036">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1036.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-09T19:24:51Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Small Community Drinking Water Funding Act - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish within EPA, not later than July 1, 2008, a Small Public Water System Assistance Program for states and Indian tribes. Directs the head of such Program to: (1) establish and administer a small public water system assistance program for, and provide grants to, eligible entities located in areas governed by Indian tribes; (2) identify priorities for program activities; (3) provide funds to states for establishing small public water system assistance programs; and (4) report to the Administrator on program activities.

Defines: (1) "small public water system" as a public water system that serves a population of 10,000 or fewer; and (2) "eligible entity" as such a system that is located in a state or an area governed by an Indian tribe and that serves a disadvantaged community. Sets forth criteria for the allocation and use of funds for state and Indian tribe small public water systems.

Requires the Administrator to report annually between 2009 and 2014 to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works on Program activities and make such reports public.

Sets forth requirements for state and Indian tribe small public water system assistance programs, including identification of priorities relating to health and compliance with national primary water regulations, use of funds, cost sharing, and reporting.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2008-FY2014.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 110-475</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
