<bill session="115" type="h" number="3706" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:45Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native Health and Wellness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Health and Wellness Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the public health system in tribal communities and increase the number of American Indians and Alaska Natives pursuing health careers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2017-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T17:12:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Native Health and Wellness Act of 2017

This bill amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to award grants to Indian tribes or tribal organizations for promoting health, preventing disease, and reducing health disparities among American Indians and Alaska Natives. Specifically, grants may be used to:

 establish or support preventive health service programs that facilitate the achievement of health-status goals; establish or support public health services that reduce the prevalence of chronic disease among American Indians and Alaska Natives, or strengthen public health infrastructure to facilitate the surveillance and response to infectious disease and foodborne illness outbreaks. In addition, the Department of Health and Human Services must make grants to Indian tribes and tribal organizations for recruiting and mentoring American Indian and Alaska Native youth and young adults in health professions.</summary>
</bill>
