<bill session="116" type="h" number="5926" updated="2022-04-22T15:45:22Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESILIENT Networks Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for expedient restoration of advanced communications service networks during times of emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinforcing and Evaluating Service Integrity, Local Infrastructure, and Emergency Notification for Today&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Networks Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESILIENT Networks Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2020-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-22T15:32:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Reinforcing and Evaluating Service Integrity, Local Infrastructure, and Emergency Notification for Today's Networks Act or the RESILIENT Networks Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to adopt certain rules, recommend best practices, and issue reports intended to promote the resiliency of communications networks during emergencies.

Specifically, the bill requires the FCC to adopt rules that provide for (1) coordination among communications providers during emergencies; and (2) coordination and outage information sharing between communications providers, public safety answering points (i.e., the points where emergency calls are routed), and certain public safety entities responsible for emergency management functions.

Additionally, the FCC must conduct a study to determine the feasibility of expanding the one-call notification system, used to identify the location of electric and gas transmission lines, to cover communications services.

The FCC must recommend best practices and establish a process for coordination and information sharing between communications providers and utilities during emergencies and planned power shutoffs. The FCC must also ensure that communications providers take measures to integrate backup power into their networks to maintain operation during emergencies.

Further, the FCC must report on any unique challenges or advantages of fifth generation (5G) wireless networks regarding their resiliency to withstand disruptions during emergencies.

The Government Accountability Office must conduct a performance audit of the FCC's efforts to restore communications services in Puerto Rico during, and following, the 2017 hurricane season, and the FCC must commence a proceeding to address the findings and recommendations of such audit.</summary>
</bill>
