<bill session="119" type="s" number="2050" updated="2025-07-25T16:16:08Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ASSIST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASSIST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to provide for an increased Federal medical assistance percentage for State expenditures on certain behavioral health services furnished under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T16:15:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act or the ASSIST Act

This bill establishes programs and requirements to support the provision of mental health and substance use disorder services at schools.

Specifically, the bill provides for a 90% Federal Medical Assistance Percentage (i.e., federal matching rate) under Medicaid for services that are furnished by mental health and substance use disorder providers at schools or school-based health centers. Qualifying services include those provided by school counselors, social workers, and psychologists.&#160;

The bill also establishes a grant program to increase the number of mental health and substance use disorder providers at schools, colleges, and other educational institutions.</summary>
</bill>
