<bill session="118" type="s" number="1385" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recreation for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recreation for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to develop a national strategy to increase the number of youth recreation visits to Federal land, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="873" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-28T17:41:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recreation for All Act

This bill addresses ways to increase recreation and youth visits to federal land.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture to develop and make public a national strategy to increase the number of youth recreation visits to federal land. Such strategy shall meet specified requirements, including to emphasize increased recreational opportunities on federal land for underserved youth.

Further, the departments must

 establish pilot protocols at not fewer than 10 land management units to model recreation use patterns that may not be effectively measured by existing general and opportunistic survey and monitoring protocols; and alert the public to any closure or disruption to public campsites, trails, roads, and other public areas and access points in a timely manner, through an online alert system. The Office of Management and Budget must make public online a report that describes and itemizes the total amount of funding relating to outdoor recreation that was obligated in the preceding fiscal year in Treasury accounts for the departments.</summary>
</bill>
