<bill session="115" type="h" number="5515" updated="2023-03-22T19:50:55Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-13">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-08-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2019 for military activities of the Department of Defense, for military construction, and for defense activities of the Department of Energy, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2019 for military activities of the Department of Defense and for military construction, to prescribe military personnel strengths for such fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">National Guard Promotion Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Federal Maritime Commission Authorization Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Guardians of America's Freedom Medal Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">National Guard Promotion Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">National Timing Resilience and Security Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Purple Heart and Disabled Veterans Equal Access Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">United States Virgin Islands Small Business Contracting Assistance Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Foreign Investment Risk Review Modernization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Anti-Boycott Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Export Control Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Export Controls Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Foreign Investment Risk Review Modernization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Purple Heart and Disabled Veterans Equal Access Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report">John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Anti-Boycott Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Export Control Reform Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Export Controls Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Foreign Investment Risk Review Modernization Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="conference report" partial="1">Purple Heart and Disabled Veterans Equal Access Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000238"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2018-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Strategic Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Tactical Air and Land Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Seapower and Projection Forces.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats and Capabilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 60 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Armed Services. H. Rept. 115-676.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-05-15" calendar="Union" number="521">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 521.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-05-21T19:19:02-04:00">
      <text>SUPPLEMENTAL FILING AUTHORITY - Mr. Mitchell asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Armed Services be authorized to file a supplemental report on the bill H.R. 5515. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-21">
      <text>Supplemental report filed by the Committee on Armed Services, H. Rept. 115-676, Part II.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-21T21:28:11-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 905 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5515, S. 204 and S. 2155. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 5515, S. 204 and S. 2155. The resolution provides for consideration of S. 2155 and S. 204 under a closed rule. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5515 under a structured rule and makes an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 115-70 considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:43:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 905.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4367-4562" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4378-4556" label="text of amendment in nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:43:29-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5515, S. 204 and S. 2155. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 5515, S. 204 and S. 2155. The resolution provides for consideration of S. 2155 and S. 204 under a closed rule. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 5515 under a structured rule and makes an amendment in the nature of a substitute consisting of the text of Rules Committee Print 115-70 considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:43:39-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Gregg Harper to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:43:39-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 905 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T17:45:18-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T18:45:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Thornberry amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T18:50:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Nolan amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:00:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nolan amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Nolan demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:01:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Gabbard amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:10:51-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gabbard amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Gabbard demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:11:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Aguilar amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:20:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Aguilar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Aguilar demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:21:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:31:41-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garamendi amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Smith (WA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:31:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:32:16-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:32:28-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5515 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:32:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4562-4580" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:33:18-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:35:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:45:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 905, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:55:52-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:56:05-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T19:56:12-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5515 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-22T23:35:59-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 908 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5515. The resolution makes in order only those further amendments printed in the Rules Committee report. The rule provides that on any legislative day during the period from May 25, 2018 through June 4, 2018: the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved; and the Chair may at any time declare the House adjourned to meet at a date and time to be announced by the Chair in declaring the adjournment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:04:28-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 908 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:04:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4603-4606" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:04:56-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:05:52-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:26:42-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5515 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:27:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4606-4672" label="Consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:28:10-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:35:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 1, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:48:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Guthrie amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T14:56:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Amodei amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:06:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amodei amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lowenthal demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:07:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the McGovern amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:10:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McGovern amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:11:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the McKinley amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:20:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McKinley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McKinley demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:21:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:30:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tenney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Tenney demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:31:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Engel amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:34:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Engel amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Engel demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:35:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Polis amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:42:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Polis amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Polis demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:43:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeed with 10 minutes of debate on the Gallagher amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T15:54:58-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:51:28-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:51:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:51:49-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5515 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:52:57-04:00">
      <text>Thornberry amendment en bloc No. 4; modified by unanimous consent. Modification strikes amendment No. 69 printed in House Report 115-698.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:52:59-04:00">
      <text>THORNBERRY EN BLOC NO. 4, AS MODIFIED - Amendments en bloc offered by Mr. Thornberry, comprised of the following amendments printed in House Report 115-698 as En Bloc No. 4: Nos. 55, as modified, 57, 58, 59, 60, 61, 62, 63, 64, 65, 66, 67, 68, and 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:53:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4673-4682" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:53:41-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T16:55:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T17:15:32-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T17:15:46-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-23T17:15:56-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5515 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:14:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4699-4722" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:14:49-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:15:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:27:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:29:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:30:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Thornberry En Bloc amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:39:05-04:00">
      <text>The Committee resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:39:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 908, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ferguson amendment No. 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:44:37-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:45:34-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:45:46-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4717" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:46:39-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (CA) moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4717-4720" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:46:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, pending the reservation of a point of order. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to add, at the end of the bill a new section consisting of the bill titled "Public Safety and Second Amendment Rights Protection Act of 2018".</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:54:25-04:00">
      <text>Point of order sustained against the motion to recommit with instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:54:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry raised a point of order against the motion to recommit with instructions. Mr. Thornberry made a point of order that the amendment violates clause 10 of rule 21 by proposing an increase in mandatory spending over a relevant period of time. Sustained by the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:55:38-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thompson (CA) appealed the ruling of the chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T09:55:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T10:23:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion to table the motion to appeal the ruling of the chair Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 191 (Roll no. 229).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="230" datetime="2018-05-24T10:33:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 351 - 66 (Roll no. 230).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T10:33:09-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T10:33:13-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-05-24T10:33:14-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-06-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="442">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 442.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3005-3023" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-06">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3005"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-07">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3281-3289" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="119" datetime="2018-06-07" where="s" result="pass">
      <text>Cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 92 - 4. Record Vote Number: 119.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3282"/>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2018-06-11">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3395"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-11">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 4. Record Vote Number: 120.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-11">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3403-3596" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-12">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3730-3754, S3756-3757" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-12">
      <text>Cloture motion on the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3757" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-13">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3866-3899" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3932-3943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-14">
      <text>Cloture on the measure invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 81 - 15. Record Vote Number: 126.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-18">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3961-3973" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="128" datetime="2018-06-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 85 - 10. Record Vote Number: 128.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-06-19">
      <text>Senate ordered measure printed as passed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:09:06-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5782-5783" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5782" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:09:41-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and request a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:09:42-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Carbajal moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:10:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the Carbajal motion to instruct conferees on H.R. 5515. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to agree to section 703 of the Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:26:27-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:26:28-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 188 - 231 (Roll No. 300).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:53:51-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry moved to close portions of the conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:56:27-04:00">
      <text>On Closing Portions of the Conference Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 403 - 15 (Roll no. 301).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T15:56:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T16:12:55-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Armed Services for consideration of the House bill and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Thornberry, Wilson of South Carolina, LoBiondo, Bishop of Utah, Turner, Rogers of Alabama, Shuster, Conaway, Lamborn, Wittman, Coffman, Hartzler, Austin Scott of Georgia, Cook, Byrne, Stefanik, Bacon, Banks of Indiana, Smith of Washington, Davis of California, Langevin, Cooper, Bordallo, Courtney, Tsongas, Garamendi, Speier, Veasey, Gabbard, O'Rourke, and Murphy of Florida.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T16:13:24-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Energy and Commerce for consideration of title XVII of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Latta, Johnson (OH), and Pallone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T16:13:39-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Financial Services for consideration of title XVII of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Hensarling, Barr, and Waters, Maxine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27T16:13:47-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Foreign Affairs for consideration of title XVII of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Royce (CA), Kinzinger, and Engel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:06:55-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence for consideration of matters within the jurisdiction of that committee under clause 11 of rule X: Nunes, Stewart, and Schiff.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:07:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on the Budget for consideration of secs. 1252 and 1523 of the House bill, and secs. 4, 1002, 1032, and 1721 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Womack and Yarmuth.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:07:15-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Education and the Workforce for consideration of secs. 228, 563, 564, 1094, and 3120C of the House bill, and secs. 561-63 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Foxx and Scott (VA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:07:30-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Energy and Commerce for consideration of secs. 701, 712, 1083, 1096, 3111-13, 3118, 3119, 3132, and 4305 of the House bill, and secs. 315, 601, 714, 3111-15, 5802, and 7509 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Walden, Hudson, and Pallone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:07:45-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Financial Services for consideration of 1299O-2 and 1236 of the House bill, and modifications committed to conference: Hensarling, Barr, and Waters, Maxine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:08:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Foreign Affairs for consideration of secs. 346, 1042, 1202-06, 1210, 1211, 1221-23, 1230A, 1230D, 1230F, 1231, 1234, 1236, 1237, 1239, 1240, 1254-56, 1264, 1267, 1268, 1271, 1274, 1276, 1278, 1280, 1282, 1288, 1299O-1, 1299O-2, 1299O-3, 1299O-4, 1301, 1302, 1521, 1522, and 3116 of the House bill, and secs. 331, 1061, 1063, 1201-04, 1207, 1211, 1213, 1221-23, 1231-33, 1241, 1244, 1245, 1261, 1262, 1264-66, 1269, 1301, 1302, 1531, 1622, 1623, 1654, 3113, 3116, 6002, 6202-04, 6701, and 6702 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Royce (CA), Mast, and Engel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:08:20-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Homeland Security for consideration of sec. 1634 of the House bill, and modifications committed to conference: McCaul, Ratcliffe, and Thompson (MS).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:08:30-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on the Judiciary for consideration of secs. 826, 1043, 1050B, 1073, 1074, 1079, 1085, 1087, 1090, 1299O-2, 4319, and 4710 of the House bill, and secs. 1025, 1035 and 1715 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Goodlatte, Sensenbrenner, and Nadler.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:09:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Natural Resources for consideration of secs. 313, 314, 316, 342, 1043, 1076, 1079, 2822, 2830, 2830A, 2831, 2832, 2845-47, 3402, 3549, 4810, 4837, division E, and sec. 6101 of the House bill, and secs. 601, 2833, 2836, and 7518 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Westerman and Grijalva.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:09:35-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform for consideration of secs. 506, 511, 569, 822, 831, 832, 834, 835, 860, 875, 880-84, 886, 917, 1101-11, 4711, and 4829 of the House bill, and secs. 568, 595, 607, 632, 702, 813, 902, 937, 1101-05, 1122-25, 1254B, 1628, 1639, 1640, 1716, 1726, 2835, and 6702 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Sanford, Ross, and Lynch.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:10:00-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology for consideration of secs. 854, 858, and 1603 of the House bill, and secs. 893 and 1604 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Smith (TX), Lucas, and Johnson, E. B..</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:10:32-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Small Business for consideration of secs. 811, 851-58, 861, 863-68, and 2803 of the House bill, and secs. 893, 1626, and 6006 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Chabot, Knight, and Velazquez.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:10:50-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure for consideration of secs. 518, 554, 883, 1044, 1049, 1050B, 1075, 1095, 1111, 2848, 3501, 3504, 3522-25, 3528, 3529, and division D of the House bill, and secs. 153, 556, 601, 1604, 3501, 3502, 7501, 7502, 7507-09, 7515, and 7517 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Comstock and Brownley (CA).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:11:30-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Veterans' Affairs for consideration of secs. 547, 552, 582, 1411, and 2844 of the House bill, and secs. 721, 726, and 1431 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Roe (TN), Poliquin, and Walz.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:11:45-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed additional conferees - from the Committee on Ways and Means for consideration of sec. 701 of the House bill, and sec. 6201 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Reichert, Roskam, and Neal.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:12:15-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed a conferee for consideration of secs. 313, 314, 316, 342, 1043, 1076, 1079, 1252, 1523, 2822, 2830, 2830A, 2831, 2832, 2845-47, 3402, 3549, 4810, 4837, division E, and sec. 6101 of the House bill and secs. 4, 601, 1002, 1032, 1721, 2833, 2836, and 7518 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Bergman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-03T11:12:45-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed a conferee for consideration of secs. 228, 518, 554, 563, 564, 883, 1044, 1049, 1050B, 1075, 1094, 1095, 1111, 2848, 3120C, 3501, 3504, 3522-25, 3528, 3529, and division D of the House bill and secs. 153, 556, 561-63, 601, 1604, 3501, 3502, 7501, 7502, 7507-09, 7515, and 7517 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Lewis (MN).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion to insist on Senate amendment to House bill, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion to insist on Senate amendment to House bill, agree to request for conference, and authorize the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 91 - 8. Record Vote Number: 147.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, agrees to request for conference, and authorizes the Presiding Officer to appoint conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion by Senator Cornyn to instruct Senate conferees made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion by Senator Cornyn to instruct Senate conferees (Committee on Foreign Investment) agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 2. Record Vote Number: 148.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reed to instruct Senate conferees made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Motion by Senator Reed to instruct Senate conferees (NATO) agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 97 - 2. Record Vote Number: 149.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-10">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees. McCain; Inhofe; Wicker; Fischer; Cotton; Rounds; Ernst; Tillis; Sullivan; Perdue; Cruz; Graham; Sasse; Scott; Crapo; Reed; Nelson; McCaskill; Shaheen; Gillibrand; Blumenthal; Donnelly; Hirono; Kaine; King; Heinrich; Warren; Peters; Brown.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-23T20:51:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 115-863 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6653-7088" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24T20:38:00-04:00">
      <text>House recommitted the conference report pursuant to H. Res. 1019.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-24T20:38:07-04:00">
      <text>House recommitted the conference report pursuant to H.Res. 1019</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25T14:26:00-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 115-874 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7202-7637" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25T16:42:59-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1027 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T10:27:07-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1027 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T10:29:14-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Thornberry brought up conference report H. Rept. 115-874 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 1027.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7699-7709" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T10:30:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T11:12:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 5515.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T11:33:54-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="379" datetime="2018-07-26T12:11:41-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 359 - 54 (Roll no. 379).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7708-7709" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26T12:11:43-04:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5412-5417" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-26">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report to accompany H.R. 5515 presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5412"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-01">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5538-5543" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-01">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report to accompany H.R. 5515 withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="181" datetime="2018-08-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 87 - 10. Record Vote Number: 181.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-08-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2018-08-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2018-08-13" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="115-232" type="public" datetime="2018-08-13">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 115-232.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Reporting, Markup, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS26" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Intelligence and Special Operations" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS28" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Seapower and Projection Forces" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS25" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Tactical Air and Land Forces" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS29" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Strategic Forces" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6368" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6328" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="1027" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6862" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6712" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5901" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3509" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="7180" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="140" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1887" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2211" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2954" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2987" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2518" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2593" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1129" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4663" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2893" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="908" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5921" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="847" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5746" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="905" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="1019" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3607" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2702" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5178" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5236" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4319" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6141" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5038" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="hr" number="846" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="88" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="256" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="555" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="788" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="941" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1800" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2056" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2364" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3897" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4171" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4299" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4486" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4754" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4939" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5326" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5348" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5356" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5452" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5591" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5622" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5681" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5707" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5713" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="526" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="593" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1534" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2088" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2801" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5467" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3201" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2805" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2333" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5040" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5841" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2098" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2789" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces Retirement Home"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Burkina Faso"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chad"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mali"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Mauritania"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Military law"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Niger"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Somalia"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h660"/>
    <amendment number="h659"/>
    <amendment number="h658"/>
    <amendment number="h657"/>
    <amendment number="h656"/>
    <amendment number="h655"/>
    <amendment number="h654"/>
    <amendment number="h653"/>
    <amendment number="h652"/>
    <amendment number="h651"/>
    <amendment number="h650"/>
    <amendment number="h649"/>
    <amendment number="h648"/>
    <amendment number="h647"/>
    <amendment number="h646"/>
    <amendment number="h645"/>
    <amendment number="h644"/>
    <amendment number="h643"/>
    <amendment number="h642"/>
    <amendment number="h641"/>
    <amendment number="h640"/>
    <amendment number="h639"/>
    <amendment number="h638"/>
    <amendment number="h637"/>
    <amendment number="h636"/>
    <amendment number="h635"/>
    <amendment number="h634"/>
    <amendment number="s2909"/>
    <amendment number="s2908"/>
    <amendment number="s2906"/>
    <amendment number="s2905"/>
    <amendment number="s2904"/>
    <amendment number="s2903"/>
    <amendment number="s2902"/>
    <amendment number="s2901"/>
    <amendment number="s2900"/>
    <amendment number="s2899"/>
    <amendment number="s2898"/>
    <amendment number="s2897"/>
    <amendment number="s2896"/>
    <amendment number="s2895"/>
    <amendment number="s2894"/>
    <amendment number="s2893"/>
    <amendment number="s2892"/>
    <amendment number="s2891"/>
    <amendment number="s2890"/>
    <amendment number="s2889"/>
    <amendment number="s2888"/>
    <amendment number="s2887"/>
    <amendment number="s2886"/>
    <amendment number="s2885"/>
    <amendment number="s2884"/>
    <amendment number="s2883"/>
    <amendment number="s2882"/>
    <amendment number="s2881"/>
    <amendment number="s2880"/>
    <amendment number="s2879"/>
    <amendment number="s2878"/>
    <amendment number="s2877"/>
    <amendment number="s2876"/>
    <amendment number="s2875"/>
    <amendment number="s2874"/>
    <amendment number="s2873"/>
    <amendment number="s2872"/>
    <amendment number="s2871"/>
    <amendment number="s2870"/>
    <amendment number="s2869"/>
    <amendment number="s2868"/>
    <amendment number="s2867"/>
    <amendment number="s2866"/>
    <amendment number="s2865"/>
    <amendment number="s2864"/>
    <amendment number="s2863"/>
    <amendment number="s2862"/>
    <amendment number="s2861"/>
    <amendment number="s2860"/>
    <amendment number="s2859"/>
    <amendment number="s2858"/>
    <amendment number="s2857"/>
    <amendment number="s2856"/>
    <amendment number="s2855"/>
    <amendment number="s2854"/>
    <amendment number="s2853"/>
    <amendment number="s2852"/>
    <amendment number="s2851"/>
    <amendment number="s2850"/>
    <amendment number="s2849"/>
    <amendment number="s2848"/>
    <amendment number="s2847"/>
    <amendment number="s2846"/>
    <amendment number="s2845"/>
    <amendment number="s2844"/>
    <amendment number="s2843"/>
    <amendment number="s2842"/>
    <amendment number="s2841"/>
    <amendment number="s2840"/>
    <amendment number="s2839"/>
    <amendment number="s2838"/>
    <amendment number="s2837"/>
    <amendment number="s2836"/>
    <amendment number="s2835"/>
    <amendment number="s2834"/>
    <amendment number="s2833"/>
    <amendment number="s2832"/>
    <amendment number="s2831"/>
    <amendment number="s2830"/>
    <amendment number="s2829"/>
    <amendment number="s2828"/>
    <amendment number="s2827"/>
    <amendment number="s2826"/>
    <amendment number="s2825"/>
    <amendment number="s2824"/>
    <amendment number="s2823"/>
    <amendment number="s2822"/>
    <amendment number="s2821"/>
    <amendment number="s2820"/>
    <amendment number="s2819"/>
    <amendment number="s2818"/>
    <amendment number="s2817"/>
    <amendment number="s2816"/>
    <amendment number="s2815"/>
    <amendment number="s2814"/>
    <amendment number="s2813"/>
    <amendment number="s2812"/>
    <amendment number="s2811"/>
    <amendment number="s2810"/>
    <amendment number="s2809"/>
    <amendment number="s2808"/>
    <amendment number="s2807"/>
    <amendment number="s2806"/>
    <amendment number="s2805"/>
    <amendment number="s2804"/>
    <amendment number="s2803"/>
    <amendment number="s2802"/>
    <amendment number="s2801"/>
    <amendment number="s2800"/>
    <amendment number="s2799"/>
    <amendment number="s2798"/>
    <amendment number="s2797"/>
    <amendment number="s2796"/>
    <amendment number="s2795"/>
    <amendment number="s2794"/>
    <amendment number="s2793"/>
    <amendment number="s2792"/>
    <amendment number="s2791"/>
    <amendment number="s2790"/>
    <amendment number="s2789"/>
    <amendment number="s2788"/>
    <amendment number="s2787"/>
    <amendment number="s2786"/>
    <amendment number="s2785"/>
    <amendment number="s2784"/>
    <amendment number="s2783"/>
    <amendment number="s2782"/>
    <amendment number="s2781"/>
    <amendment number="s2780"/>
    <amendment number="s2779"/>
    <amendment number="s2778"/>
    <amendment number="s2777"/>
    <amendment number="s2776"/>
    <amendment number="s2775"/>
    <amendment number="s2774"/>
    <amendment number="s2773"/>
    <amendment number="s2772"/>
    <amendment number="s2771"/>
    <amendment number="s2770"/>
    <amendment number="s2769"/>
    <amendment number="s2768"/>
    <amendment number="s2767"/>
    <amendment number="s2766"/>
    <amendment number="s2765"/>
    <amendment number="s2764"/>
    <amendment number="s2763"/>
    <amendment number="s2762"/>
    <amendment number="s2761"/>
    <amendment number="s2760"/>
    <amendment number="s2759"/>
    <amendment number="s2758"/>
    <amendment number="s2757"/>
    <amendment number="s2756"/>
    <amendment number="s2755"/>
    <amendment number="s2754"/>
    <amendment number="s2753"/>
    <amendment number="s2752"/>
    <amendment number="s2751"/>
    <amendment number="s2750"/>
    <amendment number="s2749"/>
    <amendment number="s2748"/>
    <amendment number="s2747"/>
    <amendment number="s2746"/>
    <amendment number="s2745"/>
    <amendment number="s2744"/>
    <amendment number="s2743"/>
    <amendment number="s2742"/>
    <amendment number="s2741"/>
    <amendment number="s2740"/>
    <amendment number="s2739"/>
    <amendment number="s2738"/>
    <amendment number="s2737"/>
    <amendment number="s2736"/>
    <amendment number="s2735"/>
    <amendment number="s2734"/>
    <amendment number="s2733"/>
    <amendment number="s2732"/>
    <amendment number="s2731"/>
    <amendment number="s2730"/>
    <amendment number="s2729"/>
    <amendment number="s2728"/>
    <amendment number="s2727"/>
    <amendment number="s2726"/>
    <amendment number="s2725"/>
    <amendment number="s2724"/>
    <amendment number="s2723"/>
    <amendment number="s2722"/>
    <amendment number="s2721"/>
    <amendment number="s2720"/>
    <amendment number="s2719"/>
    <amendment number="s2718"/>
    <amendment number="s2717"/>
    <amendment number="s2716"/>
    <amendment number="s2715"/>
    <amendment number="s2714"/>
    <amendment number="s2713"/>
    <amendment number="s2712"/>
    <amendment number="s2711"/>
    <amendment number="s2710"/>
    <amendment number="s2709"/>
    <amendment number="s2708"/>
    <amendment number="s2707"/>
    <amendment number="s2706"/>
    <amendment number="s2705"/>
    <amendment number="s2704"/>
    <amendment number="s2703"/>
    <amendment number="s2702"/>
    <amendment number="s2701"/>
    <amendment number="s2700"/>
    <amendment number="s2699"/>
    <amendment number="s2698"/>
    <amendment number="s2697"/>
    <amendment number="s2696"/>
    <amendment number="s2695"/>
    <amendment number="s2694"/>
    <amendment number="s2693"/>
    <amendment number="s2692"/>
    <amendment number="s2691"/>
    <amendment number="s2690"/>
    <amendment number="s2689"/>
    <amendment number="s2688"/>
    <amendment number="s2687"/>
    <amendment number="s2686"/>
    <amendment number="s2685"/>
    <amendment number="s2684"/>
    <amendment number="s2683"/>
    <amendment number="s2682"/>
    <amendment number="s2681"/>
    <amendment number="s2680"/>
    <amendment number="s2679"/>
    <amendment number="s2678"/>
    <amendment number="s2677"/>
    <amendment number="s2676"/>
    <amendment number="s2675"/>
    <amendment number="s2674"/>
    <amendment number="s2673"/>
    <amendment number="s2672"/>
    <amendment number="s2671"/>
    <amendment number="s2670"/>
    <amendment number="s2669"/>
    <amendment number="s2668"/>
    <amendment number="s2667"/>
    <amendment number="s2666"/>
    <amendment number="s2665"/>
    <amendment number="s2664"/>
    <amendment number="s2663"/>
    <amendment number="s2662"/>
    <amendment number="s2661"/>
    <amendment number="s2660"/>
    <amendment number="s2659"/>
    <amendment number="s2658"/>
    <amendment number="s2657"/>
    <amendment number="s2656"/>
    <amendment number="s2655"/>
    <amendment number="s2654"/>
    <amendment number="s2653"/>
    <amendment number="s2652"/>
    <amendment number="s2651"/>
    <amendment number="s2650"/>
    <amendment number="s2649"/>
    <amendment number="s2648"/>
    <amendment number="s2647"/>
    <amendment number="s2646"/>
    <amendment number="s2645"/>
    <amendment number="s2644"/>
    <amendment number="s2643"/>
    <amendment number="s2642"/>
    <amendment number="s2641"/>
    <amendment number="s2640"/>
    <amendment number="s2639"/>
    <amendment number="s2638"/>
    <amendment number="s2637"/>
    <amendment number="s2636"/>
    <amendment number="s2635"/>
    <amendment number="s2634"/>
    <amendment number="s2633"/>
    <amendment number="s2632"/>
    <amendment number="s2631"/>
    <amendment number="s2630"/>
    <amendment number="s2629"/>
    <amendment number="s2628"/>
    <amendment number="s2627"/>
    <amendment number="s2626"/>
    <amendment number="s2625"/>
    <amendment number="s2624"/>
    <amendment number="s2623"/>
    <amendment number="s2622"/>
    <amendment number="s2621"/>
    <amendment number="s2620"/>
    <amendment number="s2619"/>
    <amendment number="s2618"/>
    <amendment number="s2617"/>
    <amendment number="s2616"/>
    <amendment number="s2615"/>
    <amendment number="s2614"/>
    <amendment number="s2613"/>
    <amendment number="s2612"/>
    <amendment number="s2611"/>
    <amendment number="s2610"/>
    <amendment number="s2609"/>
    <amendment number="s2608"/>
    <amendment number="s2607"/>
    <amendment number="s2606"/>
    <amendment number="s2605"/>
    <amendment number="s2604"/>
    <amendment number="s2603"/>
    <amendment number="s2602"/>
    <amendment number="s2601"/>
    <amendment number="s2600"/>
    <amendment number="s2599"/>
    <amendment number="s2598"/>
    <amendment number="s2597"/>
    <amendment number="s2596"/>
    <amendment number="s2595"/>
    <amendment number="s2594"/>
    <amendment number="s2593"/>
    <amendment number="s2592"/>
    <amendment number="s2591"/>
    <amendment number="s2590"/>
    <amendment number="s2589"/>
    <amendment number="s2588"/>
    <amendment number="s2587"/>
    <amendment number="s2586"/>
    <amendment number="s2585"/>
    <amendment number="s2584"/>
    <amendment number="s2583"/>
    <amendment number="s2582"/>
    <amendment number="s2581"/>
    <amendment number="s2580"/>
    <amendment number="s2579"/>
    <amendment number="s2578"/>
    <amendment number="s2577"/>
    <amendment number="s2576"/>
    <amendment number="s2575"/>
    <amendment number="s2574"/>
    <amendment number="s2573"/>
    <amendment number="s2572"/>
    <amendment number="s2571"/>
    <amendment number="s2570"/>
    <amendment number="s2569"/>
    <amendment number="s2568"/>
    <amendment number="s2567"/>
    <amendment number="s2566"/>
    <amendment number="s2565"/>
    <amendment number="s2564"/>
    <amendment number="s2563"/>
    <amendment number="s2562"/>
    <amendment number="s2561"/>
    <amendment number="s2560"/>
    <amendment number="s2559"/>
    <amendment number="s2558"/>
    <amendment number="s2557"/>
    <amendment number="s2556"/>
    <amendment number="s2555"/>
    <amendment number="s2554"/>
    <amendment number="s2553"/>
    <amendment number="s2552"/>
    <amendment number="s2551"/>
    <amendment number="s2550"/>
    <amendment number="s2549"/>
    <amendment number="s2548"/>
    <amendment number="s2547"/>
    <amendment number="s2546"/>
    <amendment number="s2545"/>
    <amendment number="s2544"/>
    <amendment number="s2543"/>
    <amendment number="s2542"/>
    <amendment number="s2541"/>
    <amendment number="s2540"/>
    <amendment number="s2539"/>
    <amendment number="s2538"/>
    <amendment number="s2537"/>
    <amendment number="s2536"/>
    <amendment number="s2535"/>
    <amendment number="s2534"/>
    <amendment number="s2533"/>
    <amendment number="s2532"/>
    <amendment number="s2531"/>
    <amendment number="s2530"/>
    <amendment number="s2529"/>
    <amendment number="s2528"/>
    <amendment number="s2527"/>
    <amendment number="s2526"/>
    <amendment number="s2525"/>
    <amendment number="s2524"/>
    <amendment number="s2523"/>
    <amendment number="s2522"/>
    <amendment number="s2521"/>
    <amendment number="s2520"/>
    <amendment number="s2519"/>
    <amendment number="s2518"/>
    <amendment number="s2517"/>
    <amendment number="s2516"/>
    <amendment number="s2515"/>
    <amendment number="s2514"/>
    <amendment number="s2513"/>
    <amendment number="s2512"/>
    <amendment number="s2511"/>
    <amendment number="s2510"/>
    <amendment number="s2509"/>
    <amendment number="s2508"/>
    <amendment number="s2507"/>
    <amendment number="s2506"/>
    <amendment number="s2505"/>
    <amendment number="s2504"/>
    <amendment number="s2503"/>
    <amendment number="s2502"/>
    <amendment number="s2501"/>
    <amendment number="s2500"/>
    <amendment number="s2499"/>
    <amendment number="s2498"/>
    <amendment number="s2497"/>
    <amendment number="s2496"/>
    <amendment number="s2495"/>
    <amendment number="s2494"/>
    <amendment number="s2493"/>
    <amendment number="s2492"/>
    <amendment number="s2491"/>
    <amendment number="s2490"/>
    <amendment number="s2489"/>
    <amendment number="s2488"/>
    <amendment number="s2487"/>
    <amendment number="s2486"/>
    <amendment number="s2485"/>
    <amendment number="s2484"/>
    <amendment number="s2483"/>
    <amendment number="s2482"/>
    <amendment number="s2481"/>
    <amendment number="s2480"/>
    <amendment number="s2479"/>
    <amendment number="s2478"/>
    <amendment number="s2477"/>
    <amendment number="s2476"/>
    <amendment number="s2475"/>
    <amendment number="s2474"/>
    <amendment number="s2473"/>
    <amendment number="s2472"/>
    <amendment number="s2471"/>
    <amendment number="s2470"/>
    <amendment number="s2469"/>
    <amendment number="s2468"/>
    <amendment number="s2467"/>
    <amendment number="s2466"/>
    <amendment number="s2465"/>
    <amendment number="s2464"/>
    <amendment number="s2463"/>
    <amendment number="s2462"/>
    <amendment number="s2461"/>
    <amendment number="s2460"/>
    <amendment number="s2459"/>
    <amendment number="s2458"/>
    <amendment number="s2457"/>
    <amendment number="s2456"/>
    <amendment number="s2455"/>
    <amendment number="s2454"/>
    <amendment number="s2453"/>
    <amendment number="s2452"/>
    <amendment number="s2451"/>
    <amendment number="s2450"/>
    <amendment number="s2449"/>
    <amendment number="s2448"/>
    <amendment number="s2447"/>
    <amendment number="s2446"/>
    <amendment number="s2445"/>
    <amendment number="s2444"/>
    <amendment number="s2443"/>
    <amendment number="s2442"/>
    <amendment number="s2441"/>
    <amendment number="s2440"/>
    <amendment number="s2439"/>
    <amendment number="s2438"/>
    <amendment number="s2437"/>
    <amendment number="s2436"/>
    <amendment number="s2435"/>
    <amendment number="s2434"/>
    <amendment number="s2433"/>
    <amendment number="s2432"/>
    <amendment number="s2431"/>
    <amendment number="s2430"/>
    <amendment number="s2429"/>
    <amendment number="s2428"/>
    <amendment number="s2427"/>
    <amendment number="s2426"/>
    <amendment number="s2425"/>
    <amendment number="s2424"/>
    <amendment number="s2423"/>
    <amendment number="s2422"/>
    <amendment number="s2421"/>
    <amendment number="s2420"/>
    <amendment number="s2419"/>
    <amendment number="s2418"/>
    <amendment number="s2417"/>
    <amendment number="s2416"/>
    <amendment number="s2415"/>
    <amendment number="s2414"/>
    <amendment number="s2413"/>
    <amendment number="s2412"/>
    <amendment number="s2411"/>
    <amendment number="s2410"/>
    <amendment number="s2409"/>
    <amendment number="s2408"/>
    <amendment number="s2407"/>
    <amendment number="s2406"/>
    <amendment number="s2405"/>
    <amendment number="s2404"/>
    <amendment number="s2403"/>
    <amendment number="s2402"/>
    <amendment number="s2401"/>
    <amendment number="s2400"/>
    <amendment number="s2399"/>
    <amendment number="s2398"/>
    <amendment number="s2397"/>
    <amendment number="s2396"/>
    <amendment number="s2395"/>
    <amendment number="s2394"/>
    <amendment number="s2393"/>
    <amendment number="s2392"/>
    <amendment number="s2391"/>
    <amendment number="s2390"/>
    <amendment number="s2389"/>
    <amendment number="s2388"/>
    <amendment number="s2387"/>
    <amendment number="s2386"/>
    <amendment number="s2385"/>
    <amendment number="s2384"/>
    <amendment number="s2383"/>
    <amendment number="s2382"/>
    <amendment number="s2381"/>
    <amendment number="s2380"/>
    <amendment number="s2379"/>
    <amendment number="s2378"/>
    <amendment number="s2377"/>
    <amendment number="s2376"/>
    <amendment number="s2375"/>
    <amendment number="s2374"/>
    <amendment number="s2373"/>
    <amendment number="s2372"/>
    <amendment number="s2371"/>
    <amendment number="s2370"/>
    <amendment number="s2369"/>
    <amendment number="s2368"/>
    <amendment number="s2367"/>
    <amendment number="s2366"/>
    <amendment number="s2365"/>
    <amendment number="s2364"/>
    <amendment number="s2363"/>
    <amendment number="s2362"/>
    <amendment number="s2361"/>
    <amendment number="s2360"/>
    <amendment number="s2359"/>
    <amendment number="s2358"/>
    <amendment number="s2357"/>
    <amendment number="s2356"/>
    <amendment number="s2355"/>
    <amendment number="s2354"/>
    <amendment number="s2353"/>
    <amendment number="s2352"/>
    <amendment number="s2351"/>
    <amendment number="s2350"/>
    <amendment number="s2348"/>
    <amendment number="s2347"/>
    <amendment number="s2346"/>
    <amendment number="s2345"/>
    <amendment number="s2344"/>
    <amendment number="s2343"/>
    <amendment number="s2342"/>
    <amendment number="s2341"/>
    <amendment number="s2340"/>
    <amendment number="s2339"/>
    <amendment number="s2338"/>
    <amendment number="s2337"/>
    <amendment number="s2336"/>
    <amendment number="s2335"/>
    <amendment number="s2334"/>
    <amendment number="s2333"/>
    <amendment number="s2332"/>
    <amendment number="s2331"/>
    <amendment number="s2330"/>
    <amendment number="s2329"/>
    <amendment number="s2328"/>
    <amendment number="s2327"/>
    <amendment number="s2326"/>
    <amendment number="s2325"/>
    <amendment number="s2324"/>
    <amendment number="s2323"/>
    <amendment number="s2322"/>
    <amendment number="s2321"/>
    <amendment number="s2320"/>
    <amendment number="s2319"/>
    <amendment number="s2318"/>
    <amendment number="s2317"/>
    <amendment number="s2316"/>
    <amendment number="s2315"/>
    <amendment number="s2314"/>
    <amendment number="s2313"/>
    <amendment number="s2312"/>
    <amendment number="s2311"/>
    <amendment number="s2310"/>
    <amendment number="s2309"/>
    <amendment number="s2308"/>
    <amendment number="s2307"/>
    <amendment number="s2306"/>
    <amendment number="s2305"/>
    <amendment number="s2304"/>
    <amendment number="s2303"/>
    <amendment number="s2302"/>
    <amendment number="s2301"/>
    <amendment number="s2300"/>
    <amendment number="s2299"/>
    <amendment number="s2298"/>
    <amendment number="s2297"/>
    <amendment number="s2296"/>
    <amendment number="s2295"/>
    <amendment number="s2294"/>
    <amendment number="s2293"/>
    <amendment number="s2292"/>
    <amendment number="s2291"/>
    <amendment number="s2290"/>
    <amendment number="s2289"/>
    <amendment number="s2288"/>
    <amendment number="s2287"/>
    <amendment number="s2286"/>
    <amendment number="s2285"/>
    <amendment number="s2284"/>
    <amendment number="s2283"/>
    <amendment number="s2282"/>
    <amendment number="s2281"/>
    <amendment number="s2280"/>
    <amendment number="s2279"/>
    <amendment number="s2278"/>
    <amendment number="s2277"/>
    <amendment number="s2276"/>
    <amendment number="s2275"/>
    <amendment number="s2274"/>
    <amendment number="s2273"/>
    <amendment number="s2272"/>
    <amendment number="s2271"/>
    <amendment number="s2270"/>
    <amendment number="s2269"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-01-04T18:54:29Z" status="Public Law">Highlights:

The John McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 authorizes FY2019 appropriations and sets forth policies regarding the military activities of the Department of Defense (DOD), military construction, and the national security programs of the Department of Energy (DOE).

The bill authorizes appropriations, but does not provide appropriations, which are considered in subsequent appropriations legislation.

 Among other things, the bill authorizes appropriations to DOD for

 Procurement; Research, Development, Test, and Evaluation; Operation and Maintenance; Cooperative Threat Reduction; Working Capital Funds; Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction; Defense-Wide Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities; the Defense Inspector General; the Armed Forces Retirement Home; and the Defense Health Program. This bill also authorizes appropriations for overseas contingency operations (OCO), which are exempt from limits on discretionary spending. OCO appropriations authorized in the bill support base budget requirements as well as OCO activities.

The bill authorizes the FY2019 personnel strengths for active duty and reserve forces and sets forth policies regarding military personnel; compensation and other personnel benefits; health care; acquisition policy and management; DOD organization and management; civilian personnel matters; matters relating to foreign nations; strategic programs; and cyber and intelligence matters.

The bill authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies regarding military construction for the Army, the Navy, the Air Force, defense agencies, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program, and Guard and Reserve Forces facilities.

The bill authorizes appropriations for base realignment and closure (BRAC) activities and prohibits an additional BRAC round.

The bill also authorizes appropriations and sets forth policies for DOE national security programs, including the National Nuclear Security Administration (NNSA).

Full Summary:

John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019

(Sec.3)This bill defines "congressional defense committees" as the House and Senate Armed Services and Appropriations Committees.

(Sec.4)The bill requires the budgetary effects of this bill to be determined in accordance with the procedures established in the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010.

DIVISION A--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE AUTHORIZATIONS

TITLE I--PROCUREMENT

Subtitle A--Authorization Of Appropriations

(Sec. 101)The bill authorizes appropriations to the DOD for procurement at the levels identified in section 4101 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Army Programs

(Sec. 111)The bill modifies reporting requirements for the National Guard and Reserves equipment report to include a joint assessment by the Army and National Guard Bureau on the efforts of the Army to achieve parity among the active component, the Army Reserve, and the Army National Guard with respect to equipment and capabilities.

(Sec. 112)The Army must certify whether there is a need to deploy an interim missile defense capability.

Subtitle C--Navy Programs

(Sec. 121)The Navy may contract for the procurement of one Ford class aircraft carrier to be designated CVN-81.

(Sec. 122)The Navy must ensure that full ship shock trials results are incorporated into the construction of the CVN-81 aircraft carrier.

(Sec. 123)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States should accelerate the production of aircraft carriers.

(Sec. 124)The Navy may contract for the procurement of no more than 625 standard missile-6 missiles.

(Sec. 125)The Navy may contract for the procurement of no more than 24 E-2D aircraft.

(Sec. 126)The Navy may contact for the procurement of F/A-18E/F aircraft and EA-18G aircraft.

(Sec. 127)The Navy must modify the F/A-18 aircraft to mitigate physiological episodes affecting crew members of the F/A-18 aircraft.

(Sec. 128)The Navy must require that proposals for the procurement of any frigate class ship stipulate that the offeror agrees to convey technical data if they are awarded the frigate class ship construction contract.

(Sec. 129)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to require the Navy to procure a Virginia class submarine in both FY2022 and FY2023.

(Sec. 130)DOD is prohibited from using funds to procure legacy waterborne security barriers for Navy ports.

(Sec. 131)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to extend through FY2019 the limitation on use of sole-source shipbuilding contract for joint high speed vessels or expeditionary fast transports.

(Sec. 132)The bill limits the availability of funds for the M27 Infantry Automatic Rifle program of the Marine Corps.

(Sec. 133)The Navy must report on degaussing standards for the DDG-51 destroyer.

Subtitle D--Air Force Programs

(Sec. 141)The Air Force must maintain a total of not less than 479 air refueling tanker aircraft in its aircraft inventory. The bill limits the retirement of the KC-10A aircraft.

(Sec. 142)The Air Force may enter into one or more multiyear contracts beginning in FY2019 for the procurement of C-130J aircraft.

(Sec. 143)The Air Force must ensure that any contract for logistics support for the VC-25B aircraft does not exceed five years.

(Sec. 144)The bill deems the retirement date for VC-25A aircraft to be not later than December 31, 2025.

(Sec. 145)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to eliminate the funding restriction for the EC-130H Compass Call Recapitalization program.

(Sec. 146)The bill limits the funds that may be used to procure the KC-46A aircraft until the Air Force submits a specified certification.

(Sec. 147)The bill limits the funds that may be used to retire the E-8 Joint Surveillance Target Attack Radar System aircraft.

(Sec. 148)The Air Force must report on the long-term modernization of the B-52H aircraft.

Subtitle E--Defense-wide, Joint, and Multiservice Matters

(Sec. 151)The U.S.Coast Guard may enter into one or more contracts for the procurement of up to five polar-class icebreaker vessels.

(Sec. 152)DOD may procure an excess quantity of F-35 aircraft.

(Sec. 153)Before entering into a contract for the procurement of a fighter aircraft, attack aircraft, or a fixed wing trainer aircraft, each military department must certify that the aircraft to be procured will include the most recent technological advancements necessary to minimize the impact of physiological episodes on aircraft crewmembers.

(Sec. 154)The Army must ensure that inspections are conducted for armored commercial passenger-carrying vehicles.

(Sec. 155)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must report on the progress of the F-35 Joint Strike Fighter program.

TITLE II--RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, TEST, AND EVALUATION

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 201)The bill authorizes appropriations for research, development, test, and evaluation at the levels identified in section 4201 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Program Requirements, Restrictions, and Limitations

(Sec. 211)The bill modifies the authority of DOD to carry out certain prototype projects.

(Sec. 212)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to extend the authority for DOD to develop directed energy weapons.

(Sec. 213)The bill prohibits the use of funds for the Weather Common Component program.

(Sec. 214)The bill limits the funds that may be used for the F-35 continuous capability development and delivery program.

(Sec. 215)The bill limits the funds that may be used for the Air Force Air and Space Operations Centers.

(Sec. 216)The bill limits the funds that may be used by DOD for high energy laser programs.

(Sec. 217)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must submit a plan for the DOD Strategic Capabilities Office.

(Sec. 218)DOD must develop a strategy to articulate its science and technology priorities, goals, and investments and make recommendations on the future of the defense research and engineering enterprise.

(Sec. 219)The Navy must modify the CVN-73 aircraft carrier to support the fielding of the MQ-25 unmanned aerial vehicle.

(Sec. 220)The Defense Technical Information Center must establish an innovators information repository within DOD.

(Sec. 221)The bill modifies the strategic plan requirements for DOD test and evaluation resources.

(Sec. 222)DOD may prioritize innovative collaboration between its science and technology reinvention laboratories, industry, and academia.

(Sec. 223)DOD must develop and incorporate technology protection features during the research and development phase of defense systems.

(Sec. 224)DOD must establish a competitive, merit-based program to stimulate innovative technologies and reduce acquisition or lifecycle costs for its major defense acquisition programs.

(Sec. 225)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must prescribe procedures for the designation and development of emerging technologies.

(Sec. 226)The Army must identify and develop personal equipment to provide enhanced protection against injuries caused by blasts in combat and training.

(Sec. 227)DOD must develop and provide for the carrying out of human factors modeling and simulation activities.

(Sec. 228)The bill expands the mission areas for expedited access to university technical expertise.

(Sec. 229)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must jointly establish at least one activity per military service to demonstrate advanced manufacturing techniques and capabilities at depot-level activities or military arsenal facilities.

(Sec. 230)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must develop interaction between DOD and the commercial technology industry and academia with regard to emerging hardware products and technologies that have national security applications.

(Sec. 231)Each science and technology reinvention laboratory may use partnership intermediaries to promote defense research and education.

(Sec. 232)The bill limits the funds that may be used to procure a Surface Navy Laser Weapon System.

(Sec. 233)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to expand the activities and organizations that DOD may support for national security innovation and entrepreneurial education programs.

(Sec. 234)DOD must carry out a quantum information science and technology research and development program.

(Sec. 235)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must develop, establish, and coordinate directed energy testing activities for DOD.

(Sec. 236)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018to require DOD to establish one or more multi-institution task order contracts, consortia, cooperative agreements, or other arrangements to facilitate expedited access to university technical expertise, including faculty, staff, and students, in support of its missions.

(Sec. 237)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to expand the authority of the Joint Directed Energy Transition Office to conduct research related to directed energy systems.

(Sec. 238)DOD must establish a set of activities to coordinate its efforts to develop, mature, and transition artificial intelligence technologies into operational use.

Subtitle C--Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 241)The Army must report on its efforts to improve the survivability of air defense artillery.

(Sec. 242)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018to modify the Navy's efforts to combat physiological episodes on certain aircraft.

(Sec. 243)The Air Force must report on its efforts to reduce the occurrence of, and mitigate the risk posed by, physiological episodes affecting crew members of certain aircraft.

(Sec. 244)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must report on the Defense Innovation Unit Experimental, including the metrics used to measure the effectiveness of the unit and the results of such metrics.

(Sec. 245)The bill modifies funding criteria for DOD to carry out programs for historically black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions of higher education.

(Sec. 246)The Air Force must report on the OA-X light attack aircraft experiment and how the program incorporates partner nation requirements.

(Sec. 247)DOD must submit to Congress a set of classified reports that sets forth a direct comparison between the capabilities of the United States in emerging technology areas and the capabilities of adversaries of the United States in such areas.

(Sec. 248)The Army must report on technologies related to active protection systems for armored combat and tactical vehicles.

(Sec. 249)The Army must ensure that all necessary resources are planned and programmed for accelerated prototyping, component development, testing, or acquisition for the next generation combat vehicle.

(Sec. 250)DOD must establish and maintain mechanisms for the continuous collection of information on achievements, best practices identified, lessons learned, and challenges arising in providing funds for defense laboratories.

(Sec. 251)The Army must provide a briefing to Congress on its requirements for Mobile Protected Firepower vehicles and the Future Vertical Lift plan to develop military helicopters.

(Sec. 252)The Air Force may use funds for nontraditional technologies and sustainment practices and to improve its supply chain.

(Sec. 253)DOD must review the decibel level exposure, concussive effects exposure, and the frequency of exposure to heavy weapons fire of an individual during training exercises to establish appropriate limitations on these exposures.

(Sec. 254)The Army must develop a strategy to competitively procure a new transmission for the Bradley Fighting Vehicle family of armored vehicles.

(Sec. 255)DOD must enter into an arrangement with the private scientific advisory group to assess strategies and programs related to electronic warfare.

TITLE III--OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 301)The bill authorizes appropriations for operation and maintenance activities at the levels identified in section 4301 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Energy and Environment

(Sec. 311)DOD must carry out an Explosive Ordnance Disposal Defense Program to ensure close and continuous coordination between military departments on matters relating to explosive ordnance disposal support for commanders of geographic and functional combatant commands.

(Sec. 312)DOD must include its energy security and resilience goals in the installation energy report, including the amount of critical energy load necessary to achieve energy security and resilience.

(Sec. 313)The bill sets forth requirements for the use of proceeds from a sale of electrical energy that is generated from any geothermal energy resource.

(Sec. 314)The bill sets forth operational energy policy for DOD, including authorizing DOD to require each military department or the commander of a combatant command to assess the energy supportability of systems.

(Sec. 315)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to authorize the use of DOD funds to conduct a study on the on the human health implications of per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances in drinking water.

(Sec. 316)The bill modifies the time period for permitted incidental takings of marine mammals.

(Sec. 317)The bill expresses the sense of Congress regarding DOD environmental restoration and base realignment and closure programs.

(Sec. 318)DOD must enter into an arrangement with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to conduct a study on the impacts of wind farms on weather radars.

(Sec. 319)The Air Force must conduct a core sampling study along the proposed route of the W-6 wastewater treatment line.

(Sec. 320)The bill authorizes the Army to provide by contract or otherwise for the production, treatment, management, and use of natural gas located under Fort Knox, Kentucky.

Subtitle C--Logistics and Sustainment

(Sec. 321)Each military department may use a working capital fund to carry out minor military construction projects for the revitalization and recapitalization of a defense industrial base facility.

(Sec. 322)The bill requires the Navy to examine its vessels with minimal notice to the crew of such vessels.

(Sec. 323)The Navy must ensure that certain vessels are not forward deployed overseas for a period in excess of ten years.

(Sec. 324)DOD must ensure that for each military department depot or arsenal, outlay rates account for the varying repair cycle times of the workload supported.

(Sec. 325)The bill prohibits the use of funds for any construction, alteration, repair, or development of the Navy Ship Repair Facility in Guam.

(Sec. 326)The Air Force must prepare a business case analysis on the proposed relocation of the J85 Engine Regional Repair Center.

(Sec. 327)DOD must report on a pilot program to provide resilience for critical national security infrastructure at its facilities and operate at least one licensed micro-reactor.

(Sec. 328)The bill requires the Navy to notify Congress before making modifications to the Navy Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization structure or mechanism that would modify duty relationships or significantly alter the existing structure.

Subtitle D--Reports

(Sec. 331)The bill modifies DOD's readiness reporting system, including to set forth new capabilities for the system.

(Sec. 332)The bill revises the quarterly reporting requirements of DOD regarding the military readiness of the active and reserve components of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 333)The Government Accountability Office (GAO)must conduct an annual review of the readiness of the Armed Forces to conduct full spectrum operations.

(Sec. 334)The bill expresses the sense of Congress regarding surface warfare training and requires the Navy to report on the surface warfare officer assessments process.

(Sec. 335)The Navy must report on optimizing its surface vessel inspections and crew certifications to reduce the burden of inspection type visits that vessels undergo.

(Sec. 336)DOD must report on labor hours and depot maintenance and repair.

(Sec. 337)DOD must report on the wildfire suppression capabilities within the active duty and reserve components of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 338)DOD must develop a report describing the potential impacts of relocating steam turbine production for Nimitz-class and Ford-class aircraft carriers and the Virginia-class and Columbia-class submarines.

(Sec. 339)The Air Force must report on existing specialized undergraduate pilot training production, resourcing, and locations.

(Sec. 340)The Air Force must report on the operational requirements for its airfields.

(Sec. 341)The Navy must report on surface ship repair contract costs.

Subtitle E--Other Matters

(Sec. 351)The bill modifies membership on the DOD Explosives Safety Board to include the Coast Guard.

(Sec. 352)The bill requires each military department to transport to the United States retired overseas military working dogs that are suitable for adoption.

(Sec. 353)The bill amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to revise the scope of authority for DOD to restore land due to its mistakes.

(Sec. 354)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to require the shredding of surplus firearms before the Army transfers such firearms.

(Sec. 355)DOD must report on the feasibility of phasing out the use of open burn pits.

(Sec. 356)Each military department must notify the Defense Logistics Agency of any plan to implement a change to any uniform or uniform component of a member of the uniformed services.

(Sec. 357)DOD and each military department must report the budgeted amount for each subactivity group, as detailed in the department's future years defense program.

(Sec. 358)The bill prohibits the use of funds to develop service-specific Defense Readiness Reporting Systems.

(Sec. 359)DOD must establish prioritization metrics for facilities deemed eligible for demolition within the Facilities Sustainment, Restoration, and Modernization process.

(Sec. 360)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the Soo Locks in Sault Ste. Marie, Michigan, are of critical importance to the national security of the United States.

(Sec. 361)The bill requires that at least $4 million be used to fund additional U.S. special operations civilian personnel.

TITLE IV--MILITARY PERSONNEL AUTHORIZATIONS

Subtitle A--Active Forces

(Sec. 401)The bill authorizes specified end strengths for active duty personnel of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 402)The bill establishes new minimum active duty end strengths for the Army, Navy, Marine Corps, and Air Force.

Subtitle B--Reserve Forces

(Sec. 411)The bill authorizes specified end strengths for Selected Reserve personnel.

(Sec. 412)The bill authorizes specified end strengths for reserves on active duty in support of the reserves.

(Sec. 413)The bill authorizes specified end strengths for military technicians (dual status).

(Sec. 414)The bill authorizes the maximum number of reserve personnel who may be on active duty or full-time National Guard duty to provide operational support during FY2019.

Subtitle C--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 421)The bill authorizes appropriations for military personnel at the levels identified in section 4401 of this bill.

TITLE V--MILITARY PERSONNEL POLICY

Subtitle A--Officer Personnel Policy

(Sec. 501)The bill eliminates the qualification requirement that commissioned officers be able to complete 20 years of service by 62 years of age.

(Sec. 502)The bill authorizes additional service credit in each military department for special training or experience upon appointment as a commissioned officer.

(Sec. 503)The bill provides temporary promotion authority in each military department for officers in certain grades with critical skills.

(Sec. 504)The bill provides authority for promotion selection boards to recommend officers of a particular merit be placed higher on the promotion list.

(Sec. 505)Each military department may allow officers to be excluded from promotion board consideration.

(Sec. 506)Each military department may authorize an officer in a grade above O-2 to remain on active duty in certain military specialties and career tracks.

(Sec. 507)The bill provides statutory authority for alternative promotion of officers in designated competitive categories.

(Sec. 508)The bill provides that a general officer serving as Attending Physician to the Congress holds the grade of major general, and a flag officer serving as Attending Physician to the Congress holds the grade of rear admiral (upper half).

(Sec. 509)The bill authorizes DOD and each military department to conditionally determine the highest grade of satisfactory service of an officer.

(Sec. 510)The bill provides for grades of the Chief of Chaplains in the Navy and the Air Force.

(Sec. 511)The bill eliminates the original appointment qualification requirement for warrant officers in the Army.

(Sec. 512)The bill reduces from 10 to 8 the number of years of active naval service required for appointment as a limited duty officer.

(Sec. 513)Each military department shall not consider certain reserve officers for promotion until they complete two years of service in active duty status.

(Sec. 514)The GAO must conduct a review of Navy surface warfare career paths.

Subtitle B--Reserve Component Management

(Sec. 515)The bill authorizes specified in-grade strengths and distributions for the Air National Guard.

(Sec. 516)The bill revises membership requirements for the Army Reserves Policy Committee.

(Sec. 517)The bill expands the number of personnel subject to the authority of the National Guard Bureau.

(Sec. 518)The bill provides each military department with authority to adjust the effective date of a promotion in the event of undue delay.

(Sec. 519)The bill authorizes the use of DOD equipment and facilities to carry out the National Guard Youth Challenge Program.

(Sec. 520)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to extend the pilot program on the use of retired senior enlisted members of the Army National Guard to serve as recruiters.

Subtitle C--General Service Authorities and Correction of Military Records

(Sec. 521)The bill authorizes each military department to enlist certain individuals who possess a critical skill or expertise that is vital to the national interest.

(Sec. 522)Each military department must provide a potential member retiree with a current assessment of all benefits to which that member may be entitled.

(Sec. 523)The bill grants DOD certain authority to accept gifts to facilitate accounting for missing persons from past conflicts.

(Sec. 524)The Navy must complete a comprehensive assessment of a standard workweek in the Navy.

(Sec. 525)The Navy must notify Congress within 15 days regarding the manning fit and fill of certain vessels.

(Sec. 526)The Navy must require that key watchstanders on Navy surface ships maintain a career record of watchstanding hours and specific operational evolutions.

(Sec. 527)The Navy must report on the adequacy of individual training for certain watchstations.

Subtitle D--Military Justice

(Sec. 531)The bill revises the Uniform Code of Military Justice to include strangulation and suffocation in the definition of aggravated assault.

(Sec. 532)The bill revises the Uniform Code of Military Justice to include a punitive article on domestic violence.

(Sec. 533)The bill amends the Carl Levin and Howard P. `Buck' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to modify the authority of the DOD Advisory Committee on Investigation, Prosecution, and Defense of Sexual Assault in the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 534)DOD must report on the feasibility and advisability of expanding eligibility for the Special Victims' Counsel programs to include victims of domestic violence.

(Sec. 535)DOD must establish a uniform command action form for reporting the final disposition of certain sexual assault cases.

(Sec. 536)DOD must modify all policies that it determines are necessary to establish a standardized expedited transfer process for a member of the Armed Forces who is the alleged victim of sexual assault or physical domestic violence.

Subtitle E--Other Legal Matters

(Sec. 541)The bill modifies term limitations for an appellate military judge that serves on the U.S. Court of Military Commission Review.

(Sec. 542)DOD must conduct security clearance re-investigations of certain personnel who commit certain offenses.

(Sec. 543)DOD must develop a plan to implement harassment prevention and response programs.

(Sec. 544)DOD must designate an official to provide oversight of its registered sex offender management program.

(Sec. 545)Each military service academy must develop and maintain a resource guide for students at the respective military service academies regarding sexual assault.

(Sec. 546)DOD must establish a consolidated tracking process to ensure increased oversight of crime reporting.

(Sec. 547)The Defense Advisory Committee on Investigation, Prosecution, and Defense of Sexual Assault in the Armed Forces must report on victims of sexual assault in the case files of a military criminal investigative organization.

Subtitle F--Member Education, Training, Resilience, and Transition

(Sec. 551)Each military department may carry out programs under which active duty and reserve duty members of the Armed Forces may be inactivated to meet personal or professional needs.

(Sec. 552)The bill revises programs to assist members of the Armed Forces, whose discharge or release is anticipated as of a specific date, with preseparation counseling and transition plans.

(Sec. 553)The bill eliminates the DOD program to encourage members and former members of the Armed Forces to enter into public and community service jobs.

(Sec. 554)The bill revises application requirements under the Troops-to-Teachers Program for members of the Armed Forces that have a specified date of retirement or are part of the retired reserve.

(Sec. 555)DOD may employ and compensate civilian faculty members at the Joint Special Operations University.

(Sec. 556)DOD and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must carry out a program to assist members of the Armed Forces in obtaining professional credentials that translate into civilian occupations.

(Sec. 557)The bill provides authority for each military department to convert a Junior Reserve Officers' Training Corps to a National Defense Cadet Corps program unit in lieu of closing the junior corps unit.

(Sec. 558) The bill expands the period of eligibility for the Military OneSource program of DOD for retired and discharged members of the Armed Forces and their immediate families.

(Sec. 559)The bill prohibits the use of funds for enlisted personnel to attend senior level and intermediate level officer professional military education courses.

Subtitle G--Defense Dependents' Education

(Sec. 561)The bill authorizes funds for assistance to local educational agencies that have higher concentrations of military children with severe disabilities.The bill also authorizes assistance to schools with a significant number of military dependent students.

(Sec. 562)The DOD Education Activity must establish policies and procedures to protect students at schools on military installations who are victims of sexual harassment.

(Sec. 563)DOD must consolidate the various databases and mechanisms for the reporting and tracking of juvenile misconduct into one comprehensive database.

(Sec. 564)DOD must conduct an assessment of strategies that may be used to address an active shooter incident at schools located on military installations.

Subtitle H--Military Family Readiness Matters

(Sec. 571)The bill revises membership requirements, duties, and reporting requirements for the DOD Military Family Readiness Council.

(Sec. 572)The bill revises family support services for immediate family members of members of the special operations forces.

(Sec. 573)The bill expands the authority for the head of a federal agency to appoint military spouses.

(Sec. 574)DOD must ensure that certain military spouses are made aware of the My Career Advancement Account program.

(Sec. 575)DOD must conduct an assessment of the effects of frequent, permanent changes of station on the stability of employment among spouses of members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 576)DOD must implement a policy to permit the issuance on a provisional or interim basis of clearances for childcare services at military childcare centers.

(Sec. 577)Each military department must establish multidisciplinary teams on child abuse and other domestic violence at its military installations.

(Sec. 578)The Defense Health Agency must carry out a pilot program to provide information on the prevention of child abuse and training on safe childcare practices.

(Sec. 579)DOD must conduct an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of permitting military spouses to engage in small business activities on military installations.

Subtitle I--Decorations and Awards

(Sec. 581)DOD must design and produce an Atomic Veterans Service Certificate to honor retired and former members of the Armed Forces who were exposed to radiation.

(Sec. 582)Each military department must carry out a program to award medals or other commendations to handlers of military working dogs.

(Sec. 583)The Army may award the Distinguished-Service Cross to Justin T. Gallegos for acts of valor.

Subtitle J--Miscellaneous Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 591)The bill modifies annual defense manpower reporting requirements for DOD.

(Sec. 592)The bill authorizes the burial of a military prisoner at the United States Disciplinary Barracks Cemetery located in Fort Leavenworth, Kansas.

(Sec. 593)The bill modifies duties for the Air Force Academy Board of Visitors.

(Sec. 594)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to revise the definition of national service and public service.

(Sec. 595)DOD must quarterly publicize the top-line numbers of deployed members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 596)DOD must report on general and flag officer costs.

(Sec. 597)The GAO must report on the effects of consecutive service on active duty service obligations for medical training as they relate to other service obligations for education or training.

(Sec. 598)The Army must prescribe revised criteria for interment at Arlington National Cemetery that preserve the cemetery as an active burial ground.

(Sec. 599)The Army must report on its marketing and advertising program concerning contract oversight and return on investment.

(Sec. 600)The bill amends the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act to authorize creditors to use independent verification for purposes of finding out if a service member is on active duty.

TITLE VI--COMPENSATION AND OTHER PERSONNEL BENEFITS

Subtitle A--Pay and Allowances

(Sec. 601)The bill eliminates the authorization for allowances for senior enlisted members of the military.

(Sec. 602)The bill modifies eligibility for reserve members to receive high-deployment allowances.

(Sec. 603)DOD and each military department are prohibited from making allowance reductions based on the duration of a temporary assignment.

(Sec. 604)The bill extends the eligibility for parking expense allowances to include recruiting facilities.

(Sec. 605)The bill revises the eligibility of reserve members to not have their pay reduced while serving in the uniformed services or National Guard.

(Sec. 606)DOD must develop measures to address the future sustainment, recapitalization, and financial condition of the Military Housing Privatization Initiative.

Subtitle B--Bonuses and Special Incentive Pays

(Sec. 611)The bill extends certain bonus and special pay authorities for the reserve forces, health care professionals, and nuclear officers.

(Sec. 612)DOD must examine the current processes for awarding imminent danger pay and hostile fire pay to members of the Armed Forces.

Subtitle C--Other Matters

Purple Heart and Disabled Veterans Equal Access Act of 2018

(Sec. 621) The bill extends certain morale, welfare, and recreation privileges to certain veterans and their caregivers.

(Sec. 622)The bill modifies special survivor indemnity allowances for the military.

(Sec. 623)Each military department may award damaged personal protective equipment to separating members and veterans.

(Sec. 624)The bill modifies eligible individuals under the DOD transportation travel program to include veterans with permanent service-connected disabilities.

(Sec. 625)The bill revises insurance coverage for members deployed to combat theaters of operations.

(Sec. 626)DOD and DHS must jointly establish procedures to provide access to military installations for certain spouses and next of kin of members.

(Sec. 627)DOD must conduct a study to determine the feasibility of consolidating the military resale entities into a single defense resale system. TITLE VII--HEALTH CARE PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--TRICARE and Other Health Care Benefits

(Sec. 701)The bill eliminates the requirement for a mental health assessment of members after redeployment from a contingency operation upon discharge or release from the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 702)DOD may carry out a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of using intensive outpatient programs to treat members of the Armed Forces suffering from post-traumatic stress disorder resulting from military sexual trauma.

Subtitle B--Health Care Administration

(Sec. 711)The bill sets forth responsibilities for the Defense Health Agency and DOD regarding military medical treatment facilities.

(Sec. 712)The Defense Health Agency must implement an organizational framework for the military healthcare system to support the medical requirements of the combatant commands.

(Sec. 713)DOD must administer TRICARE dental plans through the federal employees dental and vision insurance program.

(Sec. 714)DOD must streamline the process by which beneficiaries enrolled in TRICARE Prime are referred to the civilian provider network for inpatient or outpatient care.

(Sec. 715)DOD must establish a Military Health System Prescription Drug Monitoring Program.

(Sec. 716)The Defense Health Agency must implement a comprehensive pilot program on opioid management.

(Sec. 717)DOD must update policies and procedures relating to the care and management of recovering service members.

(Sec. 718)DOD must use medical simulation technology before the use of live tissue training to train medical professionals and combat medics.

(Sec. 719)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify the partnerships that DOD may enter into regarding trauma education and training.

(Sec. 720)The bill revises congressional notification requirements for each military department regarding hospitalization of combat wounded members of the Armed Forces.

Subtitle C--Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 731)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2010 to extend funding authority through September 30, 2020, for the Joint Department of Defense-Department of Veterans Affairs Medical Facility Demonstration Fund.

(Sec. 732)DOD must develop a process to establish required joint force medical capabilities for members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 733)DOD must incorporate medical screening questions specific to gambling disorders into the annual health assessments of members of the Armed Forces.

(Sec. 734)DOD, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the Social Security Administration must jointly report on the requirement for certain members of the Armed Forces to enroll in certain medical programs to be eligible for TRICARE.

(Sec. 735)The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Health Affairs may conduct a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of partnerships between special operations forces and institutions of higher education and health care systems through which special operations forces medics earn credit for their military operation work toward the master's degree of physician assistant.

(Sec. 736)DOD must submit to Congress a comprehensive strategic medical research plan.

(Sec. 737)The GAO must report on oversight conducted by the Defense Health Agency with respect to the current transition between managed care support contractors for the TRICARE program.

(Sec. 738)The GAO must conduct a study on the availability of long-term care options from the Department of Veterans Affairs for veterans with combat-related disabilities.

(Sec. 739)The bill increases the number of appointed members in the Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine.

TITLE VIII--ACQUISITION POLICY, ACQUISITION MANAGEMENT, AND RELATED MATTERS

(Sec. 800)The bill sets forth the effective dates for Parts I, II, and III of this subtitle.

Subtitle A--Streamlining of Defense Acquisition Statutes and Regulations

Part I--Consolidation of Defense Acquisition Statutes in New Part V of Subtitle A of Title 10, United States Code

(Sec. 801)The bill provides statutory authority for the consolidation of defense acquisition statutes.

Part II--Redesignation of Sections and Chapters of Subtitles B, C, and D to Provide Room for New Part V of Subtitle A

(Sec. 806)The bill redesignates provisions of the U.S. Code regarding the Air Force.

(Sec. 807)The bill redesignates provisions of the U.S. Code regarding the Navy and Marine Corps.

(Sec. 808)The bill redesignates provisions of the U.S. Code regarding the Army.

(Sec. 809) The bill modifies provisions to maintain the cross references for sections or chapters redesignated by this part.

Part III--Repeals of Certain Provisions of Defense Acquisition Law

(Sec. 811)The bill eliminates requirements for certain positions and offices in DOD.

(Sec. 812)The bill eliminates certain defense acquisition provisions.

(Sec. 813)The bill revises certain DOD reporting requirements.

Subtitle B--Amendments to General Contracting Authorities, Procedures, and Limitations

(Sec. 816)The bill modifies the authority to award single task and delivery order contracts.

(Sec. 817)The bill modifies DOD authority to carry out a defense acquisition program using multiyear contracts.

(Sec. 818)The bill revises reporting requirements for DOD regarding service contracts.

(Sec. 819)The bill modifies inventory summary requirements regarding the procurements of services by DOD.

(Sec. 820)DOD must submit to Congress a report clarifying service contracting definitions.

(Sec. 821)The bill increases the micro-purchase threshold for DOD.

(Sec. 822)DOD must study the frequency and effects of bid protests regarding contract dispute matters.

(Sec. 823)DOD must develop policies to ensure the best information regarding past performance of certain subcontractors and joint venture partners is available when awarding its contracts.

(Sec. 824)The bill amends the Ike Skelton National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2011 to modify contractor business system requirements.

(Sec. 825)The bill amends the Bob Stump National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2003 to modify certification requirements for waivers of cost accounting standards.

Subtitle C--Provisions Relating to Major Defense Acquisition Programs

(Sec. 831)The bill revises authority regarding program cost targets and fielding targets for major defense acquisition programs.

(Sec. 832)DOD must implement recommendations of the independent study on the operation and sustainment of existing major weapon systems.

(Sec. 833)The GAO must submit to Congress an annual assessment of certain DOD acquisition programs and initiatives.

Subtitle D--Provisions Relating to Commercial Items

(Sec. 836)The bill separates the commercial item definition into definitions of commercial product and commercial service.

(Sec. 837)The bill revises the applicability of defense-unique statutes to contracts for commercial items.

(Sec. 838)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to make modifications to the program for procurement through commercial e-commerce portals.

(Sec. 839)The bill sets forth certain requirements for the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council, including to review regulations on commercial products, commercial services, and commercially available off-the-shelf items.

Subtitle E--Industrial Base Matters

(Sec. 841)The Navy must report on whether competition for the procurement of certain components should be limited to sources in the national technology and industrial base.

(Sec. 842)The bill eliminates the requirement for certain entities to obtain a national interest determination as a condition for access to proscribed information.

(Sec. 843)The Undersecretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must establish a pilot program to test the feasibility and reliability of using machine-vision technologies to determine the authenticity and security of microelectronic parts in weapon systems.

(Sec. 844)DOD must analyze and assess potential items that may be required to be procured from a manufacturer that is part of the national technology and industrial base.

(Sec. 845)DOD must report on the health of the defense electronics industrial base.

(Sec. 846)DOD may establish a program to make long-term investments in critical skills, facilities, research and development, and small business support.

(Sec. 847)The bill prohibits DOD from procuring certain items if the manufacturer of the item is not in the United States.

Subtitle F--Small Business Matters

(Sec. 851)DOD must implement a small business strategy that meets certain requirements.

(Sec. 852)DOD must establish an accelerated payment date for small business contractors.

(Sec. 853)The bill increases the Small Business Administration (SBA)microloan intermediary lending limit, and it requires the SBA to report on the microloan program, including how to encourage increased participation in the program.

(Sec. 854)The bill modifies the Small Business Innovation Research (SBIR) program and the Small Business Technology Transfer (STTR) program.

(Sec. 855)The bill sets forth requirements for federal agencies regarding construction contracts.

(Sec. 856)The GAO must conduct a study evaluating the impact of broadband speed and price on small business concerns.

(Sec. 857)The Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering must include in its budget materials, a display of the funds assessed for the SBIR program or the STTR program.

(Sec. 858)The bill increases the amount of assistance DOD may provide to business entities to furnish procurement technical assistance. The bill also increases the amount of funding for eligible entities.

(Sec. 859)The bill revises the authority of the Defense Logistics Agency to cover certain costs related to the procurement technical assistance program.

(Sec. 860)The bill requires certain agencies to implement a commercialization assistance pilot program, under which certain entities may receive a Phase II SBIR award.

(Sec. 861)The bill addresses small business concerns in Puerto Rico, including incentives and credits for businesses.

(Sec. 862)The bill expands the SBA loan program, including by establishing a Small Business Employee Ownership and Cooperatives Promotion Program to offer technical assistance and training on the transition to employee ownership through cooperatives and qualified employee trusts.

Subtitle G--Provisions Related to Software and Technical Data Matters

(Sec. 865)The bill revises criteria for validation of proprietary data restrictions.

(Sec. 866)DOD or a military department to which milestone decision authority has been delegated may authorize use of technical data in dispute if compelling mission readiness requirements will not permit awaiting a final decision by the agency Board of Contract Appeals or the United States Claims Court.

(Sec. 867)The bill modifies requirements for negotiation of technical data price before development, production, or sustainment of a major weapon system.

(Sec. 868)DOD must implement recommendations from the final report of the Defense Science Board Task Force on the Design and Acquisition of Software for Defense Systems.

(Sec. 869)DOD must include specified systems in its pilot program to use agile or iterative development methods.

(Sec. 870)DOD must report on the feasibility and advisability of requiring access to digital technical data in all future acquisitions of combat, combat service, and combat support systems.

Subtitle H--Other Matters

(Sec. 871)The bill prohibits DOD from procuring sensitive materials from certain foreign nations.

(Sec. 872)The bill amends the Carl Levin and Howard P. `Buck' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to extend through December 31, 2021, the prohibition on providing funds to certain persons or entities.

(Sec. 873)The bill requires the Service Acquisition Executives of the military departments to collect data on the use of other transactions by DOD and the military departments. The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Acquisition shall analyze this data and use it to update policy and guidance related to the use of other transactions.

(Sec. 874)DOD must provide a plan to standardize the formatting of unclassified DOD reports that are required by Congress.

(Sec. 875)The bill amends the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 to revise the required regulations for preventing abuse of interagency contracts.

(Sec. 876)The bill provides exceptions for certain indefinite and service contracts.

(Sec. 877)The bill prohibits an individual acquisition for commercial leasing services from being construed as a purchase of property or services if the acquisition is made on a no cost basis and pursuant to a multiple award contract awarded in accordance with specified requirements. The GAO must conduct biennial audits of the General Services Administration (GSA) National Broker Contract and review provisions related to acquiring commercial leasing services.

(Sec. 878)The Office of Federal Procurement Policy must develop a definition and plan for procurement administrative lead time.

(Sec. 879)DOD must provide a briefing to Congress regarding the funding for product support strategies for major weapon systems.

(Sec. 880)The Federal Acquisition Regulations must be revised to require that lowest price technically acceptable source selection criteria are used in certain situations.

(Sec. 881)The bill revises requirements relating to supply chain risk management.

(Sec. 882)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must review guidance regarding commercially available market research.

(Sec. 883)DOD must direct the Defense Business Board to convene an integrated review team to undertake a study on facilitating the exchange of defense industry personnel on term assignments.

(Sec. 884)DOD must establish an exchange program for the temporary assignment of civilian personnel in the DOD acquisition workforce.

(Sec. 885)DOD must develop a process and procedures for limiting foreign access to technology through contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, or other transactions, when this limitation is in the interest of national security.

(Sec. 886)The bill authorizes DOD and each military department to procure telecommunications supplies for experimental purposes.

(Sec. 887)The bill requires that the DOD Director of Operational Test and Evaluation be given access to all data regarding modeling and simulation activity proposed to be used by military departments and defense agencies in support of operational or live fire test and evaluation of military capabilities.

(Sec. 888)DOD must include an instruction on the pilot program regarding contractors employing persons with disabilities.

(Sec. 889)The bill prohibits the procurement of certain telecommunications and video surveillance services or equipment.

(Sec. 890)DOD must establish a pilot program to reform and accelerate the contracting and pricing processes associated with contracts in excess of $50 million.

TITLE IX--DEPARTMENT OF DEFENSE ORGANIZATION AND MANAGEMENT

Subtitle A--Office of the Secretary of Defense and Related Matters

(Sec. 901)DOD must report on how it will allocate the former responsibilities of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition, Technology, and Logistics.

(Sec. 902)The bill modifies the responsibilities of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy.

(Sec. 903)The bill modifies the responsibilities and duties of the Chief Information Officer of DOD.

(Sec. 904)The bill revises the authority of the DOD Test Resource Management Center.

(Sec. 905)The Defense Technical Information Center must execute the Global Research Watch Program and develop and maintain data repositories on research and engineering activities.

Subtitle B--Organization and Management of Other Department of Defense Offices and Elements

(Sec. 911)The Navy must conduct a comprehensive review of its operational and administrative chains-of-command and functions.

(Sec. 912)The bill modifies certain responsibilities of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff relating to joint force development activities.

(Sec. 913)The bill revises certain requirements of the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff in connection with the National Military Strategy.

(Sec. 914)The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Special Operations and Low Intensity Conflict must conduct a comprehensive review of the United States Special Operations Command.

(Sec. 915)The bill expands the duties of the Assistant Secretary of the Navy for Research, Development, and Acquisition.

(Sec. 916)The bill sets forth the qualifications for an individual to be appointed as Deputy Chief Management Officer of specified military departments.

(Sec. 917)The bill sets forth a deadline for DOD to implement requirements regarding organization of its management of special operations.

(Sec. 918)DOD must establish a cross-functional team on electronic warfare and issue criteria for distinguishing among DOD's different cross-functional teams.

(Sec. 919)The Navy must report on a timeline for the transfer of the Chemical, Biological, and Radiological Defense Division from Virginia to another location.

Subtitle C--Comprehensive Pentagon Bureaucracy Reform and Reduction

(Sec. 921)The bill sets forth the authorities and responsibilities of the Chief Management Officer of DOD.

(Sec. 922)The Chief Management Officer of DOD must develop a policy on analysis of datasets on business management and business operations by the public.

(Sec. 923)The Chief Management Officer of DOD must conduct a periodic review of the efficiency and effectiveness of each Defense Agency and DOD Field Activity.

(Sec. 924)The Defense Logistics Agency and the Chief Management Officer of DOD must jointly develop and implement an efficient comprehensive system for its customers.

(Sec. 925)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment and the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must conduct a joint review of the functions of the Defense Contract Audit Agency and the Defense Contract Management Agency.

(Sec. 926)The Chief Management Officer of DOD and the Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must conduct a joint review of the activities of the Defense Finance and Accounting Service.

(Sec. 927)The Chief Information Officer and Chief Management Officer of DOD must conduct an assessment of chief information officer functions in connection with a transition to enterprise-wide management of information technology networks and computing.

(Sec. 928)The GAO must report on cross-enterprise activities of the Inspectors General of the organizations and elements of DOD, including public affairs, human resources, and services contracting.

(Sec. 929)The plans and reports required to be submitted to Congress under this subtitle may be combined and submitted as a single document.

Subtitle D--Other Department of Defense Organization and Management Matters

(Sec. 931)The bill limits the availability of funds for major headquarters activities of DOD.

(Sec. 932)DOD must establish a civilian fellowship program to provide leadership development and the commencement of a career track toward senior leadership.

(Sec. 933)The bill revises the performance of civilian functions by military personnel.

(Sec. 934)DOD must report on the implementation of providing procedures to estimate and compare the full costs of active duty military and civilian manpower and contract support.

(Sec. 935)The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must conduct a review of foreign currency exchange rates and an analysis of foreign currency fluctuations.

(Sec. 936)The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy must designate a senior civilian official to develop, coordinate, and oversee compliance relating to civilian casualties resulting from U.S.military operations.

(Sec. 937)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to revise reporting requirements for the Security Executive Agent regarding background and security investigations for DOD personnel.

(Sec. 938)The Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence must develop a plan on research and development activities to advance the capabilities of DOD in data integration and advanced analytics in connection with personnel security activities.

Subtitle E--Other Matters

(Sec. 941)The Security Executive Agent and the Suitability/Credentialing Executive Agent must implement a program to share relevant background information for national security positions and positions of trust.

(Sec. 942)The Security Executive Agent must report on expedited processing of security clearances for mission-critical positions.

(Sec. 943)The Security Executive Agent must report on the requirements, feasibility, and advisability of implementing a clearance in person concept. TITLE X--GENERAL PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--Financial Matters

(Sec. 1001)The bill permits DOD to make transfers between amounts authorized for FY2019 in division A of this bill, subject to specified limitations and a congressional notification requirement.

(Sec. 1002)The bill makes technical corrections regarding DOD audit remediation plans.

(Sec. 1003)DOD may transfer up to $2 million to the Office of the Director of National Intelligence for CAPNET.

(Sec. 1004)The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must ensure that each major implementation of a DOD financial business system is reviewed by professional accountants.

(Sec. 1005)DOD must report on auditable financial statements for all military departments and defense agencies.

(Sec. 1006)DOD must require any accounting firm providing audit services to provide a statement setting forth the details of disciplinary proceedings.

Subtitle B--Naval Vessels and Shipyards

(Sec. 1011)The bill includes operation and sustainment costs in annual naval vessel construction plans.

(Sec. 1012)The bill modifies the authority of DOD to purchase vessels using funds in the National Defense Sealift Fund.

(Sec. 1013)The bill requires DOD to notify Congress before entering into a contract for the purchase of vessels built in foreign shipyards.

(Sec. 1014)The bill revises the date for listing vessels as battle force ships in the Naval Vessel Register or other fleet inventory measures.

(Sec. 1015)The bill makes technical revisions regarding naval vessels, including eliminating a provision related to when vessels are considered to be under-age.

(Sec. 1016)The Navy must report a cost and schedule baseline for the dismantlement and disposal of nuclear-powered aircraft carriers before awarding a contract for this dismantlement and disposal.

(Sec. 1017)The bill prohibits the Navy from using funds to retire, transfer, or place in storage any hospital ship.

(Sec. 1018)DOD must include a detailed aircraft carrier refueling overhaul budget request in annual budget justification materials.

(Sec. 1019)The Navy must report on business case analysis options for the Ready Reserve Force.

(Sec. 1020)The bill authorizes the President to transfer the OLIVER HAZARD PERRY class guided missile frigate ex-USS ROBERT G. BRADLEY to the government of Bahrain.

Subtitle C--Counterterrorism

(Sec. 1031)The bill revises notification requirements for sensitive military operations.

(Sec. 1032)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to extend the prohibition on using funds to close U.S. Naval Station, Guantanamo Bay, Cuba (Guantanamo).

(Sec. 1033)The bill prohibits DOD from using funds to transfer or release detainees at Guantanamo to or within the United States, its territories, or possessions.

(Sec. 1034)The bill prohibits DOD from using funds to construct or modify facilities in the United States, its territories, or possessions to house detainees transferred from Guantanamo.

(Sec. 1035)The bill prohibits DOD from using funds to transfer, release, or assist in the transfer or release of any individual detained at Guantanamo to Libya, Somalia, Syria, or Yemen.

Subtitle D--Miscellaneous Authorities and Limitations

(Sec. 1041)The bill revises DOD requirements for specified strategic guidance documents.

(Sec. 1042)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify notice requirements for DOD on the provision of defense sensitive support.

(Sec. 1043)The President must designate an employee of the National Security Council to be responsible for the coordination of the interagency process for combating malign foreign influence operations and campaigns.

(Sec. 1044)The bill revises the obligations that the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) may incur for soundproofing and acquisition of certain residential properties.

(Sec. 1045)The bill modifies numerical limitations for nonimmigrant workers in Guam and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.

(Sec. 1046)The Department of Transportation (DOT) may not require the installation of automatic dependent surveillance-broadcast equipment on certain military aircraft.

(Sec. 1047)The bill limits the amount of funds that may be used for unmanned surface vehicles.

(Sec. 1048)DOD must establish a pilot program for oversight of controlled unclassified information in the hands of defense contractors with foreign ownership, control, or influence concerns.

(Sec. 1049)DOD must establish and maintain a list of acquisition programs, technologies, manufacturing capabilities, and research areas that are critical for maintaining the national security technological advantage of the United States.

(Sec. 1050)DOD must carry out an educational campaign to inform individuals about Airborne Hazards and the Open Burn Pit Registry.

(Sec. 1051)The bill establishes an independent commission to review advances in artificial intelligence, related machine learning developments, and associated technologies.

(Sec. 1052)DOD may transfer funds for the Bien Hoa dioxin cleanup in Vietnam.

(Sec. 1053)DOD must establish processes and procedures on the electronic warfare mission area and the conduct of joint electromagnetic spectrum operations.

Subtitle E--Studies and Reports

(Sec. 1061)The bill establishes annual reporting requirements for each branch of the military (other than the Coast Guard) regarding unconstrained total munitions and inventory numbers.

(Sec. 1062)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to revise annual reporting requirements on civilian casualties in connection with U.S. military operations.

(Sec. 1063)The Army must report on the capabilities and capacities of Armored Brigade Combat Teams.

(Sec. 1064)The bill sets forth activities and reporting requirements that the Chief Information Officer of DOD must carry out relating to DOD's Cloud Initiative.

(Sec. 1065)The bill prohibits the use of funds for the U.S. Special Operations Command's Global Messaging and Counter-Messaging platform until DOD submits a specified report.

(Sec. 1066)DOD must conduct a comprehensive review of the ethics programs and professionalism programs of special operations forces.

(Sec. 1067) The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must report on certain munitions assessments and future-years defense program requirements.

(Sec. 1068)The Army must report on the establishment of Army Futures Command.

(Sec. 1069)The President must report on the effects of cyber-enabled information operations on the national security of the United States.

(Sec. 1070)DOD and the FAA must report on whether legislative action is required to prevent low flying unmanned aircraft from disrupting funerals at Arlington National Cemetery.

(Sec. 1071)DOD must report on an updated Arctic strategy to improve and enhance joint operations.

(Sec. 1072)DOD must report on the availability of military installations for disaster response.

(Sec. 1073)The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy must report on DOD participation in the export license application review process.

(Sec. 1074)DOD must report on military aviation readiness in support of the National Defense Strategy (NDS).

(Sec. 1075)DOD must report on its highest priority missions and the role of the Armed Forces in carrying out such missions.

Subtitle F--Other Matters

(Sec. 1081)The bill makes technical revisions, including revisions regarding post-trial procedure and review of military commissions.

(Sec. 1082)DOD may designate a Principal Advisor on Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction.

(Sec. 1083)The bill modifies the authority of DHS to transfer aircraft to other agencies for wildfire suppression purposes.

(Sec. 1084)The bill amends the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 to modify the DOD database on emergency response capabilities.

(Sec. 1085)The bill sets forth reporting requirements for U.S.-based foreign media outlets.

(Sec. 1086)The bill declares that it is U.S. policy to fly, sail, and operate throughout the oceans, seas, and airspace of the world wherever international law allows.

(Sec. 1087)The bill establishes the National Commission on Military Aviation Safety to examine and make recommendations with respect to certain U.S. military aviation mishaps.

(Sec. 1088)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that gaining and maintaining situational awareness and operational control of the international borders of the United States is critical to national security.

(Sec. 1089)DOD must establish a policy on its response to allegations of juvenile-on-juvenile problematic sexual behavior on military installations.

(Sec. 1090)DOD may provide support for a parade to honor American veterans.

(Sec. 1091)The bill prohibits the use of DOD funds for Chinese language instruction provided by a Confucius Institute.

(Sec. 1092) The bill expresses the sense of Congress that U.S. military commanders must engage with certain entities to advance the military missions of the Armed Forces.

TITLE XI--CIVILIAN PERSONNEL MATTERS

(Sec. 1101)The bill provides DOD with authority to expedite the hiring of civilian personnel for certain positions.

(Sec. 1102)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify the direct hire authority of DOD for post-secondary students and recent graduates.

(Sec. 1103)The bill extends the authority of the Navy to pay overtime rates to civilian employees performing temporary duty in Japan in support of the forward deployed nuclear-powered aircraft carrier.

(Sec. 1104)The bill amends the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 to extend through 2019 the authority to waive the annual limitation on premium pay and aggregate limitation on pay for civilian employees working overseas.

(Sec. 1105)The bill extends through December 31, 2020, authority to conduct telework travel expenses test programs.

(Sec. 1106)The bill expands the authority of the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to conduct demonstration projects.

(Sec. 1107)The bill provides federal agencies flexibility in setting the minimum number of candidates who must be considered on a referral list for each vacancy.

(Sec. 1108)The bill provides expedited hiring authority for college graduates and post-secondary students.

(Sec. 1109)DOD may appoint senior executive service employees without such individuals being subject to the certification of executive qualifications by the OPM.

(Sec. 1110)DOD must report on its engagement with historically black colleges and universities and minority-serving institutions to increase its hiring from these institutions for certain positions.

(Sec. 1111)The bill expands personnel management authority to attract experts in science and engineering.

(Sec. 1112)The bill modifies flexible management authorities for science and technology reinvention laboratories in DOD.

(Sec. 1113)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to expand direct hire authority for financial management experts.

(Sec. 1114)The Navy may prescribe regulations establishing a program to conduct on-duty reasonable suspicion alcohol testing and post-accident alcohol testing of civil service mariners of the Military Sealift Command who are assigned to vessels.

(Sec. 1115)The bill extends authority to grant allowances, benefits, and gratuities to civilian personnel on official duty in a combat zone.

TITLE XII--MATTERS RELATING TO FOREIGN NATIONS

Subtitle A--Assistance and Training

(Sec. 1201)The bill modifies the authority for DOD and the Department of State to build the capacity of foreign security forces.

(Sec. 1202)The bill modifies the authority for DOD to provide training support services to foreign ministries.

(Sec. 1203)The bill increases the cost limitation of and revises notification requirements for certain small-scale construction activities.

(Sec. 1204)The bill revises provisions relating to the Defense Security Cooperation Agency.

(Sec. 1205)DOD and the State Department must conduct a review of the processes and procedures used to determine if a foreign security force has committed a gross violation of human rights.

(Sec. 1206)DOD must report on the use of security cooperation funding to counter malign influence campaigns by strategic competitors and other state actors directed at allied and partner countries and posing a significant threat to the national security of the United States.

(Sec. 1207)DOD may authorize members of the Armed Forces and civilian personnel to participate in and support the Inter-American Defense College.

(Sec. 1208)DOD may operate a Naval Small Craft Instruction and Technical Training School.

(Sec. 1209)DOD may pay costs associated with regional defense in combating terrorism or irregular warfare.

(Sec. 1210)The bill modifies the DOD State Partnership Program.

(Sec. 1211)The bill sets forth funding to be allocated for the assessment, monitoring, and evaluation of security cooperation activities.

(Sec. 1212)The Under Secretary of Defense for Policy must conduct a review of the legal and policy frameworks associated with advise, assist, and accompany missions by U.S. military personnel.

(Sec. 1213)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to extend and modify the authority of DOD to support border security activities of certain foreign countries.

(Sec. 1214)DOD and the State Department must establish an agreement setting forth a framework for obtaining concurrence to participate in activities of DOD Regional Centers for Security Studies.

Subtitle B--Matters Relating to Afghanistan and Pakistan

(Sec. 1221)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2013 to extend through December 31, 2020, the authority of DOD to transfer defense articles and provide defense services to the military and security forces of Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1222)The bill extends and modifies reporting requirements for special immigrant visas for the Afghan allies program.

(Sec. 1223)The bill provides authority for the Afghanistan Security Forces Fund.

(Sec. 1224)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to extend and modify the Commanders' Emergency Response Program in Afghanistan.

(Sec. 1225)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to extend and modify the authority of DOD to reimburse certain coalition nations.

Subtitle C--Matters Relating to Syria, Iraq, and Iran

(Sec. 1231)The bill amends the Carl Levin and Howard P. `Buck' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to extend and modify the authority of DOD to provide assistance to the vetted elements of the Syrian opposition.

(Sec. 1232)The State Department must report on war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide in Syria.

(Sec. 1233)The bill amends the Carl Levin and Howard P. `Buck' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to extend the authority to provide assistance to counter the Islamic State of Iraq and Syria (ISIS).

(Sec. 1234)The bill prohibits the use of funds to provide assistance to any group that is, or that is known to be affiliated with, the Iranian Revolutionary Guard Corps-Quds Force or a state sponsor of terrorism.

(Sec. 1235)The bill extends and modifies the authority to support operations and activities of the Office of Security Cooperation in Iraq.

(Sec. 1236)The bill modifies annual reporting requirements of DOD on the military power of Iran.

(Sec. 1237)DOD and the State Department may develop a strategy with foreign partners to counter the destabilizing activities of Iran.

Subtitle D--Matters Relating to the Russian Federation

(Sec. 1241)The bill prohibits funds from being used to implement any activity that recognizes the sovereignty of Russia over Crimea. DOD may waive the prohibition by certifying to Congress that it is in the national security interest of the United States.

(Sec. 1242)The bill prohibits the use of funding to modify any U.S. aircraft for purposes of implementing the Open Skies Treaty until the President certifies that he has imposed treaty violations responses and legal countermeasures.

(Sec. 1243)The President must submit to Congress a determination of whether (1) Russia is in material breach of its obligations under the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty, and (2) the prohibitions in the treaty remain binding on the United States.

(Sec. 1244)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that (1) the actions undertaken by Russia in violation of the INF Treaty have defeated the object and purpose of the treaty and constitute a material breach of the treaty, (2) the United States is legally entitled to suspend the operation of the treaty for so long as Russia continues to be in material breach, (3) and the United States should take actions to encourage Russia to return to compliance with the treaty.

(Sec. 1245)The President must report on implementation of the New START Treaty.

(Sec. 1246)The bill modifies and extends the authority of DOD to provide security assistance and intelligence support to military and other security forces of the government of Ukraine.

(Sec. 1247)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to extend the prohibition on funds being used for bilateral military-to-military cooperation between the United States and Russia.

(Sec. 1248)The bill expresses that it is U.S. policy to pursue an integrated approach to strengthening the defense of allies and partners in Europe as part of a broader, long-term strategy to deter and, if necessary, defeat Russian aggression.

Subtitle E--Matters Relating to the Indo-Pacific Region

(Sec. 1251)The bill revises the name of the United States Pacific Command to the United States Indo-Pacific Command.

(Sec. 1252)The bill expands and extends the Southeast Asia Maritime Security Initiative, and it redesignates it as the Indo-Pacific Maritime Security Initiative.

(Sec. 1253)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to modify the Indo-Asia-Pacific Stability Initiative and to redesignate the initiative as the Indo-Pacific Stability Initiative.

(Sec. 1254)DOD must enter into an agreement with an independent entity to conduct an assessment of the geopolitical conditions in the Indo-Pacific region.

(Sec. 1255)The bill expresses the sense of Congress on extended nuclear deterrence in the Indo-Pacific region.

(Sec. 1256)The bill reinstates certain reporting requirements regarding U.S. relations with Hong Kong.

(Sec. 1257)DOD must conduct a comprehensive assessment of Taiwan's military forces to improve the efficiency, effectiveness, readiness, and resilience of Taiwan's self-defense capabilities.

(Sec. 1258)The bill expresses the sense of Congress regarding Taiwan.

(Sec. 1259)The bill prohibits the participation of China in any Rim of the Pacific naval exercise.

(Sec. 1260)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2000 to revise annual reporting requirements on military and security developments involving China.

(Sec. 1261)The President must report on U.S. strategy with respect to China.

(Sec. 1262)DOD must report on the military and coercive activities of China in the South China Sea.

(Sec. 1263)DOD must evaluate the operational requirements for members of the Armed Forces possessing foreign language expertise in critical languages, including Chinese, Korean, Russian, Farsi, and Arabic.

(Sec. 1264)The bill prohibits the use of funds to reduce the total number of members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty who are deployed to South Korea unless DOD makes certain certifications.

(Sec. 1265)DOD must report on the status of the nuclear program of North Korea.

(Sec. 1266)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to revise reporting requirements on enhancing defense and security cooperation with India.

Subtitle F--Reports and Other Matters

(Sec. 1271)The bill modifies reporting requirements for DOD regarding acquisition and cross-servicing agreements.

(Sec. 1272)The bill limits the use of funds to establish capabilities for countering unmanned aerial systems that threaten the United States or Israel.

(Sec. 1273)The President may conduct a joint assessment of the quantity and type of precision guided munition for Israel.

(Sec. 1274)DOD must conduct a review to determine whether the Armed Forces or coalition partners of the United States violated federal law, the laws of armed conflict, or DOD policy while conducting operations in Yemen.

(Sec. 1275)DOD and the State Department must report on U.S. programs relating to security cooperation with and assistance to Mexico.

(Sec. 1276)DOD must report on its missions, operations, and activities in Niger.

(Sec. 1277)DOD and the State Department must jointly report on the security relationship between the United States and Cyprus.

(Sec. 1278)The bill expresses the sense of Congress on detention of U.S. citizens by the government of Turkey.

(Sec. 1279)The bill revises provisions related to the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Support and Procurement Organization.

(Sec. 1280)DOD must report on the feasibility and advisability of permanently stationing United States forces in Poland.

(Sec. 1281)DOD must report on enhancing U.S. leadership and collaboration with NATO to build cyber-defense capacity and deter cyberattacks among NATO member countries.

(Sec. 1282)DOD must report on the status of the United States relationship with Turkey.

(Sec. 1283)The bill expresses the sense of Congress concerning military-to-military dialogues.

(Sec. 1284)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify the State Department's Global Engagement Center.

(Sec. 1285)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that DOD and the State Department should prioritize the submission of a required report outlining a comprehensive strategy to counter malign activities of Russia.

(Sec. 1286)DOD must establish an initiative to work with academic institutions who perform defense research and engineering activities.

(Sec. 1287)The State Department must report on narcotics trafficking corruption and illicit campaign finance in Honduras, Guatemala, and El Salvador.

(Sec. 1288)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify reporting requirements for the DOD Freedom of Navigation report.

(Sec. 1289)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify the coordination of efforts to negotiate free trade agreements with certain sub-Saharan African countries.

(Sec. 1290)The bill limits the use of funds to provide authorized in-flight refueling of Saudi or Saudi-led coalition aircraft conducting missions in Yemen.

(Sec. 1291)The bill removes the Rwandan Patriotic Front and the Rwandan Patriotic Army from treatment as terrorist organizations.

(Sec. 1292)The bill limits the use of funds to implement the Arms Trade Treaty.

(Sec. 1293)The bill prohibits funds from being used to provide weapons or any other form of support to Al Qaeda, ISIS, Jabhat Fateh al Sham, or any individual or group affiliated with any such organization.

(Sec. 1294)The bill authorizes the President to waive sanctions with respect to persons engaging in transactions with the government of Russia.

(Sec. 1295)The bill does not authorize the use of force against Iran or North Korea.

TITLE XIII--COOPERATIVE THREAT REDUCTION

(Sec. 1301)The bill allocates authorizations of appropriations of funds for the Cooperative Threat Reduction (CTR) program in FY2019.

(Sec. 1302)The bill specifies the CTR programs and authorizations of appropriations included in this bill and authorizes CTR funds to be obligated for FY2019-FY2021.

TITLE XIV--OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

Subtitle A--Military Programs

(Sec. 1401)The bill authorizes appropriations for working capital funds and revolving funds at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1402)The bill authorizes appropriations for Chemical Agents and Munitions Destruction, Defense, at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1403)The bill authorizes appropriations for Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, Defense-wide, at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1404)The bill authorizes appropriations for the DOD Office of the Inspector General at the levels identified in section 4501.

(Sec. 1405)The bill authorizes appropriations for the Defense Health Program at the levels identified in section 4501.

Subtitle B--Armed Forces Retirement Home

(Sec. 1411)The bill authorizations appropriations for the Armed Forces Retirement Home in FY2019.

(Sec. 1412)The bill expands eligibility for persons to become residents of the Armed Forces Retirement Home.

(Sec. 1413)The bill modifies the duties of the Senior Medical Advisor of the Armed Forces Retirement Home.

(Sec. 1414)The bill modifies the authority of the Chief Operating Officer of the Armed Forces Retirement Home to accept gifts.

(Sec. 1415)The bill prohibits the removal or release of a resident of the Armed Forces Retirement Home based solely upon the inability to pay.

(Sec. 1416)The bill limits the applicability of the fee increase for residents of the Armed Forces Retirement Home.

Subtitle C--Other Matters

(Sec. 1421)The bill authorizes DOD to transfer funds from the Defense Health Program to the Joint DOD-VA Medical Facility Demonstration Fund for the Captain James A. Lovell Health Care Center.

(Sec. 1422)The bill revises the duties of each military department to accomplish economical and efficient operation of working capital fund activities.

(Sec. 1423)The bill amends the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act to modify reporting requirements for the President.

(Sec. 1424)The bill modifies reporting requirements for DOD to include quarterly briefings to Congress on the progress of the chemical demilitarization program.

TITLE XV--AUTHORIZATION OF ADDITIONAL APPROPRIATIONS FOR OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS

Subtitle A--Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 1501)The bill specifies that the purpose of this title is to authorize FY2019 appropriations for overseas contingency operations (OCO).

(Sec. 1502)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for procurement at the levels identified in section 4102.

(Sec. 1503)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for research, development, test, and evaluation at the levels identified in section 4202.

(Sec. 1504)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for operation and maintenance at the levels identified in section 4302.

(Sec. 1505)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for military personnel at the levels identified in section 4402.

(Sec. 1506)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for DOD working capital funds at the levels identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1507)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for Drug Interdiction and Counter-Drug Activities, Defense-wide, at the levels identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1508)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for the DOD Office of the Inspector General at the levels identified in section 4502.

(Sec. 1509)The bill authorizes additional appropriations for the Defense Health Program at the levels identified in section 4502.

Subtitle B--Financial Matters

(Sec. 1511)The bill specifies that appropriations authorized by this title are in addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated.

(Sec. 1512)The bill authorizes the transfer of up to $3.5 billion of the FY2019 OCO funding authorized by this title.

(Sec. 1513)The bill authorizes FY2019 appropriations for OCO in specified amounts.

Subtitle C--Other Matters

(Sec. 1521)The bill authorizes specified amounts for the Joint Improvised-Threat Defeat Organization. The bill authorizes $15 million to DOD to provide training, equipment, supplies, and services to ministries and other entities of foreign governments that have been identified as critical for countering the flow of improvised explosive device precursor chemicals.

(Sec. 1522)The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must report on enduring costs funded through OCO.

(Sec. 1523)The GAO must report on how funds authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2018 for OCO were obligated.

TITLE XVI--STRATEGIC PROGRAMS, CYBER, AND INTELLIGENCE MATTERS

Subtitle A--Space Activities

(Sec. 1601)The bill establishes the U.S. Space Command to carry out joint space warfighting operations.

(Sec. 1602)The bill establishes a Space Rapid Capabilities Office within the Air Force Space Command.

(Sec. 1603)The bill revises U.S. policy regarding assured access to space to include the availability of rapid, responsive, and reliable space launches for national security space programs.

(Sec. 1604)DOD may provide space situational awareness services and information to non-U.S. government entities if such actions are necessary to meet the U.S. national security interests.

(Sec. 1605)The bill revises budget assessment requirements for DOD national security space programs.

(Sec. 1606)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to modify the requirements for commercial space launch activities.

(Sec. 1607)DOD must develop a space warfighting policy.

(Sec. 1608)DOD must submit to Congress a briefing on the risks, benefits, and cost savings associated with using small- and medium-size buses for strategic and tactical satellite payloads.

(Sec. 1609)The Air Force must ensure that military global positioning system user equipment terminals have the capability to receive signals from the Galileo satellites of the European Union and the QZSS satellites of Japan.

(Sec. 1610)DOD must designate a component of the Office of the Secretary of Defense to be responsible for coordinating common solutions for the M-code modernization efforts among the military departments, defense agencies, and other appropriate elements of DOD.

(Sec. 1611)The bill requires a component of DOD or a military department to be responsible for coordination of commercially hosted payload information.

(Sec. 1612)The bill limits the availability of funds for the Joint Space Operations Center mission system.

(Sec. 1613)DOD must conduct evaluations of the supply chain vulnerabilities for protected satellite communications and overhead persistent infrared systems.

(Sec. 1614)DOD must report on how certain programs will meet the requirements for resilience, mission assurance, and the nuclear command, control, and communication missions.

(Sec. 1615)DOD must submit to Congress a report that identifies whether the current Global Positioning System Operational Control Segment can be incrementally improved to achieve capabilities similar to the Next Generation Operational Control Segment.

(Sec. 1616)The Air Force must report on options to provide the United States Central Command with persistent weather imagery.

(Sec. 1617)DOD and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence must jointly conduct a study on the capabilities of the private sector with respect to space-based radio frequency mapping.

(Sec. 1618)DOD must seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct a study on space launch locations.

(Sec. 1619)DOD and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence must jointly submit to Congress a briefing detailing the costs, risks, and operational benefits of leveraging commercial satellite servicing capabilities for national security satellite systems.

Subtitle B--Defense Intelligence and Intelligence-Related Activities

(Sec. 1621)The bill modifies the role and responsibilities of the Under Secretary of Defense for Intelligence.

(Sec. 1622)DOD must develop uniform and consistent standards and a centralized process for the screening and vetting of certain foreign individuals requiring access to DOD systems, facilities, personnel, information, or operations.

(Sec. 1623)The bill revises the DOD counterintelligence polygraph program, including to revise persons who are covered under the program.

(Sec. 1624)The Chief Management Officer of DOD must develop and implement standardized business process rules for the planning, programming, budgeting, and execution process for the Military Intelligence Program.

(Sec. 1625)The bill amends the Carl Levin and Howard P. `Buck' McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 to modify the annual briefing on the intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance requirements of the combatant commands.

(Sec. 1626)DOD must develop and establish in policy a framework and supporting processes to help ensure that the missions, roles, and functions of the combat support agencies are appropriately balanced and resourced.

Subtitle C--Cyberspace-Related Matters

(Sec. 1631)The bill reorganizes and consolidates certain cyber provisions.

(Sec. 1632)The bill affirms the authority of DOD to conduct military activities and operations in cyberspace.

(Sec. 1633)The bill revises requirements in selecting recipients for scholarships or grants under the DOD cyber scholarship program.

(Sec. 1634)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to make revisions to the pilot program regarding cyber vulnerabilities of DOD critical infrastructure.

(Sec. 1635)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to modify the acquisition authority of the U.S. Cyber Command.

(Sec. 1636)The bill states that it is U.S. policy with respect to cyberspace, cybersecurity, cyber warfare, and cyber deterrence to employ all instruments of national power to deter and respond to all cyberattacks or other malicious cyber activities of foreign powers that target U.S. interests.

(Sec. 1637)DOD must submit to Congress a consolidated Cyber Vulnerability Evaluation and Mitigation budget justification display for each major weapons system.

(Sec. 1638)DOD must submit to Congress a report containing a determination regarding the roles, missions, and responsibilities of the Commander, Joint Force Headquarters-Department of Defense Information Networks of the Defense Information Support Agency.

(Sec. 1639)The bill sets forth procedures and reporting requirements for DOD regarding the loss of personally identifiable information and controlled unclassified information.

(Sec. 1640)DOD may carry out a program to establish a Cyber Institute at institutions of higher learning that have a Reserve Officers' Training Corps program.

(Sec. 1641)DOD must transfer the operations and maintenance for the Sharkseer cybersecurity program from the National Security Agency to the Defense Information Systems Agency.

(Sec. 1642)The National Command Authority may authorize DOD to take appropriate and proportional action in foreign cyberspace to disrupt, defeat, and deter cyberattacks from certain countries.

(Sec. 1643)DOD must designate one official to be responsible for matters relating to integrating cybersecurity and industrial control systems.

(Sec. 1644)DOD must take actions necessary to enhance awareness of cybersecurity threats among small manufacturers and universities working on DOD programs and activities.

(Sec. 1645)DOD must implement a plan relating to electronic mail and internet website security and authentication.

(Sec. 1646)The Principal Cyber Adviser, the Chief Information Officer, and the U.S. Cyber Command must select a network or network segment to conduct a demonstration and evaluation of one or more existing security product integration frameworks.

(Sec. 1647)The bill limits the availability of funds to prepare the cybersecurity scorecard for the Secretary of Defense unless DOD is implementing certain funded capabilities.

(Sec. 1648)The U.S. Cyber Command, the U.S. Northern Command, and certain other commands or components of DOD must conduct a tier 1 exercise of support to civil authorities for a cyber incident.

(Sec. 1649)The Assistant Secretary of Defense for Homeland Defense and Global Security must carry out a pilot program to model cyberattacks on critical infrastructure.

(Sec. 1650)DOD may provide, detail, or assign technical personnel to DHS on a non-reimbursable basis to enhance cybersecurity cooperation, collaboration, and unity of government efforts.

(Sec. 1651)The Army may carry out a pilot program to establish a National Guard training center to provide cybersecurity training for the Army National Guard.

(Sec. 1652)The bill establishes a commission to develop a consensus on a strategic approach to defending the United States in cyberspace against cyber attacks.

(Sec. 1653)Each military department must conduct a study on the feasibility and advisability of establishing reserve component cyber civil support teams.

(Sec. 1654)DOD must create a list of countries that pose a risk to the cybersecurity of United States defense and national security systems and infrastructure.

(Sec. 1655)DOD is prohibited from using the products, services, or systems relating to information or operational technology of providers who have obligations to foreign governments unless such providers make certain disclosures.

(Sec. 1656)DOD must report on the feasibility of establishing a Cybersecurity Apprentice Program to support on-the-job training for certain cybersecurity positions and facilitate the acquisition of cybersecurity certifications.

(Sec. 1657) The Principal Cyber Adviser to the Secretary of Defense, the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering, and the Chief Information Officer of DOD must jointly report on the enhancement of software security for critical systems.

Subtitle D--Nuclear Forces

(Sec. 1661)The bill revises membership requirements of the Nuclear Weapons Council to include the Under Secretary of Defense for Research and Engineering.

(Sec. 1662)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 to revise the requirement for the Air Force to develop a follow-on air-launched cruise missile to the AGM-86.

(Sec. 1663)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must implement (1) a plan to accelerate the development, procurement, and fielding of the ground-based strategic deterrent program; and (2) a plan to accelerate the development, procurement, and fielding of the long-range standoff weapon.

(Sec. 1664)The bill specifies the amount of funds available to procure certain parts of intercontinental ballistic missile fuzes.

(Sec. 1665)The bill prohibits the use of funds to reduce the intercontinental ballistic missiles of the United States.

(Sec. 1666)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to extend the prohibition on the availability of funds for a mobile variant of the ground-based strategic deterrent missile.

(Sec. 1667)The Nuclear Weapons Council and the NNSA must jointly establish an exchange program for nuclear weapons program employees.

(Sec. 1668)DOD must develop a plan to train, educate, manage, and track officers of the Armed Forces in nuclear command, control, and communications.

(Sec. 1669)DOD must seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct a study on options for increasing presidential decision-time regarding the employment of nuclear weapons.

(Sec. 1670)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 to extend requirements for the President to submit an annual report regarding nuclear weapons.

(Sec. 1671)The Nuclear Weapons Council must submit to Congress a plan containing a proposal for better aligning the acquisition of warhead life extension programs and delivery vehicles for such warheads.

(Sec. 1672)The Air Force must submit to Congress an annual report describing the joint development of the long-range stand-off weapon.

(Sec. 1673)The bill expresses the sense of Congress on the nuclear posture of the United States.

Subtitle E--Missile Defense Programs

(Sec. 1675)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to revise the requirements of the Missile Defense Agency (MDA)in developing space-based sensor architecture that is capable of supporting the ballistic missile defense system.

(Sec. 1676)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to direct the MDA to develop boost phase intercept capabilities.

(Sec. 1677)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to extend the reporting requirement for the MDA on unfunded priorities.

(Sec. 1678)The bill extends through January 1, 2021, the prohibition relating to providing Russia with missile defense information and systems.

(Sec. 1679)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to modify the requirement related to the transition of ballistic missile defense programs to the military departments.

(Sec. 1680)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to modify the requirement for the MDA to develop a space-based ballistic missile intercept layer.

(Sec. 1681)The bill limits the availability of funds to change the non-standard acquisition processes and responsibilities of the MDA.

(Sec. 1682)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the United States must explore and deploy capabilities that increase the layered defense of the U.S. homeland.

(Sec. 1683)The MDA may not make a lot production decision for the redesigned kill vehicle unless the vehicle has undergone at least one successful flight intercept test that meets certain criteria.

(Sec. 1684)The Navy must assess the requirements for ballistic missile defense capable ships and advanced ballistic missile defense capabilities.

(Sec. 1685)DOD may enter into one or more multiyear contracts for the procurement of standard missile-3 block IB guided missiles.

(Sec. 1686)The bill limits the availability of funds for a lower tier air and missile defense sensor.

(Sec. 1687)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the MDA must ensure the on-time deployment of the discrimination radar in Hawaii.

(Sec. 1688)The bill authorizes specified funds for the MDA to provide to the government of Israel to procure certain missile defense systems.

(Sec. 1689)The MDA must accelerate the hypersonic missile defense program.

(Sec. 1690)DOD must submit to Congress a report that addresses the implications of the recommendations of the Ballistic Missile Defense Review on current programs of record, costs and resource prioritization, and strategic stability.

(Sec. 1691)The bill expresses the sense of Congress on allied partnerships for missile defense.

(Sec. 1692)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the MDA should enhance its missile defense test criteria to more rapidly deliver capabilities to the warfighter.

Subtitle F--Other Matters

(Sec. 1695)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 to extend authority for the Commission to Assess the Threat to the United States from Electromagnetic Pulse Attacks and Similar Events.

(Sec. 1696)The Army and the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must jointly conduct a business case analysis of the federal government using a government-owned, contractor-operated model to ensure a robust domestic industrial base to supply specialty chemicals for use in solid rocket motors.

(Sec. 1697)The Under Secretary of Defense (Comptroller) must include in the budget justification materials, a budget exhibit on support provided to the Executive Office of the President.

(Sec. 1698)DOD must submit to Congress a validated requirement for ground-, sea-, or air-launched (or a combination thereof) conventional prompt global strike hypersonic capabilities.

(Sec. 1699)The Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment must report on whether the federal government will sustain more than one supplier for large solid rocket motors.

TITLE XVII--REVIEW OF FOREIGN INVESTMENT AND EXPORT CONTROLS

Subtitle A--Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States

Foreign Investment Risk Review Modernization Act of 2018

(Sec. 1702)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that (1) foreign investment provides substantial economic benefits to the United States, and (2) the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) must review foreign transactions to protect U.S. national security.

(Sec. 1703)The bill amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to expand the scope of "covered transaction" subject to the review of the CFIUS. CFIUS analyzes the national security implications of foreign investment in the United States.

(Sec. 1704)CFIUS must provide comments on a draft or formal written notice or accept a formal written notice with respect to a covered transaction not later than the date that is 10 business days after the date of submission of the draft or formal written notice.

(Sec. 1705)CFIUS may require a written notice submitted to include a copy of any partnership agreements, integration agreements, or other side agreements relating to the transaction.

(Sec. 1706)CFIUS must prescribe regulations establishing requirements for declarations submitted for certain covered transactions. In prescribing such regulations, the Committee must ensure that such declarations are submitted as abbreviated notifications that would not generally exceed five pages in length.

(Sec. 1707)In a written notice or declaration, a party to a transaction may stipulate that the transaction is a covered transaction and that the transaction is a foreign government-controlled transaction.

(Sec. 1708)The bill provides authority for CFIUS to unilaterally initiate national security reviews and investigations.

(Sec. 1709)The bill extends from 30 days to 45 days the deadline for the completion of national security reviews and investigations.

(Sec. 1710)CFIUS must establish a process to identify covered transactions of non-notified and non-declared transactions.

(Sec. 1711)The bill revises how CFIUS may submit certifications to Congress.

(Sec. 1712)The Office of the Director of National Intelligence must expeditiously carry out a thorough analysis of any threat to the national security of the United States posed by any covered foreign transaction.

(Sec. 1713)CFIUS must establish a formal process for the exchange of information with governments of countries that are allies or partners of the United States to protect the national security of the United States and those countries.

(Sec. 1714)The bill revises the timeframe for when the President may take action to suspend or prohibit any covered transaction that threatens to impair the national security of the United States.

(Sec. 1715)A civil action challenging an action or finding under this subtitle may be brought only in the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit.

(Sec. 1716)The bill revises the regulations that the President must direct to be carried out under this subtitle.

(Sec. 1717)The bill sets forth hiring authority for members and staff of CFIUS.

(Sec. 1718)CFIUS may suspend a proposed or pending covered transaction that may pose a risk to the national security of the United States for such time as the covered transaction is under review or investigation. Further, CFIUS may refer the transaction to the President for certain action.

(Sec. 1719)The bill modifies reporting requirements for CFIUS.

(Sec. 1720)CFIUS may not complete a review of a covered transaction and may recommend that the President suspend or prohibit the transaction if it determines a party has failed to submit proper notice.

(Sec. 1721)CFIUS and the Department of Commerce must develop plans to implement this subtitle.

(Sec. 1722)The President must assess the need for additional resources for CFIUS.

(Sec. 1723)The bill establishes the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States Fund.

(Sec. 1724)The chairperson of CFIUS may centralize certain functions of the committee within the Department of the Treasury for the purpose of enhancing interagency coordination and collaboration.

(Sec. 1725)The bill revises the authority of CFIUS to review certain mergers, acquisitions, and takeovers.

(Sec. 1726)The Department of the Treasury must provide a briefing to Congress on information from transactions reviewed by CFIUS relating to foreign efforts to influence democratic institutions and processes.

(Sec. 1727)The bill sets forth effective dates for the provisions of this subtitle.

(Sec. 1728)The bill provides that if any provision of this subtitle or an amendment made by this subtitle is held to be invalid, the remainder of the provisions of this subtitle and the amendments made by this subtitle must not be affected.

Subtitle B--Export Control Reform

Export Control Reform Act of 2018

(Sec. 1742)The bill sets forth definitions under this subtitle.

Part I--Authority and Administration of Controls

Export Controls Act of 2018

(Sec. 1752)The bill provides a statement of U.S. policy regarding export controls.

(Sec. 1753)The bill grants the President authority to control (1) the export, re-export, and transfer of items (commodities, software, or technology), whether by U.S. persons (including corporations) or by foreign persons, wherever located; and (2) the activities of U.S. persons, wherever located, relating to specific nuclear explosive devices, missiles, chemical or biological weapons, whole plants for chemical weapons precursors, foreign maritime nuclear projects, and foreign intelligence services.

(Sec. 1754)The bill provides specific authority to Commerce regarding export controls.

(Sec. 1755)The President must rely on the heads of federal agencies to administer export controls.

(Sec. 1756)Commerce must establish a procedure to license or otherwise authorize the export, re-export, and in-country transfer of items in order to carry out U.S. policy.

(Sec. 1757)The President may authorize Commerce to establish a system to provide U.S. persons with compliance assistance.

(Sec. 1758)The President must establish and lead a regular, ongoing interagency process to identify and control the export of emerging and foundational technologies.

(Sec. 1759)Commerce must conduct a review of license requirements for exports, re-exports, or in-country transfers of items to countries subject to a comprehensive United States arms embargo.

(Sec. 1760)The bill provides penalties for violations of this subtitle.

(Sec. 1761)Commerce may exercise additional enforcement measures to carry out this subtitle.

(Sec. 1762)Commerce may appoint administrative law judges and designate properly appointed administrative law judges from other federal agencies.

(Sec. 1763)The President must review and evaluate the interagency export license referral, review, and escalation processes for dual-use items and munitions to determine whether current practices and procedures are consistent with established national security and foreign policy objectives.

(Sec. 1764)Commerce must consult with DOD, the State Department, and DOE regarding commodity classifications materially significant enough to warrant interagency consultation.

(Sec. 1765)Commerce must submit to Congress an annual report on the implementation of this part during the preceding fiscal year.

(Sec. 1766)The bill repeals the Export Administration Act of 1979.

(Sec. 1767)Nothing contained in this part shall be construed to modify, repeal, supersede, or otherwise affect the provisions of any other laws authorizing control over the export or re-export of any item.

(Sec. 1768) The bill establishes transition provisions whereby all administrative action under the Export Administration Act of 1979 shall continue in effect until modified, superseded, set aside, or revoked under the authority of this part.

Part II--Anti-Boycott Act of 2018

Anti-Boycott Act of 2018

(Sec. 1772)The bill states it is U.S. policy to (1) oppose restrictive trade practices or boycotts fostered or imposed by any foreign country against other countries friendly to the United States, and (2) foster international cooperation and the development of international rules and institutions to assure reasonable access to world supplies.

(Sec. 1773)The President must prohibit any U.S. person from taking or knowingly agreeing to take certain actions with intent to comply with, further, or support any boycott fostered or imposed by any foreign country against a country which is friendly to the United States.

(Sec. 1774)The bill sets forth criminal and civil penalties for violations under this subtitle.

Part III--Administrative Authorities

(Sec. 1781)The bill provides that any reference to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration shall be deemed a reference to the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security.

Subtitle C--Miscellaneous

(Sec. 1791)The bill extends authority through September 30, 2025, for the Defense Production Act of 1950.

(Sec. 1792)The bill limits DOD from canceling the designation of the Secretary of the Air Force as a DOD Executive Agent for a certain Defense Production Act Program.

(Sec. 1793)DOD and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence must review and report on certain national security technologies that are critical to the United States maintaining superior military capabilities.

DIVISION B--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION AUTHORIZATIONS

Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019

(Sec. 2002)The bill specifies that the authorizations provided in titles XXI through XXVII, and title XXIX will expire on October 1, 2023, or the date of enactment of an act authorizing funds for military construction for FY2024, whichever is later.

(Sec. 2003)The bill specifies that titles XXI through XXVII and title XXIX will take effect on October 1, 2018, or the date of enactment of this bill, whichever is later.

TITLE XXI--ARMY MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2101)The bill authorizes specified Army construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2102)The bill authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Army.

(Sec. 2103)The bill authorizes appropriations for Army military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2104)The bill extends the authorizations for specified FY2015 projects.

(Sec. 2105)The bill extends the authorizations for the Virginia Arlington National Cemetery project.

TITLE XXII--NAVY MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2201)The bill authorizes specified Navy construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2202)The bill authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Navy.

(Sec. 2203)The bill authorizes the Navy to make improvements to existing units of family housing.

(Sec. 2204)The bill authorizes appropriations for Navy military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

TITLE XXIII--AIR FORCE MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2301)The bill authorizes specified Air Force construction and land acquisition projects.

(Sec. 2302)The bill authorizes new construction and planning and design of family housing units for the Air Force.

(Sec. 2303)The bill authorizes the Air Force to make improvements to existing units of family housing.

(Sec. 2304)The bill authorizes appropriations for Air Force military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2305)The bill modifies the authorization for the Air Force to carry out specified FY2015-FY2017 projects.

(Sec. 2306)The bill modifies the authorization for construction of a basic military training recruit dormitory at Joint Base San Antonio, Texas.

(Sec. 2307)The bill modifies the authorization for construction of a cyberworks facility at the U.S. Air Force Academy, Colorado.

(Sec. 2308)The bill authorizes appropriations for the Air Force to carry out specified FY2019 projects.

(Sec. 2309)The bill authorizes appropriations for the Air Force to construct a high-bay air cargo pallet storage and marshaling enclosure at Travis Air Force Base, California.

TITLE XXIV--DEFENSE AGENCIES MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2401)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for defense agencies.

(Sec. 2402)The bill authorizes DOD to carry out specified energy conservation projects.

(Sec. 2403)The bill authorizes appropriations for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of defense agencies at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2404)The bill extends the authorizations for specified FY2015 projects.

(Sec. 2405)The bill extends the authorizations for construction of the Texas Fort Bliss Blood Processing Center.

TITLE XXV--INTERNATIONAL PROGRAMS

Subtitle A--North Atlantic Treaty Organization Security Investment Program

(Sec. 2501)The bill authorizes DOD to make specified contributions to the NATO Security Investment Program in an amount not to exceed the sum of amount authorized in section 2502 and the amount collected from NATO for construction previously financed by the United States.

(Sec. 2502)The bill authorizes appropriations for the NATO Security Investment Program at the levels identified in section 4601.

Subtitle B--Host Country In-kind Contributions

(Sec. 2511)The bill authorizes DOD to accept specified military construction projects from South Korea as in-kind contributions.

TITLE XXVI--GUARD AND RESERVE FORCES FACILITIES

Subtitle A--Project Authorizations and Authorization of Appropriations

(Sec. 2601)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Army National Guard.

(Sec. 2602)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Army Reserve.

(Sec. 2603)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Navy Reserve and Marine Corps Reserve.

(Sec. 2604)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Air National Guard.

(Sec. 2605)The bill authorizes specified construction and land acquisition projects for the Air Force Reserve.

(Sec. 2606)The bill authorizes appropriations for acquisition, architectural and engineering services, and construction of facilities for the National Guard and Reserve at the levels identified in section 4601.

Subtitle B--Other Matters

(Sec. 2611)The bill modifies the authorization for construction of a Reserve Training Center Complex at Dam Neck, Virginia.

(Sec. 2612)The bill extends the authorizations for additions and alterations to the National Guard Readiness Center at Fort Belvoir, Virginia.

(Sec. 2613)The bill extends the authorizations for a specified FY2019 project.

TITLE XXVII--BASE REALIGNMENT AND CLOSURE ACTIVITIES

(Sec. 2701)The bill authorizes appropriations for ongoing Base Realignment and Closure (BRAC) activities at the levels identified in section 4601.

(Sec. 2702)The bill authorizes DOD to realign or close certain military installations.

(Sec. 2703)The bill specifies that nothing in this bill authorizes an additional BRAC round.

TITLE XXVIII--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION GENERAL PROVISIONS

Subtitle A--Military Construction Program and Military Family Housing

(Sec. 2801)The bill modifies each military department's contracting authority for the acquisition, construction, or furnishing of test facilities and equipment.

(Sec. 2802)The bill modifies the conditions on leases for non-excess property of the military departments and defense agencies.

(Sec. 2803)The bill revises reporting requirements when carrying out a construction project, land acquisition, or defense road project.

(Sec. 2804)The bill increases from $300,000 to $1 million the threshold for contracts regarding architectural and engineering services and construction design.

(Sec. 2805)DOD must modify and update DOD Form 1391 to require certain disclosures for any major or minor construction project that need congressional notification or approval.

(Sec. 2806)DOD and each military department must include a project spending plan for any military construction project over $90 million.

(Sec. 2807)The bill amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 to extend the limitation on the use of operation and maintenance funds for certain construction projects outside the United States.

(Sec. 2808)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to authorize DOD to obtain architectural and engineering services for certain projects.

(Sec. 2809)The bill eliminates the limitation for the Navy to carry out any construction activity on the Replace Andersen Housing Phase II project in Guam.

(Sec. 2810)The bill authorizes each military department to carry out military construction projects to enhance force protection and safety on military installations.

(Sec. 2811)The bill limits the availability of funds for the acquisition of furnished energy for the new Rhine Ordnance Barracks Army Medical Center until DOD submits specified certifications.

Subtitle B--Real Property and Facilities Administration

(Sec. 2821)DOD must develop a force structure plan for each military department and a model of infrastructure capabilities necessary to support the force structure.

(Sec. 2822)The bill provides an exemption from certain property disposal requirements for excess or underutilized non-mobile property of DOD.

(Sec. 2823)Each military department must carry out a program to retrofit or replace existing windows in military family housing units to install fall prevention devices.

(Sec. 2824)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to modify the prohibition on the use of certain assessments of public schools on DOD installations.

(Sec. 2825)The bill requires each military department to conduct a study of the feasibility of entering into 20-year intergovernmental support agreements for installation support services.

(Sec. 2826)The GSA must notify the senior mission commander of an installation prior to representing it in negotiations with carriers and public utilities.

(Sec. 2827)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that state-owned National Guard installations qualify as military installations.

Subtitle C--Land Conveyances

(Sec. 2841)The Air Force may convey to the Tucson Airport Authority specified acres of real property on Air Force Plant 44, Arizona, located adjacent to the airport.

(Sec. 2842)The Navy may transfer specified parcels of real property at the Marine Corps Air Ground Combat Center Twentynine Palms, California, to the Department of the Interior (DOI). DOI may transfer specified parcels of real property at the Marine Corps Air Station, Yuma, Arizona, to the Navy

(Sec. 2843)The Navy must take steps to restore the Mare Island Firing Range in Vallejo, California.

(Sec. 2844)The Navy may convey specified parcels of real property to the Regents of the University of California.

(Sec. 2845)The Navy may convey parcels of real property and accept parcels at the Southeast Federal Center in the vicinity of the Washington Navy Yard in the District of Columbia.

(Sec. 2846)The Air Force may convey specified parcels of real property to the Air Force Enlisted Village.

(Sec. 2847)The Navy must maintain and update regularly an inventory of all land parcels located on Guam which meet certain conditions.

(Sec. 2848)The bill amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1996 to modify the conditions on the land conveyance of the Joliet Army Ammunition Plant in Illinois.

(Sec. 2849)The Navy may convey the Naval Academy dairy farm located in Gambrills, Maryland, to Anne Arundel County, Maryland.

(Sec. 2850)The bill amends the Military Construction Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2014 to revise the description of the Limestone Hills Training Area Land Withdrawal and Reservation in Montana.

(Sec. 2851)The Department of Agriculture must convey specified parcels of real property to the Utah State University Research Foundation.

(Sec. 2852)The Army must name the newly constructed gate located at the intersection of Hobson Drive and Southgate Road Freedman's Village Gate.

Subtitle D--Other Matters

(Sec. 2861)DOD may provide grants, conclude cooperative agreements, and supplement funds to state and local governments to address deficiencies in community infrastructure supportive of a military installation.

(Sec. 2862)DOD must develop and implement a comprehensive strategic plan to identify and address deficits in its capabilities to execute the NDS.

(Sec. 2863)The bill limits the use of funds for the development of public infrastructure in the Northern Mariana Islands.

(Sec. 2864)The United States Transportation Command must conduct a study of the feasibility and desirability of including the George P. Coleman Memorial Bridge on the York River, Virginia, and United States Route 17 in the Strategic Highway Network.

(Sec. 2865)The bill authorizes the use of funds to repair or mitigate the risks posed to highways by recurrent flooding and sea level fluctuation.

(Sec. 2866)DOD may transfer up to 50% of the shared costs of constructing the Indian River Bridge.

(Sec. 2867)The Navy must plan to allow increased public access to the National Naval Aviation Museum and Barrancas National Cemetery at Naval Air Station Pensacola.

TITLE XXIX--OVERSEAS CONTINGENCY OPERATIONS MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 2901)The bill authorizes specified OCO construction and land acquisition projects for the Army.

(Sec. 2902)The bill authorizes specified OCO construction and land acquisition projects for the Navy.

(Sec. 2903)The bill authorizes specified OCO construction and land acquisition projects for the Air Force.

(Sec. 2904)The bill authorizes specified OCO construction and land acquisition projects for the defense agencies.

(Sec. 2905)The bill authorizes appropriations for OCO military construction at the levels identified in section 4602.

(Sec. 2906)The bill prohibits the use of funds for planning and design costs of any project associated with the European Deterrence Initiative until DOD submits to Congress a list of all the military constructions projects associated with the initiative that DOD anticipates will be carried out during each of fiscal years 2019 through 2023.

DIVISION C--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY AUTHORIZATIONS AND OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

TITLE XXXI--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY PROGRAMS

Subtitle A--National Security Programs and Authorizations

(Sec. 3101)The bill authorizes appropriations to DOE for the NNSA at the levels identified in section 4701 of this bill. The bill also authorizes new plant projects for the NNSA at specified locations.

(Sec. 3102)The bill authorizes appropriations to DOE for Defense Environmental Cleanup activities at the levels identified in section 4701 of this bill.

(Sec. 3103)The bill authorizes appropriations to DOE for other defense activities in carrying out programs as specified in section 4701 of this bill.

(Sec. 3104)The bill authorizes appropriations to DOE for nuclear energy as specified in section 4701 of this bill.

Subtitle B--Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations

(Sec. 3111)The NNSA may carry out the engineering development phase, and any subsequent phase, to modify or develop a low-yield nuclear warhead for submarine-launched ballistic missiles.

(Sec. 3112)The bill modifies authority for the DOE counterintelligence polygraph program.

(Sec. 3113)The bill amends the National Nuclear Security Administration Act to modify the duties of the Director for Cost Estimating and Program Evaluation.

(Sec. 3114)The bill amends the Ronald W. Reagan National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2005 to modify the authority of DOE to accept, retain, and use contributions for removal or security of fissile materials, radiological materials, and related equipment at vulnerable sites worldwide.

(Sec. 3115)The bill sets forth notification requirements for DOE regarding air release of radioactive or hazardous material.

(Sec. 3116)The bill modifies the prohibition on delegation of authority relating to special nuclear material. The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2016 to modify reporting requirements for DOE regarding transfers of nuclear technology to foreign countries.

(Sec. 3117)The bill extends the authority for DOE to carry out enhanced procurement to manage supply chain risk.

(Sec. 3118)The bill extends the authority of the Office of River Protection in DOE.

(Sec. 3119)DOE must carry out construction and project support activities relating to the Mixed Oxide (MOX) fuel fabrication facility located in Aiken, South Carolina.

(Sec. 3120)DOD must seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct an assessment of the plutonium strategy of the NNSA.

(Sec. 3121)DOE must establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of conducting background reviews for access by certain individuals to national security laboratories.

(Sec. 3122)The bill prohibits the use of funds to provide assistance to Russia.

(Sec. 3123)The bill prohibits the use of funds to plan or carry out research and development of an advanced naval nuclear fuel system based on low-enriched uranium.

(Sec. 3124)The bill limits the availability of funds relating to the submission of annual reports on unfunded priorities.

Subtitle C--Plans and Reports

(Sec. 3131)The NNSA must provide to Congress a cost-benefit analysis for competition of management and operating contracts.

(Sec. 3132)DOE must seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences for an independent assessment of nuclear forensic analyses.

(Sec. 3133)DOE must enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a review of the defense environmental cleanup activities of the Office of Environmental Management.

(Sec. 3134)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that DOE should protect whistleblowers and take action against contractors and subcontractors that retaliate against whistleblowers.

(Sec. 3135)The NNSA must report on the implementation of the 2018 Nuclear Posture Review.

(Sec. 3136)The NNSA must submit to Congress a report that includes a detailed proposal for a survey of the workforce of the national security laboratories and nuclear weapons production facilities.

(Sec. 3137)The bill eliminates certain reporting requirements.

Subtitle D--Other Matters

(Sec. 3141)The NNSA must ensure that the goal of the Cesium Irradiator Program and the Off-Site Source Recovery Program is to eliminate the use of blood irradiation devices in the United States that rely on cesium chloride.

(Sec. 3142)The bill expresses the sense of Congress that the U.S. government should appropriately compensate and recognize individuals who were exposed to radiation through uranium mining and nuclear testing during the Cold War.

TITLE XXXII--DEFENSE NUCLEAR FACILITIES SAFETY BOARD

(Sec. 3201)The bill authorizes appropriations for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.

TITLE XXXIV--NAVAL PETROLEUM RESERVES

(Sec. 3401)The bill authorizes appropriations for the operation and maintenance of the Naval Petroleum Reserves.

TITLE XXXV--MARITIME MATTERS

Subtitle A--Maritime Administration

(Sec. 3501)The bill authorizes appropriations for (1)national security aspects of the Merchant Marine, (2)the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy, (3)U.S. Maritime Administration (MARAD)operations and programs, (4)the National Security Multi-Mission Vessel Program, (5)the federal ship financing loan guarantee program, (6)state maritime academies, (7)the National Defense Reserve Fleet, and (8)the small shipyards program.

(Sec. 3502)DOD must make modifications to Ready Reserve Fleet vessels to comply with the requirements for lifeboats and fire suppression.

(Sec. 3503)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to prohibit the use of MARAD funds to procure a used vessel.

(Sec. 3504)The bill provides permanent authority for DOT to issue vessel war risk insurance.

(Sec. 3505)MARAD must implement a program of training vessel sharing, requiring maritime academies to share training vessels among maritime academies.

(Sec. 3506)The bill authorizes DOT to establish concurrent jurisdiction with New York over lands constituting the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy in King's Point, New York.

(Sec. 3507)The bill revises the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.

(Sec. 3508)MARAD must report on its progress in implementing recommendations on closing gaps in the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy's Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Program.

(Sec. 3509)MARAD must report on the impediments to the application of the Uniform Code of Military Justice at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy.

(Sec. 3510)The Coast Guard must ensure that electronic records on mariner availability may be used by DOT to meet national security sealift needs.

(Sec. 3511)MARAD must post a Notice of Funding Opportunity regarding grants for small shipyards.

(Sec. 3512)The bill sets forth requirements for vessel operations in the Maritime Security Program and the U.S. Navy's Military Sealift Command.

(Sec. 3513)The GAO must report on the key challenges to ensuring that the U.S. marine transportation system and merchant marine are sufficient to support United States economic and defense needs.

(Sec. 3514)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to allow multi-year or block contracting for the procurement of up to six new vessels.

(Sec. 3515)The bill amends the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to make revisions regarding noncommercial vessels and passenger records.

(Sec. 3516)DOT must initiate an audit of the financial controls and protections included in its policies for approving loan applications for the loan guarantee program.

Subtitle B--Coast Guard

(Sec. 3521)The Coast Guard must notify Congress if there is not a general order or regulation prohibiting sexual harassment by its members that clearly states a violation is punishable in accordance with the Uniform Code of Military Justice.

(Sec. 3522)The bill modifies requirements for the Coast Guard to ensure that developmental tests and evaluations and operational tests and evaluations of a capability or asset and the subsystems of the capability or asset are met.

(Sec. 3523)The bill sets forth requirements for terminating a procurement or acquisition contract.

(Sec. 3524)The bill requires that certain beneficiaries be reimbursed for reasonable travel expenses.

(Sec. 3525)The bill revises requirements for the Coast Guard capital investment plan.

(Sec. 3526)The Coast Guard must brief Congress regarding a current assessment of the risks associated with all current major acquisition programs.

(Sec. 3527)The Coast Guard must report on the status of implementation for certain marine safety actions.

(Sec. 3528)The bill requires a Vice Commandment who is not reappointed or appointed Commandant to be retired with the grade of admiral.

(Sec. 3529)The Coast Guard must issue large recreational vessel regulations.

Subtitle C--Coast Guard and Shipping Technical Corrections

Chapter 1--Coast Guard

(Sec. 3531)The bill defines Commandant as Commandant of the Coast Guard.

(Sec. 3532)The bill sets forth training requirements for certain Coast Guard flag officers and Coast Guard Senior Executive Service employees.

(Sec. 3533)The bill makes technical revisions to U.S. Code provisions related to the Coast Guard.

(Sec. 3534)The bill requires the Coast Guard to maintain a memorandum of understanding with the Navy for technical assistance.

(Sec. 3535)The bill eliminates guidance on excessive pass-through charges related to the Deepwater acquisition program.

(Sec. 3536)The bill revises requirements for the Coast Guard to submit to Congress an integrated major acquisition mission need statement.

(Sec. 3537)The bill revises requirements for Coast Guard officers to continue serving on active duty.

(Sec. 3538)The bill revises the requirements for prior authorization of appropriations.

(Sec. 3539)The bill requires the Coast Guard to maintain an inventory of real property.

Chapter 2--Maritime Transportation

(Sec. 3541)The bill defines Commandant as Commandant of the Coast Guard.

(Sec. 3542)The Coast Guard may maintain different structural fire protection, manning, operating, and equipment requirements for vessels.

(Sec. 3543)The bill revises passenger vessel security and safety requirements and crime scene preservation training requirements for crew members.

(Sec. 3544)The bill modifies tank vessel construction standards.

(Sec. 3545)The bill revises grounds for denial of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner's document due to dangerous drugs.

(Sec. 3546)The bill makes technical revisions to several U.S. Code provisions related to the Coast Guard.

(Sec. 3547)The bill amends the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 to make certain technical revisions.

(Sec. 3548)The bill authorizes the Coast Guard to issue regulations regarding the anchorage and movement of vessels during a national emergency.

DIVISION D--FUNDING TABLES

(Sec. 4001)The bill provides for the allocation of funds among programs, projects, and activities in accordance with the tables in division D, subject to reprogramming requirements.

TITLE XLI--PROCUREMENT

(Sec. 4101)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for procurement.

(Sec. 4102)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for procurement for OCO.

TITLE XLII--RESEARCH, DEVELOPMENT, TEST, AND EVALUATION

(Sec. 4201)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for research, development, test, and evaluation.

(Sec. 4202)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for research, development, test, and evaluation for OCO.

TITLE XLIII--OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE

(Sec. 4301)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for operation and maintenance.

(Sec. 4302)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for operation and maintenance for OCO.

TITLE XLIV--MILITARY PERSONNEL

(Sec. 4401)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for military personnel.

(Sec. 4402)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for military personnel for OCO.

TITLE XLV--OTHER AUTHORIZATIONS

(Sec. 4501)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for the Working Capital Fund.

(Sec. 4502)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for the Working Capital Fund for OCO.

TITLE XLVI--MILITARY CONSTRUCTION

(Sec. 4601)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for military construction.

(Sec. 4602)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for military construction for OCO.

TITLE XLVII--DEPARTMENT OF ENERGY NATIONAL SECURITY PROGRAMS

(Sec. 4701)The bill sets forth amounts requested and authorized for DOE national security programs.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-676,Part 2</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-863</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-676</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-874</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
