<bill session="119" type="h" number="514" updated="2025-11-18T23:14:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a competitive bidding process for the relocation of the headquarters of Executive agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2025-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="22" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-19T21:45:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Strategic Withdrawal of Agencies for Meaningful Placement Act or the SWAMP Act

This bill prohibits new construction, major renovation, leasing, or renewing a lease of certain executive agency headquarters in the District of Columbia metropolitan area and establishes a competitive bidding process for the relocation of such headquarters.

The General Services Administration (GSA) must (1) establish a process to allow an executive agency to request the GSA to issue a solicitation for the relocation of its headquarters or allow the GSA to issue such a solicitation without a request, if necessary; (2) allow any state or political subdivision of a state to respond to a solicitation with a proposal for the relocation of the agency's headquarters; and (3) in consultation with the executive agency, select a state or political subdivision of a state for the relocation of the agency's headquarters using a competitive bidding procedure based on certain considerations.</summary>
</bill>
