<bill session="118" type="s" number="295" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Countering Economic Coercion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Economic Coercion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to grant certain authorities to the President to combat economic coercion by foreign adversaries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1135" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-03T16:55:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Countering Economic Coercion Act of 2023

This bill authorizes the President to take certain actions to assist foreign trading partners affected by economic coercion and penalize foreign adversaries. Economic coercion refers to actions, practices, or threats undertaken by a foreign adversary to unreasonably restrain, obstruct, or manipulate trade, foreign aid, investment, or commerce with the intent to cause economic harm to achieve strategic political objectives or influence sovereign political actions.

Specifically, the bill authorizes the President (upon a determination that a foreign trading partner is subject to economic coercion) to exercise specified authorities to support or assist the foreign trading partner. These authorities include, among others, decreasing duties or modifying tariff-rate quotas on imports from the foreign trading partner, requesting appropriations for foreign aid, and expediting export licensing decisions and regulatory processes.

Further, the bill authorizes the President to exercise specified authorities to penalize a foreign adversary engaged in economic coercion. The authorities include increasing duties and modifying tariff-rate quotas.

The bill outlines consultation and notification requirements. It also provides a process for an expedited determination regarding economic coercion.

Any determination of economic coercion must be revoked at the earliest of (1) two years from the date of determination, (2) upon a joint resolution of disapproval, or (3) when the President revokes the determination.

The bill also directs the President to endeavor to coordinate with other foreign trading partners to broaden economic support for the foreign trading partner and condemn the actions of the foreign adversary.</summary>
</bill>
