<bill session="108" type="s" number="2313" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restore Elector Confidence in Our Representative Democracy Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require a voter-verified permanent record or hardcopy under title III of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RECORD Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Elector Confidence in Our Representative Democracy Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2004-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000725" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2004-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2004-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2004-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2004-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-08">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4051-4052"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
    <term name="Voting machines"/>
    <term name="Voting of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-21T21:32:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restore Elector Confidence in Our Representative Democracy Act of 2004 or the RECORD Act of 2004 - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require each voting system used in an election for Federal office to: (1) produce an individual voter-verifiable paper record of the vote that shall be made available for inspection and verification by the voter at the time the vote is cast; and (2) provide the voter with an opportunity to correct any error made by the system in the voter-verifiable paper record before the permanent voter-verified paper record is preserved.

Requires the permanent voter verified paper record to be preserved within the polling place for later use in any manual audit. Makes such paper record the official record used for any recount.

Requires the voting system accessible for individuals with disabilities, including nonvisual accessibility for the blind and visually impaired, to meet the requirements of this Act by using a mechanism that separates the function of vote generation from the function of vote casting without requiring the voter to view or handle paper.

Requires each State to ensure that election officials are instructed on the right of any individual who requires assistance to vote by reason of blindness, other disability, or inability to read or write to be given assistance by a person chosen by that individual under the Voting Rights Act of 1965.

Prohibits any voting system from: (1) containing or using any software that does not disclose any source code, object code, and executable representation; or (2) using any wireless communication device.

Requires any electronic voting system to: (1) use only software and hardware certified by laboratories accredited by the Election Assistance Commission (EAC); and (2) meet specified security standards.

Requires each State and jurisdiction to: (1) meet the requirements of this Act in time for the November 2004 Federal general election; or (2) use a paper ballot voting system in such election.

Directs the EAC, beginning with the November 2004 Federal general election, and immediately following the election, to conduct random unannounced manual mandatory recounts of the voter-verified records in two percent of the jurisdictions in each State and with respect to two percent of the ballots cast by uniformed and overseas voters.

Directs the EAC to study, test, and develop best practices to enhance accessibility and voter-verification mechanisms for individuals with disabilities.

Requires the EAC to make certain payments to assist States in paying for implementation of the voter-verification and audit capacity requirements of this Act.

Requires the EAC to report to Congress on: (1) a proposed security review and certification process for all voting systems used in Federal elections; and (2) operational and management systems applicable to such elections.

Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to provide security consultation services to States and local jurisdictions on the administration of Federal elections.</summary>
</bill>
