<bill session="116" type="s" number="5010" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Servicemembers and Veterans Initiative Act of 2020.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemembers and Veterans Initiative Act of 2020.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Servicemembers and Veterans Initiative within the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2020-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8354" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4915" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-13T17:57:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Servicemembers and Veterans Initiative Act of 2020

This bill establishes the Servicemembers and Veterans Initiative within the Civil Rights Division of the Department of Justice (DOJ).

The initiative shall

 serve as legal and policy advisor on DOJ's efforts to enforce criminal and civil laws that impact service members, veterans, and their families; develop policy recommendations for improved enforcement of federal law to support service members, veterans, and their families; serve as the liaison and point of contact between DOJ and the military departments; provide counsel for the Office of Justice Programs to ensure that funding decisions take into account service members, veterans, and their families; serve as a liaison and point of contact with the Consumer Protection Branch of DOJ's Civil Division with respect to the prosecution of federal crimes involving fraud that target service members; and serve as a liaison and point of contact with other DOJ components as needed to support the enforcement of other federal laws that protect service members and veterans.</summary>
</bill>
