<bill session="117" type="h" number="5690" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to follow certain procedures in placing a child who has been removed from the custody of his or her parents.</title>
    <title type="display">Samier Amer Foster Care Improvement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Samier Amer Foster Care Improvement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2022-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Worker and Family Support.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM03" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Work and Welfare" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-08T16:11:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Samier Amer Foster Care Improvement Act of 2021 

This bill revises notification requirements that are triggered when states decide to remove a child from the custody of the child's parent(s) and to place the child in another home.

Specifically, states must provide notice of the decision to each relative who expressed an interest in caring for the child, the guardian of the child, the guardian ad litem for the child, the attorney for the child, the attorney for each parent of the child, the child (if the child is able to express an opinion regarding placement), and the prosecutor involved. The notice must be provided within 90 days after the state makes a placement decision.

States must establish procedures to (1) allow an individual&#160;who receives such a notice to request documentation of the reasons for the decision involved, (2) allow the attorney for the child to petition the court involved to review the decision, and (3) require the court to commence a review after receiving a petition.</summary>
</bill>
