<bill session="108" type="h" number="3110" updated="2023-01-15T06:48:04Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To specify locations where certain citizens and nationals of Mexico may be removed from the United States into Mexico.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To specify locations where certain citizens and nationals of Mexico may be removed from the United States into Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000617"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-30T20:15:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to specify the following locations where certain citizens and nationals of Mexico may be removed from the United States: (1) in the case of an alien who arrives by land from Mexico (whether or not at a designated port of entry), such removal shall be at the port of entry on the United States border with Mexico that is closest to the location where such alien was first inspected by an immigration officer; (2) in the case of an alien who is removed by land to Mexico upon release from imprisonment for a criminal offense, such removal shall be at the port of entry on the United States border with Mexico that is closest to the facility where such alien last was imprisoned for such offense; and (3) in the case of an alien who is removed by land to Mexico upon acquittal of a criminal charge, such removal shall be at the port of entry on the United States border with Mexico that is closest to the courthouse where such acquittal occurs.</summary>
</bill>
