<bill session="119" type="s" number="666" updated="2025-08-06T19:32:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Responders Wellness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responders Wellness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase access to mental health, substance use, and counseling services for first responders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2025-02-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-06T19:31:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">First Responders Wellness Act

This bill establishes a national mental health hotline for first responders and provides mental health services for emergency response providers responding to major disasters.

The bill requires the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA) to establish a mental health hotline staffed with specialists trained to provide first responders and their families with peer support, mental and behavioral health and substance use disorder assistance, and referral services. SAMHSA must raise awareness about the hotline and develop guidance regarding first responders for personnel operating the 988 Suicide and Crisis Lifeline. SAMHSA must report to Congress annually on the hotline.

Also, the bill expands the Crisis Counseling Assistance and Training Program, which provides mental health services to victims of major disasters, so that emergency response providers responding to major disasters may also receive these services.

Additionally, the bill requires&#160;SAMHSA to publish a report with recommendations for establishing a mobile health care delivery site to provide crisis services to emergency response providers responding to a major disaster.</summary>
</bill>
