<bill session="111" type="s" number="3176" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:11Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Justice Global Advisory Committee Authorization Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to further the mission of the Global Justice Information Sharing Initiative Advisory Committee by continuing its development of policy recommendations and technical solutions on information sharing and interoperability, and enhancing its pursuit of benefits and cost savings for local, State, tribal, and Federal justice agencies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Justice Global Advisory Committee Authorization Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2010-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2010-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2120"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2120-2121" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4970" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-22T18:42:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Justice Global Advisory Committee Authorization Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Attorney General to provide technical and financial assistance and support to the Global Justice Information Sharing Initiative Advisory Committee. Expands the activities of the Committee to include the gathering of views from federal, state, local, and tribal law enforcement and other agencies that work to support public safety and justice and to provide recommendations for improving the administration of justice and the protection of the public through information sharing.

Expresses the sense of Congress that state, local, and tribal governments and other relevant entities should use the recommendations developed by the Committee to evaluate, improve, and develop effective strategies and technologies to improve public safety and information sharing.

Directs the Attorney General to review the state of information sharing between corrections and law enforcement agencies and report recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
