<bill session="117" type="h" number="4477" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the expedited review of applications of aliens applying for admission to the United States under section 101(a)(15)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act who are coming to the United States to participate in a program under which they will receive graduate medical education or training, require the Secretary of State to provide relevant Foreign Service officers with training regarding such aliens, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">GRAD Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GRAD Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Grant Residency for Additional Doctors Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2021-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2021-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E765"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-15T19:54:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Grant Residency for Additional Doctors Act of 2021 or the GRAD Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of State to take certain actions to expedite the processing of visas for aliens entering the United States for graduate medical education or training.

Specifically, the State Department shall designate an officer or employee whose sole responsibility from March through June (and in any other time period as necessary) is to facilitate the expedited review of visa applications for such aliens.

The State Department shall also provide relevant Foreign Service officers with training related to medical graduates and medical graduate programs in the countries where the officers are serving.</summary>
</bill>
