<bill session="118" type="s" number="824" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Risk Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National Risk Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Risk Management Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a national risk management cycle, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with amendments. With written report No. 118-20.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="59">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 59.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5439" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-16T13:25:09Z" status="Reported to Senate">National Risk Management Act of 2023

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a recurring process to identify and assess risks to critical infrastructure and requires the President to deliver to Congress a national critical infrastructure resilience strategy designed to address the risks identified.

The process shall include elements to

 collect relevant information from Sector Risk Management Agencies relating to the threats, vulnerabilities, and consequences related to the particular sectors of such agencies; allow critical infrastructure owners and operators to submit relevant information to DHS for consideration; and outline how DHS will solicit input from other federal departments and agencies. DHS must brief the Senate and House homeland security committees on

 the national risk management cycle activities undertaken pursuant to the strategy, and the amounts and timeline for funding that DHS has determined would be necessary to address risks and successfully execute the full range of activities proposed by the strategy.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-20</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
