<bill session="111" type="h" number="2493" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:11Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Judgment Evading Foreign States Accountability Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent wealthy and middle-income foreign states that do business, issue securities, or borrow money in the United States, and then fail to satisfy United States court judgments totaling $100,000,000 or more based on such activities, from inflicting further economic injuries in the United States, from undermining the integrity of United States courts, and from discouraging responsible lending to poor and developing nations by undermining the secondary and primary markets for sovereign debt.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judgment Evading Foreign States Accountability Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001234" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001060" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000453" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2009-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2009-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000676" joined="2010-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000057" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000370" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001171" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001174" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001161" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001178" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000169" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2009-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000030" joined="2009-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2010-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2009-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2010-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-19">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="5564" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-18T20:11:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Judgment Evading Foreign States Accountability Act of 2009 - States the policy of the United States regarding: (1) advocacy within the governing bodies of international organizations and other foreign policy settings for the full compensation and fair treatment of persons in whose favor judgments have been awarded by U.S. courts; (2) protection of economic interests of persons and nations that benefit from a reliable flow of foreign capital by restricting the access to U.S. capital markets of judgment evading foreign states (foreign states that fail to fully satisfy a final judgment exceeding a certain amount for more than two years) and their state-owned corporations, warning of the dangers of dealing financially with such states and state-owned corporations, and congressional scrutiny of requests for aid made by such states; and (3) protection of the authority of the U.S. courts by preventing such states from willfully flouting the judgments of those courts.

Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to: (1) deny a judgment evading foreign state access to U.S. capital markets unless the proceeds of borrowing or securities issuance are to be used in the first instance to satisfy in full all final judgments that form the basis for such designation as such a state; and (2) require all periodic filings made by such a state with the SEC to prominently bear a warning describing its failure to satisfy outstanding judgments. Imposes similar restrictions on state-owned corporations of such states.

Requires: (1) a proposal to extend bilateral or multilateral assistance to a judgment evading state to bear notice that such state is a judgment evading state; and (2) the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to Congress identifying each such state.</summary>
</bill>
