<bill session="117" type="h" number="9585" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Property Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose a tax on foreign-owned under-utilized residential real property.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Property Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000020"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9438" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-09T17:35:23Z" status="Introduced in House">American Property Act 

This bill imposes an excise tax on foreign persons who own any specified under-utilized residential real property for more than one-half of any taxable year. The amount of such tax is 1% of the estimated value of such property.

The bill defines specified under-utilized residential real property as any specified residential property located in the United States that is occupied as a dwelling unit for less than 180 days during the taxable year. Specified residential property means a single-family home or structure consisting of four residential units or less, or a part of a building that is a semi-detached house, rowhouse unit, residential condominium unit or other similar premises that is, or is intended to be, a separate parcel or other division of real property, and includes any land that was conveyed with such home, structure, or building.</summary>
</bill>
