<bill session="110" type="h" number="884" updated="2023-01-11T20:00:41Z">
  <state datetime="2007-02-27T19:19:20-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-02-27T19:19:20-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the establishment of the Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PACTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">PACTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Promoting Antiterrorism Cooperation through Technology and Science Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PACTS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Antiterrorism Cooperation through Technology and Science Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000210"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000606" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000603" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000604" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000480" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001151" joined="2007-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000578" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2007-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2007-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2007-02-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emerging Threats, Cybersecurity, and Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T15:05:10-05:00">
      <text>Mr. King (NY) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T15:06:37-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1909-1914" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T15:06:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 884.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T15:26:25-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T19:11:24-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1932-1933" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="105" datetime="2007-02-27T19:19:20-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 396 - 16 (Roll no. 105).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1909-1910" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-02-27T19:19:20-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="105" datetime="2007-02-27T19:19:20-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 396 - 16 (Roll no. 105).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1909-1910" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2007-02-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-03">
      <text>Provisions of measure incorporated into Title XIX of H.R. 1, P.L. 110-53.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Africa (Sub-Saharan)"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animal diseases"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Singapore"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-03-22T22:22:19Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Promoting Antiterrorism Cooperation through Technology and Science Act, or PACTS Act - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish the Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office (the Office).

Provides for the Office to be headed by a Director, who: (1) shall be selected by and shall report to the Under Secretary; and (2) may be an officer of DHS serving in another position.

Requires the Director to: (1) develop, in consultation with the Department of State, understandings or agreements that allow and support international cooperative activity in support of homeland security research, development, and comparative testing; (2) develop, in coordination with the Directorate of Science and Technology, the other components of DHS, and other federal agencies, strategic priorities for such activity; and (3) facilitate the planning, development, and implementation of international cooperative activity to address such priorities.

 Requires the Director to: (1) facilitate the matching of U.S. entities with non-U.S. entities that may partner in homeland security research activities; and (2) ensure that activities are coordinated with those of other relevant research agencies. Permits the Director to run projects jointly with other agencies.

Authorizes the Director to hold international homeland security technology workshops and conferences to improve contact among the international community of technology developers and to help establish direction for future technology goals.

Authorizes the Under Secretary to carry out international cooperative activities to support specified responsibilities of the Under Secretary, including through the award of grants and the entering into of cooperative agreements or contracts. Instructs the Under Secretary to ensure that funding and resources expended in international cooperative activities will be equitably matched by the foreign partner organization through direct funding or funding of complimentary activities, or through the provision of staff, facilities, materials, or equipment.

Permits the Under Secretary to make or accept loans of equipment for research and development and comparative testing purposes.

Authorizes the Under Secretary to conduct international cooperative activities jointly with other agencies.

Specifies that foreign partners may include: (1) Israel; (2) the United Kingdom; (3) Canada; (4) Australia; (5) Singapore; and (6) other allies in the global war on terrorism, as appropriate.

Authorizes the Under Secretary, in coordination with the Chief Medical Officer, as part of the international cooperative activities authorized by this Act, to facilitate the development of information sharing and other types of cooperative mechanisms with foreign countries, including African nations, to strengthen American preparedness against threats to the U.S's agricultural and public health sectors from exotic diseases.

Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of DHS, which shall be derived from amounts otherwise authorized for the Directorate of Science and Technology, for FY2008-FY2011 for activities under this Act.

States that, whenever the Office participates in an international cooperative activity with a foreign country on a cost-sharing basis, any reimbursements or contributions received from that foreign country to meet its share of the project may be credited to appropriate current appropriations accounts of the Directorate of Science and Technology.

Requires the Under Secretary, acting through the Director, to transmit: (1) a specified report to Congress on such international cooperative activities; and (2) updates of such report every five years.</summary>
</bill>
