<bill session="109" type="h" number="2738" updated="2022-02-03T05:26:03Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Railroad Retirement Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="display">Railroad Retirement Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 to provide that a current connection is not lost by an individual who is misled or not properly informed by the Railroad Retirement Board of the requirement for, and the circumstances resulting in the loss of, a current connection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001045"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Railroad Retirement Board"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-17T21:29:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Railroad Retirement Fairness Act - Amends the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 to provide that an individual who, at the time the individual makes an inquiry to the Railroad Retirement Board, has a current connection with the railroad industry shall not be deemed to have lost that current connection thereafter: (1) if the Board misleads or fails to properly inform that individual about that requirement; and (2) if that conduct by the Board, according to the principles of equity, should stop the Board from deeming the individual to have lost that current connection.

(Current law deems an individual to have "a current connection with the railroad industry" at the time an annuity begins to accrue to that individual and at death, provided certain conditions exist.)</summary>
</bill>
