<bill session="108" type="h" number="3926" updated="2023-01-15T10:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-04-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to promote organ donation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000213" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000355" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000031" joined="2004-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2004-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23T14:33:00-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (MI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23T14:33:15-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1335-1339" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23T14:33:55-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3926.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23T14:48:33-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T12:06:03-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1393" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="76" datetime="2004-03-24T12:24:33-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 2 (Roll no. 76).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 3/23/2004 H1335-1336" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-24T12:24:43-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-03-25" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Received in the Senate, considered, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3172" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-04-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-216" type="public" datetime="2004-04-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-216.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="573" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Evaluation research (Social action programs)"/>
    <term name="Eye banks"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical statistics"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Tissue banks"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trauma care"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-20T16:01:25Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.)

Organ Donation and Recovery Improvement Act - (Sec. 3) Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants to States, transplant centers, qualified organ procurement organizations or other public or private entities to reimburse travel, subsistence, and incidental nonmedical expenses incurred by individuals toward making living organ donations.

(Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary to establish a public education program to increase awareness about organ donation and the need to provide for an adequate rate of donations. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) make peer-reviewed grants to, or contracts with, public and nonprofit private entities for studies and demonstration projects to increase organ donation and recovery rates, including living donations; (2) make grants to States for organ donor awareness, public education, and outreach activities and programs designed to increase the number of organ donors within the State; and (3) support the development and dissemination of educational materials to inform health care professionals about organ, tissue, and eye donation issues.

Authorizes the Secretary to award matching grants to qualified organ procurement organizations and hospitals to establish programs coordinating organ donation activities of eligible hospitals and qualified organ procurement organizations. (Defines "eligible hospital" as a hospital that performs significant trauma care, or a hospital or consortium of hospitals that serves a population base of not fewer than 200,000 individuals.) Requires a grantee to: (1) establish joint organ procurement organization and hospital designated leadership responsibility and accountability; (2) develop agreed upon project performance goals; (3) collaboratively design and implement a data collection process to provide ongoing project feedback; and (4) contribute at least 30 percent of the grant amount awarded. Requires the Secretary, within three years, to evaluate the extent to which the programs have increased the rate or organ donation.

 (Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality, to: (1) develop scientific evidence supporting increased organ donation and improved recovery, preservation, and transportation of organs; and (2) support research to develop a uniform clinical vocabulary, to apply information technology to support clinical operations of organ procurement organizations, to enhance the skills of the organ procurement workforce, and to assess organ recovery, preservation, and transportation technologies.

Authorizes appropriations for FY 2005 through 2009.

(Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to report on organ donation and recovery activities.

(Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary to establish and maintain mechanisms to evaluate the long-term effects associated with living organ donations by individuals who have served as living donors.

(Sec. 8) Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on the ethical implications of increasing cadaveric donations.

(Sec. 9) Eliminates certain grant authority with respect to qualified organ procurement organizations.</summary>
</bill>
