<bill session="117" type="s" number="1804" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mothers and Newborns Success Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve maternal health and promote safe motherhood.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mothers and Newborns Success Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2021-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3425" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-07T13:50:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mothers and Newborns Success Act

This bill directs the Health Resources Services Administration (HRSA), the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), and the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to take certain actions to improve, and reduce racial, ethnic, and geographic disparities in, maternal health outcomes.

First, with respect to HRSA, the bill provides statutory authority for grants that support (1) state efforts to reduce disparities in maternal health; and (2) increased access to maternal and obstetrics care in rural areas, including through telehealth. HRSA must also award grants to identify best practices to improve pregnancy and postpartum outcomes.

Second, the bill authorizes the CDC to establish or expand, and provide technical assistance on capturing racial and other demographic data related to, maternal health data collection. It also expands the scope of safe motherhood grants awarded to government health departments to include (1) classifying birthing facilities based on the level of maternal and neonatal care the facilities provide, and (2) improving the validity of pregnancy data on death certificates. In addition, the CDC must award grants for a campaign targeting health care providers and the public to increase awareness of maternal and child health issues.

Lastly, the NIH must establish the National Maternal Health Research Network to support efforts to improve diagnostics and clinical treatments, improve health outcomes, and reduce inequities to reduce maternal mortality and promote maternal health.</summary>
</bill>
