<bill session="111" type="h" number="6054" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 38, United States Code, to increase and to provide for an annual adjustment of the amounts of assistance payable by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for veterans' funeral and burial expenses.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to increase and to provide for an annual adjustment of the amounts of assistance payable by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for veterans' funeral and burial expenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001161"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4045" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-19T15:22:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Increases the authorized allowance for burial and funeral expenses for deceased veterans who: (1) at the time of death were in receipt of veterans' disability compensation or veterans' pension benefits; or (2) were veterans of any war or were discharged or released from active military service for a service-connected disability and for whom there is no next of kin or sufficient resources to cover funeral and burial costs.

Increases the burial plot allowance for veterans who, at the time of death, were receiving hospital or nursing home care in or through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Increases the authorized allowance for burial and funeral expenses for veterans who die as a result of a service-connected disability.

Authorizes the annual adjustment of such allowances by the same percentage increase as adjustments to benefit amounts payable under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act.</summary>
</bill>
