<bill session="117" type="h" number="5080" updated="2023-01-01T20:18:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit a person who fails to meet age and residential requirements from shipping, transporting, possessing, or receiving firearms and ammunition, to increase the penalties for transfer of a firearm to any person who is under indictment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Secure Background Checks Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Background Checks Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2021-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000299" joined="2021-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2021-08-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-03T21:39:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Secure Background Checks Act of 2021

This bill extends federal restrictions on the receipt, possession, shipment, and transportation of firearms and ammunition to two new categories of persons:

 persons who fail to meet the minimum age requirements imposed by federal law and by the law of their resident state; and persons who are out-of-state residents and do not qualify for an exception, such as the temporary loan or rental of a firearm for lawful sporting purposes. Additionally, the bill imposes criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to 10 years, or both&#8212;on an individual who ships, transports, or receives a firearm or ammunition while under indictment for a crime punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year.</summary>
</bill>
