<bill session="108" type="h" number="2500" updated="2023-01-15T16:33:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Migratory Bird Research and Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enable the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to investigate effects of migratory birds on sustained productivity of stocks of fish of common concern in the Great Lakes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Migratory Bird Research and Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001045"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-02T19:50:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Lakes Migratory Bird Research and Management Act - Amends the Great Lakes Fishery Act of 1956 to authorize the Great Lakes Fishery Commission to carry out activities relating to the investigation of migratory bird depredation on commercial and sport fisheries in the Great Lakes. Amends the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to issue permits to cooperating State, Provincial, Tribal, First Nation, and U.S. and Canadian Federal agencies with migratory bird management authority, and signatory to a Memorandum of Understanding with the Great Lakes Fishery Commission, to manage and take migratory birds, for the purpose of control of depredation by such birds on commercial and sport fisheries in the Great Lakes.</summary>
</bill>
