<bill session="116" type="h" number="8245" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">The Dr. Joseph Costa Honoring Essential Americans Risking Their Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Dr. Joseph Costa Honoring Essential Americans Risking Their Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make payments to hospitals in COVID-19 hot spots to provide hero pay to eligible workers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000576"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2020-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001080" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2020-10-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Education and Labor, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-30T20:48:40Z" status="Introduced in House">The Dr. Joseph Costa Honoring Essential Americans Risking Their Safety Act of 2020

This bill establishes a compensation program for, and registry to monitor the health of, certain individuals who worked in hospitals during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency. It also establishes educational benefits for eligible individuals who provided care to residents of long-term care, skilled nursing, post-acute care, and other nursing facilities during the emergency.

With respect to hospital workers, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must provide funds to hospitals in COVID-19 hot spots for supplemental payments for workers who provide direct care, which may include cleaning and other nonmedical activities, to COVID-19 patients during the emergency.

Additionally, the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) must develop a voluntary registry of physicians, nurses, and non-physician health care specialists who worked at a hospital or other care site during the emergency and must monitor the long-term health status of individuals on this registry who test positive for COVID-19. NIOSH must also make the registry available to public health researchers and may award grants to states to facilitate its development.

With respect to the educational benefits, the Department of Education or HHS must repay or cancel a percentage of certain loans for each six-month period an individual works in a qualifying facility, subject to a maximum percentage cap. HHS must also provide eligible individuals with an educational grant, subject to certain conditions, to obtain post-secondary credentials for health care careers in nursing care facilities.</summary>
</bill>
