<bill session="118" type="h" number="3653" updated="2025-11-19T04:22:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">UNITED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Undertaking Negotiations on Investment and Trade for Economic Dynamism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UNITED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide the President with authority to enter into a comprehensive trade agreement with the United Kingdom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000929" joined="2023-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="629" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-19T14:36:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Undertaking Negotiations on Investment and Trade for Economic Dynamism Act or the UNITED Act

This bill grants certain authorities to the President for entering into a comprehensive trade agreement between the United States and the United Kingdom (UK).

Specifically, the bill directs the President to seek to initiate negotiations with the UK regarding tariff and nontariff barriers affecting any industry, product, or service sector.

The bill authorizes the President to enter into a comprehensive trade agreement with the UK, with such authority expiring on March 1, 2025. Further, the President may proclaim a modification or continuance of any existing duty or continuance of existing excise or duty-free treatment to carry out an agreement, with certain limitations.

The bill also requires the President to consult with and notify Congress regarding the intention of the President to enter into an agreement or make a proclamation.</summary>
</bill>
