<bill session="118" type="h" number="4069" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Coasts and Cities from Severe Weather Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Coasts and Cities from Severe Weather Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase observations, understanding, and forecasting of coastal flooding and storm surge events, to address weather observation gaps in highly vulnerable areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000398"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6093" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-27T21:08:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Coasts and Cities from Severe Weather Act&#160;

This bill establishes certain programs and requirements to support weather forecasting with respect to coastal flooding, storm surges, and underserved areas.

Specifically, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) must establish a program that improves coastal flooding and storm surge forecasts, such as improvements to real-time predictions of ocean activity. NOAA must evaluate and incorporate innovative observation methods and emerging technologies into the program. NOAA must also improve weather observation in underserved areas, including by identifying challenges to weather observation in these areas and utilizing advanced technology to make changes.&#160;

In addition, the National Weather Service and the Federal Emergency Management Agency must establish a partnership&#160;to implement pilot projects that support the use of localized weather data in infrastructure and emergency management decisions at the federal, state, and local levels.</summary>
</bill>
