<bill session="110" type="h" number="3873" updated="2023-01-11T20:23:48Z">
  <state datetime="2008-01-23T13:25:37-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-01-23T13:25:37-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expedite the transfer of ownership of rural multifamily housing projects with loans made or insured under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949 so that such projects are rehabilitated and preserved for use for affordable housing.</title>
    <title type="display">Section 515 Rural Housing Property Transfer Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Section 515 Rural Housing Property Transfer Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Section 515 Rural Housing Property Transfer Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Section 515 Rural Housing Property Transfer Improvement Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001234" joined="2007-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2007-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2007-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 110-464.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-12-04" calendar="Union" number="288">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 288.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T13:13:07-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Hodes moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T13:13:23-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H410-412" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T13:13:26-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3873.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2008-01-23T13:25:37-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H410" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23T13:25:39-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3363" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Apartment houses"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-07T14:00:48Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Section 515 Rural Housing Property Transfer Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) implement administrative and procedural changes to expedite the application approval process for transferring ownership of Section 515 rural multifamily housing projects for which a loan is either made or insured for a project's preservation, continued use restriction, and rehabilitation; and (2) actively facilitate such transfers. (A Section 515 project is one involving housing and related facilities for elderly persons and families or other persons and families of low income.)

Grants final regulatory authority over such property transfers to the Office of Rental Housing Preservation of the Rural Housing Service of the Department of Agriculture.

Authorizes such Office, with respect to such transfers, to work with and seek recommendations from the State Rural Development offices of the Department of Agriculture.

Sets forth deadlines for the processing of transfer applications by such Office as well as by state and local offices.

Instructs the Secretary of Agriculture to report to certain congressional committees on: (1) actions taken to coordinate with other federal agencies, including the Department of Housing and Urban Development and the Internal Revenue Service, and, in particular, with the program for rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937, the multifamily mortgage insurance programs under title II of the National Housing Act, and the programs for low-income housing tax credits and for tax-exempt bonds under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; (2) resulting improvements within the Rural Housing Service in expediting the transfer of ownership of projects with loans made or insured under section 515 of the Housing Act of 1949; and (3) recommended legislative changes.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-464</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
