<bill session="108" type="s" number="2218" updated="2023-01-15T11:03:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a rural water supply program in the Reclamation States for the purpose of providing a clean, safe, affordable, and reliable water supply to rural residents and for other purposes, to authorize the Secretary to conduct appraisal and feasibility studies for rural water projects, and to establish the guidelines for any projects authorized under this program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-539.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hydraulic engineering"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-27T14:11:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reclamation Rural Water Supply Act of 2004 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a competitive program to plan, design, and construct rural water supply projects in cooperation with non-Federal project entities in States and areas referred to in the Reclamation Act of 1902. Requires that each rural water supply project be performed in cooperation with a qualifying non-Federal project entity.

Directs the Secretary to develop and publish criteria for determining which projects are eligible for participation, considering factors such as whether a project serves rural areas and communities or Indian tribes, shows economic benefits, and is cost-effective and whether and to what extent the local project sponsors can meet certain cost-share and repayment criteria.

Authorizes the Secretary to undertake: (1) appraisal investigations to identify and study opportunities for construction of projects to determine if they meet the criteria; and (2) studies to determine the feasibility of rural water supply systems recommended for study. Limits the Federal cost share of feasibility studies to 50 percent of total study costs, with an exception.

Declares that non-Federal entities must have the capability to pay all operation, maintenance, and replacement costs of the project facilities.

Directs the Secretary to coordinate with existing Federal and State rural water and wastewater programs to determine the most appropriate agency to undertake recommended projects and to otherwise facilitate the most efficient and effective solution to meeting the water needs of the non-Federal project sponsors.</summary>
</bill>
