<bill session="109" type="h" number="6029" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:21Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize improvements for the security of dams and other facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize improvements for the security of dams and other facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001050" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000962" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000413" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000528" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000574" joined="2006-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="4079" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Seismology"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Water rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-16T15:26:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Reclamation Safety of Dams Act of 1978 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make modifications that are reasonably required to preserve the site security of Bureau of Reclamation dams and related facilities. Provides for specified reimbursement for costs incurred for building and site security activities.

Requires dam safety and site security costs allocated to irrigation, municipal, and industrial water service for the Central Valley Project, California, to be collected by the Secretary exclusively through inclusion of such costs in operation and maintenance rates, capital water rates, or both, not segregated from other project costs for separate allocation or repayment. Directs the Secretary, during site security-related construction, to consider cost containment measures.

 Prohibits the obligation of funds exceeding a specified amount for carrying out actual construction to modify an existing dam, the cause of which results from new hydrologic or seismic data or changes in the state-of-the-art criteria deemed necessary for site security or structural safety purposes, prior to 30 calendar days after the Secretary has transmitted a report on such existing dam to Congress.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) report annually to Congress on building and site measures undertaken (including a summary of expenditures and information relating to a five-year plan for security measures detailed to show pre- and post-September 11, 2001 costs); (2) provide written notice to project beneficiaries upon identifying a Bureau facility for a site security measure; and (3) include in required reports the Secretary's response when a modification is the result of new data deemed necessary for structural safety purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to waive reporting requirements that could adversely impact site security.</summary>
</bill>
