<bill session="108" type="s" number="1981" updated="2023-01-15T09:17:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Constitution Heritage Act of 1988 to provide for the operation of the National Constitution Center.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Constitution Heritage Act of 1988 to provide for the operation of the National Constitution Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civics education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-16T14:57:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Constitution Heritage Act of 1988 to set forth requirements for cooperative agreements between the Secretary of the Interior and the National Constitution Center for the operation of the Center, including a requirement that revenues from the operation of the Center be made available to the Center (without further appropriation) to offset its operating expenses, and requirements that the Center: (1) maintain appropriate risk insurance; (2) maintain its tax-exempt status; and (3) report annually to the Secretary or Congress on its activities, goals and plans. Authorizes the Secretary to terminate a cooperative agreement in the public interest.

Exempts agreements, leases, contracts or other arrangements entered into under this Act from certain requirements for leases of buildings by the Federal Government and for the award of concession contracts in units of the National Park System.</summary>
</bill>
