<bill session="116" type="s" number="4583" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion, intensification, and coordination of the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to Tourette syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2020-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2020-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1131" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-23T14:21:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2020 or the CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2020

This bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to expand, intensify, and coordinate NIH research on Tourette syndrome.

The NIH must (1) develop a system to collect data on Tourette syndrome, including epidemiological information and data on the availability of medical and social services for individuals with Tourette syndrome and their families; (2) support Collaborative Research Centers for Tourette Syndrome to conduct basic and clinical research; (3) award grants for research on Tourette syndrome symptoms and treatment options for particular patient subpopulations; and (4) designate funding to carry out Tourette syndrome programs and activities.</summary>
</bill>
