<bill session="116" type="h" number="7912" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">INPATIENT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing National Patient Access To Improved Effective Necessary Mental Health Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INPATIENT Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a demonstration program and pilot project to expand choice for inpatient psychiatric services under Medicaid and Medicare.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001058"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2020-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-25T18:39:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Increasing National Patient Access To Improved Effective Necessary Mental Health Treatment Act of 2020 or the INPATIENT Act of 2020

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to establish programs that test the impact of expanding the coverage of certain psychiatric services under Medicaid.

Specifically, the CMS must establish a demonstration program to test the impact of waiving the institutions for mental diseases (IMDs) Medicaid payment exclusion on specified metrics relating to inpatient psychiatric hospital services and substance abuse services. (Current law generally prohibits federal payment under Medicaid for services provided in IMDs for individuals under the age of 65, although states may receive payment through certain mechanisms like Medicaid demonstration waivers.)

The CMS must also establish a pilot program to test the impact of eliminating the Medicare 190-day lifetime limit&#160;for inpatient psychiatric hospital services, particularly the impact on value, choice, and the alignment of inpatient mental health benefits with inpatient physical health care benefits under Medicare.</summary>
</bill>
