<bill session="108" type="s" number="2927" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 to clarify the definition of manipulation with respect to currency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 to clarify the definition of manipulation with respect to currency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2004-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2004-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2004-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-01T22:04:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 with respect to bilateral negotiations with countries considered to manipulate the rate of exchange between their currency and the U.S. dollar for purposes of preventing effective balance of payments adjustments or gaining unfair competitive advantage in international trade.

Reduces the preconditions for the initiation of negotiations by the Secretary of the Treasury to possession of significant bilateral trade surpluses with the United States (removing the other current condition of possession of material global current account surpluses).

Declares that a country shall be considered to be manipulating the rate of exchange between its currency and the U.S. dollar if there is a protracted large-scale intervention in one direction in the exchange markets.

Requires the Secretary's annual report to specified congressional committees on international economic policy to include a detailed explanation of the test the Secretary uses to determine whether or not a country is manipulating the rate of exchange.</summary>
</bill>
