<bill session="112" type="s" number="622" updated="2020-02-10T17:03:12Z">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act</title>
    <title type="display">Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000360" joined="2011-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3578" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-04-04T18:19:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to establish the Commission on Effective Regulation and Assessment Systems for Public Schools, composed of certain government officials, educators, and education policy experts.

Requires the Commission to: (1) examine the effect government regulations have on elementary and secondary education; (2) recommend ways to align and improve those regulations to improve performance and innovation in education; and (3) recommend ways to improve and align assessment systems to provide reliable and meaningful information to parents, teachers, and students to improve student achievement, teacher performance, and innovation.</summary>
</bill>
