<bill session="118" type="s" number="1337" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:30Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Increase Reliable Services Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increase Reliable Services Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to temporarily prohibit the hiring of additional Internal Revenue Service employees until a certain level of taxpayer services have improved, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1420-1421" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-08T18:18:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increase Reliable Services Now Act 

This bill imposes limits on Internal Revenue Service (IRS) enforcement activities and hiring.

The bill prohibits the IRS from hiring any person for enforcement activities until the end of a period in which the IRS has maintained for 6 consecutive months a level of access for phone lines of not less than 90%, and an average speed of answering calls in 4 minutes or less. The bill also requires that not less than 90% of regular IRS employees perform work in person at their job sites.

The bill prohibits the IRS from auditing taxpayers with taxable incomes below $400,000 at a greater rate than before the enactment of this bill.

Further, the IRS may not hire additional personnel (other than for return processing activities and call center operations) until its tax return processing backlog is not in excess of 5 million cases and it issues tax refunds within 6 weeks or less after receipt of a tax return.</summary>
</bill>
