<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1539</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:18:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:18:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-07-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-07-29T21:38:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-07-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S8277-8278)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-07-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rockefeller, John D., IV [D-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>JAY</firstName>
        <lastName>ROCKEFELLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000032</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Nelson, Bill [D-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>CLARENCE</firstName>
        <lastName>NELSON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>WILLIAM</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-07-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-09-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Earth sciences</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Environmental Protection</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-12-04T20:58:55Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Greenhouse Gas Observation and Analysis System Act - Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish a greenhouse gas observation and analysis system that will offer the resolution and widespread coverage required to verify reduction and mitigation of greenhouse gases. Requires the system to: (1) be an operational and scientifically robust greenhouse gas observation system that provides quantitative information about sources, sinks, and fluxes of greenhouse gases at relevant temporal and spatial scales; (2) be capable of differentiating between source and sink exchanges, identifying types of emissions, and tracking agricultural and other sinks; and (3) include sustained ground, sea, and air-based measurements, sustained space-based observations, measurements of tracer, carbon cycle monitoring and modeling, traceability to the International System of Units, and data assimilation and analysis.</p> <p>Directs the Administrator to develop and submit to specified congressional committees a plan for an integrated and comprehensive greenhouse gas observation and analysis system, which shall: (1) describe current greenhouse gas observation networks, modeling, and data analysis efforts; (2) contain an inventory of agency data relevant to greenhouse gases; (3) assess gaps, conflicts, and opportunities with respect to such efforts and data; (4) establish priorities, define agency roles, and make recommendations on necessary capacity and capabilities for measurements, monitoring, modeling, analysis, and data management; (5) establish mechanisms for ensuring continuity of greenhouse gas measurements; and (6) contribute to international efforts to build and operate a global greenhouse gas information system.</p> <p>Requires the Administrator to report to Congress every four years on the effectiveness of the system, progress in achieving plan objectives, the consistency of reported greenhouse gas emissions with independent observations, and changes in Earth-system sources and sinks of greenhouse gases.</p> <p></p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Greenhouse Gas Observation and Analysis System Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Greenhouse Gas Observation and Analysis System Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish a comprehensive greenhouse gas observation and analysis system, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Greenhouse Gas Observation and Analysis System Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-07-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-07-29</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S8277-8278)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
