<bill session="116" type="s" number="3429" updated="2022-02-08T23:23:01Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farmer Driven Conservation Outcomes Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmer Driven Conservation Outcomes Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Soil and Water Resources Conservation Act of 1977 with respect to assessments of conservation programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2020-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6182" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-07T14:32:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farmer Driven Conservation Outcomes Act of 2020

This bill modifies the authority of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) with respect to strategic assessment and planning for the conservation, protection, and enhancement of soil, water, and related natural resources.

USDA may establish a conservation effects assessment project to

 quantify the environmental and economic effects of conservation practices, develop the science base for managing the agricultural landscape for environmental quality and sustainable productive capacity, and improve the efficacy of conservation practices and programs by evaluating conservation effects. USDA must establish a goals and assessment process for conservation programs that includes (1) the identification of natural resource and environmental objectives, outcomes, and results for the programs; (2) assessments of the resulting changes in the status and conditions of natural resources and the environment; and (3) a monitoring and evaluation process for the programs and initiatives.

In implementing the monitoring and evaluation process, USDA must use certain funds provided for conservation programs and establish a National Technical Committee.

The bill also sets forth reporting requirements regarding the progress conservation programs have made in achieving the objectives and outcomes.</summary>
</bill>
