<bill session="117" type="s" number="2001" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Meat Inspection Act to exempt from inspection the slaughter of animals and the preparation of carcasses conducted at a custom slaughter facility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PRIME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIME Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Processing Revival and Intrastate Meat Exemption Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2021-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3835" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-01T12:08:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Processing Revival and Intrastate Meat Exemption Act or the PRIME Act 

This bill expands the exemption of custom slaughtering of animals from federal inspection requirements.

Under current law, the exemption applies if the meat is slaughtered for personal, household, guest, and employee uses. The bill expands the exemption to include meat that is

 slaughtered and prepared at a custom slaughter facility in accordance with the laws of the state where the facility is located; and prepared exclusively for distribution to household consumers in the state or restaurants, hotels, boarding houses, grocery stores, or other establishments in the state that either prepare meals served directly to consumers or offer meat and food products for sale directly to consumers in the state. The bill does not preempt any state law concerning (1) the slaughter of animals or the preparation of carcasses, parts thereof, meat and meat food products at a custom slaughter facility; or (2) the sale of meat or meat food products.</summary>
</bill>
