<bill session="118" type="s" number="181" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Vaccine Passports Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Vaccine Passports Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect individual liberty, ensure privacy, and prohibit discrimination with respect to the vaccination status of individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="118" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="167" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-14T14:06:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Vaccine Passports Act

This bill restricts collection and disclosure of an individual's vaccination status, including for COVID-19 vaccinations. It also makes it unlawful to discriminate based on COVID-19 vaccination status and to mandate vaccination in certain circumstances.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the use of federal funds to establish or collaborate with federal, state, private, or international systems that track or monitor an individual's COVID-19 vaccination status. Additionally, federal agencies must destroy existing records that contain information about an individual's COVID-19 vaccination status within 30 days. Furthermore, agencies may not issue vaccine passports or similar standardized documentation of COVID-19 vaccination status.

The bill also prohibits discrimination based on COVID-19 vaccination status or willingness to provide documentation of vaccination status in employment, public accommodations, and certain public programs and services. Remedies and enforcement mechanisms available under federal civil rights laws apply to violations under this bill.

In addition, federal privacy standards for health information must prohibit the disclosure of non-anonymized information about the status of any vaccination without a patient's express consent. Moreover, the bill makes anyone who requests an individual's vaccination status subject to these standards.

The bill temporarily bans (1) mandates for vaccines authorized for use under emergency procedures, and (2) administration of those vaccines to minors or individuals who lack capacity to consent to vaccinations without the consent of their parent or guardian. It also prohibits public disclosure of an individual's COVID-19 vaccination status without express, written consent. Violations of these prohibitions are subject to criminal and civil penalties.</summary>
</bill>
