<bill session="111" type="s" number="543" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:47Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran and Servicemember Caregiver Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Veteran and Servicemember Caregiver Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a pilot program on training, certification, and support for family caregivers of seriously disabled veterans and members of the Armed Forces to provide caregiver services to such veterans and members, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2009-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001266" joined="2009-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2009-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000373" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2009-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2009-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2866-2867"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2867-2869" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-23T19:42:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veteran and Servicemember Caregiver Support Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a two-year pilot program of training, certification, and support for eligible family caregivers of eligible veterans and members of the Armed Forces.

Defines as: (1) eligible family caregivers those family members who agree to provide such services, are accepted by the veteran or member as the provider, and are determined qualified to provide such services; and (2) eligible veterans and members those veterans and members who have a service-connected disability incurred or aggravated on or after September 11, 2001, and require caregiver services because of such disability.

Requires: (1) the pilot program to be conducted at at least six medical facilities; (2) at least one facility to be a private facility with expertise in providing rehabilitative care; (3) at least one facility to be a Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical center in a rural area; and (4) the Secretary, in selecting locations, to give special emphasis to VA polytrauma centers designated as Tier I polytrauma centers.

Directs the Secretary to provide training to each eligible family caregiver under the program, and to certify the caregiver as qualified upon training completion. Requires caregivers to be paid for providing such services.

Requires: (1) a review of VA and Department of Defense (DOD) respite care programs, as well as a study on enhancing the availability of such programs; (2) the provision of psychological and social support services to caregivers; and (3) a national survey of family caregivers of seriously disabled veterans and members.</summary>
</bill>
