<bill session="117" type="s" number="5321" updated="2023-08-22T23:30:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DIGITAL Reservations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deploying the Internet by Guaranteeing Indian Tribes Autonomy over Licensing on Reservations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DIGITAL Reservations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve Indian Tribes' and Native Hawaiian organizations' autonomy of access to spectrum over Tribal lands and expedite immediate deployment of telecommunications services for critical government services, including national emergencies, natural disasters, public health and bio-hazard threats, safety, education, opportunity to participate in the broadband economy, self-governance, access to Federal, State, and Tribal voting and elections, and the Federal census count, for the protection of life and property in furtherance of the Federal trust responsibility, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-22T23:20:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deploying the Internet by Guaranteeing Indian Tribes Autonomy over Licensing on Reservations Act or the DIGITAL Reservations Act

This bill grants Indian tribes and Native Hawaiian organizations exclusive rights to all available or unlicensed electromagnetic spectrum over their tribal lands and prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from taking specified actions related to spectrum licenses over tribal lands. It also requires the FCC to establish a fund to support tribal access to broadband and telecommunications services.</summary>
</bill>
