<bill session="116" type="h" number="8585" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Right to Family Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Right to Family Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 240A of the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for cancellation of removal and temporary resident status for certain parents of citizens of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2020-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-02T15:06:47Z" status="Introduced in House">American Right to Family Act

This bill requires the cancellation of removal and adjustment of status for an alien parent who meets certain requirements.

To be eligible for cancellation of removal and adjustment of status under this bill, an alien must (1) meet certain residency-related requirements, such as having been physically present in the United States for at least 10 years or having received a deferral of removal under the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals policy; (2) be a parent of either a U.S. national or an individual who first entered the United States under 16 years of age and has been continuously present in the United States since entry; and (3) not be barred from receiving certain immigration benefits on specified grounds, including certain grounds related to criminal conduct or national security.

The Department of Homeland Security may waive certain crime-related grounds of inadmissibility for reasons related to the public interest, subject to various limitations.

An alien whose removal is canceled under this bill shall be adjusted to temporary resident status for a three-year period, which may be renewed. Furthermore, a cancellation for removal or adjustment of status under this bill shall not count toward certain annual numerical limitations on such actions.</summary>
</bill>
