<bill session="118" type="h" number="2801" updated="2025-01-16T11:48:07Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Kids PRIVACY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kids PRIVACY Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Information of our Vulnerable Adolescents, Children, and Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 to update and expand the coverage of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000148" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2023-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2024-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000375" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000617" joined="2023-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2023-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001226" joined="2023-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2023-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2024-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000040" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2023-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-29T16:57:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting the Information of our Vulnerable Adolescents, Children, and Youth Act or the Kids PRIVACY Act 

This bill expands the requirements for digital services when handling the personal information of children. The bill establishes requirements for digital services directed to children and digital services likely to be accessed by children or teenagers.

Specifically, the bill requires children's digital services to obtain express, affirmative consent that is specific, informed, and unambiguous before processing certain personal information of a child or teenager under the age of 18. The bill also prohibits the operator of a children's service from using information in a harmful manner or in a way that has been shown to be detrimental to the well-being of children and teenagers. Teenagers or the parents of children are allowed to access, correct, or delete personal information.

A service likely to be used by children or teenagers is prohibited from using information for the purpose of targeted advertisements or marketing to a specific child or teenager (or group of children or teenagers) based on specified information or behavior. Regulations promulgated under the bill must require an operator to consider the best interests of children and teenagers when designing a service likely to be used by children or teenagers.

The bill increases the civil penalty for violations of children's online privacy protections and provides for enforcement by the Federal Trade Commission and a private right of action.</summary>
</bill>
