<bill session="112" type="h" number="1174" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:18Z">
  <state datetime="2011-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet Gambling Regulation, Consumer Protection, and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to provide for the licensing of Internet gambling activities by the Secretary of the Treasury, to provide for consumer protections on the Internet, to enforce the tax code, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internet Gambling Regulation, Consumer Protection, and Enforcement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000022" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2011-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001232" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2011-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000169" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2011-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2011-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2011-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2011-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2011-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on the Judiciary, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2366" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-05-12T14:15:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Internet Gambling Regulation, Consumer Protection, and Enforcement Act - Grants the Secretary of the Treasury regulatory and enforcement jurisdiction over the Internet Gambling Licensing Program established by this Act.

Prescribes administrative and licensing requirements for Internet betting, including background check requirements and suitability standards for license applicants. Prohibits any person from operating an Internet gambling facility that knowingly accepts bets or wagers from persons located in the United States without a license issued by the Secretary.

 Prescribes safeguards to: (1) ensure the legal age of any wagering individual as well as a permissible location for placing the wager; (2) combat fraud, money laundering, and terrorist finance; and (3) combat compulsive Internet gambling.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) compile and make available to the public, on the Secretary's website, datasets on player behavior; (2) assess civil penalties on licensees or other persons for willful violations of this Act; (3) monitor, evaluate, and measure compliance effectiveness of software and other mechanisms used by licensees to prevent minors from Internet wagering and impose a fine for ineffective protections; and (4) place court-ordered child support delinquents on the self-exclusion list (established by this Act) as long as they remain delinquent in their support obligations.

Requires the Secretary and any qualified state or tribal regulatory body to prescribe regulations for: (1) development of a Problem Gambling, Responsible Gambling, Consumer Safeguards, and Self-Exclusion Program; (2) a list of persons self-excluded from gambling activities at licensee sites; and (3) a program to alert the public to the existence, consequences, and availability of the self-exclusion list.

Prohibits a person who is prohibited from gambling with a licensee, including anyone on the self-exclusion list, from collecting any winnings or recovering any losses that arise as a result of prohibited gambling activity. 

Shields a financial transaction provider from liability for engaging in financial activities and transactions on behalf of a licensee, or involving a licensee, including payments processing activities, unless the provider has knowledge that the specific financial activities or transactions are conducted in violation of federal or state law.

Requires the Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network to submit to the Secretary a list of unlawful Internet gambling enterprises which violate this Act for distribution in electronic format to all persons required to comply with regulations under this Act.

Permits states and Indian tribal authorities to opt-out of Internet gambling activities within their respective jurisdictions. Prohibits licensees from engaging in the operation of an Internet gambling facility that knowingly accepts bets or wagers initiated by persons who reside in any opt-out state or the tribal lands of any opt-out Indian tribe.

Prohibits: (1) sports betting on the Internet, except pari-mutuel racing, and the use of credit cards for Internet gambling; and (2) electronic cheating devices.

 Directs the Secretary to: (1) report to Congress on the licensing and regulation of Internet gambling operators, and (2) conduct a feasibility study on safeguards to address gambling while impaired.</summary>
</bill>
