<bill session="116" type="h" number="3218" updated="2022-11-01T07:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Diamond and Silk Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain Federal funds from being made available to sanctuary jurisdictions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diamond and Silk Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Sanctuaries and Help Our American Homeless and Veterans Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000362"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2019-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2019-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2020-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001088" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2019-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2019-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000065" joined="2019-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="9064" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-01T13:48:01Z" status="Introduced in House">End Sanctuaries and Help Our American Homeless and Veterans Act or the Diamond and Silk Act

This bill imposes penalties on any state or local jurisdiction that has an ordinance, policy, or practice that prohibits or restricts federal, state, or local government entities, officials, or other personnel from enforcing or assisting with enforcing immigration laws.

Such a jurisdiction shall be barred from receiving any federal financial assistance, and certain funds that would have gone to the jurisdiction shall be reallocated to programs to reduce homelessness and address mental illness.

A victim (or certain family members if the victim is deceased) of any felony for which an alien was convicted and sentenced to at least one year in prison may sue a state or local jurisdiction if (1) the jurisdiction knew the alien was unlawfully present in the United States and released the alien prior to the crime's commission, or (2) the crime was a consequence of the jurisdiction refusing to honor a detainer or warrant issued for an alien believed to be unlawfully present and in violation of controlled substances laws. A prevailing plaintiff shall be entitled to reasonable attorney's fees and costs.

A jurisdiction that receives federal financial assistance shall waive sovereign immunity against such lawsuits.</summary>
</bill>
