<bill session="119" type="h" number="919" updated="2025-03-08T06:28:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-04T14:29:31-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-04T14:29:31-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chronic Disease Flexible Coverage Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Chronic Disease Flexible Coverage Act</title>
    <title type="short">Chronic Disease Flexible Coverage Act</title>
    <title type="display">Chronic Disease Flexible Coverage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To codify Internal Revenue Service guidance relating to treatment of certain services and items for chronic conditions as meeting the preventive care deductible safe harbor for purposes of high deductible health plans in connection with health savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001260"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2025-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04T14:16:35-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MO) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04T14:16:49-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H964-966" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04T14:16:51-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 919.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-03-04T14:29:31-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H964" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04T14:29:33-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-07T14:03:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Chronic Disease Flexible Coverage Act

This bill provides statutory authority for guidance from the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) that expands the types of preventive care that may be offered under a high deductible health plan (HDHP) without requiring a deductible&#160;or with a deductible below the minimum threshold.

Under current law, to be considered health savings account-eligible, an HDHP must have a deductible above a certain minimum threshold amount, which is adjusted annually. However, an HDHP may cover certain types of preventive care without requiring a deductible or with a deductible below the minimum threshold.&#160;

The IRS issued guidance expanding the types of preventive care that may be covered by an HDHP without requiring a deductible or with a deductible below the minimum threshold to include

angiotensin converting enzyme inhibitors for individuals with congestive heart failure, diabetes, or coronary artery disease;anti-resorptive therapy for individuals with osteoporosis or&#160;osteopenia;beta-blockers for individuals with congestive heart failure or coronary artery disease;blood pressure monitors for individuals with hypertension;inhaled&#160;corticosteroids and peak flow meters for individuals with asthma;insulin and other glucose lowering agents, retinopathy screening,&#160;glucometers, and hemoglobin A1c testing for individuals with diabetes;international normalized ratio testing for individuals with liver disease or bleeding disorders;low-density lipoprotein testing for individuals with heart disease;statins for individuals with heart disease or diabetes; andselective&#160;serotonin reuptake inhibitors for individuals with depression.&#160;The bill provides statutory authority for the IRS's guidance.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
