<bill session="117" type="s" number="4613" updated="2023-08-31T11:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maximize Americans' Retirement Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maximize Americans' Retirement Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to clarify the fiduciary duty of plan administrators to select and maintain investments based solely on pecuniary factors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2022-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2022-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2022-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-31T11:01:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maximize Americans' Retirement Security Act

This bill revises the fiduciary duties for a retirement or employee benefit plan that is regulated under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974.

The bill generally requires a fiduciary to select and maintain investments for a plan based solely on pecuniary factors. Under the bill, a pecuniary factor is a factor that is expected to have a material effect on the risk or return of an investment based on appropriate investment horizons that are consistent with the plan's investment objectives and funding policy.

A fiduciary may only use nonpecuniary factors if the fiduciary is unable to distinguish between investment alternatives on the basis of pecuniary factors alone. In such a case, the fiduciary must provide specified documentation to the plan's participants and beneficiaries, including an explanation of how the chosen nonpecuniary factors are consistent with their interests.</summary>
</bill>
