<bill session="118" type="hr" number="922" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-12T14:09:30-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-12T14:09:30-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1147) to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow schools that participate in the school lunch program under such Act to serve whole milk; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 357) to require the head of an agency to issue and sign any rule issued by that agency, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1147) to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow schools that participate in the school lunch program under such Act to serve whole milk; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 357) to require the head of an agency to issue and sign any rule issued by that agency, and for other purposes; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000470"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-11">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-308, by Mrs. Fischbach.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-11T20:11:22-05:00">
      <text>The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 1147 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and H.R. 357 under a closed rule with one hour of general debate. The resolution provides for a motion to recommit on both measures. It also provides that on any legislative day of the second session of the 118th Congress before January 9, 2024, the Speaker may dispense with organizational and legislative business and that the Journal of the proceedings of the previous day shall be considered as approved if applicable.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-11" calendar="House" number="53">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 53.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T12:19:24-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6828-6832" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T12:22:54-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 922.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T12:50:32-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 922, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Scanlon demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T13:31:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6832-6833" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T14:03:30-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 205 (Roll no. 710).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6832-6833" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="711" datetime="2023-12-12T14:09:30-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 215 - 207 (Roll no. 711).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6828-6829" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12T14:09:32-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1147" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="357" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-21T22:07:22Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (H.R. 1147) to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to allow schools that participate in the school lunch program under such act to serve whole milk.

 It further provides for consideration of the bill (H.R. 357) to require the head of an agency to issue and sign any rule issued by that agency.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-308</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
