<bill session="118" type="s" number="4708" updated="2025-11-18T19:29:39Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Child Exploitation Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Child Exploitation Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Strengthening Child Exploitation Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to modify provisions relating to kidnapping, sexual abuse, and illicit sexual conduct with respect to minors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2024-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6734-6735" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6734-6735" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-11-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-22T13:04:01-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-22T13:16:45-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="9047" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3306"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-08-22T19:17:33Z" status="Passed Senate">Strengthening Child Exploitation Enforcement Act

This bill makes changes to federal criminal laws related to various offenses, particularly sexual abuse offenses against minors.

The bill revises the federal kidnapping statute by specifying that obtaining a victim by defrauding or deceiving a third party constitutes the offense of kidnapping.&#160;Additionally, for a kidnapping offense that involves a victim who has not attained the age of 16, the bill specifies that it is not a defense that the victim consented to the conduct of the offender, unless the offender establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the offender reasonably believed that the victim had attained the age of 16.

The bill also revises statutes related to sexual abuse offenses against minors to specify the following:

that crossing international lines with the intent to engage in a sexual act with a child who has not attained the age of 12 constitutes aggravated sexual abuse (currently, the statute only references crossing state lines),that the offense of sexual abuse of a minor also includes knowingly causing the intentional touching of any person by a person who has not attained the age of 16, andthat attempting to commit abusive sexual contact is also a crime that is subject to the same penalty as the completed offense.</summary>
</bill>
