<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="626" updated="2022-02-03T04:56:49Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4614" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-06-25T12:54:54-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-06-25"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following: \   SEC.__. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to deny requests for the public release of documents or evidence obtained through or in the Western Energy Markets: Enron Investigation (Docket No. PA02-2), the California Refund case (Docket No. EL00-95), the Anomalous Bidding Investigation (Docket No. IN03-10), or the Physical Withholding Investigation.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to add a new section at the end of the bill providing that none of the funds in the bill may be used to deny requests for the public release of documents or evidence obtained through or in the Western Energy Markets: Enron Investigation (Docket No. PA02-2), the California Refund case (Docket No. EL00-95), the Anomalous Bidding Investigation (Docket No. IN03-10), or the Physical Withholding Investigation.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-06-25T12:54:54-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Eshoo amendment (A004) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T12:12:28-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Ms. Eshoo.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5111-5116" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5111" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T12:12:28-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A004) offered by Ms. Eshoo.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5111-5116" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5111" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T12:54:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25T12:54:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Eshoo amendment (A004) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
