<bill session="117" type="s" number="2558" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide incentives for livestock processing facilities.</title>
    <title type="display">FAIR Meat Packing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAIR Meat Packing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feed America by Incentivizing Rural Meat Packing Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4854" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-21T20:54:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Feed America by Incentivizing Rural Meat Packing Act or the FAIR Meat Packing Act

This bill allows an investment tax credit through 2026 for 25% of the basis of each livestock processing facility property placed in service during the taxable year. The amount of the credit may not exceed $250,000 in any taxable year and is not available to taxpayers whose gross receipts exceed $100 million in a taxable year.

The bill defines livestock processing facility as a facility that slaughters livestock (i.e., cattle, sheep, goats, bison, swine, and poultry) for processing into meat and meat products and participates in a meat and poultry inspection program, The facility must employ an average of fewer than 500 employees and include property used for the intake or storage of livestock, the disposal or management of livestock waste, or the packaging, handling, warehousing, or storage of meat products.

The bill also allows a refundable income tax credit for the startup and organizational expenditures of livestock processing facilities.</summary>
</bill>
