<bill session="109" type="s" number="4032" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:01Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Iran Nuclear Nonproliferation Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to discourage international assistance to the nuclear program of Iran and transfers to Iran of advanced conventional weapons and missiles.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Nuclear Nonproliferation Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000439" joined="2006-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2006-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2006-11-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control verification"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fuels"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Reactor fuel reprocessing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-30T20:42:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Iran Nuclear Nonproliferation Act of 2006 - States that it should be U.S. policy to neither negotiate nor seek to bring into force an agreement for cooperation with the government of any country that is assisting Iran's nuclear program or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran unless the President has made specified determinations under this Act.

States that no agreement for cooperation between the United States and the government of any country that is assisting Iran's nuclear program or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran may be submitted to the President or to Congress pursuant to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954, no such agreement may enter into force with such country, no export license may be issued to such country for any nuclear material, facilities, components, or other goods, services, or technology that would be subject to such agreement, and no approval may be given for the transfer or retransfer to such country of any nuclear material, facilities, components, or other goods, services, or technology that would be subject to such agreement, until the President determines and reports to the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations and the House Committee on International Relations that: (1) Iran has suspended all enrichment-related and reprocessing-related activity, has committed to verifiably refrain permanently from such activity, and is abiding by that commitment; or (2) the government of the country that is assisting Iran's nuclear program or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran has suspended all nuclear assistance to Iran and all transfers of advanced conventional weapons and missiles to Iran, and is committed to maintaining that suspension until Iran has implemented measures that would permit the President to make such determination.</summary>
</bill>
