<bill session="118" type="h" number="986" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COLLABORATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COLLABORATE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coordinating Our Local Liaisons And Bringing Out Related Agency Technical Expertise Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to enter into an agreement to coordinate government contracting assistance offered by small business development centers and APEX Accelerators, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000614"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2023-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-08-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-05T19:36:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Coordinating Our Local Liaisons And Bringing Out Related Agency Technical Expertise Act or the COLLABORATE Act

This bill requires the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition &amp; Sustainment and the Small Business Administration to enter an interagency agreement to coordinate the government contracting assistance provided by small business development centers and APEX Accelerators.

Small business development centers provide business advising and technical assistance to existing small businesses and pre-venture entrepreneurs. The APEX Accelerators program provides education and training to support the capacity for businesses to participate in federal, state, and local government contracts.</summary>
</bill>
