<bill session="111" type="s" number="849" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:12Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study on black carbon emissions.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study on black carbon emissions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2009-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2009-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2009-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Boxer without amendment. With written report No. 111-58.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-07-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="125">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 125.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-26T19:49:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to conduct a study of black carbon emissions, which shall include the following elements:

 Phase I will establish for the scientific community standard definitions of the terms "black carbon" and "organic carbon." Phase II will summarize the available scientific and technical information concerning an identification of the major sources of black carbon emissions in the United States and throughout the world, an estimate of the quantity of current and projected emissions and the net climate effects of the emissions from those sources, the most effective control strategies for additional domestic and international reductions in black carbon emissions, and the health benefits associated with additional reductions. Phase III will summarize the amount, type, and direction of all actual and potential financial, technical, and related assistance provided by the United States to foreign countries to reduce, mitigate, or otherwise abate black carbon emissions and any health, environmental, and economic impacts associated with those emissions and to identify opportunities to achieve significant black carbon emission reductions in foreign countries through the provision of technical assistance or other approaches. Phase IV will provide recommendations regarding areas of focus for additional research for cost-effective technologies, operations, and strategies with the highest potential to reduce black carbon emissions and protect public health and regarding government actions to encourage or require additional black carbon emission reduction. Sets forth reporting deadlines for each phase.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 111-58</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
