<bill session="108" type="h" number="4812" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:16Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stem Cell Discovery Through Diversity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the National Institutes of Health to conduct and support research using human embryonic stem cells, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stem Cell Discovery Through Diversity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000275"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2004-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2004-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2004-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Cytology"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Genetic research"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human embryology"/>
    <term name="Informed consent (Medical law)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Reagan Administration"/>
    <term name="Reproduction"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-20T14:44:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Stem Cell Discovery Through Diversity Act - Requires the Director of the National Institutes of Health (NIH), acting through the national research institutes, to conduct and support research that uses human embryonic stem cells in accordance with the final guidelines issued by NIH and published in the Federal Register on August 25, 2000, including: (1) the requirements that stem cells used in research be derived from human embryos that were created in vitro for fertility treatments and were in excess of the clinical needs of the individual seeking such treatment and that such individuals voluntarily donated such embryos with informed consent; and (2) the prohibition against the use of Federal funds to derive such cells from the embryos. Provides that restrictions on such research established by the Department of Health and Human Services pursuant to policies announced by the President on August 9, 2001, have no legal effect after enactment of this Act. Prohibits additional Federal administrative policies on such research from being established or applied.

Requires the Director to ensure that such research program include a significant number of donations from individuals who are members of racial or ethnic minority groups in order to make progress toward the goal of developing an understanding of whether the variables studied in clinical research affect such groups differently.

Requires the Director to establish the Ronald Reagan Office of Human Stem Cell Research to coordinate all research conducted or supported by NIH that used human pluripotent stem cells.</summary>
</bill>
