<bill session="109" type="h" number="3556" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:31Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Housing Affordability for Teachers and Public Officers Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out pilot programs to insure low-downpayment mortgages to enable teachers and public safety officers to purchase homes in the jurisdictions they serve and to assist Federal, State, and local public safety officers purchasing homes in locally-designated at-risk areas.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Affordability for Teachers and Public Officers Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001035"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School personnel"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Settlement costs"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-07T18:08:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing Affordability for Teachers and Public Safety Officers Act of 2005 - Amends the National Housing Act to provide for one percent downpayments (and deferral and reduction of up-front payments) for Federal Housing Administration (FHA) mortgage loans for qualified elementary and secondary school teachers, teacher assistants, and administrators and public safety officers (as defined by the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968) to purchase homes within the jurisdictions of their employing agencies. Authorizes program suspension for fraud or program integrity issues. Limits aggregate mortgages insured under such program to 50,000.

Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a mortgage assistance pilot program to assist federal, state, and local public safety officers purchase primary residences in locally-designated at-risk areas. Authorizes program suspension for fraud or program integrity issues. Prohibits application approvals after the expiration of the three-year period beginning on the date that the Secretary first makes program assistance available.</summary>
</bill>
