<bill session="116" type="s" number="3533" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize and establish minimum standards for electronic and remote notarizations that occur in or affect interstate commerce, to require any Federal court located in a State to recognize notarizations performed by a notary public commissioned by another State when the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce, and to require any State to recognize notarizations performed by a notary public commissioned by another State when the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce or when the notarization was performed under or relates to a public act, record, or judicial proceeding of the State in which the notary public was commissioned.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2020-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2020-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6364" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T19:59:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2020

This bill allows a notary public commissioned under state law to remotely notarize electronic records and requires recognition of notarizations performed under the laws of other states.

Under the bill, a notary public may remotely notarize electronic records occurring in or affecting interstate commerce if (1) the individual and the notary public are able to electronically communicate by sight and sound simultaneously (i.e., by video chat); (2) the notary verifies the individual's identity and records the notarization; and (3) the notarization complies with other requirements, such as those relating to the attachment of a stamp or seal to the electronic record.

Additionally, the bill allows a notary public to remotely notarize electronic records involving an individual located outside of the United States, subject to certain requirements.

The bill also requires U.S. courts and states to recognize notarizations, including remote notarizations of electronic records, that occur in or affect interstate commerce and are performed by a notary public commissioned under the laws of other states.</summary>
</bill>
