<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="299" updated="2022-02-03T05:36:15Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2745" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-06-16T19:07:51-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-06-16"/>
  <description>In section 402(1) (relating to reform of United Nations peacekeeping operations), add at the end the following new subparagraph: \   (E) GRATIS MILITARY PERSONNEL.--The General Assembly should lift restrictions on the utilization at the headquarters in New York, the United States, of the Department of Peacekeeping Operations of gratis military personnel by the Department so that the Department may accept secondments from Member States of military personnel with expertise in mission planning, logistics, and other operational specialties.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in subpart B of Part 1 of House Report 109-132 to add the lifting of restrictions on the secondment of military personnel to serve at the Department of Peacekeeping Operations headquarters in New York to the list of reforms which the United States should pursue. It is not linked to a certification requirement and withholding of assistance.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-06-16T19:07:51-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Boozman amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T18:56:18-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Boozman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4634-4636" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4634-4635" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T18:56:18-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Boozman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4634-4636" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4634-4635" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T19:07:51-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Boozman amendment (A006) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16T19:07:51-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-16">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
