<bill session="108" type="hc" number="133" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:24Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the concern of Congress over Russian and Syrian actions in support of Iraq.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the concern of Congress over Russian and Syrian actions in support of Iraq.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000090"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Officer personnel"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-08T20:10:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Condemns: (1) the Syrian Government's actions in transferring military equipment to the terrorist government of Iraq at a time when coalition forces are fighting to liberate the Iraqi people, and demands that such transfers cease immediately; (2) Syria's policy of allowing terrorists to cross its border to fight for the regime of Saddam Hussein; and (3) the failure of the Russian Federation to intercede and prevent Russian private entities from engaging in the sale of lethal military weapons and other military goods to the terrorist government of Iraq.

Demands that Syria and all other states bordering Iraq prevent the crossing into Iraq of Iraqi or non-Iraqi individuals or groups who intend to fight in support of the regime of Saddam Hussein and the emigration from Iraq of Iraqi soldiers or officials affiliated with such regime. Declares that any state that continues to assist the Saddam Hussein regime will be seen by the U.S. people as opposing the vital interests of the United States and that there should be the most severe consequences for the future relations between the United States and such state.</summary>
</bill>
