<bill session="117" type="s" number="2588" updated="2023-01-01T20:17:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to study the extent to which individuals are more at risk of maternal mortality or severe maternal morbidity as a result of being a victim of intimate partner violence, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Protect Moms From Domestic Violence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Moms From Domestic Violence Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2021-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4916" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-26T17:35:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Moms From Domestic Violence Act

This bill establishes a grant program and requires studies to address adverse maternal health outcomes among victims of intimate partner violence, human trafficking, forced marriage, and similar harms.

Specifically, the Health Resources and Services Administration must award grants to state, tribal, or local governments, maternal care providers, institutions of higher education, and community organizations for improving maternal and child health outcomes for victims of such harms.

In addition, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must study the relative risk of maternal mortality and severe maternal morbidity for victims of such harms. HHS must also contract with the National Academy of Medicine (or a similar entity) to conduct another study examining whether these harms increase the risk of suicide and substance use among pregnant and postpartum persons and other maternal health topics.

The bill also requires HHS to disseminate guidance on developing protocols and creating partnerships to address intimate partner violence and similar harms.</summary>
</bill>
