<bill session="117" type="s" number="1714" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:09Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HAVANA Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Central Intelligence Agency Act of 1949 to authorize the provision of payment to personnel of the Central Intelligence Agency who incur qualifying injuries to the brain, to authorize the provision of payment to personnel of the Department of State who incur similar injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HAVANA Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping American Victims Afflicted by Neurological Attacks Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2021-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001197" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2021-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2784" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1828" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3356" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-25T18:15:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping American Victims Afflicted by Neurological Attacks Act of 2021 or the HAVANA Act of 2021

This bill specifically authorizes the Central Intelligence Agency, the Department of State, and other agencies to provide payments to agency personnel who incur brain injuries from hostilities while on assignment.

Specifically, the bill allows agency personnel and their families to receive payments for brain injuries that are incurred (1) during a period of assignment to a foreign duty station; (2) in connection with war, insurgency, hostile acts, terrorist activity, or other agency-designated incidents; and (3) not as the result of willful misconduct.

The bill's authority applies to injuries incurred before, on, or after the date of the bill's enactment. Agencies must submit classified reports on the bill's implementation, including the number of payments made and the amount of each payment.

Since 2016, some intelligence, diplomatic, and other governmental personnel have reported experiencing unusual cognitive and neurological impairments while on assignment (particularly abroad), the source of which is currently under investigation. Symptoms were first reported by personnel stationed in Cuba and have since been collectively referred to as Havana Syndrome.</summary>
</bill>
