<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1128</number>
    <updateDate>2020-02-10T17:06:56Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2020-02-10T17:06:56Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-26T22:39:56Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>2006</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-06-03</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Menendez, Robert [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <firstName>Robert</firstName>
        <lastName>Menendez</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Child health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hereditary and development disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Neurological disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-08-02T20:28:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative in the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to improve the lives of individuals with autism spectrum disorders through research focused on prevention, treatment, services, and cures. Requires the Secretary to: (1) act as the primary federal official with responsibility for overseeing all NIH research on autism spectrum disorders; (2) review and approve or reject the autism spectrum disorder research strategic plan developed by the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee and be responsible for implementation of any approved plan; (3) receive directly from the President and the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) all funds available for autism spectrum disorder activities of NIH; (4) allocate such funds in accordance with the strategic plan; (5) allocate amounts within 30 days after receipt, to the extent practicable; (6) plan and evaluate NIH research and other activities related to autism spectrum disorders; (7) maintain communications with all relevant federal departments to ensure the timely transmission of information concerning autism spectrum disorders; and (8) carry out this Act in consultations with the heads of NIH agencies and their advisory councils, and the Interagency Autism Coordinating Committee. Authorizes the Secretary to reallocate up to 3% of funds allocated for NIH autism spectrum disorder activities as needs change and opportunities arise. </p> <p>Expands authorized research for centers of excellence for autism spectrum disorders to include translational research. Requires the Director of NIH to provide for a program under which biomaterials for induced pluripotent stem cells and biosamples relevant to environmental exposures that are of use in research on autism spectrum disorders are donated, collected, preserved, and made available for such research. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Autism Spectrum Disorders Initiative Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to establish a National Autism Spectrum Disorder Initiative and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1128is/xml/BILLS-112s1128is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
