<bill session="117" type="s" number="4773" updated="2023-01-21T05:15:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FISH Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fighting Foreign Illegal Seafood Harvests Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FISH Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to combat illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing at its sources globally.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2022-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-18T18:47:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fighting Foreign Illegal Seafood Harvests Act of 2022 or the FISH Act of 2022 

This bill addresses illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing (IUU fishing).

For example, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration must establish, publish, and put vessels on a U.S. black list that denies port privileges, certain travel through, delivery of supplies, delivery of services, or transshipment in the exclusive economic zone for vessels that have conducted IUU fishing and vessels that have the same owner as a vessel on the black list.

The President shall impose sanctions with respect to each foreign person that the President determines is the beneficial owner of a vessel on the black list.

Further, the U.S. Coast Guard must (1) increase its observation and boarding of vessels on the high seas that are suspected of IUU fishing, and (2) coordinate with regional fisheries management organizations to determine what corrective measures each nation has taken after its vessels have been boarded for suspected IUU fishing.</summary>
</bill>
