<bill session="119" type="h" number="1906" updated="2025-05-09T14:43:35Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Wellness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Wellness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the prioritization of projects that provide behavioral and mental health treatment services in selecting grantees under certain rural development programs, and extend the substance abuse disorder set-aside and priority under the programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001315"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000490" joined="2025-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-09T14:27:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Wellness Act

This bill prioritizes behavioral and mental health treatment services under certain rural development grant and loan programs.&#160;The bill also reauthorizes through FY2029 the set-asides and prioritizations for substance use disorder treatment services under&#160;the Department of Agriculture's (1) Community Facilities Direct Loan and Grant&#160;Program, (2) Rural Health and Safety Education Competitive Grants Program, and (3) Distance Learning and Telemedicine Grant Program.

Under the community facilities program, the bill prioritizes direct loans and grants for the development of behavioral and mental health services facilities, including facilities that provide treatment services. Further, loans and grants provided under the program may be used to develop facilities and systems&#160;to provide telehealth services for behavioral and mental health treatment.

Under the&#160;Rural Health and Safety Education Competitive Grants Program, the bill prioritizes grants for behavioral and mental health education and treatment.

Under the Distance Learning and Telemedicine Grants Program, the bill includes a 17% set-aside for telemedicine&#160;projects that provide substance use disorder treatment services (currently a 20% set-aside).&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
