<bill session="119" type="h" number="1750" updated="2025-09-03T08:05:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEARD Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Equity and Rare Disease Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEARD Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for greater investments in research on rare diseases and conditions disproportionately affecting minority populations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2025-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2025-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T20:15:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Equity and Rare Disease Act of 2025 or the HEARD Act of 2025

This bill establishes Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) grants and other initiatives to address rare diseases or conditions (e.g., those affecting less than 200,000 people in the United States) in racial and ethnic minority populations.&#160;

For example, to advance such purposes, the bill establishes within&#160;HHS

grants to public and private nonprofit entities for data collection and public outreach,grants to health professions schools to improve health care and minority representation in research regarding rare diseases and conditions,grants to tribal epidemiology centers and tribal and urban Indian health centers for research regarding rare diseases and conditions in tribal communities,scholarships and educational loan repayment for medical school students who agree to work as health care professionals serving populations with rare diseases or conditions,initiatives to coordinate research and other activities across the National Institutes of Health, andpublic health awareness and education campaigns.Also, the bill requires&#160;HHS to submit various reports to Congress on topics including (1) the federal government&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s research and public health activities regarding rare diseases or conditions in minority populations, (2) regulatory barriers to treating rare diseases in Medicare beneficiaries of color, and (3) strategies for research and development of treatments for rare diseases or conditions that disproportionately impact minority populations.</summary>
</bill>
