<bill session="116" type="h" number="6796" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nuclear Energy for the Future Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish and support advanced nuclear research and development programs and infrastructure at the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Energy for the Future Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000814"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-02T15:51:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Nuclear Energy for the Future Act

This bill addresses advanced nuclear energy research and development at the Department of Energy (DOE).

DOE must

 carry out a program to conduct research relating to the development of advanced nuclear energy technologies that may offer improved safety, functionality, and affordability; make available nuclear energy research infrastructure to industry partners in order to achieve faster and cost-effective development of advanced nuclear energy technologies toward commercial readiness; select industry partners for awards on a competitive merit-reviewed basis; construct a versatile reactor-based fast neutron source which shall operate as a national user facility; and ensure the coordination of, and avoid unnecessary duplication of, the activities of its high-performance computation collaborative research program to develop new reactor technologies with other research entities of DOE, including the National Laboratories.</summary>
</bill>
