<bill session="117" type="h" number="5279" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Defense to update the Unified Facilities Criteria to the most updated energy efficiency codes and standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Defense Energy Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Energy Efficiency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2021-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-29T17:06:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Defense Energy Efficiency Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to amend the Unified Facilities Criteria relating to military construction planning and design to ensure that DOD building practices and standards incorporate the latest consensus-based codes and standards for energy efficiency and conservation.

Not more than 25% of the funds authorized for FY2022 for DOD planning and design accounts relating to military construction projects may be obligated until DOD certifies that it has initiated the Unified Facilities Criteria amendment process and intends to complete the process by September 1, 2022.

Any DOD Form 1391 submitted after September 1, 2022, must comply with the amended Unified Facilities Criteria. Not later than March 1, 2023, DOD must certify to Congress the completion and full incorporation of the amendments to the Unified Facilities Criteria into military construction planning and design.

DOD must annually review the Unified Facilities Criteria to compare it to industry best practices for energy efficiency and energy conservation.</summary>
</bill>
