<bill session="112" type="h" number="4320" updated="2022-03-02T05:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reinvesting and Ensuring America's Ability to Lead Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Reinvesting and Ensuring America's Ability to Lead Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require long-term cost benefit analyses of introduced bills.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000043"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-23T21:11:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Reinvesting and Ensuring America's Ability to Lead Act of 2012 - Requires the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to: (1) prepare a 10-year long-term cost benefit analysis for each public introduced bill or resolution that determines its impact on American global competitiveness; and (2) devise criteria to evaluate such competitiveness, including the measure's impact on job creation, economic growth, consumption, investments, and savings.

Requires the analysis to evaluate whether the legislation will positively or negatively impact America's economic ability to compete globally compared to member nations of the Group of Twenty, or G-20, which comprise 19 country members and the European Union (EU), accounting for 90% of global gross domestic product (GDP) and 80% of global trade.</summary>
</bill>
