<bill session="108" type="h" number="3749" updated="2023-01-15T09:32:50Z">
  <state datetime="2004-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Government Internet Tobacco Sales Enforcement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise and reform the Act commonly called the Jenkins Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Government Internet Tobacco Sales Enforcement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000792"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Smokeless tobacco"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-04T18:42:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Government Internet Tobacco Sales Enforcement Act of 2004 - Amends the Jenkins Act to require each person who engages in an interstate sale of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco or in an interstate distribution of cigarettes or smokeless tobacco to comply with all applicable excise, sales, and use tax laws in the State and place in which the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco are delivered.

 Prohibits the cigarettes or smokeless tobacco from being delivered to the buyer unless in advance of the delivery the excise tax has been paid and any required stamps or other indicia that such tax has been paid are properly affixed or applied, with an exception.

Authorizes a State attorney general or the chief law enforcement officer of a local government that imposes an excise tax on cigarettes or smokeless tobacco to bring a civil action to obtain appropriate relief against anyone who violates such prohibition or who knowingly assists or participates in such a violation. Declares that the Act does not prohibit an authorized State, local, or tribal government official from proceeding in State or tribal court. Makes the Act's provisions regarding State tax collection inapplicable to certain sales that occur exclusively in Indian country. Expresses the sense of Congress that unique harms are associated with the remote interstate sales of cigarette and smokeless tobacco. Affirms Congress' longstanding interest in encouraging compliance and enforcement of State laws that relate to remote (including Internet) sales of such products.</summary>
</bill>
