<bill session="117" type="s" number="2561" updated="2023-08-23T20:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to provide that a land resource management plan or land use plan approved, amended, or revised under those Acts shall not be considered to be a continuing Federal agency action or constitute a discretionary Federal involvement or control for a distinct Federal purpose, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 to provide that a land resource management plan or land use plan approved, amended, or revised under those Acts shall not be considered to be a continuing Federal agency action or constitute a discretionary Federal involvement or control for a distinct Federal purpose, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2022-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with amendments and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 117-198.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-11-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="549">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 549.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-23T20:11:05Z" status="Reported to Senate">This bill addresses consultation after approval of certain land and resource management plans and land use plans.

Specifically, the bill provides that the Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management shall not be required to reinitiate consultation under the Endangered Species Act on a completed land resource management plan or a completed land use plan that has no on-the-ground effects when

 a new species is listed or a new critical habitat is designated under that act, or new information reveals effects of such plan that may affect a species listed or critical habitat designated under that act in a manner or to an extent not previously considered.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-198</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
