<bill session="117" type="s" number="1985" updated="2022-12-30T21:30:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Rural Opportunities to Use Transportation for Economic Success Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">ROUTES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ROUTES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Opportunities to Use Transportation for Economic Success Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2016" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2595" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-23T18:20:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Opportunities to Use Transportation for Economic Success Act or the ROUTES Act 

This bill provides statutory authority for a Department of Transportation (DOT) initiative by establishing the Rural Opportunities to Use Transportation for Economic Success (ROUTES) Office within DOT.

The purpose of the office is to (1) improve analysis of projects from rural and tribal areas, and underserved communities in such areas that are applying for DOT discretionary grants, including ensuring that project costs, local resources, and the larger benefits to the American people and economy are appropriately considered; and (2) provide rural, tribal, and underserved communities in these areas with technical assistance for meeting transportation infrastructure investment needs in a financially sustainable manner.

To carry out the mission of the office, DOT must establish the ROUTES Council.</summary>
</bill>
