<bill session="116" type="s" number="4868" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:21Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century Community Learning Centers Coronavirus Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Community Learning Centers Coronavirus Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow eligible entities under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to use subgrant funds for activities authorized under such part, regardless of whether such activities are conducted during nonschool hours or periods when school is not in session, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2020-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-25T17:25:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">21st Century Community Learning Centers Coronavirus Relief Act of 2020

This bill expands the allowable uses for subgrants provided under the 21st Century Community Learning Centers Program during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) public health emergency. Additionally, the bill provides funds to subgrant recipients for specified activities and supplies.

Specifically, the bill allows eligible entities (e.g., local educational agencies and community-based organizations) that are awarded program subgrants for community learning centers to use these subgrants to carry out activities that advance student academic achievement and support student success during the regular school day when full-time in-person instruction is not available to students. Further, eligible entities may carry out these activities regardless of whether such activities are conducted in person or virtually. (Currently, the program only supports academic enrichment opportunities for children during non-school hours or periods when school is not in session.)

Subgrant recipients must comply with all applicable health and safety requirements.

Finally, the bill provides funds for subgrant recipients to provide additional hours of service, hire additional staff to maintain social distancing, and purchase cleaning supplies and personal protective equipment.</summary>
</bill>
