<bill session="118" type="s" number="609" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NEW START Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Necessary Entrepreneurship Workshops via the SBA to Transform and Assist Re-entry Training Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEW START Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a pilot program awarding competitive grants to organizations administering entrepreneurial development programming to formerly incarcerated individuals, and other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000141"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T19:49:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Necessary Entrepreneurship Workshops via the SBA to Transform and Assist Re-entry Training Act of 2023 or the NEW START Act of 2023

This bill establishes a pilot program for providing entrepreneurial development assistance to formerly incarcerated individuals.

Specifically, the bill requires the Small Business Administration to establish a pilot program whereby it awards grants to organizations or partnerships that create or support entrepreneurship programs for providing assistance to formerly incarcerated individuals. Such assistance shall be in the form of entrepreneurial development programming that may include the disbursement of microloans.

The Government Accountability Office must submit a report evaluating the (1) services that grant recipients provide to formerly incarcerated individuals, (2) oversight of the pilot program by the SBA, and (3) overall performance and impacts of the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
