<bill session="111" type="s" number="1800" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to provide compensation for certain persons injured in the course of employment at the Feed Materials Production Center (commonly referred to as "Fernald") or the Piqua Organic Moderated Reactor in Ohio.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to provide compensation for certain persons injured in the course of employment at the Feed Materials Production Center (commonly referred to as "Fernald") or the Piqua Organic Moderated Reactor in Ohio.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3992" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-12T19:50:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include as a member of the Special Exposure Cohort entitled to compensation with respect to chronic beryllium disease under the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program any Department of Energy (DOE) employee or a DOE contractor or subcontractor employee who was employed for an aggregate number of at least 250 work days before January 1, 2009, at the Feed Materials Production Center (Fernald) or the Piqua Organic Moderated Reactor in Ohio.

Requires any claim that an individual qualifies by reason of this Act for compensation or benefits to be considered for such compensation or benefits notwithstanding any denial of any other claim for compensation with respect to the individual.</summary>
</bill>
