<bill session="108" type="s" number="594" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Indian School Construction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the issuance of bonds to provide funding for the construction of schools of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian School Construction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2003-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2003-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3517-3518"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mutual funds"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Indian School Construction Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish a pilot program under which eligible Indian tribes have the authority to issue tribal school modernization bonds to provide funding for the construction, rehabilitation, or repair of tribal schools, including advance planning and design.Permits a tribe to use amounts received through a bond issue to enter contracts: (1) for the design and engineering of the school; and (2) with financial advisors, underwriters, attorneys, trustees, and other professionals who would be able to provide assistance to the tribe in issuing bonds.Makes any tribal school modernization bond issued by a tribe subject to a trust agreement.Authorizes the Secretary to deposit not more than $30 million each fiscal year into a tribal school modernization escrow account beginning in FY 2004 from amounts made available for school replacement under the construction account of the Bureau of Indian Affairs. Requires the Secretary to use any amounts deposited to make payments to trustees or for advance planning and design.Declares that no bond shall be an obligation of, nor shall payment of the principal be guaranteed by, the United States, the tribes, or their schools. Exempts from Federal income tax any earnings through the investment of funds under the control of a trustee. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a tax credit to individuals who hold such bonds.</summary>
</bill>
