<bill session="117" type="sr" number="329" updated="2022-09-04T13:14:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution amending the eligibility criteria for the Senate Employee Child Care Center.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending the eligibility criteria for the Senate Employee Child Care Center.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2021-07-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5193" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5181" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-04T18:00:21Z" status="Passed Senate">This resolution revises the eligibility criteria for the Senate Employee Child Care Center.

For FY2022, and each fiscal year afterwards, the Senate shall reimburse the Senate Employee Child Care Center for the cost of the basic pay paid to the Executive Director and the Assistant Director of the center.

As a condition of receiving such reimbursement, the center must terminate the enrollment of a child at the center within 120 days of the date on which the child does not have a parent or guardian who is serving as an employee of the Senate, an employee of the center, a congressional employee, or a federal employee.

As a condition of receiving reimbursement under this resolution, the center shall provide enrollment

 first, to a child of an individual serving as a Senate employee or as an employee of the center; second, to a child of an individual serving as a congressional employee; and third, to a child of a federal employee if certain conditions are met. Under the resolution, the center may provide enrollment to the child of a federal employee if

 there is an enrollment slot available; no child of an individual serving as an employee of the Senate, as an employee of the center, or as a congressional employee accepts the slot; and no currently enrolled child is ready to transition to the class in which the slot is available.</summary>
</bill>
