<bill session="117" type="s" number="3844" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Economic Continuity and Stability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Continuity and Stability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a clear and uniform process, on a nationwide basis, for replacing the London interbank offered rate in existing contracts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2022-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4616" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3779" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-08T18:30:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Economic Continuity and Stability Act

This bill provides for the transition of certain financial contracts away from the London Interbank Offered Rate (LIBOR), a reference interest rate based upon the lending terms certain banks offer to each other for various lengths of time. LIBOR is set to be retired in 2023. Various financial contracts reference LIBOR as a benchmark for prevailing interest rates and use LIBOR in calculating certain payments or obligations.

In the event a contract referencing LIBOR does not have a fallback or replacement rate provision in effect when LIBOR is retired, or a replacement rate is not selected by a determining person as defined by the bill, the bill provides for a transition to a replacement rate selected by the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System. The bill also provides for conforming changes to these contracts, the continuity and enforceability of these contracts, tax treatment, and protections against liability as a result of such a transition.</summary>
</bill>
