<bill session="116" type="h" number="6403" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Business Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Innovation and Startups Equity Investment Program in the Department of the Treasury, through which the Secretary of the Treasury shall allocate money to certain States to assist high-potential scalable startups access venture capital to commercialize innovations, create jobs, and accelerate economic growth, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Business Preservation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2020-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000616" joined="2020-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2020-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2020-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3515" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-18T12:04:43Z" status="Introduced in House">New Business Preservation Act

This bill establishes and provides funding for the Innovation and Startups Equity Investment Program, through which the Department of the Treasury shall work with states to invest in new businesses.

Specifically, the bill requires Treasury to provide certain funds to participating states, which such states shall use to administer specified approved programs that provide equity investment in new businesses. Certain areas with high levels of venture capital activity are excluded from the calculation of funds allocated to a participating state. Treasury shall also award funds to approved state programs to provide follow-on investments.

If a state receives funds from an exit, the state shall use such funds to further invest in startups under the approved program. An exit is defined as the (1) acquisition of a startup in which a state has invested under the program; (2) sale of a share of such startup following an initial public offering; or (3) voluntary purchase of a state's ownership interest by the startup, investors, or existing shareholders.</summary>
</bill>
