<bill session="115" type="s" number="3377" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:40Z">
  <state datetime="2018-08-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-08-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-08-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Procurement Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the purchase of certain items related to national security according to certain criteria.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Procurement Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOPR Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2018-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-08-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5574" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-07T15:37:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeland Procurement Reform Act or the HOPR Act

This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) procure certain critical equipment of the quality and innovation necessary to carry out effectively its security, enforcement, and investigative missions; and (2) ensure that funds appropriated or otherwise available to its front line operational components are used for the procurement of covered items only if they meet specified criteria (e.g., that the contractor agree to store items not assembled in the United States in a locked area, report theft of insignia prior to delivery, destroy defective items with any unit or agency insignia, and maintain records of such destruction).

"Front line operational component" includes: (1) U.S. Customs and Border Protection, (2) U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, (3) the Transportation Safety Administration, (4) the Coast Guard, (5) the U.S. Secret Service, (6) the National Protection and Programs Directorate, (7) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), and (8) the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers.

"Covered items" include: (1) body armor components intended to provide ballistic protection for an individual, (2) helmets that provide head protection, (3) respiratory protection masks, and (4) other critical safety items as determined appropriate by DHS.

This bill: (1) does not apply to any procurements by vessels in foreign waters, nor in response to a major disaster declared by the President, and (2) applies to contracts entered into by DHS or any of its component agencies on or after October 1, 2018.</summary>
</bill>
