<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="477" updated="2022-02-03T04:57:33Z">
  <amends type="h" number="339" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-03-10T17:34:50-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-03-10"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (preceding the amendment to the long title), insert the following new section: \   SEC. 5. ACTIONS INVOLVING WEIGHT-LOSS PRODUCTS. \   Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, this Act shall not apply to an action alleging that a product claiming to assist in weight loss caused heart disease, heart damage, primary pulmonary hypertension, neuropsychological damage, or any other complication which may also be generally associated with a person's weight gain or obesity.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in the Congressional Record to provide that the bill would not apply to civil actions that allege a product claiming to assist in weight loss caused heart disease, heart damage, primary pulmonary hypertension, neuropsychological damage, or any other complication which may be generally associated with a person's weight gain or obesity.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-03-10T17:34:50-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="52">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A009) Failed by recorded vote: 166 - 250 (Roll no. 52).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:39:10-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A009) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H974-976, H979-980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H974" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T16:39:10-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A009) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H974-976, H979-980" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H974" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T17:34:50-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T17:34:50-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10T17:34:50-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A009) Failed by recorded vote: 166 - 250 (Roll no. 52).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
