<bill session="115" type="h" number="3795" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:42Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tijuana River Valley Comprehensive Protection and Rehabilitation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tijuana River Valley Comprehensive Protection and Rehabilitation Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to carry out a comprehensive protection and rehabilitation program for the Tijuana River Valley, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000130"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000598" joined="2018-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2017-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2017-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Western Hemisphere.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA07" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-13T19:35:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Tijuana River Valley Comprehensive Protection and Rehabilitation Act of 2017

This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to carry out a comprehensive protection and rehabilitation program to enhance the physical infrastructure in both the United States and Mexico to prevent flooding and wastewater, sewage, trash, and sediment spills in the Tijuana River Valley, including carrying out coordinated restoration and protection activities that enhance the infrastructure. Grants and technical assistance must be provided under the program to state and local governments, nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education, in both countries.

In addition, the Corps of Engineers must develop a feasibility and technical assistance plan for updated wastewater infrastructure and flood preparedness in the river valley.

Using the systems of the International Boundary and Water Commission, United States and Mexico, the Department of State must establish the Transboundary Waterway Alert System, an updated and online system to protect U.S. citizens from undue and avoidable harm from wastewater, sewage, trash, and sediment spills and flooding for each major waterway along the U.S.-Mexico border.

The State Department must notify Mexico, the cities of San Diego and Imperial Beach, and the county of San Diego upon the initial discovery of such spills.</summary>
</bill>
