<bill session="108" type="s" number="2934" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combating Methamphetamine Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to combat methamphetamine abuse in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Methamphetamine Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10731-10732"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Community policing"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse treatment"/>
    <term name="Drug courts"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family courts"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Methamphetamine"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-23T15:11:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Methamphetamine Act of 2004 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General, through the Bureau of Justice Assistance (BJA), to make grants to States to address the manufacture, sale, and use of methamphetamine (methamphetamine use) to enhance public safety. Lists eligible programs, projects, and activities, including: (1) arresting individuals violating methamphetamine laws; (2) undertaking clandestine methamphetamine lab seizures and environmental cleanup; (3) providing community-based education, awareness, and prevention; and (4) providing Drug Court and Family Drug Court services to address methamphetamine use. Sets forth grant application requirements.

Authorizes the Attorney General, through BJA, to make grants to States, Indian tribal governments, and multijurisdictional or regional consortia thereof to develop a comprehensive, cooperative strategy to address methamphetamine use to enhance public safety. Earmarks specified sums (according to a specified formula) to each State.

Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) collect systematic data on the effectiveness of the programs assisted under this Act in reducing methamphetamine use; (2) establish a national clearinghouse of information on effective programs to address such use that shall disseminate to State and local agencies a description of the results of research on reduction efforts and information on effective programs, best practices, and Federal resources; (3) establish a program within the Department of Justice to facilitate the sharing of knowledge in best practices among States addressing such use; and (4) provide technical assistance to State and local agencies implementing effective programs to reduce methamphetamine use.</summary>
</bill>
