<bill session="117" type="h" number="231" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Service Spending Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the enrichment of certain Government officers and employees or their families through Federal funds or contracting, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Service Spending Integrity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2093" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-18T20:18:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Service Spending Integrity Act

This bill restricts federal spending at businesses of the President, specified other officials, or their family members.

Specifically, the bill prohibits federal funds from being obligated or expended for purposes of procuring goods or services at any business owned or controlled by a covered individual or family member of such individual, except for certain authorized security purposes. A covered individual is defined to include the President, the Vice President, the head of any executive department, and any individual occupying a position designated by the President as a cabinet-level position. No federal agency may enter into a contract with a business owned or controlled by a covered individual or family member.

A business shall be deemed to be owned or controlled by a covered individual or family member if any such person (1) is a member of the board of directors or similar governing body of the business, (2) directly or indirectly owns or controls more than 50% of the voting shares of the business, or (3) is the beneficiary of a trust which owns or controls more than 50% of the business and can direct distributions under the terms of the trust.</summary>
</bill>
