<bill session="108" type="s" number="1680" updated="2023-01-15T07:17:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense Production Act Reauthorization of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Defense Production Act Reauthorization of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Defense Production Act Reauthorization of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Production Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Defense Production Act Reauthorization of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Defense Production Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to reauthorize the Defense Production Act of 1950, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Shelby. With written report No. 108-156.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-09-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="294">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 294.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-09-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12206-12208" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01T10:03:31-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T16:31:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. King (NY) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T16:31:56-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9416-9418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T16:32:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1680.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2003-10-15T16:45:28-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9416-9417" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15T16:45:31-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-16">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="pingpong" datetime="2003-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Senate concurred in the House amendment with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15480-15481" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S15480-15481" label="text as Senate agreed to House amendment with an amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:06:01-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ney asked unanimous consent that the House agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12861-12862" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="pingpong" datetime="2003-12-08T17:07:42-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House agree to the Senate amendment to the House amendment Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H12861" label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment to House amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-12-08T17:07:43-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-12-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-12-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-195" type="public" datetime="2003-12-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-195.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1280" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Industrial capacity"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Military electronics"/>
    <term name="Nuclear warfare"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2209"/>
    <amendment number="s1792"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-01-23T15:32:14Z" status="Public Law">Defense Production Act Reauthorization of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Defense Production Act of 1950 to extend its expiration date and authorization of appropriations through FY 2008.

(Sec. 3) Authorizes the President to: (1) take action to correct an industrial resource shortfall for radiation-hardened electronics to the extent that such action does not cause the aggregate outstanding amount of all such actions for industrial resource shortfalls to exceed $200 million; and (2) obtain information in order to perform industry studies assessing capabilities of the U.S. industrial base to support the national defense. Requires a report from the Secretary of Defense to specified congressional committees on the current state of the domestic industrial base for, and Department of Defense requirements, intentions, and plans for, radiation-hardened electronics. (Sec. 4) Defines "critical infrastructure" under such Act as systems and assets, whether physical or cyber-based, so vital to the United States that their degradation or destruction would have a debilitating impact on national security, including national economic security and national public health or safety. (Sec. 6) Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on the extent to which contracts entered into under such Act during the one-year period after the enactment of this Act have been contracts with minority- and women-owned businesses. (Sec. 7) Requires the Secretary of Commerce, as part of an annual report from the President to specified congressional committees on the impact of offsets on U.S. defense preparedness, industrial competitiveness, employment, and trade, to: (1) detail the number of foreign contracts involving domestic contractors that used offsets or similar arrangements during the preceding five-year period; (2) calculate the values of such contracts and offsets; and (3) describe the impact of international or foreign sales of U.S. defense products and related offsets and arrangements on domestic prime contractors and lower-tier subcontractors during the preceding five-year period. Expresses the policy of Congress that the President shall designate a chairman of an interagency team to consult with foreign nations on limiting the adverse effects of offsets in defense procurement without damaging the U.S. economy, industrial base, or defense production or preparedness. Requires annual interagency team reports to Congress. Directs the interagency team to make recommendations to the President for modifications of any existing or proposed memorandum of understanding between the United States and one or more foreign countries relating to: (1) research, development, or production of defense equipment; or (2) the reciprocal procurement of defense items.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-156</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
