<bill session="118" type="s" number="2326" updated="2025-11-19T03:58:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SNAP Nutrition Security Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Nutrition Security Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to improve diet quality and nutrition security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4909" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-25T18:47:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">SNAP Nutrition Security Act of 2023

This bill expands the policy of the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) to include reducing food insecurity, increasing nutrition security, and improving diet quality for low-income people in the United States. It also&#160;requires additional&#160;related reporting by states and the Department of Agriculture (USDA).

The bill defines (1) food security as access by all people at all times to enough food for an active, healthy life; (2) nutrition security as consistent and equitable access to healthy, safe, affordable foods essential to optimal health and well-being; and (3) diet quality as the extent to which a set of foods aligns with key recommendations of the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans.

Under current requirements, a state agency that provides nutrition education and obesity prevention services under SNAP must submit an annual report to USDA. The bill requires the report to include (1) state actions taken to enhance the food and nutrition security of SNAP participants, and (2) recommendations regarding administering SNAP in a manner that would enhance state food and nutrition security in the state.

Further, USDA must submit an annual report to Congress on U.S. food security, nutrition security, and diet quality.

USDA must use data collected from retail stores participating in SNAP to&#160;submit a report to Congress at least every four years on food sales in SNAP.&#160;The report must be made publicly available and include an analysis of the specific food items acquired with SNAP benefits by eligible households.&#160;&#160; &#160;</summary>
</bill>
