<bill session="117" type="h" number="8494" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trauma-Informed Schools Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trauma-Informed Schools Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide criteria for use of Federal funds to support trauma-informed practices in schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001101"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2022-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4614" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-03T15:26:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Trauma-Informed Schools Act of 2022

This bill provides for the&#160;use of trauma-informed practices in public elementary and secondary schools and allows states to use certain federal funds to train teachers and other staff in such practices.

The bill defines trauma-informed practices to include

 evidence-based professional development that promotes a shared understanding among teachers and other staff that adverse and potentially traumatic experiences are common among students and that school-wide learning environments where all students and adults feel safe, welcomed, and supported can enable students to succeed despite such experiences; adoption of disciplinary procedures and practices that utilize evidence-based restorative practices that build a culture of trust; and activities that engage teachers, other staff, and families in a process of school-based planning to help all students feel safe and connected to the school community.</summary>
</bill>
