<amendment session="112" chamber="s" number="14" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:21Z">
  <amends type="s" number="223" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-02-15">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-02-01"/>
  <description>To exclude employees of the Transportation Security Administration from the collective bargaining rights of Federal employees and provide employment rights and an employee engagement mechanism for passenger and property screeners.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Proposed amendment SA 14 as modified, pursuant to the order of 2/14/2011, having failed to achieve the required 60 votes for the adoption of the amendment, was withdrawn in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S720" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote datetime="2011-02-15" how="roll" result="fail" roll="17">
      <text>Amendment SA 14 as modified not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 51. Record Vote Number: 17.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S709, S716-720" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S653" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S622" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-07">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S586, S589-590" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S589-590" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Amendment SA 14 proposed by Senator Wicker. (consideration: CR S501-502, S532, S538; text: CR S501) To exclude employees of the Transportation Security Administration from the collective bargaining rights of Federal employees and provide employment rights and an employee engagement mechanism for passenger and property screeners.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 14 as modified not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 51. Record Vote Number: 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-15">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 14 as modified not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 47 - 51. Record Vote Number: 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 14 proposed by Senator Wicker.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S501-502, S532, S538" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S501" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-01">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
