<bill session="116" type="h" number="7198" updated="2022-02-09T03:56:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PIPELINE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a scholarship program to diversify the national security workforce through partnership with historically Black colleges and universities and other minority institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pathway for Inclusive Participation of Emerging Leaders and Institutions in the NatSec Enterprise Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PIPELINE Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2020-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2020-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6395" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-22T17:12:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Pathway for Inclusive Participation of Emerging Leaders and Institutions in the NatSec Enterprise Act of 2020 or the PIPELINE Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Defense to establish a federal scholarship-for-service program to recruit, train, and diversify the next generation of national security professionals to meet the needs of federal, state, local, and tribal governments.

Specifically, the program must (1) provide scholarships to students who are enrolled in programs of study related to national security at historically Black colleges and universities or at institutions of higher education with at least 50% of total student enrollment from ethnic groups that are underrepresented in the fields of science and engineering, (2) provide scholarship recipients with internship opportunities or other temporary appointments in the federal national security workforce, and (3) prioritize the employment placement of scholarship recipients in the federal government.

Additionally, the post-award employment obligations of a scholarship recipient must include three years of work in a position related to national security at a federal, state, local, or tribal agency. A scholarship recipient may fulfill this condition by serving in the Armed Forces.

Finally, a scholarship recipient who completes less than the required three years of service must repay the scholarship, or the scholarship must&#160;be treated as a Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loan that is subject to repayment.</summary>
</bill>
