<bill session="112" type="h" number="3737" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:15Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ULTRA</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlocking Lifesaving Treatments for Rare-Diseases Act</title>
    <title type="display">ULTRA</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to fast track approval of certain orphan drugs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2012-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001271" joined="2012-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000554" joined="2012-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001181" joined="2012-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000587" joined="2012-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000580" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2012-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2011-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2012-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-03-05T22:10:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Unlocking Lifesaving Treatments for Rare-Diseases Act or ULTRA - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to approve an application for a drug as a fast track product using a surrogate endpoint, based on the existence of reasonable scientific data that support and qualify the relevance of such endpoint to the disease state and treatment, if the Secretary: (1) makes an initial determination that the drug is eligible for approval as a drug designated for a rare disease or condition (orphan drug) and as a fast track product, and (2) determines that the drug is a treatment for a disease or condition that affects a small number of patients in the United States. Prohibits the Secretary from requiring clinical treatment or other historical clinical data on such endpoint as a prerequisite to assessment of that endpoint if such scientific data is not available.

Directs the Secretary to issue guidance providing details and options for qualifying surrogate endpoints without clinical data, taking into account and balancing: (1) the unmet need served by the drug and the adverse effects of the rare disease or condition on quality and length of life, (2) the very low likelihood that clinical data would exist or that clinical studies would be completed to support a surrogate endpoint due to the small size of the U.S. patient population and other significant barriers inherent in performing such studies due to the prevalence of the disease or related factors, and (3) the full scope of available basic scientific data and information that the Secretary deems reasonably predictive of a clinical benefit in the absence of clinical data.</summary>
</bill>
