<bill session="109" type="s" number="1519" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:22Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Economic Impact Analysis Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for an economic analysis of the impact in small business concerns and small governmental jurisdictions of agency and other decisions that result in a net loss of at least 1,000 jobs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Economic Impact Analysis Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2005-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-06T16:16:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Economic Impact Analysis Act of 2005 - Prohibits an agency from making a qualified termination or restructuring (a termination of the use of a facility or restructuring that will result in the net loss of at least 1,000 jobs in a state) unless it conducts a detailed analysis of the impact on small businesses and small governmental jurisdictions of the proposed termination or restructuring. Requires: (1) a related cost-benefit analysis; and (2) the agency to publish a draft of the analysis at least 180 days before undertaking the termination or restructuring.

Directs the: (1) agency to publish a final economic analysis; and (2) Comptroller General to review such final analysis. Prohibits an agency from taking final action on a termination or restructuring until its analysis receives a satisfactory review from the Comptroller General.

Authorizes judicial review for any small business or small governmental jurisdiction adversely affected or aggrieved by a qualifying termination or restructuring.</summary>
</bill>
