<bill session="117" type="s" number="411" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MOM&#194;&#173;MA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal efforts with respect to the prevention of maternal mortality, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MOM&#194;&#173;MA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mothers and Offspring Mortality and Morbidity Awareness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2021-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-02-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S859-863" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1314" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2786" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3407" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4486" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8862" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Dental care"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-24T15:42:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mothers and Offspring Mortality and Morbidity Awareness Act or the MOMMA's Act

This bill establishes various programs and requirements to reduce maternal mortality. It also increases federal tobacco taxes and equalizes the tax treatment of different tobacco products.

Specifically, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must provide technical assistance and best practices for collecting data, standardizing reporting, and preventing maternal mortality. The CDC must consult with the Health Resources and Services Administration (HRSA) on this assistance.

The bill also provides statutory authority for

 CDC grants for state-based collaboratives to improve care immediately before and after birth and to improve maternal and infant health outcomes, and a HRSA program to improve the quality and safety of maternity care. Furthermore, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must establish regional centers through health professional schools and training programs to educate health care providers about implicit bias and culturally competent care.

In addition, the bill expands eligibility for Medicaid, the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP), and other benefits for pregnant and postpartum individuals. Specifically, it

 extends postpartum eligibility for Medicaid and CHIP for one year; provides coverage for oral health services for pregnant and postpartum individuals under Medicaid and CHIP; and extends postpartum eligibility for the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children for two years. HHS must also take steps to publicize the benefits available to pregnant and postpartum individuals under Medicaid and CHIP, and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services must provide guidance on Medicaid coverage for doula services.</summary>
</bill>
