<bill session="117" type="s" number="2649" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a demonstration program to provide integrated care for Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal disease, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">BETTER Kidney Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BETTER Kidney Care Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bringing Enhanced Treatments and Therapies to ESRD Recipients Kidney Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4942" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-21T01:40:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bringing Enhanced Treatments and Therapies to ESRD Recipients Kidney Care Act or the BETTER Kidney Care Act

This bill requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) to establish a demonstration program for Medicare beneficiaries with end-stage renal disease (ESRD).

Under the program, renal dialysis facilities, kidney disease specialists, physician practices, and other health care practitioners may form an organization that partners with certain health care entities to provide integrated care to beneficiaries with ESRD. Such care must include all covered Medicare benefits as well as transition services for transplantations, palliative care, and hospice. Each organization must have a minimum number or percentage of participating beneficiaries (350 or 60% of beneficiaries served at the organization's facilities) and must also comply with certain fiscal, governance, and quality of care requirements.

Additionally, the Government Accountability Office must study certain data that is reported to the CMS regarding pediatric dialysis care, as well as the effects of race-based corrections to a specified kidney function test on referrals of ESRD patients for transplant evaluations.</summary>
</bill>
