<bill session="116" type="h" number="1425" updated="2022-11-01T17:03:33Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-29T17:18:42-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-06-29T17:18:42-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">State Health Care Premium Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Health Care Premium Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to provide for a Improve Health Insurance Affordability Fund to provide for certain reinsurance payments to lower premiums in the individual health insurance market.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2019-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001308" joined="2019-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2019-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2019-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001123" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2019-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2019-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2019-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000467" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2019-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001064" joined="2019-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001087" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2019-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2019-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000379" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2019-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2019-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2019-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2019-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001209" joined="2019-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2019-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001207" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2019-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2019-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2019-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000613" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000616" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2019-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2019-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2019-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2019-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2019-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2019-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000040" joined="2019-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2019-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2019-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000825" joined="2019-11-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 18 - 13 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-09">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 116-414.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-03-09" calendar="Union" number="334">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 334.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-06-24T19:02:39-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1017 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1425, H.R. 5332, H.R. 7120, H.R. 7301 and H.J. Res. 90. The resolution provides that the provisions of section 125(c) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall not apply during the remainder of the 116th Congress and the resolution amends H.Res. 967, agreed to on May 15, 2020.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T10:11:44-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1017.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2599-2644" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T10:11:49-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1425, H.R. 5332, H.R. 7120, H.R. 7301 and H.J. Res. 90. The resolution provides that the provisions of section 125(c) of the Uruguay Round Agreements Act shall not apply during the remainder of the 116th Congress and the resolution amends H.Res. 967, agreed to on May 15, 2020.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T10:13:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with three hours of debate on H.R. 1425.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T13:59:46-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T14:00:44-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2642-2643" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T14:00:56-04:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Walden motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to prevent the bill from taking effect unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies that no provision of the bill would adversely affect research related to any drug intended to treat or prevent the virus that causes COVID-19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T14:08:54-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T14:09:28-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the motion to recommit with instructions, the Chair put the question on the motion and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Walden demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further consideration on the motion to recommit until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T15:55:36-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2664-2665" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T16:39:10-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 187 - 223 (Roll no. 123).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="124" datetime="2020-06-29T17:18:42-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 179 (Roll no. 124).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2599-2614" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-06-29T17:18:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-13">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-09-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="523">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 523.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="1017" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1884" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6136" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6151" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1879" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6130" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6149" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1905" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="986" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="987" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1385" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1386" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1870" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4821" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1400" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2218" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="584" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5291" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6135" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="455" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="585" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4521" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h819"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-08-10T18:59:23Z" status="Passed House">Patient Protection and Affordable Care Enhancement Act This bill modifies various health insurance programs related to consumer costs for private health insurance plans, Medicaid funding and eligibility, and prescription drug pricing. Specifically, the bill increases the amount and income thresholds for the premium assistance tax credit program and expands access to such tax credit for employees with employer-provided family plans that cost in excess of 9.5% of the employee's household income. Further, the bill provides additional funding for states to establish health insurance exchanges and establishes the Improve Health Insurance Affordability Fund. States must use allocated funds to (1) issue reinsurance payments to health insurers (i.e., reimbursements to protect insurers against exceedingly high claims) for individual health insurance coverage, or (2) provide other assistance to reduce out-of-pocket costs (e.g., copayments, coinsurance, and deductibles) for qualified health plans offered in the individual market through an exchange. The bill also nullifies a rule that expands short-term, limited-duration health insurance plans. Such plans may offer coverage for only a limited amount of time and are exempt from certain coverage requirements. The bill also nullifies guidance that alters how states may satisfy the criteria for approval of State Innovation Waivers from certain health insurance coverage requirements. Additionally, the bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to conduct outreach, education, and reporting activities related to enrollment in plans through health insurance exchanges, particularly in areas with disparities in income or health outcomes. It also establishes and funds grants to states to promote enrollment in health insurance coverage and requires health insurance exchanges to establish network adequacy standards. The bill makes recipients of benefits under the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals Program eligible for qualified health plans offered through such exchanges. With respect to Medicaid, the bill increases to 100% the federal share of the cost for states to meet the minimum Medicaid expansion requirements and to cover newly-eligible individuals; the current federal share of such costs is 90%. It also requires states to provide 12 months of continuous coverage to individuals enrolling in Medicaid or the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) and extends postpartum Medicaid and CHIP coverage to 12 months. The bill further reduces federal matching funds for administrative costs and expands reporting requirements for states that have not met specified Medicaid expansion requirements. Additionally, the bill

 extends through FY2024 the minimum payment requirements for primary care services; permanently extends CHIP funding and eligibility, enrollment, and quality assurance provisions; increases the permissible family income threshold for children whom states may make eligible for Medicaid and CHIP; extends Medicaid coverage to residents of the Freely Associated States (i.e., Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau); and increases the federal medical assistance percentage for services provided through Indian Health Care Services. The bill also establishes the Fair Drug Pricing Program that directs HHS to negotiate with manufacturers to set the price for selected drugs and biological products. HHS must select certain drugs and biological products that are among the most costly based on spending under Medicare and enter a voluntary negotiation with manufacturers to establish a maximum price for each drug or product. The negotiation must consider, among other factors, the cost of research and development of the selected drug or biological product, the cost of production, national sales data, and information about alternative products. The bill establishes an excise tax on manufacturers that do not comply with a negotiated fair price agreement in the amount of specified percentages of the sales of such drug or product. The bill also creates a fund to implement the Fair Drug Pricing Program.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-414</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
