<bill session="118" type="s" number="1285" updated="2025-11-19T03:35:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Shooting Safety and Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Shooting Safety and Preparedness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the National Center for Education Statistics to produce an annual report on indicators of school crime and safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001267"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2869" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-04T12:19:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">School Shooting Safety and Preparedness Act

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) to publish an annual report on indicators of school crime and safety.

The report must collect specified information, including

 the number of school shootings that have taken place nationwide and the number of those that were mass shootings; the number of people killed or injured in each school shooting; the age, gender, race, ethnicity, and nationality of each victim; the motivation of the shooter; how the shooting was stopped; the number and type of firearms and ammunition used in each shooting; and the response time of law enforcement. ED must direct the National Center for Education Statistics to collect and publish specified data on school shootings.

 The center must collect information on the existence or absence of specified measures at the time of the shooting, including physical and other types of security measures, a communication plan with local law enforcement, a response plan that includes coordination with local agencies, an active shooter response plan, and a trauma response plan.</summary>
</bill>
