<bill session="111" type="h" number="4744" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:27Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">E-Verify Loan Origination Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require, as a condition for purchase of a home mortgage loan by Fannie Mae or Freddie Mac, and insurance of a home mortgage loan under the National Housing Act, that the mortgagor be verified under the E-Verify program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">E-Verify Loan Origination Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001158"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4586" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-07T13:35:56Z" status="Introduced in House">E-Verify Loan Origination Act of 2010 - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to prohibit the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae) and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act (Freddie Mac) from purchasing a single-family housing (1-to-4 family residence) mortgage unless the identity and work eligibility of the mortgagor has been confirmed by an inquiry made through the basic pilot E-Verify program under the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996. Permits the lender, Fannie Mae, and Freddie Mac to submit such inquiries.

Amends the National Housing Act to prohibit the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) from insuring any single-family housing mortgage unless the identity and work eligibility of the mortgagor has been confirmed by an inquiry made through the basic pilot E-Verify program. Permits the lender and the Secretary to submit such inquiries.</summary>
</bill>
