<bill session="118" type="h" number="1264" updated="2024-12-21T09:05:48Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commonsense Reporting Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commonsense Reporting Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To streamline the employer reporting process and strengthen the eligibility verification process for the premium assistance tax credit and cost-sharing subsidy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2023-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-25T17:12:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Commonsense Reporting Act of 2023

This bill addresses the eligibility verification process for the premium assistance tax credit and cost-sharing subsidy under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (PPACA). It requires the Department of the Treasury to develop and implement a reporting system that allows employers to voluntarily report information about their health plans for the current plan year prior to the beginning of open enrollment. The bill also allows electronic transmission of employee and enrollee statements and permits Treasury to accept full names and dates of birth in lieu of dependents' and spouses' Social Security account numbers.

The bill also allows certain large employers who do not offer their employees minimum health care coverage 90 days to appeal an assessment for not providing such coverage.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate (1) for the period beginning on January 1, 2015, and ending on December 31, 2022, the notification of employers by PPACA exchanges of the eligibility of employees for advance payments of the premium assistance tax credit or cost-sharing subsidies; and (2) for calendar year 2024, the functionality of the prospective reporting system established by this bill, including the accuracy of information collected.</summary>
</bill>
