<bill session="116" type="h" number="7429" updated="2022-02-08T23:15:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Cross-border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a more uniform, transparent, and modern process to authorize the construction, connection, operation, and maintenance of international border-crossing facilities for the import and export of oil and natural gas and the transmission of electricity.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Cross-border Energy Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-25T19:13:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Cross-border Energy Infrastructure Act

This bill establishes a new process for approving the construction and operation of energy infrastructure across an international border of the United States and replaces the existing process established under specified executive orders.

Specifically, this bill requires a person to obtain a certificate of crossing before constructing, connecting, operating, or maintaining a border-crossing facility for the import or export of oil, natural gas, or electricity across an international border. A certificate must be obtained from the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) for a facility consisting of oil or natural gas pipelines or the Department of Energy (DOE) for an electric transmission facility.

As a condition of issuing a certificate, DOE must require that an electric transmission facility be constructed, connected, operated, or maintained consistent with specified policies and standards.

FERC and DOE must meet a deadline for issuing a certificate as set forth by this bill. The bill also requires FERC to meet a deadline for approving applications to import or export natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</summary>
</bill>
