<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="276" updated="2022-07-15T07:16:25Z">
  <amends type="h" number="7900" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-07-14T14:35:19-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-07-14"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 399 printed in Part A of House Report 117-405 to prohibit the President from selling or exporting new F-16s or F-16 upgrade technology or modernization kits to Turkey unless the President provides a certification to Congress that such a transfer is in the national interest of the United States and includes a detailed description of concrete steps taken to ensure that such F-16s are not used by Turkey for repeated unauthorized territorial overflights of Greece.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment prohibits the President from selling or exporting new F-16s or F-16 upgrade technology or modernization kits to Turkey unless the President provides a certification to Congress that such a transfer is in the national interest of the United States and includes a detailed description of concrete steps taken to ensure that such F-16s are not used by Turkey for repeated unauthorized territorial overflights of Greece.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-07-14T14:35:19-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="339">
      <text>On agreeing to the Pallone amendment (A032) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 179 (Roll no. 339).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6595-6596" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T00:36:03-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A032) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T00:24:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A032) offered by Mr. Pallone.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6455-6456" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6455" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14"/>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T00:24:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A032) offered by Mr. Pallone.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:35:19-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Pallone amendment (A032) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 179 (Roll no. 339).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:35:19-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14T14:35:19-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Pallone amendment (A032) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 179 (Roll no. 339).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
