<bill session="119" type="s" number="835" updated="2025-09-26T13:29:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reduce Food Loss and Waste Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reduce Food Loss and Waste Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to establish a voluntary program to reduce food loss and waste, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2025-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1498-1499" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-26T13:26:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reduce Food Loss and Waste Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a voluntary Food Loss and Waste Reduction Certification Program in order to reduce food loss and waste, increase donations of excess food to certain nonprofit organizations, and increase the use of alternative disposal methods for food (e.g., redirection to animal feed and composting).

Specifically,&#160;USDA must establish criteria for the certification of eligible participants (e.g., state or local governments, corporations, farms or food producers, retail grocers, restaurants, and schools).

USDA must also establish criteria for recognizing accreditation bodies to accredit third-party certifiers to review and certify program participants.&#160;Preference in accrediting third-party certifiers must be given to institutions of higher education that have expertise in food loss and waste reduction.&#160;USDA must maintain on a publicly available USDA website a list of (1) recognized accreditation bodies, and (2) accredited third-party certifiers.

Further, USDA must establish a voluntary label that certified program participants may use to indicate that they are certified. USDA must also promote certified participants on the USDA website and through&#160;events.

Finally, USDA, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA), and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must revise a Memorandum of Understanding (MOU) signed on December 17, 2020, and relating to cooperation and coordination on food loss and waste.&#160;USDA must&#160;implement this bill in coordination with the FDA and the EPA and in accordance with the revised MOU.</summary>
</bill>
