<bill session="118" type="s" number="3092" updated="2025-09-11T10:23:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Collision Avoidance Systems Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collision Avoidance Systems Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify certain regulations to allow for the installation of pulsating light systems for high-mounted stop lamps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5455" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-11T10:21:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Collision Avoidance Systems Act of 2023

This bill allows for the use of a pulsating light system for vehicle braking.

Specifically, Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard Number&#160;108 (Standard 108)&#160;must be deemed to allow for the use of a pulsating light system on&#160;covered vehicles (i.e., passenger cars, multipurpose passenger vehicles, trucks, buses, trailers, and motorcycles). The Department of Transportation must issue regulations to update Standard 108 to (1) include performance-based standards for pulsating light systems, and (2)&#160;allow for the use of the systems on motor vehicles.

As background, Standard 108 regulates all automotive lighting, signaling, and reflective devices. Under the bill, a pulsating light system includes a system for a high-mounted stop lamp in which the lamp pulses rapidly no more than four times and for no more than 1.2 seconds when the brake of the vehicle is applied and then converts to a continuous light (as a normal stop lamp) until the brake is released.</summary>
</bill>
