<bill session="117" type="s" number="2428" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 31, United States Code, to modify False Claims Act procedures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">False Claims Amendments Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">False Claims Amendments Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">False Claims Amendments Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Durbin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="166">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 166.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-18T22:24:25Z" status="Reported to Senate">False Claims Amendments Act of 2021

This bill revises procedures under the False Claims Act (FCA), a law that rewards whistleblowers (known as relators) who bring claims on behalf of the government by allowing them to share in the recovery in cases where the government recovers funds lost to fraud.

To be recoverable under the FCA, a fraud must meet, among other conditions, standards for materiality. In determining materiality, the decision of the government to forego a refund or to pay a claim despite actual knowledge of fraud or falsity shall not be considered dispositive if other reasons exist for that decision with respect to such refund or payment.

In dismissing an action over the objections of the relator, the government must identify a valid government purpose and a rational relation between dismissal and accomplishment of the purpose. The relator must have the opportunity to show that the dismissal is fraudulent, arbitrary and capricious, or contrary to law.

The bill extends relief from retaliatory actions to former employees.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the effectiveness of the FCA.</summary>
</bill>
