<bill session="108" type="s" number="710" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:27Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Anti-Atrocity Alien Deportation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that aliens who commit acts of torture, extrajudicial killings, or other specified atrocities abroad are inadmissible and removable and to establish within the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice an Office of Special Investigations having responsibilities under that Act with respect to all alien participants in war crimes, genocide, and the commission of acts of torture and extrajudicial killings abroad.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Anti-Atrocity Alien Deportation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Atrocity Alien Deportation Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2003-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2003-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2003-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4436-4439"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S4439" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-06">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="373">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 373.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-24">
      <text>By Senator Hatch from Committee on the Judiciary filed written report. Report No. 108-209.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8667"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1440" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Due process of law"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Extradition"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Foreign leaders"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Nazism"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Torture"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Anti-Atrocity Alien Deportation Act of 2003 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for the inadmissibility and removability of aliens who have committed, ordered, assisted, incited, or otherwise participated in acts of torture (as defined in title 18, United States Code) or extrajudicial killings abroad (as defined in the Torture Victims Protection Act of 1991).Redefines "genocide" for such purposes to cover an alien who has ordered, incited, assisted, or otherwise participated in conduct outside the United States that would, if committed in the United States or by a U.S. national, be genocide (as defined in title 18, United States Code).Redefines "severe violations of religious freedom" with respect to the inadmissibility and removability of a foreign government official to cover an alien who, while serving as a foreign government official, was responsible for or directly carried out at any time severe violations of religious freedom (as defined in the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998). Eliminates the bar to the admission of such person's spouse or children.Prohibits the waiver of inadmissibility and temporary admission of such aliens.Prohibits an alien who has engaged in Nazi persecution, genocide, acts of torture, extrajudicial killings, or severe violations of religious freedom from establishing good moral character under such Act.Directs the Attorney General to: (1) establish within the Criminal Division of the Department of Justice an Office of Special Investigations to investigate and denaturalize an alien who has participated in Nazi persecution, genocide, torture, or extrajudicial killing abroad; and (2) consult with the Secretary of Homeland Security regarding actions to prosecute or extradite such aliens.States that in determining the proper legal action against such an alien, consideration shall be given to the availability of U.S. prosecution or removal to a foreign jurisdiction for prosecution.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-209</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
