<bill session="116" type="h" number="3892" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">START Career Pathways Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to award competitive grants for the purpose of developing, offering, improving, and providing educational or career pathway programs for workers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Short-Term Accelerated Reskilling Tracks Career Pathways Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">START Career Pathways Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2019-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education and literacy"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-22T15:10:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Short-Term Accelerated Reskilling Tracks Career Pathways Act or the START Career Pathways Act

This bill directs the Department of Labor, in coordination with the Department of Education, to award competitive grants to eligible institutions of higher education and vocational institutions to develop, offer, improve and provide educational or career pathway programs for workers. Grants funds must be used for specified purposes, including for career pathway programs that provide relevant job training to meet the needs of employers in high-skill, high-wage, or in demand sectors or occupations and that may include registered apprenticeship programs. .

Beginning on October 1, 2019, Labor shall carry out a program to award START federal Pell Grants to students in short-term programs that prepare participants for employment opportunities in high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand sectors or occupations in a geographic area in which the programs are offered.</summary>
</bill>
