<bill session="118" type="h" number="2824" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIGDA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIGDA Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Innovation in Global Development Assistance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support prioritization and expanded use of innovation at the United States Agency for International Development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2023-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-14T21:38:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Fostering Innovation in Global Development Assistance Act of 2023 or the FIGDA Act of 2023

This bill addresses innovation in U.S. development assistance.

For example, the bill authorizes or provides statutory authority for the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) to

 appoint a chief innovation officer; employ innovation fellows to expand the use of innovation, technology, and research with respect to USAID development assistance authorities; provide flexible funding to support expanded use of innovation; and participate in the Global Innovation Fund and designate a USAID employee to serve on the fund's board as a representative of the United States. The bill also requires USAID to establish a program to integrate proven and rigorously demonstrated innovations into USAID programming and operating budgets.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
