<bill session="119" type="s" number="3012" updated="2025-11-24T20:30:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-11-07">PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-11-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shutdown Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Shutdown Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to appropriate funds for pay and allowances of excepted Federal employees for periods of work performed during a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2025-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2025-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2025-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001243" joined="2025-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2025-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-15">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="191">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 191.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-10-21">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7184-7185" label=""/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-21">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7185" label=""/>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="585" datetime="2025-10-23" where="s" result="fail" state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 54 - 45. Record Vote Number: 585.</text>
    </vote-aux>
    <action datetime="2025-10-23">
      <text>Motion by Senator Thune to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the motion to proceed to S. 3012 was not invoked (Record Vote No. 585) made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-07">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of the motion to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the motion to proceed to S. 3012 was not invoked (Record Vote No. 585) agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-11-07">
      <text>Motion by Senator Thune to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the motion to proceed to S. 3012 was not invoked (Record Vote No. 585) agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <vote-aux how="roll" type="cloture" roll="609" datetime="2025-11-07" where="s" result="fail" state="PROV_KILL:CLOTUREFAILED">
      <text>Upon reconsideration, cloture on the motion to proceed to the measure not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 53 - 43. Record Vote Number: 609.</text>
    </vote-aux>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3001" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5801" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3933"/>
    <amendment number="s3932"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2025-10-20T19:23:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Shutdown Fairness Act

This bill provides appropriations to pay federal employees who work during a government shutdown.

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations for federal agencies to provide standard rates of pay, allowances, pay differentials, benefits, and other payments to excepted employees for work performed during any period in which interim continuing appropriations or full-year appropriations are not in effect for a fiscal year (i.e., a government shutdown). An excepted employee is an employee who is required to work during a government shutdown.

Under current law, excepted employees are not paid until the government shutdown is over. This bill provides appropriations to pay excepted employees during a government shutdown. The bill also specifies that the term&#160;excepted employee includes certain contractors who support federal employees during a government shutdown and members of the Armed Forces who are on active duty.&#160;

A federal agency may not use the funds provided by this bill during any period in which continuing appropriations are in effect for the purpose of paying&#160;excepted employees of the agency.

The bill must take effect as if it had been enacted on September 30, 2025.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
