<bill session="119" type="h" number="1831" updated="2025-06-03T13:58:29Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a pilot program for the prevention and mitigation of acts of terrorism using motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out a pilot program for the prevention and mitigation of acts of terrorism using motor vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism and Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-03T13:52:20Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a pilot program for the prevention and mitigation of acts of terrorism using motor vehicles.

Among other things, the pilot program must&#160;

develop a uniform standard for the type of information collected by rental agencies;distribute guidance for improving the suspicious activity reporting process; andestablish a procedure for dealers and rental companies to check information against a designated watch list to&#160;provide notice of a sale or rental to the Federal Bureau of Investigation, if DHS determines that this is&#160;necessary.Under the bill, a dealer or rental company is not liable for any action taken in accordance with the pilot program.

DHS and the Transportation Security Administration must jointly submit regular reports to Congress on the pilot program.&#160;

In addition, DHS must submit a study to Congress that examines how to work with rental car and ride sharing companies on how to identify risks and threats of terrorist attacks.</summary>
</bill>
