<bill session="118" type="s" number="1969" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">De Minimis Reciprocity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">De Minimis Reciprocity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to require reciprocity with respect to de minimis entries of articles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7571" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3878" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-05T14:23:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">De Minimis Reciprocity Act of 2023

This bill makes various changes to&#160;de minimis treatment of U.S. imports. (Current law allows for imports under a de minimis threshold to enter the United States&#160;free of tariffs and taxes with minimal inspection. In 2016, Congress raised&#160;this threshold from $200 to $800.)

Specifically, the Department of the Treasury must prescribe&#160;regulations to establish dollar amount thresholds (which may not exceed $800) for de minimis entries. Treasury must establish a threshold for each country that takes into consideration (1) the dollar amount threshold of that country for de minimis entries from the United States; and (2) any related thresholds of that country, such as a threshold relating to a value-added tax on imports.

The bill establishes in the Treasury the Re-shoring and Near-shoring Account. Amounts in&#160;this account must be available for facilitating the movement of manufacturing from China to the United States.

Treasury must annually publish a list of countries that are not eligible for de minimis treatment. Treasury must establish the conditions for including a country on this list, with specified considerations. Further, the bill requires China and Russia to be included on this list.

The bill&#160;requires that imports&#160;eligible for de minimis treatment must be&#160;transported into the United States&#160;by a contract carrier. The&#160;contract carrier must&#160;(1) collect additional data related to these imports, and (2) collect duties and taxes&#160;owed on these imports and remit those duties and taxes to&#160;U.S. Customs and Border Protection. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
