<bill session="108" type="h" number="670" updated="2023-01-15T21:48:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Flood Loss Mitigation Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to provide for identification, mitigation, and purchase of properties insured under the national flood insurance program that suffer repetitive losses.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Loss Mitigation Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Buildings"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Flood damage prevention"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Flood Loss Mitigation Act of 2003 - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to authorize the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to: (1) carry out mitigation activities that reduce flood damages to qualified repetitive loss structures; and (2) purchase such structures, but only for public or open space use that is consistent with sound land management and use policies.Requires the Director to determine for each fiscal year the portion of amounts in the National Flood Insurance Fund attributable to savings from such activities and purchases, which shall be available for such activities and purchases in that fiscal year. Allows the Director, after determining that 75 percent of such existing qualified repetitive loss structures have been provided mitigation that sufficiently reduces the risk of losses from flooding or have been purchased, to use up to 75 percent of the amount reserved for such activities and purchases for the costs of mapping activities.Allows the Director, in cases of such structures whose owners refused purchase or mitigation offers: (1) to deny the provision of new flood insurance coverage and to cancel existing coverage; or (2) to increase the chargeable risk premium rate for new coverage to an amount that is not more than the applicable estimated risk premium rate. Allows the Director to deny or cancel existing coverage for properties for which fraudulent claims have been made. Permits appeals by owners aggrieved by any such determinations.</summary>
</bill>
