<bill session="117" type="h" number="6510" updated="2022-12-30T03:49:00Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP Campus Hunger Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Campus Hunger Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Transparency to Overcome Poverty and Campus Hunger Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require that certain information with respect to nutrition assistance programs be annually disclosed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2022-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2022-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-31T19:39:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Transparency to Overcome Poverty and Campus Hunger Act or the STOP Campus Hunger Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student-aid programs to provide students with certain information related to nutrition assistance.

Specifically, such IHEs must annually provide students with

 information on the most recent student eligibility guidance for the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) and the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC); contact information for the state agencies that administer SNAP and WIC; and information on food pantries, food assistance facilities, and other services that are available to enrolled students. The bill also requires the Department of Education to annually update its College Navigator website with the most recent student eligibility guidance for SNAP and WIC.</summary>
</bill>
