<bill session="118" type="h" number="9781" updated="2024-12-16T19:17:07Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing Real Opportunities for Growth to Rising Entrepreneurs for Sustained Success (PROGRESS) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Real Opportunities for Growth to Rising Entrepreneurs for Sustained Success (PROGRESS) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a tax credit for investors in start-up businesses, to provide a credit for wages paid by start-up businesses to their first employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001080"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2024-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2024-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5144" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-25T18:49:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Real Opportunities for Growth to Rising Entrepreneurs for Sustained Success (PROGRESS) Act

This bill provides a new small business investor tax credit for investments made into a small business (typically a start-up), subject to single year and lifetime limits. The bill also provides a first employee business wage tax credit for wages paid or incurred by a small business, subject to single year and lifetime limits.

Under the bill, an investor may claim as part of the general business tax credit up to 50% of the amount of a loan or purchase of stock in a small business, limited to $10,000 in a single year and $50,000 in total.&#160;

The bill also allows a small business owner to claim as part of the general business tax credit up to 25% of employee wages, limited to $10,000 in a single year and $40,000 in total. The employee wage business tax credit may be claimed against the business&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s income or, if elected, against the business&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s payroll taxes.

For purposes of both business tax credits, a small business is a business that has at least one full-time employee (or the equivalent) and is owned by a resident or citizen of the United States who has an average taxable income for the three prior tax years of $100,000 or less (or $200,000 if filing a joint return or as head of household).</summary>
</bill>
