<bill session="117" type="s" number="4757" updated="2023-01-19T05:15:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TICKER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TICKER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trading and Investing with Clear Knowledge and Expectations about Risk Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require national securities exchanges to identify issuers that are consolidated variable interest entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-13T15:32:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trading and Investing with Clear Knowledge and Expectations about Risk Act or the TICKER Act 

This bill requires the identification of consolidated variable interest entities on securities exchanges. Specifically, the symbol used on the exchange must identify these entities as consolidated variable interest entities. (A consolidated variable interest entity is a business structure where an investor holds a controlling interest in an entity through contractual agreements rather than having a majority of voting rights.)

In addition, the Securities and Exchange Commission must require brokers and dealers to warn investors in these entities that those investors may lack legal recourse with respect to these investments.</summary>
</bill>
