<bill session="117" type="h" number="3619" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding United States Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide increased transparency and accountability regarding potential foreign influence in research and development programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding United States Research Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2021-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000616" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-09T19:29:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding United States Research Act 

This bill imposes certain reporting requirements on the sponsor of an F, M, or J (student or exchange visitor) visa and authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to revoke such a visa in certain instances. It also expands disclosure requirements for applicants of federal research and development awards.

The Department of State must require a sponsor of a J visa to report any change to the visa holder's primary field of study. The State Department and DHS shall require a sponsor of an F, M, or J visa to report when the visa holder is participating in a federally funded research program.

DHS may review and revoke an F, M, or J visa in certain instances, such as finding that (1) the visa holder misrepresented an intention to pursue a field of study, or (2) the visa holder's participation in a federally funded research program poses a national security risk. The bill also imposes certain limits on the ability to appeal such a revocation decision.

The bill also requires applications for federal research and development awards to disclose any in-kind contributions received by the applicant. Furthermore, if an applicant works for an institution that is required to file disclosures relating to the receipt of foreign gifts, the application for the federal award must include a certification that the applicant has provided the employing institution all the information necessary to comply with that disclosure requirement.</summary>
</bill>
