<bill session="117" type="h" number="4510" updated="2023-02-06T16:00:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the designation of areas as Health Enterprise Zones to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in such areas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2021-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000874" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000385" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2021-08-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2021-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2021-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5293" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-01T14:09:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2021

This bill provides for the designation of Health Enterprise Zones in certain geographic areas with documented and measurable health disparities. This designation, which expires 10 fiscal years after the bill's enactment, confers eligibility for certain grants, student loan repayment programs, and tax credits for those working to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in these zones.

Specifically, community-based nonprofits or local government agencies, in coalition with health care providers, social service organizations, and others, may apply to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for the designation. The application must include a plan to reduce health disparities and achieve other outcomes.

In implementing the program, HHS must consult with, among others, the Department of Housing and Urban Development. When approving applications, HHS shall consider factors including geographic diversity and the commitment of supporting funds from the private sector. HHS (1) may award grants to organizations or agencies that applied for the designation to support activities aligned with their plans, and (2) must carry out a student loan repayment program for health care providers who agree to provide services in a Health Enterprise Zone.

In addition, the bill establishes tax credits for employers that hire, and individuals who work as, Health Enterprise Zone workers.</summary>
</bill>
