<bill session="117" type="h" number="7131" updated="2023-08-20T20:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Authority Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote economic growth and recovery throughout the Great Lakes region, to restore and to protect America's principal source of fresh water, which holds twenty percent of the world's freshwater, making it the largest system in the world, to foster innovation and to advance world-class workforce, education, training, and adjustment institutions for better jobs in the Great Lakes region, to strengthen and to expand the core U.S. manufacturing and industrial base, and the required energy systems to sustain and to power production, and to work with the Federal Government and provinces of Canada on our mutual Great Lakes challenges including the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Seaway, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Authority Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2022-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000581" joined="2022-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001214" joined="2022-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2022-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2022-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4011-4012"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-20T20:36:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Lakes Authority Act of 2022

This bill establishes the Great Lakes Authority to

 promote economic development and job creation; restore and protect fresh water; foster innovation to strengthen and expand manufacturing; promote cleaner and more sustainable power production; establish and administer funding mechanisms to finance clean energy, green infrastructure, water infrastructure, wastewater infrastructure, and broadband infrastructure projects in the region; create a regional development plan; promote affordable access to energy and broadband services in the region; provide technical assistance to entities receiving financial assistance from the authority; and select a location for the National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory established by this bill. The authority must be composed of (1) a chairperson appointed by the President; and (2) one member from each of the following states: Illinois, Indiana, Michigan, Minnesota, New York, Ohio, Pennsylvania, and Wisconsin.</summary>
</bill>
