<bill session="109" type="s" number="2399" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:51Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Volunteer Firefighter and EMS Personnel Job Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit termination of employment of volunteers firefighters and emergency medical personnel responding to emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Volunteer Firefighter and EMS Personnel Job Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2006-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2006-04-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3949" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Seniority in employment"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-08T20:18:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Volunteer Firefighter and EMS Personnel Job Protection Act - Prohibits any employee from being terminated, demoted, or discriminated against in the terms or conditions of employment because the employee is absent or late as a result of serving as a volunteer firefighter or providing volunteer emergency medical services as part of a response to an emergency or major disaster. Excludes absences for which the employee: (1) is absent for more than 14 days per calendar year; (2) responds to an emergency or major disaster without being official deployed in accordance with a coordinator national deployment system; or (3) fails to provide written verification within a reasonable period of time.

Allows employers to: (1) reduce the employee's regular pay for such time as the employee is absent; and (2) require the employee to provide written verification from the supervising Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), state, or local official that such employee responded in an official capacity at a specified time and date.

Requires such an employee to make a reasonable effort to notify his or her employer that he or she may be absent or late.

Gives such an employee a private cause of action for discrimination which violates this Act.</summary>
</bill>
