<bill session="117" type="h" number="2176" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:03Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Access to Domestic Mineral Production Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the continued and uninterrupted production of domestic minerals in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Access to Domestic Mineral Production Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-02T18:36:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Access to Domestic Mineral Production Act

This bill limits the authority of the Department of the Interior to withdraw federal public lands from mineral exploration.

Specifically, the bill prohibits Interior from making such a withdrawal until a study has been completed that demonstrates that the proposed withdrawal will not result in any negative impacts to national security by limiting access to critical minerals.

In addition, the bill requires Interior to obtain the approval of Congress before withdrawing federal public lands in excess of 5,000 acres.

Before any withdrawal is initiated, the U.S. Geological Survey must conduct a mineral assessment to ensure that the minerals to be withdrawn by a proposed withdrawal do not impede the ability of the United States or its allies to procure a secure supply chain of essential resources needed for the U.S. economy and allied nations, including resources for national security and for U.S. energy infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
