<bill session="118" type="s" number="292" updated="2025-01-14T17:12:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northern Border Regional Commission Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Border Regional Commission Reauthorization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 40, United States Code, to modify certain requirements for Regional Commissions, to reauthorize the Northern Border Regional Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4188" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-22T18:02:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Northern Border Regional Commission Reauthorization Act of 2023

This bill makes changes to the authorities and programs of regional economic and infrastructure development commissions.

 Specifically, the bill reauthorizes the Northern Border Regional Commission (NBRC) and establishes and expands NBRC grant programs. The NBRC must establish a state capacity building program to provide grants to commission states (Maine, New Hampshire, New York, and Vermont) to better support business retention and expansion in eligible counties and for other specified purposes. Each commission state shall provide to the NBRC an annual work plan that includes the proposed use of the grant.

 Additionally, the NBRC may make grants for the planning, construction, equipment, and operation of demonstration health, nutrition, and child care projects. Such grants must give special emphasis to projects and activities to address substance use disorders, including opioid and methamphetamine use.

 The bill authorizes these regional commissions (as part of economic and infrastructure development grants) to (1) design, build, implement, or upgrade transportation or basic public infrastructure or workforce capacity to support the adaptation to and mitigation of climate challenges; and (2) promote the production of housing to meet economic development and workforce needs.

Each commission may accept transfers of funds from other federal agencies. Discretionary grants made by a commission to implement significant regional initiatives, to take advantage of special development opportunities, or to respond to emergency economic distress may be made without regard to specified percentage limitations. The bill limits the aggregate amount of discretionary grants.</summary>
</bill>
