<bill session="112" type="h" number="3843" updated="2019-11-15T21:07:19Z">
  <state datetime="2012-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to the National Iranian Oil Company and the National Iranian Tanker Company.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to the National Iranian Oil Company and the National Iranian Tanker Company.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000410"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2012-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2012-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on International Monetary Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA20" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Financial Institutions and Monetary Policy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="2101" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-09T17:33:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Comprehensive Iran Sanctions, Accountability, and Divestment Act of 2010 to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to determine whether the National Iranian Oil Company (NIOC) or the National Iranian Tanker Company (NITC) is an agent or affiliate of Iran's Islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps (IRGC) and submit such determination to Congress.

Applies, 180 days after the enactment of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (P.L. 112-81), specified prohibitions and conditions on U.S. correspondent or payable-through accounts of foreign financial institutions that engage in petroleum or petroleum product transactions with, or provide related financial services to, the NIOC or NITC if the President determines that there is a sufficient supply of non-Iranian petroleum and petroleum product sources to permit purchasers of Iranian petroleum and petroleum products to reduce significantly their purchases from Iran.

Exempts from such provision foreign financial institutions from a country that has significantly reduced its crude oil purchases from Iran.</summary>
</bill>
