<bill session="116" type="s" number="4277" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:37Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Get Toxic Substances Out of Schools Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Get Toxic Substances Out of Schools Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to reauthorize healthy high-performance schools, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-12T02:27:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Get Toxic Substances Out of Schools Act of 2020

This bill reauthorizes and modifies the program of Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) grants to states for the provision of assistance, development of programs, monitoring, and remediation related to environmental hazards (e.g., hazardous substances) in school facilities.

The bill requires the EPA to perform outreach activities to provide information to states about (1) the exposure of children to environmental hazards in school facilities; (2) regulations and guidelines applicable to environmental hazards in school facilities; and (3) other materials to assist in addressing environmental problems, contaminants, hazardous substances, and pollutant emissions. Additionally, the EPA must annually convene school stakeholders (e.g., parents) to discuss topics related to the environmental health of children at school and the prevention, identification, and remediation of contaminants in school buildings and grounds.

The bill adds polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) to the list of emitted substances that the EPA must account for when issuing voluntary guidelines to states for the purpose of their environmental health programs. Such guidelines must also (1) provide technical assistance for the removal, remediation, and disposal of PCBs and other hazardous substances; and (2) collect an inventory of schools affected by PCBs and other hazardous substances.

To the maximum extent possible, the EPA must make publicly available (1) information on the exposure of children to environmental hazards in school facilities, and (2) an inventory of schools in which PCBs have been found in light ballasts or other media.</summary>
</bill>
