<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3024</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:31Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:31Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-02-23</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-02-23T21:23:07Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Small Business Job Creation Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>3103</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-03-10</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S706-707)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S704-706)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000663</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Snowe, Olympia J. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Olympia</firstName>
        <lastName>Snowe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000590</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Pryor, Mark L. [D-AR]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Pryor</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <middleName>Lunsford</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-02-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Budget process</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small Business Administration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Small business</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Unemployment</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-09-08T15:09:49Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010 - Amends the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 to require the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) to include in the statement submitted to an authorizing congressional committee for a public bill or joint resolution reported by that committee for which estimated direct costs of all federal intergovernmental mandates, or all federal private sector mandates, will equal or exceed $5 billion (adjusted annually for inflation) estimates of the potential job creation or job loss in state, local, and tribal governments, or in the private sector, as a result of such mandates. </p> <p>Amends the Regulatory Flexibility Act to require: (1) each initial regulatory flexibility analysis to contain a detailed statement estimating the additional cumulative economic impact of the proposed rule on small businesses; (2) an agency to notify the Chief Counsel for Advocacy of the Small Business Administration (SBA) of any draft rules that may have a significant economic impact on a substantial number of small businesses; (3) each final regulatory flexibility analysis to include the agency's response to any comments filed by the Chief Counsel in response to the proposed rule; and (4) the agency to publish the final regulatory flexibility analysis on its website.</p> <p>Requires each agency: (1) to place on its website its plan for the periodic review of rules, providing for the review of all agency rules at specified intervals; and (2) in reviewing the rules, to consider specified factors, including the continued need for the rule, the nature of complaints received, and the rule's complexity and current impact.</p> <p>Requires: (1) the Office of Advocacy of the SBA to carry out responsibilities concerning the analysis of regulatory functions; (2) each federal budget to include a separate statement of the amount requested for the Office, designated in a separate account in the General Fund of the Treasury; and (3) the SBA Administrator to provide the Office with appropriate office space and necessary equipment, operating budget, communications, and maintenance services.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to ensure that the creation of jobs by small businesses is considered during the Federal legislative and rulemaking process, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Job Impact Analysis Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-02-23T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3024is/xml/BILLS-111s3024is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S706-707)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
