<bill session="118" type="h" number="2568" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IMAGES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMAGES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improvement of Mapping, Addresses, Geography, Elevations, and Structures Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for improvements to National Flood Insurance Program rate maps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001195"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2023-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-02T17:11:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Improvement of Mapping, Addresses, Geography, Elevations, and Structures Act of 2023 or the IMAGES Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes through FY2029, and otherwise revises, the National Flood Mapping Program.

 Specifically, the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must (1) integrate planimetric features (i.e., nontopographic features) including parcel identification data and address information in National Flood Insurance Program (NFIP) rate maps (community maps delineating flood hazard areas, flood elevations, and flood risk zones applicable to flood insurance rate determination); (2) update rate maps to reflect specified timely geographic data and protocols; and (3) publish NFIP rate map data through a publicly available national geospatial data repository.

FEMA must also coordinate with the United States Geological Survey to ensure maintenance of stream flow gages and award certain contracts in accordance with existing qualification procedures applicable to architectural and engineering services.

 The bill also allocates funds from the National Flood Insurance Fund for the creation and maintenance of NFIP rate maps.</summary>
</bill>
