<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3285</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:22:02Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:22:02Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-10-31</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. ISSA:H.R. 3285.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:Clause 17 of Section 8 of Article I of the Constitution ofthe United States grants the Congress the power to enact thislaw. (To exercise exclusive Legislation in all Caseswhatsoever, over such District . . .)____________________[Page H7165]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
        <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo27</systemCode>
            <name>Health Care and Financial Services Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2011-11-02T20:27:09Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-10-31T17:00:25Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-11-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo27</systemCode>
            <name>Health Care and Financial Services Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-31</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsgo00</systemCode>
            <name>Oversight and Accountability Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-31</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-10-31</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000056</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Issa, Darrell E. [R-CA-49]</fullName>
        <firstName>DARRELL</firstName>
        <lastName>ISSA</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <district>49</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>District of Columbia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug, alcohol, tobacco use</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud offenses and financial crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State and local government operations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Subversive activities</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-10-31</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-02-21T17:59:16Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>District of Columbia Employee Suitability Act of 2011 - Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to establish criteria to determine whether an individual is suitable for employment with the District of Columbia government.</p> <p>Authorizes the hiring authority involved, subject to exceptions, to find an individual unsuitable and take a suitability action only on the basis of: (1) misconduct or negligence in employment; (2) criminal or dishonest conduct; (3) material, intentional false statement, or deception or fraud in examination or appointment; (4) alcohol abuse of a specified character; (5) illegal use of narcotics, drugs, or other controlled substances without evidence of substantial rehabilitation; (6) knowing and willful engagement in acts or activities designed to overthrow the U.S. government by force; and (7) any statutory or regulatory bar preventing the lawful employment of the individual involved in the position in question.</p> <p>Specifies additional factors the hiring authority may consider.</p> <p>Prohibits a hiring authority from making a new determination under this Act for an individual who has already been determined suitable or fit based on character or conduct unless: (1) a new investigation is required under the District of Columbia Government Comprehensive Merit Personnel Act of 1978 (Merit Personnel Act) or any successor law, or (2) no new investigation is required but the investigative record on file for the individual shows conduct incompatible with the core duties of the relevant covered position.</p> <p>Makes such suitability determination factors: (1) applicable to any office in the District of Columbia executive branch and to any District of Columbia independent agency, and (2) inapplicable to the Council and courts of the District of Columbia.</p> <p>Prohibits appointments to any position in the excepted service under the Merit Personnel Act unless the individual applies for and submits to a criminal background check in accordance with the Criminal Background Checks for the Protection of Children Act of 2004.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>District of Columbia Employee Suitability Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>District of Columbia Employee Suitability Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to establish factors for making determinations on the suitability of individuals for employment with the District of Columbia Government, to require individuals to undergo criminal background checks as a condition of appointment in the excepted service of the District Government, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>District of Columbia Employee Suitability Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2011-10-31T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr3285ih/xml/BILLS-112hr3285ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-11-02</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health Care, District of Columbia, Census and the National Archives.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
