<bill session="111" type="s" number="754" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:40Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Methadone Treatment and Protection Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for increased Federal oversight of methadone treatment.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Methadone Treatment and Protection Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2009-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2010-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4080"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-12T12:45:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Methadone Treatment and Protection Act of 2009 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to: (1) direct the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to award grants to states and nonprofit community organizations to distribute culturally sensitive educational materials about the dangers of opioid abuse, including methadone abuse; (2) establish a Controlled Substances Clinical Standards Commission to develop safe dosing standards for all forms of methadone, benchmark standards for the reduction of methadone abuse, appropriate conversion factors when transitioning patients from one opioid to another, guidelines for initiating pain management with methadone, and patient and practitioner education standards; (3) increase funding for the controlled substance monitoring program; and (4) require the completion of a Model Opioid Treatment Program Mortality Report and the establishment of a National Opioid Death Registry.

Amends the Controlled Substances Act to: (1) set forth training requirements for health care practitioners registered to prescribe or dispense methadone or other opioids; and (2) require opioid treatment clinics to make acceptable arrangements for the distribution of methadone to patients restricted from taking home doses when the clinic is closed.

Prohibits the writing of prescriptions or dispensing of a 40-mg diskette of methadone unless such prescription or dispensation is consistent with current Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA) methadone policy.</summary>
</bill>
