<bill session="117" type="s" number="3535" updated="2023-08-07T18:00:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Heating and Cooling Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heating and Cooling Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 to increase the availability of heating and cooling assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2022-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2022-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6437" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor and aged"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T17:50:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Heating and Cooling Relief Act

This bill provides additional energy assistance to households, including heating and cooling assistance.

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes through FY2031 and revises the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program. Under the existing program, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) may award grants to states for assisting low-income households that pay a high proportion of their income for home energy. To be eligible under the existing program, households must have incomes which do not exceed the greater of an amount equal to 150% of the poverty level for their state or an amount equal to 60% of the state median income. The bill expands eligibility to households with incomes which do not exceed the greater of an amount equal to 250% of the poverty line as defined in the Community Services Block Grant Act or an amount equal to 80% of the state median income. In addition, the bill expands eligibility to households with a monthly energy burden of 3% or more per year.

It also requires states to establish procedures to protect households receiving assistance under the program from energy shutoffs and certain late fees.

In addition, the bill requires HHS and the Department of Energy to jointly carry out a program that awards grants to states and local governments for developing and implementing interagency plans to reduce energy burdens for eligible households with high home energy use. The plans must promote the reduction of energy from fossil fuels.</summary>
</bill>
