<amendment session="109" chamber="s" number="4101" updated="2022-02-03T05:31:02Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2611" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-05-24">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001016"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-05-22"/>
  <description>To enhance border security by creating a pilot SAFE Visa Program to grant visas to authorized nationals of a NAFTA or CAFTA-DR country who receive employment offers in job areas in the United States that have been certified by the Secretary of Labor as having a shortage of workers.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-05-24" how="roll" result="fail" roll="148">
      <text>Amendment SA 4101 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 31 - 67. Record Vote Number: 148.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Amendment SA 4101 proposed by Senator Hutchison. (consideration: CR S5073-5075, S5077-5078, S5078-5080, S5092-5093; text: CR S5074-5075) To enhance border security by creating a pilot SAFE Visa Program to grant visas to authorized nationals of a NAFTA or CAFTA-DR country who receive employment offers in job areas in the United States that have been certified by the Secretary of Labor as having a shortage of workers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 4101 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 31 - 67. Record Vote Number: 148.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 4101 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 31 - 67. Record Vote Number: 148.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-24">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4101 proposed by Senator Hutchison.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5073-5075, S5077-5078, S5078-5080, S5092-5093" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5074-5075" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
