<bill session="110" type="s" number="3620" updated="2019-11-15T21:59:22Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Child Care Investment Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to enable States to carry out quality initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2008-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2008-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9685"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Group homes"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infants"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-11-28T16:17:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Child Care Investment Act of 2008 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) of title IV of the Social Security Act to increase appropriations for child care assistance grants for FY2009-FY2014.

Makes appropriations for FY2009-FY2014 for grants to states to establish: (1) a Quality Rating and Improvement System (or maintain such a system) for center-based child care providers, group home child care providers, family child care providers, and other early childhood education providers; (2) a statewide network of infant and toddler specialists to train such providers; (3) standards that require at least 40 hours of appropriate health, safety, and child development training for an individual before employment with or as a licensed or registered child care provider; and (4) requirements that licensed or registered providers are visited by monitoring staff at least twice a year.

Requires the use of such appropriations also to pay reimbursement rates at or above the 75th percentile of market rates for providers of child care services assisted under the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act of 1990.</summary>
</bill>
