<bill session="117" type="h" number="8567" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Apprenticeship Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Apprenticeship Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to support apprenticeship programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000389"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4658" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-29T18:40:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Apprenticeship Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Education to award grants to certain partnerships to enable the development and implementation of a postsecondary apprenticeship program.

An eligible partnership must consist of (1) at least one institution of higher education, (2) at least one individual employer, and (3) a workforce intermediary (an entity that demonstrates expertise in fostering partnerships in order to support postsecondary apprenticeship programs). Such partnership may also include other entities such as a state agency responsible for administering career and technical education, a labor organization, or an economic development agency.

A partnership that receives a grant must use the funds to develop and implement a postsecondary apprenticeship program in a high-skill, high-wage, and in-demand industry sector or occupation. Additionally, an apprenticeship shall qualify as a work-study program through which a student apprentice is eligible for federal financial assistance.</summary>
</bill>
