<bill session="116" type="h" number="7384" updated="2022-06-01T15:30:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safer Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform policing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-01T15:29:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Safer Communities Act

This bill requires a state or local government that receives funds under the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program to maintain a system for sharing disciplinary records of law enforcement officers. It also requires the Department of Justice to award a one-time grant to states to establish a system for sharing disciplinary records.

Additionally, the bill expands death and disability benefits under the Public Safety Officers' Benefits Program (PSOB) to retired public safety officers (e.g., law enforcement officers) and survivors of retired public safety officers who die while engaging in a public or private security obligation. The PSOB program provides death, disability, and education benefits to public safety officers and survivors of public safety officers who are killed or injured in the line of duty.

Finally, the bill directs the Government Accountability Office to study and report on settlement or collaborative agreements entered into pursuant to litigation arising out of allegations of police misconduct.</summary>
</bill>
