<bill session="117" type="s" number="3723" updated="2022-09-03T00:37:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-01">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Russian Sanctions Authority Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="display">Special Russian Sanctions Authority Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation in response to the invasion of Ukraine, to confiscate assets of the Russian Federation and remit those assets to the legitimate Government of Ukraine, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-03-02" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="293">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 293.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Militias and paramilitary groups"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T16:07:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Special Russian Sanctions Authority Act of 2022

This bill imposes sanctions pertaining to Russia and addresses related issues.

The President must impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on (1) members of the United Russia Party in the lower house of Russia's legislature, (2) Russian government officials and officers of Russia's armed forces above certain levels or ranks, and (3) and members of Russia's intelligence apparatus.

The President must also impose property-blocking sanctions on (1) specified individuals, including businessperson Roman Abramovich and Russian Prime Minister Mikhail Mishustin; and (2) the Wagner Group, a Russian private military company.

Furthermore, the bill designates (1) the Wagner Group as a specially designated global terrorist organization, (2) Vladimir Putin as a specially designated global terrorist, and (3) any country in the Western Hemisphere with a military cooperation agreement with Russia as having engaged in a grave hostile act of a foreign power.

The bill also establishes the Joint Task Force on Russian Sanctions, which must coordinate the imposition of Russia-related sanctions.

The President may confiscate and liquidate any Russian government property subject to U.S. jurisdiction and transfer the resulting funds to the government of Ukraine.

The President may provide military hardware to Ukraine's government to resist the Russian invasion.

The Department of State must close all Russian diplomatic facilities in the United States except for the Russian embassy in Washington, DC.

The Department of the Treasury must impose certain reporting requirements related to residential real estate transactions involving Russian politically exposed persons.</summary>
</bill>
