<bill session="111" type="h" number="2869" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy Market Manipulation Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Commodity Futures Trading Commission to take certain actions to prevent the manipulation of energy markets, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Market Manipulation Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2009-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1225" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Commodities markets"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-04T15:48:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Energy Market Manipulation Prevention Act - Directs the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to eliminate excessive speculation in energy contract markets, unwarranted energy price fluctuations, or other unlawful activities that prevent energy prices from accurately reflecting supply and demand.

Requires the Commission to: (1) classify immediately each bank holding company engaged in energy futures trading as a noncommercial participant subject to strict position limits; (2) require immediately hedge funds engaged in energy futures trading to register as noncommercial participants subject to strict speculation limits; (3) eliminate conflicts of interest in which one entity has a hand in predicting oil prices, operating oil assets, and buying or selling oil derivatives; and (4) revoke immediately each staff no-action letter that covers a foreign board of trade that has established trading terminals in this country to trade U.S. commodities to U.S. investors.</summary>
</bill>
