<bill session="117" type="h" number="3201" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:10Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide funds to State transportation departments for surface transportation projects.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Assistance for Vital Enhancements Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000563" joined="2021-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-27T17:59:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Assistance for Vital Enhancements Act or the PAVE Act

This bill provides FY2021 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Transportation for providing emergency assistance to states with transportation projects and activities.

Funds may be used for certain projects that are otherwise eligible for funding through the Surface Transportation Block Grant program (e.g., construction of highways, bridges, and tunnels and some transit capital projects). Funds may also be used for administrative and operating expenses, including employee salaries. Additionally, the federal share of the funds shall be up to 100% (at the election of the recipient) and shall be available for any nonfederal share of other transportation grants, programs, and projects.

The bill designates the funding as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits. Additionally, the amounts provided by the bill are designated as an emergency requirement pursuant to the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO) and the Senate PAYGO rule. (This exempts the budget effects from being counted for the purposes of enforcing the PAYGO rules.)</summary>
</bill>
