<bill session="117" type="h" number="3856" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on disparities associated with race and ethnicity with respect to certain benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on disparities associated with race and ethnicity with respect to certain benefits administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1031" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-09T16:33:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to conduct a study to assess whether there are disparities associated with race and ethnicity with respect to (1) compensation benefits administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), (2) disability ratings determined by the VA, and (3) the rejection of fully developed claims for VA benefits. Additionally, the study must assess whether there is any relationship between such disparities associated with race and ethnicity and other demographic characteristics such as gender and age. The GAO must also develop recommendations to facilitate better data collection on such disparities associated with race and ethnicity.

Within one year, the GAO must brief Congress on the initial results of the study. The GAO must also submit a final report on the study following the briefing.</summary>
</bill>
