<bill session="116" type="s" number="3868" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:19Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic Care for Burn Pits Exposure Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic Care for Burn Pits Exposure Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to evaluate members of the Armed Forces and veterans who have tested positive for a virus certified as a pandemic for potential exposure to open burn pits and toxic airborne chemicals or other airborne contaminants, to conduct a study on the impact of such a pandemic on members and veterans with such exposure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2020-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2020-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2020-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2020-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2020-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6395" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7684" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-07T14:59:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic Care for Burn Pits Exposure Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to ensure that the first health assessment conducted for a member of the Armed Forces or veteran after such an individual tests positive for a virus certified as a pandemic includes an evaluation of whether the individual has been (1) based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit was used, or (2) exposed to toxic airborne chemicals or contaminants relating to service in the Armed Forces. A burn pit is an area used for burning solid waste in open air without equipment.

If such an evaluation establishes that an individual was based or stationed at a location where an open burn pit was used, or that the individual was exposed to toxic airborne chemicals or contaminants, the individual must be enrolled in the Airborne Hazards and Open Burn Pit Registry unless they opt out of enrollment.

The VA's Airborne Hazards and Burn Pits Center of Excellence must conduct a study on the health impacts of infection with a virus designated as a global pandemic, including the coronavirus (i.e., the virus that causes COVID-19), to members of the Armed Forces and veterans who have been exposed to open burn pits and other toxic exposures. The study must be analyzed to assist in preparation for potential future pandemics.</summary>
</bill>
