<bill session="108" type="s" number="2532" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish wilderness areas, promote conservation, improve public land, and provide for the high quality development in Lincoln County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2004-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6898-6901"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-737.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4593" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquifers"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fiber optics"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorology"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pipeline siting"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Traffic signs and signals"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wells"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-23T14:42:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct specified sales of land identified for initial or annual disposal to qualified bidders. Segregates such land, with an exception, from all forms of entry and appropriation under the public land laws (including the mining laws) and operation of the mineral geothermal leasing laws. Prescribes the disposition of gross proceeds from such sales.

Designates certain Federal land in Nevada as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Withdraws such land from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. Provides for continued livestock grazing within such wilderness areas administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM). Declares that the following BLM public land in Lincoln County has been adequately studied for wilderness designation: (1) the Table Mountain Wilderness Study Area; (2) Evergreen A, B, and C Wilderness Study Areas; and (3) parts of wilderness study areas not designated as wilderness under this Act and identified as released. Makes any such land no longer subject to requirements for the status of lands during the period of review for designation as wilderness under the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Permits: (1) management activities (including occasional and temporary use of motorized vehicles) to maintain or restore fish and wildlife populations and the habitats to support them to be carried out within wilderness areas designated by this Act; and (2) Nevada to continue to use aircraft to survey, capture, and provide water for wildlife populations. Directs the Secretary to authorize structures and facilities for wildlife water development projects, including guzzlers, in such wilderness areas.

Directs the Secretary to establish a specified corridor for utilities in Lincoln County and Clark County (Nevada). Authorizes the Secretary to grant rights-of-way to the Southern Nevada Water Authority and Lincoln County Water District to Federal land in those counties for roads, wells, well fields, pipes, pipelines, pump stations, storage facilities, and other facilities and systems necessary for the construction and operation of a water conveyance system. Withdraws such land from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.

Directs the Secretary to conduct a study to investigate ground water quantity, quality, and flow characteristics in the deep carbonate and alluvial aquifers of White Pine County, Nevada.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) relinquish a specified right-of-way corridor and parts of specified utility corridors (the corridor) upon receipt of a payment for its fair market value; and (2) relocate a specified part that is located in the corridor to the area located west of and parallel to the centerline of U.S. Route 93.

Designates a specified system of trails in Lincoln County as the "Silver State Off-Highway Vehicle Trail".

Authorizes the Secretary to convey specified land to Lincoln County and the State of Nevada to be used for natural resources conservation or public parks.

Transfers administrative jurisdiction of specified lands between the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and BLM.</summary>
</bill>
