<bill session="117" type="s" number="982" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:33Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ICBM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the life of the Minuteman III and redirect savings from the development of the new ground-based strategic deterrent program toward the development of a universal coronavirus vaccine, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ICBM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in Cures Before Missiles Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2227" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-01T17:21:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Investing in Cures Before Missiles Act of 2021 or the ICBM Act

This bill addresses the transfer and use of funds intended for defense programs. Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to transfer $1 billion of unobligated balances intended for its ground-based strategic deterrent program to the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease for research on the development of a universal coronavirus vaccine.

Next, the bill requires the Department of Energy to transfer unobligated balances for the W87-1 warhead modification program administered by the National Nuclear Security Administration to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to research and combat emerging and zoonotic infectious diseases.

The bill prohibits the use of funds authorized for FY2022 for the ground-based strategic deterrent program or the W87-1 warhead modification program.

Finally, the bill requires DOD to enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences to study extending to 2050 the life of Minuteman III intercontinental ballistic missiles.</summary>
</bill>
