<bill session="116" type="h" number="8728" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:18Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Soda Ash Funding for Education Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Soda Ash Funding for Education Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require that royalties derived from the production of sodium compounds and related products are disbursed to the State in which production occurred and to the Secretary of Education for educational grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001094"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-25T13:05:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Soda Ash Funding for Education Act of 2020

This bill requires the payment to the Treasury of royalties collected on the quantity or gross value of the output of sodium compounds and related products from federal land.

Of the funds deposited in the Treasury, the Department of the Treasury shall (1) disburse 50% to the state within which such leased federal land is located, and (2) deposit 50% in the Soda Ash Education Equalization Fund established by this bill.

The fund shall be administered by the Department of Education (ED) to provide resources to local educational agencies impacted by changes in sodium royalty rates or changes in soda ash production levels.

ED shall use amounts available in the fund to provide grants to local school districts that meet specified conditions.</summary>
</bill>
