<bill session="108" type="h" number="1524" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:25Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to establish a commemorative trail in connection with the Women's Rights National Historical Park to link properties that are historically and thematically associated with the struggle for women's suffrage, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000284" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2004-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2004-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Signs and symbols"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Women's voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Votes for Women History Trail Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to establish an auto tour route, to be known as the Votes for Women History Trail, to link properties in New York State which are historically and thematically associated with the struggle for women's suffrage in the United States. Requires the National Park Service to administer the Trail through the Women's Rights National Historical Park.Requires the Secretary to: (1) produce and disseminate educational materials regarding the Trail; (2) coordinate the management, planning, and standards of the auto route in partnership with participating properties, other Federal agencies, and State and local governments; and (3) adopt an official symbol or device to mark the Trail and issue guidelines for its use.Authorizes the Secretary to designate as official stops on the Trail: (1) all Park units and programs that pertain to the struggle for women's suffrage; (2) other Federal, State, local, and privately owned properties that have a verifiable connection to such struggle; and (3) other related governmental and nongovernmental facilities and programs of an educational, commemorative, research, or interpretive nature. Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with, and provide technical and financial assistance to, other Federal agencies, New York State, localities, regional governmental bodies, and private entities to coordinate such stops.</summary>
</bill>
