<bill session="117" type="s" number="91" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:28Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Districts Provide Essential Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to include special districts in the coronavirus relief fund, to direct the Secretary to include special districts as an eligible issuer under the Municipal Liquidity Facility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Districts Provide Essential Services Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="535" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-03T17:32:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Special Districts Provide Essential Services Act

This bill makes special districts eligible for the Coronavirus Relief Fund and the Municipal Liquidity Facility program.

Specifically, the bill makes special districts eligible for payments from amounts paid to states from any new appropriations to the fund. A special district must submit a request for payment to the state with information demonstrating that the special district has experienced or is likely to experience during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency

 reduced revenue or operational funding derived from provided services, taxes, fees, or other sources of revenue; reduced indirect funding from the federal government, the state, or a unit of general government below the state level; or as a result of the COVID-19 emergency, increased expenditures necessary to continue operations. The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System shall include special districts as eligible issuers in the Municipal Liquidity Facility program, which was created in response to the COVID-19 emergency to buy municipal securities.</summary>
</bill>
