<bill session="119" type="h" number="1886" updated="2025-11-18T18:07:48Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable College Textbook Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable College Textbook Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the use of open textbooks in order to achieve savings for students and improve textbook price information.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="740" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-13T15:29:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable College Textbook Act

This bill provides statutory authority for an open textbook grant program for&#160;institutions of higher education (IHEs). (A similar program, known as the Open Textbooks Pilot program, first received federal funding in FY2018.)

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Education to make grants to IHEs or states on behalf of IHEs&#160;to support projects that expand the use of open textbooks. An open textbook is an educational resource that either resides in the public domain or has been released under an intellectual license that permits its free use, reuse, modification, and sharing with others.

Within three years of the bill's enactment, the Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on the cost of textbooks at IHEs. This report must examine, among other topics, the factors that have contributed&#160;to the change in the cost of textbooks.</summary>
</bill>
