<bill session="108" type="s" number="187" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Cyber Security Leadership Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the elimination of significant vulnerabilities in the information technology of the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Cyber Security Leadership Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000286"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1079"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cybernetics"/>
    <term name="EBB Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Cyber Security Leadership Act of 2003 - Requires the Chief Information Officer of each Federal agency to: (1) identify the significant vulnerabilities of the information technology (IT) of such agency; (2) establish performance goals for eliminating such vulnerabilities; (3) procure or develop tools to identify and eliminate those vulnerabilities in order to achieve such performance goals; (4) train personnel in the utilization of those tools; (5) test the agency's IT to determine the extent of its compliance with the performance goals; and (6) develop and implement a plan to eliminate significant vulnerabilities in order to achieve compliance.Requires: (1) each Officer to include information on the agency's activities under this Act in annual reports on the agency's information security program and practices submitted to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB); and (2) the OMB Director to ensure the review of such reports by the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST); (3) the NIST Director to designate, as the result of such review, any significant IT vulnerabilities of such broad applicability and severity so as to warrant the use of government-wide guidelines the Director shall develop and make available to such Officers for complying with this Act; and (4) the Secretary of Commerce to mandate agency use of such guidelines.</summary>
</bill>
