<bill session="116" type="h" number="9053" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Congressional Gun Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Congressional Gun Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 40, United States Code, to prevent Members of Congress and their employees from carrying firearms in the Capitol building, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2020-12-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-12-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2020-12-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="U.S. Capitol"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-25T21:52:20Z" status="Introduced in House">No Congressional Gun Loophole Act

This bill prohibits the Capitol Police Board from allowing Members of Congress or their staff to carry firearms on the grounds of the U.S. Capitol or in its buildings. Members and their staff may store firearms in their cars in Capitol complex garages if their possession complies with the firearms laws of the District of Columbia and the firearms are locked with gun locks while on the complex.

Current board regulations allow Members of Congress to keep firearms in their offices; the regulations also allow Members and their staff to transport unloaded and securely wrapped firearms within the Capitol grounds. Firearms are prohibited inside the chambers of the Senate and the House of Representatives, as well as in adjacent lobbies and cloakrooms, the galleries, the Marble Room of the Senate, and the Rayburn Room of the House, unless approved by the Sergeants at Arms for security purposes.</summary>
</bill>
