<bill session="109" type="h" number="3692" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:15Z">
  <state datetime="2005-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Marine Debris Research, Prevention, and Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the United States Coast Guard to help identify, determine sources of, assess, reduce, and prevent marine debris and its adverse impacts on the marine environment and navigation safety, in coordination with non-Federal entities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Debris Research, Prevention, and Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2006-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2005-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2005-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2005-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="362" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biodegradation"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine ecology"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Pollution control"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-23T21:12:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Marine Debris Research, Prevention, and Reduction Act - Establishes within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) a Marine Debris Prevention and Removal Program of project grants to reduce and prevent the occurrence and adverse impacts of marine debris on the marine environment and navigation safety. Requires the Administrator of NOAA to: (1) undertake marine debris mapping, impact assessment, prevention, and removal efforts, with a focus on marine debris posing a threat to living marine resources (particularly endangered or protected species) and navigation safety; (2) improve efforts and actively seek to prevent and reduce fishing gear losses, as well as their adverse impacts on living marine resources and navigation safety; and (3) undertake outreach and education of the public and other stakeholders in the fishing, fishing gear manufacturers, and other marine-dependent industries on sources of and threats associated with marine debris and approaches to identify, determine sources of, reduce, and prevent such debris and its adverse impacts on the marine environment and navigational safety.

Directs the Commandant of the Coast Guard to undertake measures to reduce violations of MARPOL Annex V (Annex V of the International Convention for the Prevention of Pollution from Ships, 1973) and the Act to Prevent Pollution from Ships with respect to the discard of plastics and other garbage from vessels.

Establishes an Interagency Committee on Marine Debris to: (1) coordinate a comprehensive program of marine debris research and activities among federal agencies, in cooperation with nongovernmental organizations, industry, universities, state governments, Indian tribes, and other nations; and (2) foster cost-effective mechanisms to identify, determine sources of, reduce, and prevent marine debris and its adverse impact on the marine environment and navigational safety, including the joint funding of research and mitigation and prevention strategies.</summary>
</bill>
