<bill session="117" type="s" number="5003" updated="2023-08-01T13:45:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Klamath Basin Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2000 to provide the Secretary of the Interior with certain authorities with respect to projects affecting the Klamath Basin watershed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9353" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-24T18:24:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act

This bill addresses projects in the Klamath River Basin in Oregon and California.

 The Bureau of Reclamation must support lowering the Klamath Irrigation District's net delivered power cost through certain agreements (e.g., an agreement with the Bonneville Power Administration).

Further, Reclamation may enter into contracts and agreements with state and local governments, tribes, and private parties to plan, construct, operate, and maintain projects in the basin watershed to include

 facilities to reduce fish entrainment (i.e., the transport of fish along the flow of water, out of their normal habitat and into unnatural or harmful environments); projects that reduce or avoid impacts on aquatic resources caused by diversion of water for irrigation; and projects that restore basin watershed habitats, including tribal fishery resources held in trust. The bill also authorizes Reclamation to pay for a portion of the operation and maintenance costs of an irrigation pumping plant in Tulelake, California. It also provides for contracts to cover certain costs involved with the replacement of the C-Canal flume within the Klamath Project.

Further, the bill provides statutory authorization for Reclamation to implement a 2016 agreement to take ownership and operation of the Keno Dam and operation of the Link River Dam.</summary>
</bill>
