<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1634</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:18:09Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:18:09Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-08-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-08-06T23:21:51Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-08-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S9030-9038)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-08-06</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9029-9030)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-08-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000361</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rockefeller, John D., IV [D-WV]</fullName>
        <firstName>JAY</firstName>
        <lastName>ROCKEFELLER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WV</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000069</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Akaka, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>AKAKA</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KOHIKINA</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-08-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000944</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Brown, Sherrod [D-OH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sherrod</firstName>
        <lastName>Brown</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>OH</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-08-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001265</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Begich, Mark [D-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Begich</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-08-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000802</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Whitehouse, Sheldon [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>Sheldon</firstName>
        <lastName>Whitehouse</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-09-08</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prescription drugs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public contracts and procurement</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-08-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-11-12T15:47:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Medicare Prescription Drug Coverage Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to establish a Federal Coordinated Health Care Office within the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to bring together Medicare and Medicaid officials in order to: (1) integrate benefits more effectively under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA) and SSA title XIX (Medicaid); and (2) improve coordination between the federal government and states for individuals dually eligible for benefits under both programs</p> <p></p> <p></p> <p>Amends Part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of SSA title XVIII to direct the HHS Secretary to: (1) offer one or more Medicare operated prescription drug plans with a service area consisting of the entire United States; and (2) enter into negotiations with pharmaceutical manufacturers to reduce the purchase cost of covered part D drugs for eligible part D individuals who enroll in such a plan. Provides a premium subsidy and cost-sharing for subsidy eligible individuals. Directs the Secretary to establish a formulary that meets certain requirements.</p> <p>Outlines accreditation requirements for all specialized Medicare Advantage plans. Revises requirements relating to specialized Medicare Advantage plans for special needs individuals.</p> <p>Requires continuous updating of eligibility and enrollment data for dual eligible individuals, continuity of prescription drug coverage for such individuals, and collection and sharing of drug utilization data and formulary information for them.</p> <p>Requires each contractor under the HHS Point of Sale Facilitated Enrollment process to enroll full-benefit dual eligible individuals into a Medicare operated prescription drug plan.</p> <p></p> <p></p> <p>Requires the Secretary to lower covered part D drug prices on behalf of Medicare beneficiaries by: (1) negotiating directly with pharmaceutical manufacturers for additional discounts, rebates, and other price concessions; (2) entering into rebate agreements with manufacturers; (3) educating physicians and pharmacists on the comparative clinical effectiveness of covered part D drugs; and (4) instituting prescription drug prices negotiated under the Federal Supply Schedule of the General Services Administration (GSA) for the reimbursement of covered part D drugs.</p> <p></p> <p>Revises requirements for the financial assistance available to low-income Medicare beneficiaries, including those related to enrollment, a Medicare plan complaint system, and use of a single, uniform exceptions and appeals process.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Medicare Prescription Drug Coverage Improvement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Medicare Prescription Drug Coverage Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to protect and improve the benefits provided to dual eligible individuals under the Medicare and Medicaid programs.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Medicare Prescription Drug Coverage Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-08-06T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s1634is/xml/BILLS-111s1634is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-08-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S9030-9038)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
