<bill session="118" type="s" number="528" updated="2025-11-18T20:00:47Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a standard financial aid offer form, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2024-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1972" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1198" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-06T18:20:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Understanding the True Cost of College Act of 2023

This bill requires standardized financial aid terminology and offer forms.

Specifically, the Department of Education (ED) must develop standard terminology and a format for financial aid offer forms based on recommendations from representatives of certain groups, including students, veterans, and institutions of higher education (IHEs).

The consumer-friendly form must include specified details and disclosures, including the estimated cost of attendance, the net price that a student or family is estimated to pay, and the terms and conditions of financial aid.

In addition, ED must (1) test the form with representatives of students, students' families, IHEs, secondary school and postsecondary counselors, and nonprofit consumer groups; and (2) use the results to develop the final form.

Each IHE that participates in federal student-aid programs must (1) use the standard form when offering financial aid to students, and (2) use the standard terminology and definitions developed by ED for all communications related to financial aid offers.</summary>
</bill>
