<bill session="116" type="s" number="3670" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Gila River System in the State of New Mexico as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, to provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2020-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-380.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-14T21:29:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act

This bill designates specified segments of rivers and creeks of the Gila River system in New Mexico as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and transfers 440 acres of land from the Gila National Forest to the Gila Cliff Dwellings Monument.

The comprehensive management plan that is to be prepared for such segments pursuant to the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act must provide for public involvement, including consultation with tribal governments.

 Any nonfederal land within or adjacent to such a segment that is acquired by the United States shall be incorporated in, and be administered as part of, the applicable segment.

No land or interest in land shall be acquired without the owner's consent.

If the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture determines that no other feasible alternative exists, then it may authorize a project or activity that affects the free-flowing characteristics or other values of a segment under its jurisdiction, including (1) the construction, maintenance, and replacement of fish barriers; or (2) the use of chemicals to manage nonnative fish species.</summary>
</bill>
