<bill session="118" type="h" number="3505" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Free Speech On Campus Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Free Speech On Campus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require public institutions of higher education, as a condition of participating in programs under title IV of such Act, to provide a written statement and educational programming to new students on the rights of students under the first amendment to the Constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000401"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-24T13:47:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Free Speech On Campus Act

This bill requires public institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student aid programs to provide students with information about their First Amendment rights.

Specifically, an IHE must provide new and transfer students attending orientation with

 a written statement (that must also be published on the IHE's website) that explains student rights under the First Amendment, affirms the commitment of the IHE to freedom of expression, and includes an assurance that students and invited speakers will not be treated in a manner that violates their freedom of expression; and educational programming (including online resources) that includes the IHE's policies for protecting freedom of expression and lessons for understanding the First Amendment.</summary>
</bill>
