<bill session="116" type="h" number="5788" updated="2022-02-09T03:26:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Sexual Harassment in Public Housing Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act to require a complaint of sexual harassment be annually reported to Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Sexual Harassment in Public Housing Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001308" joined="2020-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2020-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2020-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2020-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2020-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2020-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001175" joined="2020-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-09T19:19:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Sexual Harassment in Public Housing Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) and the Department of Justice (DOJ) to take actions related to reporting and investigating housing-related discrimination and harassment, particularly sexual harassment.

Specifically, HUD must include in its annual report to Congress tabulations of complaints of discriminatory housing practices filed with HUD or a fair housing assistance program in the preceding year. These tabulations must identify whether a complaint alleged discrimination based on race, color, religion, national origin, sex, handicap, or familial status. HUD must consider a complaint of sexual harassment under the category of discrimination based on sex and must include a separate tabulation of the total number of sexual harassment complaints filed.

Additionally, DOJ must establish an initiative to investigate and prosecute allegations of housing-related sexual harassment.</summary>
</bill>
