<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="1518" updated="2021-05-25T04:48:51Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1260" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-05-20">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000293"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-05-18"/>
  <description>To prohibit the cancellation of contracts for physical barriers and other border security measures for which funds already have been obligated and for which penalties will be incurred in the case of such cancellation and prohibiting the use of funds for payment of such penalties.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-05-20" how="roll" result="fail" roll="199">
      <text>Amendment SA 1518, under the order of 5/19/21, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 48. Record Vote Number: 199.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Amendment SA 1518 proposed by Senator Johnson to Amendment SA 1502. (consideration: CR S3176, S3180-3182, S3182-3183; text: CR S3176) To prohibit the cancellation of contracts for physical barriers and other border security measures for which funds already have been obligated and for which penalties will be incurred in the case of such cancellation and prohibiting the use of funds for payment of such penalties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 1518, under the order of 5/19/21, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 48. Record Vote Number: 199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 1518, under the order of 5/19/21, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 46 - 48. Record Vote Number: 199.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 1518 proposed by Senator Johnson to Amendment SA 1502.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
