<bill session="117" type="h" number="8689" updated="2023-01-17T17:47:34Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commercial Space Transportation Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Space Transportation Safety Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to clarify the authority of the National Transportation Safety Board to investigate commercial space transportation accidents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2022-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2022-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2022-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2022-08-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-17T17:44:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Commercial Space Transportation Safety Act of 2022

This bill requires the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) to investigate and establish the facts, circumstances, and cause or probable cause of a commercial space transportation accident in which there is (1) a fatality or significant injury of any individual, regardless of whether the individual was on board the commercial launch vehicle at the time of the accident; or (2) substantial damage to property that is not associated with commercial space launch activities and that is not located at the launch site.

The NTSB shall seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with any other government agency with the authority to certify a commercial space transportation operation or investigate a commercial space transportation accident. The memoranda must delineate the conditions under and manner in which (1) a commercial space transportation accident that may be investigated by the NTSB will be investigated by the other agency, and (2) the NTSB will participate in the other agency's investigation.</summary>
</bill>
