<bill session="108" type="hr" number="851" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:37Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit any committee from sending more than 999 copies of any mass mailing to addresses within the same Congressional district, from sending any mass mailing to an address within a Congressional district if the mailing is postmarked fewer than 90 days immediately before the date of a House election in the district, and from sending any mass mailing as franked mail which does not meet the standards applicable to franked mail sent by elected officers of the House.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit any committee from sending more than 999 copies of any mass mailing to addresses within the same Congressional district, from sending any mass mailing to an address within a Congressional district if the mailing is postmarked fewer than 90 days immediately before the date of a House election in the district, and from sending any mass mailing as franked mail which does not meet the standards applicable to franked mail sent by elected officers of the House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2004-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2004-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional districts"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional mail"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-21T21:38:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit House Committees from sending: (1) more than 999 copies of any mass mailing to addresses within the same congressional district, unless authorized to do so by resolution of the House with respect to the specific mailing; (2) any mass mailing to an address within a congressional district if the mailing is postmarked fewer than 90 days immediately before the date of a House election held in such district; or (3) any mass mailing as franked mail which does not conform to the rules, regulations, and standards prescribed by the House Commission on Congressional Mailing Standards for franked mail sent by elected officers of the House.</summary>
</bill>
