<bill session="117" type="s" number="4670" updated="2023-08-15T17:45:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Housing and Urban Development Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Transportation Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Reauthorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for the Departments of Transportation, and Housing and Urban Development, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8294" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4707" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2264" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2471" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3045" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5140" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2617" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T17:43:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transportation, Housing and Urban Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2023

This bill provides FY2023 appropriations to the Department of Transportation (DOT), the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD), and several related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to DOT for

 the Office of the Secretary, the Federal Aviation Administration, the Federal Highway Administration, the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration, the Federal Railroad Administration, the Federal Transit Administration, the Great Lakes St. Lawrence Seaway Development Corporation, the Maritime Administration, the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, and the Office of Inspector General. The bill provides appropriations to HUD for

 Management and Administration, Public and Indian Housing, Community Planning and Development, Housing Programs, the Federal Housing Administration, the Government National Mortgage Association (Ginnie Mae), Policy Development and Research, Fair Housing and Equal Opportunity, the Office of Lead Hazard Control and Healthy Homes, the Information Technology Fund, and the Office of Inspector General. The bill also provides appropriations to several related agencies, including

 the Access Board, the Federal Maritime Commission, the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) Office of Inspector General, the National Transportation Safety Board, the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation, the Surface Transportation Board, and the U.S. Interagency Council on Homelessness. The bill includes several provisions that establish requirements and authorities for HUD's programs and activities related to disaster relief and recovery.

Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
</bill>
