<bill session="112" type="h" number="4189" updated="2019-11-15T20:49:32Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Defense to provide an annual certification that all programming on the American Forces Radio and Television Service represents the best-faith efforts by the Department of Defense to provide programming for members of the Armed Forces and their families that communicates the policies, priorities, programs, goals, and initiatives of the Department while avoiding airing programming that exhibits values contrary to the values of the Armed Forces and the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">To require the Secretary of Defense to provide an annual certification that all programming on the American Forces Radio and Television Service represents the best-faith efforts by the Department of Defense to provide programming for members of the Armed Forces and their families that communicates the policies, priorities, programs, goals, and initiatives of the Department while avoiding airing programming that exhibits values contrary to the values of the Armed Forces and the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001038" joined="2012-04-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2012-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-16T18:57:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of Congress that programs broadcast by the American Forces Radio and Television Service (AFRTS) should reflect the values, including equality, freedom, and service, to which members of the Armed Forces and Americans aspire, and that the AFRTS should avoid airing programming that has a history of being contrary to such values.

Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to certify annually to Congress that such AFRTS-broadcast programming represents best-faith efforts to communicate the DOD's policies, priorities, programs, goals, and initiatives while avoiding airing programming with values contrary to Armed Forces and U.S. values.</summary>
</bill>
