<bill session="117" type="h" number="5859" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FARM Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FARM Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to require registration statements filed under such Act to be filed in a structured data format which enables the statements to be digitized for purposes of the publicly available electronic database maintained under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T13:25:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Foreign Agents Registration Modernization Act of 2021 or the FARM Act of 2021

This bill modifies requirements related to the electronic database that contains the registrations that an agent of a foreign principal must file with the Department of Justice (DOJ).

Specifically, DOJ must establish and maintain the free and publicly accessible National Foreign Agents Database, which must make such foreign agent registrations searchable, sortable, and downloadable. The database must also make updated or filed registrations immediately available for public inspection. (Currently, DOJ is required maintain a database with these features, but only to the extent that the features are technically practicable.)

The database must also meet federal standards for making digital information accessible to individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
