<bill session="118" type="s" number="2059" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Sanctions on Fentanyl Traffickers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Sanctions on Fentanyl Traffickers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to pharmaceutical companies of the People's Republic of China and certain cartels that traffic fentanyl into the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-11">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T22:47:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Sanctions on Fentanyl Traffickers Act of 2023

This bill provides statutory authority for certain sanctions and extends certain requirements with respect to foreign individuals or entities involved in trafficking fentanyl or fentanyl analogues into the United States.

For example, the bill extends until December 31, 2030, provisions that require the President to report on foreign opioid traffickers. It also requires the President to prioritize individuals who are citizens or nationals of China and entities that are based in China, including pharmaceutical companies, that are involved in trafficking fentanyl or fentanyl analogues in these reports.

In addition, the bill requires the President to continue to impose certain sanctions against specified transnational criminal cartels (i.e., Mexican cartels) and to notify Congress before ending such sanctions.

The bill also provides statutory authority for the executive order titled Imposing Sanctions on Foreign Persons Involved in the Global Illicit Drug Trade, which was issued on December 15, 2021. The order authorizes certain sanctions against foreign individuals or entities that are engaged in international drug trafficking, including blocking banking, property, and other financial transactions.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
