<bill session="119" type="h" number="928" updated="2025-11-20T09:06:42Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Railway Safety Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Railway Safety Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Safe Freight Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance safety requirements for trains transporting hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000530"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000301" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000619" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2025-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2025-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-18T19:06:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Railway Safety Act of 2025

This bill addresses safety requirements for rail carriers and trains transporting hazardous materials.

Specifically, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must issue safety regulations for trains carrying hazardous materials to require that rail carriers or shippers (1) provide state emergency response commissioners with advance notice and information about the hazardous materials; (2) reduce blocked rail crossings; and (3) comply with certain requirements regarding train length and weight specifications, track standards, speed restrictions, and response plans.

DOT must also establish requirements for wayside defect detectors. These are used by railway systems alongside the tracks to detect defects and failures (e.g., wheel bearing failures). Current federal regulations do not require their use, but federal guidance does address their placement and use. Under the bill, DOT must issue regulations establishing requirements for the installation, repair, testing, maintenance, and operation of wayside defect detectors for each rail carrier operating a train carrying hazardous materials.

The bill also

increases the maximum fines DOT may impose on rail carriers for violating safety regulations;requires DOT to update rail car inspection regulations and audit the federal inspection programs;establishes a statutory requirement&#160;for freight trains to have at least two crew&#160;members, with exceptions;phases out certain railroad tank cars by May 1, 2027;expands training for local first responders;imposes a new fee on certain rail carriers; andauthorizes grants to improve railway safety.</summary>
</bill>
