<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="5194" updated="2022-09-06T13:59:36Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5376" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-08-07">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-08-03"/>
  <description>In the nature of a substitute.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-08-07" how="Voice Vote" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 5194 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Senate struck the language on page 43, lines 3-8, page 1, lines 3-5, page 547, line 18 through page 548, line 25, and page 689, lines 8-16 of amendment SA 5194, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Amendment SA 5194, as modified, 4 points of order en bloc that: page 43, lines 3-8, page 1, lines 3-5, and page 547, line 18 through page 548, line 25, violates section 313(b)(1)(A), and page 689, lines 8-16 violates section 313(b)(1)(D) ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Point of order en bloc: page 43, lines 3-8, page 1, lines 3-5, and page 547, line 18 through page 548, line 25, violate section 313(b)(1)(A). Page 689, lines 8-16 violates section 313(b)(1)(D) raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 5194, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Senate struck the language on page 744, line 7, through page 755, line 4, of amendment SA 5194, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 5194, as modified, rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 43. Record Vote Number: 314.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Point of order that the language on page 744, line 7, through page 755, line 4, violates 313(b)(1)(D) of the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 5194, as modified.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-06">
      <text>Amendment SA 5194 proposed by Senator Schumer. (consideration: CR S4070-4144, S4201; text as modified: CR S4070-4144) In the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-06">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 5194 proposed by Senator Schumer.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 5194, as modified, rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 57 - 43. Record Vote Number: 314.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-07">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 5194 as modified agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
