<bill session="118" type="h" number="1836" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-21T14:42:31-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-21T14:42:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="display">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to make technical corrections with respect to ocean shipping authorities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2023-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001135" joined="2023-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 58 - 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-218.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-09-26" calendar="Union" number="177">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 177.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T17:16:06-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Johnson (SD) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T17:16:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1213-1216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T17:16:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1836.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T17:22:53-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:34:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1321-1322" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="98" datetime="2024-03-21T14:42:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 393 - 24 (Roll no. 98).</text>
      <reference ref="3/19/2024 CR H1213-1215" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:42:32-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-11T21:25:35Z" status="Passed House">Ocean Shipping Reform Implementation Act of 2023

This bill expands the Federal Maritime Commission's authority to regulate technology and anticompetitive practices within the international ocean transportation system.

First, the bill expands the definition of controlled carrier (a category of carriers that are subject to additional regulatory oversight) to include carriers legally or financially related to a corporation based in a nonmarket economy country.

Additionally, the bill requires the commission to accept and investigate complaints concerning alleged anticompetitive practices by registered shipping exchanges. (A shipping exchange is a data platform that enables businesses shipping goods to connect with carriers to transport those goods.)

Further, the bill requires the commission to establish a data standard to facilitate the voluntary sharing of supply chain data among U.S. shipping industry stakeholders. This standard must allow users to exchange data (using standardized terms and methods of measurement) in real time. The bill allows the Department of Transportation to require port authorities to adopt the standard to receive certain grants.

The commission must also establish standards for price indexes for containerized ocean freight that are published by shipping exchanges.

The bill also prohibits a recipient of certain federal grants from using China's logistics platform (LOGINK) or transportation logistics software controlled by&#160;a foreign adversary.

Finally, the bill establishes a National Port Advisory Committee and a National Ocean Carrier Advisory Committee. The committees, together with the existing National Shipper Advisory Committee, are charged with advising the commission on policies relating to the competitiveness, reliability, and efficiency in the international ocean freight delivery system.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-218</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
