<bill session="117" type="sr" number="503" updated="2023-01-13T05:15:39Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Government of the People's Republic of China should immediately guarantee the safety and freedom of tennis star Peng Shuai.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the Government of the People's Republic of China should immediately guarantee the safety and freedom of tennis star Peng Shuai.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2022-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S525" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-04">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and with an amended preamble. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-04-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="323">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 323.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-04-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate with an amendment and an amended preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2080-2081" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2080-2081" label="text"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="837" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-11T11:57:39Z" status="Passed Senate">This resolution expresses the sense of the Senate that the case of Peng Shuai is directly related to broader international concerns around the freedom of speech and safety in China.

The resolution expresses that the failure of the International Olympic Committee (IOC) to clearly and forcefully challenge the claims of China concerning Peng's safety raises questions about the ability and willingness of the IOC to stand up for the human rights of athletes participating in the Olympic and Paralympic games in Beijing, as well as in future games.

The resolution also expresses that China should (1) allow Peng to provide independent and verifiable proof of her own whereabouts and safety without retribution, (2) allow Peng to engage directly with the Women's Tennis Association and the United Nations to independently verify her safety and explain her absence from public life since making her allegation, (3) open an independent and transparent investigation into Peng's allegations against former senior Vice Premier Zhang Gaoli, (4) publicly commit to holding sexual violence abusers accountable, (5) cease all censorship of reporting and discussions of Peng's case, and (6) allow Peng to leave China if she so desires and prevent any retaliation against her family members remaining there.

Finally, the resolution expresses that, by failing to clearly and forcefully challenge the Chinese Communist Party's narrative, the IOC has failed to uphold its own stated commitments with regard to respect for international conventions on protecting human rights.</summary>
</bill>
