<bill session="117" type="s" number="2286" updated="2022-12-31T05:25:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to use designated funding to pay for construction of authorized rural water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Western Water, Jobs, and Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Water, Jobs, and Infrastructure Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T14:22:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Western Water, Jobs, and Infrastructure Act

This bill provides funding to carry out rural water projects, Indian water rights settlement agreements, and projects related to the Milk River Project in Montana.

First, the bill establishes and provides funds through FY2026 for the Reclamation Rural Water Project Construction Fund, from which the Bureau of Reclamation must complete construction of authorized rural water projects.

Next, the bill establishes and provides funds through October 1, 2025, for the Indian Water Rights Settlement Completion Fund, from which the Department of the Interior must implement any Indian water rights settlement agreements approved by Congress.

 In addition, the bill provides FY2022 funding for Reclamation to carry out projects to rehabilitate the Milk River Project, including projects to rehabilitate or replace infrastructure.</summary>
</bill>
