<bill session="118" type="h" number="4276" updated="2024-12-20T09:05:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Worker and Trade Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Worker and Trade Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize Trade Adjustment Assistance programs, extend and reform the Generalized System of Preferences, amend the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to modify certain rates of duty temporarily, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000399" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2023-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000173" joined="2024-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-16T20:22:33Z" status="Introduced in House">American Worker and Trade Competitiveness Act 

This bill reauthorizes and revises specified U.S. trade programs and provisions.

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes through FY2030 and revises the Trade Adjustment Assistance Program, including by expanding program eligibility to additional workers, establishing a child and other dependent care allowance, and increasing the maximum benefit of wage insurance. It also permanently extends the tax credit for health insurance costs and increases the percentage of the credit.

The bill extends through December 31, 2026, the Generalized System of Preferences (GSP), which provides duty-free treatment to products imported from designated beneficiary countries. The bill makes changes to the GSP, including by (1) adding other criteria for designation as a beneficiary developing country, (2) requiring a review of laws relating to worker and gender rights, and (3) requiring a study on rules of origin and GSP utilization rates.

Additionally, the bill provides through December 31, 2024, and retroactively applies to 120 days before this bill's enactment, temporary duty suspensions or reductions to eligible imported products. This authorization is commonly known as the Miscellaneous Tariff Bill (MTB). The last version of the MTB was enacted in September 2018 and the temporary treatment for those products listed in the MTB expired on December 31, 2020.

The bill extends the American Manufacturing Competitiveness Act of 2016 for two future MTB cycles (one in 2023 and one in 2026). This extension allows the U.S. International Trade Commission to conduct the MTB petition, review, and recommendation process for those additional cycles.</summary>
</bill>
