<bill session="116" type="h" number="8045" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:26Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Genome Editing Threat Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Genome Editing Threat Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Department of Homeland Security to develop a threat assessment on the potential homeland security vulnerabilities associated with genome modification and editing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2020-08-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8309" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-15T18:41:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Genome Editing Threat Assessment Act 

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop a threat assessment of the potential homeland security vulnerabilities associated with genome modification and editing.

Such assessment shall include information relating to

 the dual-use of emerging biotechnology; the ability of gene editing to maliciously proliferate infectious diseases and pandemics on human, animal, and plant populations; the cybersecurity vulnerabilities in computer systems analyzing genomic data; and privacy concerns associated with analyzing genomic data. Upon completion of the assessment, DHS shall make a determination if any changes to future DHS operations are required to address security vulnerabilities identified in such assessment.

DHS shall report to the congressional homeland security committees on the findings of such threat assessment, recommendations, plans for incorporating such recommendations into future DHS operations, and proposed legislative changes.</summary>
</bill>
