<bill session="117" type="s" number="2503" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide definitions of terms and services related to community-based gang intervention to ensure that funding for such intervention is utilized in a cost-effective manner and that community-based agencies are held accountable for providing holistic, integrated intervention services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Community-Based Gang Intervention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community-Based Gang Intervention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4743" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-02T19:50:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community-Based Gang Intervention Act This bill extends federal support for juvenile justice and delinquency prevention efforts to programs and activities involving community-based gang intervention. First, the bill authorizes community-based gang intervention grants for nonprofit community-based organizations to reduce and stop gang-related and gang-motivated violence and crime. Second, the bill modifies the qualifications of representatives of state advisory groups to specify that (1) a representative of a public agency includes an individual from a public agency concerned with community-based gang intervention, and (2) a representative of a nonprofit organization includes a person with a special focus on community-based gang intervention. Third, the bill adds, as a purpose area under the Incentive Youth Promise Grants for Local Delinquency Prevention Programs, providing community-based gang intervention and gang prevention activities to juveniles and their families.</summary>
</bill>
