<bill session="116" type="s" number="2830" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GI Bill Planning Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GI Bill Planning Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend the period under which an election must be made for entitlement to educational assistance under the All-Volunteer Educational Assistance Program of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to phase out the use of such program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2019-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3608" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4162" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5278" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2136" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7952" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4511" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-24T15:32:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">GI Bill Planning Act of 2019

This bill extends or removes specified deadlines for certain Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) education benefits.

Specifically, the bill updates the Montgomery GI Bill program by extending the period of time under which an election must be made for entitlement to educational assistance under the program. The bill phases the program out to end on September 30, 2029.

The bill also removes a deadline that prevents certain veterans from receiving in-state tuition, regardless of their state of residence, using VA education benefits at public institutions of higher education. Currently, a veteran who is discharged or released after at least 90 days of active service must be within three years of their discharge from active duty to receive in-state tuition (regardless of their state of residence).

The VA must post on a public VA website a database explaining any requirements established by a public institution of higher learning for an individual to be charged in-state tuition.

The VA must disapprove a course of education at a public institution of higher learning that does not provide the VA with an explanation of the requirements (or a timely update of such requirements) for an individual to be charged in-state tuition.</summary>
</bill>
