<bill session="111" type="h" number="4078" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:18Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Long-Term Care Insurance Disclosure Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop a national model disclosure form to assist consumers in purchasing long-term care insurance.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Care Insurance Disclosure Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1636" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-05T22:20:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Long-Term Care Insurance Disclosure Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop a national model disclosure form for marketing long-term care insurance policies. Sets minimum requirements for such form, including that it: (1) use standard, plain language for purposes of explaining covered services and benefits and restrictions; (2) use standard, consistent definitions for coverage of services and benefits; (3) provide for a standard, consistent disclosure of key provisions, such as monthly premiums, the maximum daily or monthly benefit, and the extent to which benefit amounts will be adjusted for inflation; and (4) have a standard, consistent format with respect to font, color, and type size to allow for easy comparison and not exceed one single-sided page.

Requires the Secretaries of the Treasury and HHS to promulgate regulations requiring issuers of qualified long-term care insurance contracts to use such form for marketing such contracts.</summary>
</bill>
