<bill session="116" type="s" number="4913" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:10Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Right Track Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Right Track Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Railroad Administration and the Federal Highway Administration to provide recommendations for reducing the number of very rural highway-rail grade crossing collisions, to authorize a public outreach and educational program to reduce such collisions, and to authorize grants to improve grade crossing safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2020-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-16T20:46:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Right Track Act 

This bill directs the Federal Railroad Administration (FRA) and the Federal Highway Administration (FHWA) to jointly (1) provide recommendations for reducing the number of collisions at highway-rail grade crossings in counties with 10 or fewer residents per square mile; and (2) conduct a public outreach and educational initiative, in cooperation with Operation Lifesaver, to reduce collisions at public highway-rail grade crossings in such counties that includes multimedia resources.

The FRA and the FHWA must use the recommendations to provide technical assistance to states seeking to make rail safety infrastructure improvements.

Additionally, the Department of Transportation must use amounts set aside under the consolidated rail infrastructure and safety improvements grant program to improve grade crossing safety in counties with 10 or fewer residents per square mile.

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
