<bill session="116" type="s" number="1005" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ending Too Big to Jail Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Too Big to Jail Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to stop financial institution crime, require certain officers of companies to certify that they have conducted due diligence relating to criminal conduct or civil fraud, create accountability in deferred prosecution agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Financial crises and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-08T15:21:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Ending Too Big to Jail Act 

This bill addresses fraud and criminal conduct within financial institutions.

The bill replaces the Office of the Special Inspector General for the Troubled&#160;Asset Relief Program with&#160;the Office of the Special Inspector General for Financial Institution Crime and tasks the office with investigating crimes within financial institutions when such institutions fail.

Financial institutions, bank holding companies, and savings and loan holding companies with assets greater than $10 billion must annually certify that all criminal conduct and civil fraud has been disclosed to the Department of Justice. The bill establishes civil and criminal penalties for violations.

The bill also revises the circumstances under which the government may enter into a deferred prosecution agreement with defendants that are not individuals. These agreements must be determined by the court to be in the public interest.</summary>
</bill>
