<bill session="111" type="h" number="3581" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 36, United States Code, to include in the Federal charter of the Reserve Officers Association leadership positions newly added in its constitution and bylaws.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 36, United States Code, to include in the Federal charter of the Reserve Officers Association leadership positions newly added in its constitution and bylaws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000556"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001065" joined="2009-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001139" joined="2009-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1599" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-11-25T17:49:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Revises the federal charter of the Reserve Officers Association of the United States to include the president elect of the Association on the national executive committee as a non-voting member.

Specifies that the three national executive committee members on the national executive committee are a minimum of three (thus allowing for an increase in such number).

Makes the president elect of the Association an officer.

Specifies that the three national executive committee members who are officers of the Association are a minimum of three (thus allowing for an increase in such number).

Eliminates the specific inclusion among the officers of a surgeon, a chaplain, a historian, and a public relations officer.

Allows the addition as officers of any others specified in the Association's constitution (currently, as decided at the national convention).

Declares that the officers shall take office at the national convention. Requires the judge advocate to be appointed by the national executive committee. Allows for appointment by the national executive committee of any other national officers specified in the Association's constitution.

Revises the requirement that minutes be kept of the proceedings of the national council. Eliminates specification of the national council and replaces it with other national entities of the Association (the minutes of whose proceedings must be kept).</summary>
</bill>
