<bill session="116" type="s" number="2960" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:09Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DESCEND Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DESCEND Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Direct Enhancement of Snapper Conservation and the Economy through Novel Devices Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require individuals fishing for Gulf reef fish to use certain descending devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2019-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5126" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-25T01:45:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Direct Enhancement of Snapper Conservation and the Economy through Novel Devices Act of 2019 or the DESCEND Act of 2019

This bill addresses the use of descending devices to release reef fish in the Gulf of Mexico. (A descending device is an instrument that will release fish at a depth sufficient for the fish to be able to recover from the effects of barotrauma.)

Specifically, the bill requires

 commercial and recreational fishermen to possess a venting tool or descending device that is rigged and ready for use when fishing for reef fish in the Gulf of Mexico Exclusive Economic Zone, the Department of Commerce to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study and produce a report on discard mortality in the Gulf reef fish fisheries, and Commerce and the Gulf of Mexico Fishery Management Council to develop guidance for reporting discards and associated mortality and develop a plan to assess the effectiveness and usage of barotrauma-reducing devices.</summary>
</bill>
