<bill session="109" type="h" number="5079" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:46Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25T14:32:02-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-25T14:32:02-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To update the management of Oregon water resources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the modification of an amendatory repayment contract between the Secretary of the Interior and the North Unit Irrigation District, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000791"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-636.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06" calendar="Union" number="376">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 376.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:29:53-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Renzi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:30:14-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6940-6941" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:30:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5079.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-09-25T14:32:02-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6940-6941" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:32:12-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T14:32:17-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2502" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Irrigation districts"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-24T14:42:08Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 6, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Oregon Water Resources Management Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Oregon Resource Conservation Act of 1996 to: (1) replace references to the Deschutes River Basin Working Group with the Deschutes River Conservancy Working Group; (2) require the two representatives of private interests from irrigated agriculture on the Working Group to actively farm more than 100 acres of irrigated land and not be irrigation district managers; (3) direct the Bureau of Reclamation to pay up to a total amount of $2 million for each of FY2006 through FY2015 for 50% of the cost of performing projects proposed by the Working Group and approved by the Secretary of the Interior; and (4) authorize appropriations for Deschutes Basin ecosystem restoration projects for FY2006-FY2015.

(Sec. 3) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to provide grants to, or enter into cooperative or other agreements with, tribal, state, and local governmental entities and the Associated Ditch Companies, Incorporated (ADC) (nonprofit corporation that operates the Wallowa Lake Dam) to plan, design, and construct facilities needed to implement the Wallowa Lake Dam Rehabilitation Program. Directs the Secretary, as a condition of providing funds, to ensure that: (1) the Rehabilitation Program meets the standards of the dam safety program of Oregon; (2) ADC agrees to assume liability for any work performed or supervised with federal funds provided to it under this section; and (3) the United States shall not be liable for damages arising out of any act relating to a facility rehabilitated or constructed with federal funds provided under this Act, both while and after activities are conducted using such funds. Limits the federal share of the cost of activities authorized under this section to 50%. Prohibits the federal government from holding title to, or being responsible for the operation and maintenance of, any facility rehabilitated or constructed under this section. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this section 10 years after its enactment.

(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Secretary, acting through the Bureau, to participate in the Water for Irrigation, Streams and the Economy Project water management feasibility study and environmental impact statement in accordance with the Memorandum of Agreement Between City of Medford and Bureau of Reclamation for the Water for Irrigation, Streams and the Economy Project, dated July 2, 2004. Authorizes appropriations. Sets the non-federal share at 50% of the Bureau's costs in carrying out this section. Permits the non-federal share to be in the form of certain in-kind services. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out this section 10 years after its enactment.

(Sec. 5) North Unit Irrigation District Act of 2006 - Modifies a repayment contract between the Secretary and the North Unit Irrigation District, Oregon, to permit the District to engage in, or take advantage of, conserved water projects authorized by Oregon law. Authorizes the Secretary to renegotiate such contract terms as the District directors determine to be necessary, only upon the written request of the District directors and the consent of the Commissioner.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-636</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
