<bill session="117" type="s" number="2471" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a community disaster assistance fund for housing and community development and to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to provide, from the fund, assistance through a community development block grant disaster recovery program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2021-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2021-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2021-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-15">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4707" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3045" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4670" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-14T14:53:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reforming Disaster Recovery Act 

This bill addresses the response of the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to disasters.

The bill establishes the Office of Disaster Management and Resiliency at HUD to coordinate HUD disaster preparedness and response responsibilities. The office must also coordinate with other federal agencies in supporting recovery and resiliency activities.

Further, the bill creates the Long-Term Disaster Recovery Fund to fund the Community Development Block Grant Disaster Recovery Program. The program must provide states, tribes, and communities with grants for rebuilding affordable housing and infrastructure after a disaster. Grantees are required to certify that funds will be administered in compliance with specified fair housing and civil rights laws. Grantees must also prioritize assistance for extremely low-, low-, and moderate-income victims of disasters, as well as other vulnerable groups.

The bill also provides for increased data sharing regarding disasters, including by requiring HUD to share data with other federal agencies regarding disaster benefits and by requiring the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and the Small Business Administration to share data on disaster benefit applicants with HUD.</summary>
</bill>
