<bill session="111" type="h" number="788" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide a safe harbor for mortgage servicers who engage in specified mortgage loan modifications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a safe harbor for mortgage servicers who engage in specified mortgage loan modifications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2009-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000243" joined="2009-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2009-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 111-13.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-02-10" calendar="Union" number="5">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 5.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-16T21:08:36Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Shields a servicer of pooled residential mortgages acting in compliance with certain fiduciary duties under the Truth in Lending Act from liability for entering into a loan modification or workout plan in connection with any such mortgages initiated before January 1, 2012.

Specifies that such servicers shall not be liable to: (1) any person based on that person's ownership of a residential mortgage loan or any interest in a pool of residential mortgage loans or in securities that distribute payments out of payments in loans on the pool; (2) any person obligated pursuant to a derivatives instrument to make payments determined in reference to any such loans or interest; or (3) any person that insures any such loans or interest under federal, state, or local law.

States that such servicers shall not be: (1) limited in loan modification ability, the number of mortgages that can be modified, the frequency of loan modifications, or the range of permissible modifications; or (2) obligated to repurchase loans from or otherwise make payments to the securitization vehicle on account of a loss mitigation workout, or other loss mitigation plan for a residential mortgage or a class of them that constitute a part or all of the mortgages in the securitization vehicle.

Makes a mortgage eligible under this Act only if: (1) mortgage default has occurred or is reasonably foreseeable; (2) the property securing the mortgage is occupied by the mortgagor; and (3) the servicer reasonably and in good faith believes that recovery of outstanding principal under the particular modification or workout plan or other loss mitigation action will exceed, on a net present value basis, the anticipated recovery to be realized through foreclosure.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-13</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
