<bill session="108" type="s" number="538" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:15Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lifespan Respite Care Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program to assist family caregivers in accessing affordable and high-quality respite care, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Lifespan Respite Care Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Lifespan Respite Care Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lifespan Respite Care Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2003-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2003-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2003-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2003-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3190-3191"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Gregg without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-04-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="69">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 69.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-04-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5254-5256" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S5254-5256" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11T10:09:53-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Caregivers"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mentally disabled"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Respite care"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced in the Senate on March 5, 2003. However, because action occurred on the measure, the summary has been expanded.)Lifespan Respite Care Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants or cooperative agreements to an agency or organization capable of operating on a statewide basis (an eligible recipient) to develop coordinated respite care programs. Defines respite care to mean planned or emergency care provided to a child or adult with a special need in order to provide temporary relief to the family caregiver of such child or adult.Instructs the Secretary to work cooperatively with existing Federal respite program officers to ensure coordination of services for family caregivers. Authorizes the Secretary to award grants or cooperative agreements to eligible recipients who submit an application containing certain information, including: (1) the extent and nature of the respite care needs of the population; and (2) how the proposed respite care activities will make use of other Federal, State, and local funds, programs, and other resources.Directs the Secretary to establish a review panel to make recommendations on applicants. Gives priority to applicants with the greatest likelihood of implementing or enhancing lifespan respite care statewide.Requires grant funds to be used for the development of lifespan respite care at the State and local levels (unless such a program already exists). Defines lifespan respite care as a system of accessible, community-based respite care services. Permits the use of funds for respite care services and training programs once a statewide program is in place and evaluated. Limits grants to five years. Permits a grant to be renewed. Requires funding to supplement, not supplant, existing government funds. Authorizes appropriations.Directs the Secretary to provide for the establishment of a National Resource Center on Lifespan Respite Care to maintain a national database and provide training, technical assistance, and information. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
