<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4289</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T22:04:15Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-24T00:37:08Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-03-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>[Pages H1740-H1741]From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. JOHNSON of Illinois:H.R. 4289.[[Page H1741]]Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:According to Article I, Section 5, paragraph 2 that ``EachHouse may determine Rules of its proceedings;'' further, inSection 8, Congress has the power to ``pay the debts andprovide for the common defence and general welfare of theUnited States.''This legislation is within the powers of Congress becauseit provides transparent accounting of travels by Members ofCongress, thereby reducing the debts incurred to pay for saidtravels. Moreover, this legislation will promote the``general welfare'' by promoting the trust in which citizensplace in their government to be good stewards of their money.</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
        <name>Committee on House Administration</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-03-28T14:03:00Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Congressional Foreign Travel Reform Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>882</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-03-02</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsha00</systemCode>
            <name>Committee on House Administration</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>J000285</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Johnson, Timothy V. [R-IL-15]</fullName>
        <firstName>TIMOTHY</firstName>
        <lastName>JOHNSON</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>V.</middleName>
        <district>15</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Congress</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional officers and employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional operations and organization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legislative rules and procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Members of Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Travel and tourism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Congress</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-06-01T20:32:32Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Transparency and Accountability in Congressional Travel Act of 2012 - Prohibits a Member of Congress or congressional employee from undertaking any official foreign travel unless, within 14 days before and within 14 days after such travel, the individual prepares and submits to the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate, as appropriate, a specified statement (in both paper and electronic form) containing travel-related information.</p> <p>Allows the Member or congressional employee to exclude classified information from such statements, so long as the Member includes documentation in support of such exclusion.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Defense (DOD) or the Secretary of State, as appropriate, for official travel by a Member or congressional employee for which any of the costs are to be paid by their respective departmental funds, to give such individual, within 10 days after completion of such travel, a written statement specifying: (1) the cost incurred, itemized by the cost of transportation, lodging, and meals; and (2) whether the aircraft used was chartered, private, military, or, in the case of commercial aircraft, whether the seating was coach, business class, or first class.</p> <p>Requires the Clerk and the Secretary to post such statements on their respective official public Internet sites.</p> <p>Prohibits a vacation stopover for annual leave at any point during official foreign travel.</p> <p>Specifies restrictions on official foreign travel by Member and House committee employees, except travel to a military installation or to a theater of operations of the Armed Forces.</p> <p>Requires each Member and congressional employee who undertakes official foreign travel to: (1) take necessary actions to reduce travel costs, and (2) return any per diem remaining unexpended at conclusion of the travel.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Transparency and Accountability in Congressional Travel Act of 2012</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Transparency and Accountability in Congressional Travel Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Transparency and Accountability in Congressional Travel Act of 2012</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To enhance the disclosure of information on official foreign travel of Members and employees of Congress, to impose additional restrictions on such travel, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2012-03-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr4289ih/xml/BILLS-112hr4289ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-03-28</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
