<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="150" updated="2022-02-03T06:09:26Z">
  <amends type="h" number="915" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-05-21T15:41:37-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000581"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-05-21"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Transportation Secretary, within 180 days of enactment, to issue regulations to require each air carrier to provide each of its passengers an option to receive a text message (or other comparable electronic service), subject to any fees applicable under the contract of the passenger for the electronic service, from the air carrier consisting of a notification of any change in the status of the flight of such passenger prior to boarding. This would only apply to air carriers that earn at least one-percent of the domestic passenger service revenue.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 3 printed in Part C of House Report 111-126 to require the Transportation Secretary, within 180 days of enactment, to issue regulations to require each air carrier to provide each of its passengers an option to receive a text message (or other comparable electronic service), subject to any fees applicable under the contract of the passenger for the electronic service, from the air carrier consisting of a notification of any change in the status of the flight of such passenger prior to boarding. This would only apply to air carriers that earn at least one-percent of the domestic passenger service revenue.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-05-21T15:41:37-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Richardson amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T15:36:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Richardson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5968-5969" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5968" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T15:41:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T15:36:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A003) offered by Ms. Richardson.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5968-5969" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5968" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21T15:41:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Richardson amendment (A003) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
