<bill session="117" type="h" number="1928" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Sexual Abuse of K&#226;&#8364;&#8220;12 Students Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to protect students from sexual abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Sexual Abuse of K&#226;&#8364;&#8220;12 Students Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-21T13:25:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Sexual Abuse of K-12 Students Act of 2021

This bill requires sexual abuse awareness training in elementary and secondary schools.

Specifically, the bill requires states receiving federal elementary and secondary education funds to establish and implement a statewide policy requiring each local educational agency to (1) develop codes of conduct to prevent sexual abuse of students by identifying acceptable and unacceptable behavior for school personnel and students; and (2) ensure that school personnel receive specified training, including training on sexual abuse and misconduct awareness and prevention.

In addition, the bill expands the allowable uses for certain grants (e.g., Student Support and Academic Enrichment grants) to include sexual abuse awareness training.

Finally, the Department of Education must make recommendations to Congress for preventing the sexual abuse of elementary and secondary school students.</summary>
</bill>
