<bill session="116" type="s" number="2916" updated="2022-10-28T02:00:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2020-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2020-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5191" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-15T15:34:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Runaway and Homeless Youth and Trafficking Prevention Act of 2019 This bill modifies and reauthorizes through FY2025 the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act, which provides community-based services for runaway or homeless youth who are in need of temporary shelter, counseling, or aftercare services. Specifically, the bill makes grants for centers and services for five-year terms and such grants must include trauma-informed and culturally-competent services, as appropriate. Grant recipients must make services accessible to runaway or homeless youth who are victims of sexual abuse, exploitation, or trafficking. Grant recipients also must collect, and keep confidential, specified aggregated data about the demographics of program participants. The bill requires grants for home-based services to (1) include suicide prevention, (2) provide staff training about trauma-informed care, and (3) ensure eligibility for youth at risk of separation from their family. The bill also revises and expands the transition living grants program to provide five-year grants to support long-term residential services for older homeless youth. Additionally, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to coordinate with specified agencies to deliver programs for runaway and homeless youth and provide five-year grants for technical assistance to regional nonprofit organizations to implement trauma-informed programs for such youth. Further, the bill authorizes five-year grants for the sexual abuse prevention program and the national communications system to connect runaway and homeless youth with their families and service providers. The bill also prioritizes grants for research and evaluation projects that examine the intersection of human trafficking and youth homelessness populations, among other provisions.</summary>
</bill>
