<bill session="118" type="s" number="2945" updated="2025-11-18T20:49:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote and ensure delivery of high-quality special education and related services to children and youth who are blind or visually impaired, deaf, hard of hearing, deafdisabled, or deafblind through instructional methodologies meeting their unique language and learning needs, to enhance accountability for the provision of such services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5748" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-22T18:23:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Alice Cogswell and Anne Sullivan Macy Act 

This bill expands special education and related services for children and youth who are deaf, hard of hearing, deafdisabled, blind, visually impaired, or&#160;deafblind.

The bill establishes additional requirements for states to identify and evaluate children who are deaf, hard of hearing, deafdisabled, blind, visually impaired, or deafblind.

A state's closure of a specialized&#160;school serving children who are blind or deaf shall count as a reduction of its financial support for special education and related services.

The bill also authorizes support, including grants for training special education personnel, to be used in preparing individuals to become qualified teachers and early intervention specialists for children who are deaf, hard of hearing,&#160;deafdisabled, or deafblind.

The bill establishes within the Department of Education the Anne Sullivan Macy Center on Visual Disability and Educational Excellence to better support students with visual disabilities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
