<bill session="116" type="h" number="7754" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">POLICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POLICE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Officer Licensing to Increase Confidence for Everyone Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish licensing standards for law enforcement, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000515"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-03T15:13:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Officer Licensing to Increase Confidence for Everyone Act or the POLICE Act

This bill establishes licensing requirements for federal law enforcement officers and reduces the amount of certain law enforcement-related grants for states that do not adopt similar requirements.

The Department of Justice (DOJ) shall, within one year of the bill's enactment, develop and issue licensing standards for law enforcement officers based on law enforcement best practices. Such standards shall be reviewed and updated every five years.

Within three years of this bill's enactment, each federal law enforcement officer shall be licensed under such standards. Each officer must also take continuing education classes as may be required by DOJ.

Within three years of this bill's enactment, each state shall establish (1) a licensing system that complies with DOJ licensing standards, and (2) a continuing education program substantially similar to the program for federal law enforcement officers. If a state fails to meet these requirements for a fiscal year, certain law enforcement-related grants that the state would have otherwise received shall be reduced by half.</summary>
</bill>
