<bill session="111" type="s" number="1042" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:02Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Illegal Garnishment Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of funds to promote the direct deposit of Veterans and Social Security benefits until adequate safeguards are established to prevent the attachment and garnishment of such benefits.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Illegal Garnishment Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2009-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2009-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3366" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-03T14:43:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Illegal Garnishment Prevention Act - Prohibits funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, or the Commissioner of Social Security for FY2010 or any fiscal year thereafter from being used to promote or otherwise encourage recipients of veterans benefits or benefits paid under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to use direct deposit for the payment of such benefits until: (1) the Secretary of the Treasury promulgates rules establishing procedures to ensure that such benefits are protected from attachment and garnishment; and (2) at least five of the seven members of the advisory committee established under this Act concur in advising the Secretary that such procedures provide adequate safeguards.

Establishes a Social Security Benefits Protection from Attachment or Garnishment Advisory Committee.</summary>
</bill>
