<bill session="117" type="h" number="6935" updated="2022-12-29T21:48:16Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voluntary Grazing Permit Retirement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voluntary Grazing Permit Retirement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the authorization of voluntary Federal grazing permit retirement, provide increased flexibility for Federal grazing permittees, promote the equitable resolution or avoidance of conflicts on Federal lands managed by the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the Interior, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-06T18:30:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Voluntary Grazing Permit Retirement Act

This bill authorizes the voluntary waiver of permits or leases for grazing on federal lands managed by the Department of Agriculture or the Department of the Interior in the 16 western states (e.g., Utah, Washington, and Wyoming).

If a permit or lease is waived by a permittee or lessee with the intention of permanently ending livestock grazing, the appropriate department must

 accept and terminate, on a first-come, first-served basis, the permit or lease; refrain from issuing any new grazing permit or lease within the grazing allotment covered by the permit or lease; and ensure a permanent end to livestock grazing on the allotment covered by the permit or lease. If an allotment covered by a waiver is also covered by another permit or lease that is not waived, the department must reduce the level of commercial livestock grazing on the allotment to reflect the waiver.

The departments must not accept more than (1) 100 grazing permits per year, in the aggregate for all of the 16 western states; and (2) 25 grazing permits for land located in whole or in part in any individual state.</summary>
</bill>
