<bill session="118" type="s" number="1846" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MAPLE SYRUP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAPLE SYRUP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Market Access, Promotion, and Landowner Education Support for Your Regionally Underserved Producers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 to reauthorize and rename the Acer Access and Development Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-12T20:58:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Market Access, Promotion, and Landowner Education Support for Your Regionally Underserved Producers Act or the MAPLE SYRUP Act

This bill reauthorizes the Acer Access and Development Program (Acer) at the Department of Agriculture through FY2028. The bill also changes the name of Acer to the Maple Research and Market Promotion Program.

The Acer competitive grant program promotes the domestic maple syrup industry through activities associated with research and education related to maple syrup production, natural resource sustainability in the maple syrup industry, and the marketing of maple syrup and maple sap products. Acer also provides grants to encourage owners and operators of privately held land containing species of trees in the genus Acer to initiate or expand maple sugaring activities, or to voluntarily make the land publicly accessible for maple sugaring activities.</summary>
</bill>
