<bill session="119" type="s" number="342" updated="2025-11-19T04:49:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Purple Heart Veterans Education Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Purple Heart Veterans Education Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize an individual who is awarded the Purple Heart for service in the Armed Forces to transfer unused Post-9/11 Educational Assistance to a family member, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2025-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2025-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-20T16:21:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Purple Heart Veterans Education Act of 2025

This bill authorizes certain Purple Heart recipients to elect to transfer to one or more eligible dependents (e.g., a spouse or child) unused portions of such recipients&#226;&#8364;&#8482; entitlement to Post-9/11 GI Bill educational assistance. This authority specifically applies to veterans who are awarded the Purple Heart for service in the Armed Forces occurring on or after September 11, 2001, and who have been discharged or released from active service.

Under the bill, the total number of months of entitlement transferred by a Purple Heart recipient may not exceed 36 months. Additionally, the Purple Heart recipient may modify or revoke any unused portion of the transferred entitlement by submitting written notice.

A transferred entitlement may not be treated as marital property or marital assets in divorce or other civil proceedings.

The death of the Purple Heart recipient must not affect the use of the entitlement by the individual who receives the transferred entitlement.

In the event of an overpayment of educational assistance, the Purple Heart recipient and the transferee of the entitlement must be held jointly and severally liable for the amount.

The bill requires the VA and DOD to coordinate to facilitate the transfer of entitlements under the bill.</summary>
</bill>
