<bill session="117" type="h" number="2978" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report regarding the scope of efforts by the People's Republic of China and Chinese Communist Party to utilize the Belt and Road Initiative to undermine the United States-led international world order and a detailed strategy regarding how the United States Government intends to counter such Initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRIDGE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build Responsible Infrastructure Development for the Global Economy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000471"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-24T17:19:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Build Responsible Infrastructure Development for the Global Economy Act or the BRIDGE Act

This bill requires the Department of State to report to Congress on China's Belt and Road Initiative and U.S. efforts to counter the initiative. (The initiative is a Chinese government effort to boost infrastructure development and expand China's influence across most of the globe.)

Within one year of the bill's passage, the State Department must also report to Congress a plan to implement a detailed strategy for the State Department, the U.S. Agency for International Development, and the Department of Commerce to coordinate resources to counter the initiative.</summary>
</bill>
