<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>916</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:53:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T05:53:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-09</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2011-08-30T17:10:55Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2011-07-21T19:56:57Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2011-05-17T19:22:05Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-09T19:51:34Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 112-64</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue right-of-way permits for a natural gas transmission pipeline in nonwilderness areas within the boundary of Denali National Park, and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>302</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2013-01-01</actionDate>
          <text>Held at the desk.</text>
          <actionTime>13:26:07</actionTime>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-08-30</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 144.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-08-30</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2011 with amendments. With written report No. 112-64.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-08-30</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/02/2011 with amendments. With written report No. 112-64.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-07-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-51.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-10</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2823-2824)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-09</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S2783-2785)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-09</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S2783)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-09</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Energy</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Alternative and renewable resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Atlantic Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Earth sciences</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy revenues and royalties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gulf of Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Energy</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-09</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-08-01T21:00:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011 - Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize appropriations for the coordination and processing of oil and gas use authorizations and for oil and gas inspection and enforcement on onshore federal land under the jurisdiction of Federal Permit Streamlining Pilot Project offices. </p> <p>Amends the of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to authorize leases for geothermal energy production on land that is under an oil and gas lease that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring.</p> <p>Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to instruct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a comprehensive inventory of oil and natural gas (including facilitating seismic studies of resources) and prepare a summary regarding how certain resource estimates in OCS areas have changed for the waters of the United States Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) in the Atlantic Region, the Eastern Gulf of Mexico, and the Alaska Region.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a regional joint OCS lease and permit processing office for the Alaska OCS region.</p> <p>Repeals: (1) incentives for natural gas production from deep wells in the shallow waters of the Gulf of Mexico, and (2) royalty relief for deep water production.</p> <p>Amends the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to authorize a certificate holder to request the Secretary to extend the period to issue federal loan guarantee instruments following the date of any proceeding relating to the certificate.</p> <p>Repeals the prerequisite that a federal guarantee instrument for a qualified infrastructure project may be issued only if the debt obligation guaranteed by the instrument has been issued by an eligible lender. Repeals the definition of "eligible lender" (Rule 144A(a) of the Securities and Exchange Commission [SEC]).</p> <p>Increases the maximum aggregate principal amount of debt obligations.</p> <p>Amends the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act to exclude the trans-Alaska oil pipeline system from consideration as a district, site, building, structure, or object for purposes of the National Historic Preservation Act.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to issue right-of-way permits for: (1) a high-pressure natural gas transmission pipeline in non-wilderness areas within the boundary of Denali National Park within, along, or near the segment of the George Parks Highway that runs through the Park; and (2) any distribution and transmission pipelines and appurtenances that the Secretary determines necessary to provide natural gas supply to the Park.</p> <p><br /> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-08-30</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-12-22T22:17:54Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011 -<b> Title I: Oil And Gas Leasing </b>(Sec. 101) Amends the Mineral Leasing Act to authorize appropriations for the coordination and processing of oil and gas use authorizations and for oil and gas inspection and enforcement on onshore federal land under the jurisdiction of Federal Permit Streamlining Pilot Project offices. and</p> <p>(Sec. 102) Amends the of the Geothermal Steam Act of 1970 to authorize leases for geothermal energy production on land that is under an oil and gas lease that is subject to an approved application for permit to drill and from which oil and gas production is occurring.</p> <p><b>Title II: Outer Continental Shelf</b> (Sec. 201) Amends the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to instruct the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a comprehensive inventory of oil and natural gas (including facilitating seismic studies of resources) and prepare a summary regarding how certain resource estimates in OCS areas have changed for the waters of the United States Outer Continental Shelf (OCS) in the Atlantic Region, the Eastern Gulf of Mexico, and the Alaska Region.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish a regional joint OCS lease and permit processing office for the Alaska OCS region, (2) enter into a memorandum of understanding with designated federal agency executives to carry out activities with respect to such office, and (3) request that the Governor of Alaska be a signatory to such memorandum.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2012-FY2022.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) Repeals: (1) incentives for natural gas production from deep wells in the shallow waters of the Gulf of Mexico, and (2) royalty relief for deep water production.</p> <p>States that the Secretary shall not be required to provide for royalty relief in the lease sale terms beginning with the first lease sale held on or after the date of enactment of this Act for which a final notice of sale has not been published.</p> <p><b>Title III: Miscellaneous</b> (Sec. 301) Amends the Trans-Alaska Pipeline Authorization Act to exclude the trans-Alaska oil pipeline system from consideration as a district, site, building, structure, or object for purposes of the National Historic Preservation Act.</p> <p> Authorizes the Secretary to identify up to three sections of the trans-Alaska oil pipeline system that possess national or exceptional historic significance, and that should remain after the pipeline is no longer used for oil transportation purposes. Declares that such sections shall be considered historic sites.</p> <p>States also that such authority, however, does not prohibit the owners of the trans-Alaska oil pipeline system from carrying out construction, maintenance, restoration, or rehabilitation activities on or for a section of the system.</p> <p>(Sec. 302) Authorizes the Secretary to issue right-of-way permits for: (1) a high-pressure natural gas transmission pipeline in non-wilderness areas within the boundary of Denali National Park within, along, or near the segment of the George Parks Highway that runs through the Park; and (2) any distribution and transmission pipelines and appurtenances that the Secretary determines necessary to provide natural gas supply to the Park.</p> <p>(Sec. 303) Requires the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration to update periodically: (1) the annual volume of refined petroleum products imported to and exported from Iran, (2) the identity and national origin of persons selling and transporting refined petroleum products to Iran, and (3) the sources of financing for imports to Iran of refined petroleum products.</p> <p>Requires such reports also to describe the involvement of foreign persons in efforts to assist Iran in: (1) importing advanced technology to upgrade existing Iranian refineries, (2) converting existing chemical plants to petroleum refineries, or (3) constructing new refineries.</p> <p>Requires such reporting requirements to remain in effect until all economic sanctions imposed by the United States with respect to Iran have been lifted. </p> <p><br /> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Oil and Gas Facilitation Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to facilitate appropriate oil and gas development on Federal land and waters, to limit dependence of the United States on foreign sources of oil and gas, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2011-08-30T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s916rs/xml/BILLS-112s916rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-09T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s916is/xml/BILLS-112s916is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-08-30</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 144.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
