<bill session="118" type="s" number="366" updated="2025-11-19T03:23:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Democracy in Design Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of General Services to ensure that the design of public buildings in the United States adheres to the guiding principles for Federal architecture, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Democracy in Design Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2024-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="964" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-25T13:00:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Democracy in Design Act

This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to ensure that the design of federal public buildings (e.g., agency office buildings) adheres to the principles of the report titled Guiding Principles for Federal Architecture.

The report was published by the Ad Hoc Committee on Federal Office Space on June 1, 1962, and serves as the policy directive for the GSA's Design Excellence Program within its Public Buildings Service. Among other principles, the report prescribes against the development of an official architectural style for government buildings and encourages the government to avoid excessive uniformity in building design.

The GSA must issue regulations to implement the amendment made by this bill and to establish minimum standards for the design of public buildings.</summary>
</bill>
