<bill session="118" type="s" number="2960" updated="2025-11-19T03:40:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding the VOTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding the Voluntary Opportunities for Translations in Elections Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding the VOTE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify certain notice requirements, to study certain election requirements, to clarify certain election requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5295" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-10T15:43:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanding the Voluntary Opportunities for Translations in Elections Act or the Expanding the VOTE Act

This bill expands access to voting materials for individuals with limited proficiency in the English language.

Section 203 of the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (VRA) requires covered states and political subdivisions to provide voting materials and other language assistance to&#160;persons who are American Indian, Asian American, Alaskan Natives, or of Spanish heritage and&#160;whose ability to speak or understand English limits electoral participation. A state or political subdivision that is subject to Section 203 is prohibited from providing English-only voting materials in an election. Among other requirements, this bill (1) requires the Department of Justice to issue a notice of prohibition, including the trigger threshold at which the prohibition applies, to certain states and political subdivisions; and (2) requires covered states and political subdivisions to provide written translations of all voting materials, with the consent of any applicable tribal government, to election workers.

Additionally, the bill requires the Election Assistance Commission to make incentive grants for states and political subdivisions to provide translated voting materials.

The bill also directs the Government Accountability Office to study and report on the impact of (1) reducing the threshold requirement under Section 203 of the VRA, and (2) expanding the definition of&#160;language minorities to include native speakers of additional languages.</summary>
</bill>
