<bill session="108" type="h" number="2887" updated="2021-09-29T23:36:53Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="display">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for naturalization through service in a combat zone designated in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1599"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-01T13:48:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Riayan Tejeda Memorial Act of 2003 - Authorizes naturalization without regard to specified Immigration and Nationality Act requirements for an alien or noncitizen national of the United States who: (1) served honorably in a combat zone in connection with Operation Iraqi Freedom; and (2) if separated from such service, was not separated except under honorable conditions. Prohibits imposition of any Federal or State naturalization fee.

Provides for overseas naturalization proceedings for members of the armed forces.

Retains immediate relative status for the alien wife, child, or parent of a U.S. citizen who died from injury or disease incurred while serving honorably in such combat zone. (Requires petition filing within two years of such death.)

States that an application for status adjustment by the alien wife, child, or parent of an alien member of the armed forces who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship based upon service in such zone may be adjudicated as if the death had not occurred. (Requires application filing prior to such death.)

Treats the spouse, child, or parent of a lawful permanent resident who was granted service-related posthumous citizenship based upon service in such zone as a valid petitioner for immediate relative status. (Requires self-petitions within two years of such death.)

Permits such aliens to apply for permanent resident status adjustment.

Waives specified grounds of inadmissibility.

Gives priority to naturalization applications as set forth in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
