<bill session="118" type="h" number="7234" updated="2025-11-19T03:22:30Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NACIE Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NACIE Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Advisory Council on Indian Education Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that the National Advisory Council on Indian Education includes at least 1 member who is the president of a Tribal College or University and to require the Secretaries of Education and Interior to consider the National Advisory Council on Indian Education's reports in the preparation of budget materials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2024-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2024-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2024-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2024-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2024-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2024-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5355" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="749" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-13T17:43:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Advisory Council on Indian Education Improvement Act or the NACIE Improvement Act

This bill revises the membership and duties of the National Advisory Council on Indian Education.

Specifically, the bill requires the President to ensure that the council includes at least one member who is the president of a tribal college or university.

Additionally, the bill requires the council to submit its annual report to the Department of Education (ED) and the Department of the Interior.

ED and Interior must consider the council's report when preparing their budget materials.</summary>
</bill>
