<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1632" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:27Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A Modest Effort to Read and Instill the Constitution Again Resolution of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require officers and employees of the House to read the Constitution of the United States each year.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">A Modest Effort to Read and Instill the Constitution Again Resolution of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AMERICA Resolution of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000548" joined="2010-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-20T21:03:07Z" status="Introduced in House">A Modest Effort to Read and Instill the Constitution Again Resolution of 2010 or AMERICA Resolution of 2010 - Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Members of Congress, who swear to uphold the Constitution of the United States and are responsible for writing laws regarding the powers granted to the government and proposing constitutional amendments, should read this important document, including its amendments.

Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House to require: (1) the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to provide a copy of the Constitution to each new Member, Delegate, Resident Commissioner, officer, and employee of the House; and (2) House officers and employees to file a certification with the Committee attesting that such individuals have read the Constitution in its entirety in the previous year.</summary>
</bill>
