<bill session="109" type="h" number="5386" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:28Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-18T22:16:58-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-05-18T22:16:58-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2007, EPA</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2007, Interior</title>
    <title type="popular">EPA FY2007 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Interior Department FY2007 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2007, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-15">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 109-465, by Mr. Taylor (NC).</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-15" calendar="Union" number="257">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 257.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17T18:00:06-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 818 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5386 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:08:37-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 818 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:17:41-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 818.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2774-2831" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2792, H2794-2796, H2797, H2801-2802, H2805, H2805-2807, H2807-2808, H2810-2811, H2813-2814" label="text of Title I as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2814-2815, H2816, H2818" label="text of Title II as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2818-2819, H2820-2824" label="text of Title III as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2824-2826" label="text of Title IV as reported in House"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2829, H2830" label="text of Title V as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:17:46-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5386 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be read by paragraph. Bill is open to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:18:13-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 818 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:18:15-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Steven C. LaTourette to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T12:18:22-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5386.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T13:31:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Slaughter amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T13:55:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Weiner amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T14:07:05-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Weiner amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Weiner demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T14:15:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Tancredo amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T14:43:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Cannon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T14:59:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Sanders amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:04:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Conaway amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:13:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a unanimous consent agreement, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Poe amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:24:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Poe amendments, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendments and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Poe demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:32:47-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Duncan raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Duncan stated that the paragraph beginning on page 73, line 3 and ending on page 73, line 8 constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:42:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with debate on the Pallone amendment under the five-minute rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:44:36-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Pallone amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pence demanded a recoreded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:45:10-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Taylor (NC) moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:45:32-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:45:42-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5386 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:52:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 5/19/2006 H2835-2873" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:52:18-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T15:56:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minuntes of debate on the Beauprez amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:06:09-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Beauprez amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Beauprez demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:16:09-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Young (AK) raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Young (AK) raised a point of order against section 425, page 125, lines 3-25 stating that it constituted legislation in an appropriations bill in violation of clause 2 of rule XXI. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:20:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:45:54-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Pearce raised a point of order against section 501 stating that it violated clause 2b of rule XXI. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:47:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Pearce raised a point of order against section 502 of the bill stating that it violated clause 2b of rule XXI and constituted legislation in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T16:49:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Hinchey amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:21:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hinchey amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hinchey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:22:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rahall amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:22:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gordon amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:25:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded witn 20 minutes of debate on the Chabot amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:44:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Chabot amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Chabot demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T17:45:03-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of specified amendments which were debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T18:51:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiahrt amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:02:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:03:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gary Miller amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:07:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 30 minutes of debate on the Oberstar amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:41:08-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Oberstar amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Oberstar demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:41:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Conaway amendment, pending reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T19:48:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 1 hour of debate on the Putnam amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T20:58:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Putnam amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Peterson (PA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T20:59:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Commitee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:03:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson-Lee amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:04:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hefley amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:06:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hefley amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Hefley demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:07:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Obey amendment, pending a reservation of a point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:09:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to a previous order of the House, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Dent amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:14:20-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:58:43-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5386.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:59:16-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T21:59:28-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="172" datetime="2006-05-18T22:16:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 293 - 128 (Roll no. 172).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-05-18T22:16:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-22">
      <text>Star Print ordered on the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on Interior and Related Agencies. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported by Senator Burns with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-275.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="507">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 507.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSAP17" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies" activity="Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="818" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cattle"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Colonias"/>
    <term name="Colorado River development"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Coral reefs"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Displaced persons"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Earthquakes"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elephants"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Everglades"/>
    <term name="Eviction"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forestry"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government aircraft"/>
    <term name="Government and the press"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Government vehicles"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Insect control"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Job creation"/>
    <term name="Judicial opinions"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Memorial Day"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="North Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Old growth forests"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Overhead costs"/>
    <term name="Pacific Ocean"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Primates"/>
    <term name="Private forests"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Professional associations"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate development"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rhinoceroses"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Smog"/>
    <term name="Snakes"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h861"/>
    <amendment number="h860"/>
    <amendment number="h859"/>
    <amendment number="h858"/>
    <amendment number="h857"/>
    <amendment number="h856"/>
    <amendment number="h855"/>
    <amendment number="h854"/>
    <amendment number="h853"/>
    <amendment number="h852"/>
    <amendment number="h851"/>
    <amendment number="h850"/>
    <amendment number="h849"/>
    <amendment number="h848"/>
    <amendment number="h847"/>
    <amendment number="h846"/>
    <amendment number="h845"/>
    <amendment number="h844"/>
    <amendment number="h843"/>
    <amendment number="h842"/>
    <amendment number="h841"/>
    <amendment number="h840"/>
    <amendment number="h839"/>
    <amendment number="h838"/>
    <amendment number="h837"/>
    <amendment number="h836"/>
    <amendment number="h835"/>
    <amendment number="h834"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2007-06-20T19:08:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2007 - Makes appropriations for FY2007 for the Department of the Interior for: (1) the Bureau of Land Management (including transfer of funds); (2) the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service; (3) the National Park Service; (4) the U.S. Geological Survey; (5) the Minerals Management Service; (6) the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement; (7) the Bureau of Indian Affairs (including transfer of funds); (8) departmental offices for insular affairs; (9) departmental management; (10) the Office of the Solicitor; (11) the Office of the Inspector General; (12) the Office of Special Trustee for American Indians; and (13) natural resource damage assessment and restoration.

Makes appropriations for FY2007 for: (1) the Environmental Protection Agency (including transfers of funds); (2) the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service (including transfers of funds); and (3) the Department of Health and Human Services for the Indian Health Service.

Makes appropriations for FY2007 for specified related agencies, including: (1) the National Institutes of Health; (2) the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; (3) the Executive Office of the President; (4) the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; (5) the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation; (6) the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development; (7) the Smithsonian Institution; (8) the National Gallery of Art; (9) the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts; (10) the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars; (11) the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities; (12) the Commission of Fine Arts; (13) the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation; (14) the National Capital Planning Commission; (15) the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum; (16) the Presidio Trust; and (17) the White House Commission on the National Moment of Remembrance.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-275</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-465</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
