<bill session="118" type="h" number="1094" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Parents Opt-in Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parents Opt-in Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the General Education Provisions Act to ensure that a student is not required to submit to a survey, analysis, or evaluation that reveals personal information about such student or their family without prior written consent.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T13:52:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Parents Opt-in Protection Act

This bill revises the Protection of Pupil Rights Amendment (PPRA), which governs the administration to students of a survey, analysis, or evaluation that reveals information related to any of the eight protected areas (e.g., political affiliations, sex behavior or attitudes, and religious beliefs).

Specifically, the bill requires prior written consent of the student (if the student is an adult or an emancipated minor) or parent (if the student is an unemancipated minor) for such a specific survey, analysis, or evaluation. Currently, PPRA does not specify that this consent must be written.

Local educational agencies must update their student privacy policies to specify that students shall not be required to submit to a survey without prior written consent.</summary>
</bill>
