<bill session="111" type="h" number="4235" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Women's Hospitals Education Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide assistance for graduate medical education funding for women's hospitals.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women's Hospitals Education Equity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001140" joined="2010-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2009-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1742" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-22T16:20:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Women's Hospitals Education Equity Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make two payments to each eligible women's hospital for each of FY2010-FY2014: (1) one payment for direct expenses associated with operating approved graduate medical residency training programs; and (2) one for indirect expenses associated with the treatment of more severely ill patients and the additional costs relating to teaching residents in such programs.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) make the payments in 12 equal interim installments based on the number of residents reported in the hospital's most recently filed Medicare cost report; (2) withhold up to 25% from each installment to ensure a hospital will not be overpaid on an interim basis; (3) determine, prior to the end of each fiscal year, any changes to the number of residents reported to determine the final amount; and (4) recoup any overpayments based on such determination. Considers the final amount so determined to be a final intermediary determination, subject to administrative and judicial review, under the Social Security Act.

 Applies to women's hospitals funded under this Act annual reporting requirements and provisions regarding direct graduate medical education payments and indirect medical education payments applicable to children's hospitals that operate graduate medical education programs.</summary>
</bill>
