<bill session="118" type="s" number="2037" updated="2025-11-19T04:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Forgotten Equines Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 to prohibit the slaughter of equines for human consumption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3475" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-12T16:15:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Save America's Forgotten Equines Act of 2023 or the SAFE Act of 2023

This bill permanently prohibits the slaughter of equines (e.g., horses and mules) for human consumption. (Current law prohibits the slaughter of dogs and cats for human consumption. This bill extends the prohibition to equines.)

Specifically, this bill prohibits a person from knowingly

 slaughtering an equine for human consumption; or shipping, transporting, possessing, purchasing, selling, or donating an equine to be slaughtered for human consumption or equine parts for human consumption. The bill subjects a violator to a fine.

The bill applies to conduct in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce or within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States. However, it does not apply to an activity carried out by an Indian for a religious ceremony.

In recent years, appropriations acts have prohibited the Department of Agriculture (USDA) from using federal funds to inspect horses before they are slaughtered for human consumption. Therefore, there are currently no USDA-inspected horse slaughter facilities in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
