<bill session="108" type="s" number="77" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:05Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthen Social Work Training Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VII of the Public Health Service Act to ensure that social work students or social work schools are eligible for support under the certain programs to assist individuals in pursing health careers and programs of grants for training projects in geriatrics, and to establish a social work training program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthen Social Work Training Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S70"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S70-71" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College teachers"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minorities in medicine"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Psychologists"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthen Social Work Training Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to make disadvantaged students enrolled in social work programs eligible for scholarships. Makes schools offering social work programs eligible for assistance for certain disadvantaged faculty programs, programs to support excellence in health profession education for minorities, and programs to support geriatric training projects.Authorizes grants to, or contracts with, hospitals, schools offering programs in social work, or other entities for the development of social work training programs and financial assistance to participants and teachers of such programs.Authorizes grants to, or contracts with, schools offering programs in social work to meet the costs of projects to establish or maintain administrative units to provide clinical instruction in social work.Authorizes and allocates appropriations.Adds "clinical social worker" to specified profession definitions under health maintenance organization provisions.</summary>
</bill>
