<bill session="110" type="h" number="713" updated="2023-01-11T14:51:57Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Niagara Falls National Heritage Area in the State of New York, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000480"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2007-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001242" joined="2007-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2007-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2007-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000364" joined="2007-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2007-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000569" joined="2007-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E199-200"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-03-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 110-219.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-07-10" calendar="Union" number="135">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 135.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2739" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="800" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-08-27T21:01:59Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Act - (Sec. 4) Establishes the Niagara Fall National Heritage Area in New York. Specifies the boundaries of the Area.

Designates as the local coordinating entity for the Area: (1) the Niagara Falls National Heritage Area Commission (established by section 5 of this Act) for a five-year period beginning on the enactment of this Act; and (2) a private nonprofit or governmental organization designated by the Commission on the expiration of such period.

 Allows the second local coordinating entity designated by this Act, subject to the prior approval of the Secretary of the Interior, using funds made available under this Act, to make grants to, and enter into cooperative agreements with, the State of New York (including a political subdivision of the State) nonprofit organizations, or any person for purposes of implementing a management plan for the Area.

(Sec. 5) Sets forth the powers and duties of the Commission, including assisting in the transition of management to the second local coordinating entity.

Prohibits the Commission from using federal funds made available to the Commission under this Act to acquire any real property or interest in real property.

(Sec. 6) Requires the Commission to submit a management plan for the Area, which shall include comprehensive policies, strategies, and recommendations for conservation, funding, management, and development of the Area.

Describes certain criteria which the Secretary shall consider in determining whether to approve or disapprove the management plan.

(Sec. 7) Authorizes the Secretary, upon request of the local coordinating entity, to provide technical and financial assistance to the Area for the development and implementation of the management plan.

Allows the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the local coordinating entity and other public or private entities to provide such assistance. Requires, in the provision of such assistance, priority to be given to actions that assist in: (1) conserving the significant natural, historic, scenic, and cultural resources of the Area; and (2) providing educational, interpretive, and recreational opportunities, consistent with the purposes of the Area.

Authorizes Secretary, upon the Commission's request, to detail to the Commission, for each fiscal year in which it is in existence, two employees of the Department of the Interior to enable the Commission to carry out its duties.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Area and prepare and submit to specified congressional committees a report with recommendations for the National Park Service's future role, if any, with respect to the Area; and (2) if the report recommends that federal funding for the Area be reauthorized, such report shall include an analysis of the ways in which federal funding for the Area may be reduced or eliminated and the appropriate time period necessary to achieve the recommended reduction or elimination.

(Sec. 8) Specifies this Act's effect with regard to: (1) other federal agencies; and (2) private property and certain related regulatory protections.

(Sec. 10) Authorizes appropriations. Limits the federal cost share of any activity carried out using any assistance made available under this Act to 50%.

(Sec. 11) Terminates the authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance under this Act 15 years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-219</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
