<bill session="109" type="s" number="2173" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:17Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicare Dual Eligible Identification and Enrollment Facilitation Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist pharmacies in facilitating enrollment of dual eligible populations under the Medicare prescription drug benefit.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Dual Eligible Identification and Enrollment Facilitation Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2005-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Pharmacies"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-03T18:35:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicare Dual Eligible Identification and Enrollment Facilitation Act of 2005 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for outreach and education to pharmacies participating under part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act, particularly independent pharmacies.

Requires such outreach and education to address: (1) the full-benefit dual eligible population; (2) the transition from Medicaid prescription drug coverage to part D coverage for such population; and (3) the processes established by the Secretary to facilitate, at point of sale, identification of the drug plan assignment of such population or enrollment of previously unidentified or new full-benefit dual eligible individuals into Medicare part D prescription drug coverage.

Directs the Secretary to reimburse pharmacies fully for: (1) any transaction fees associated with point-of-sale facilitated identification and enrollment processes; and (2) costs associated with any technology or software upgrade necessary to make any identification and enrollment inquiries as part of such processes.</summary>
</bill>
