<bill session="108" type="s" number="154" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:11Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide emergency disaster assistance to agricultural producers, to impose tariff-rate quotas on certain casein and milk protein concentrates, and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide tax relief for farmers and the producers of biodiesel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Biodiesel Renewable Fuels Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy crops"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Proteins"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff agreements"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Agricultural Disaster Assistance Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide: (1) emergency financial assistance to agricultural producers who have incurred qualifying 2001 or 2002 crop losses due to weather or related conditions; and (2) payments to livestock producers who have incurred 2001 and 2002 losses in an emergency-designated county, with set-asides for the American Indian livestock program.Amends the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States to impose tariff-rate quotas (quantitative import limits) and provide various duty rates on certain casein, caseinates, milk protein concentrate, and other casein derivatives and glues imported into the United States (except imports from Mexico).Authorizes the President to: (1) enter into a trade agreement with a foreign country to grant new concessions as compensation in order to maintain the general level of reciprocal and mutually advantageous concessions; and (2) proclaim any necessary modification or continuance of any existing duty, or continuance of existing duty-free or excise treatment. Sets forth certain limits on the reduction of duties on such products.Biodiesel Renewable Fuels Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) allow a tax credit of between 3 and 20 cents per gallon for soy or specified vegetable based biodiesel fuel mixtures; and (2) make corresponding reductions to motor fuel excise taxes.Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1922 to set forth Federal agency (except the Department of Defense) purchasing requirements for ethanol-blended gasoline and biodiesel for use in agency vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
