<bill session="112" type="h" number="5050" updated="2022-01-06T17:18:06Z">
  <state datetime="2012-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Networking Online Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Social Networking Online Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit employers and certain other entities from requiring or requesting that employees and certain other individuals provide a user name, password, or other means for accessing a personal account on any social networking website.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000179"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2012-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2012-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2012-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2012-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2012-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2012-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2012-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education and Workforce Training.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-15T21:28:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Networking Online Protection Act - Prohibits employers from: (1) requiring or requesting that an employee or applicant for employment provide a user name, password, or any other means for accessing a private email account or personal account on a social networking website; or (2) discharging, disciplining, discriminating against, denying employment or promotion to, or threatening to take any such action against any employee or applicant who refuses to provide such information, files a compliant or institutes a proceeding under this Act, or testifies in any such proceeding.

Sets forth, with respect to employer violations of this Act: (1) civil penalities; (2) the authority of the Secretary of Labor to bring injunctive actions; and (3) the jurisdiction of U.S. district courts to provide legal or equitable relief including employment, reinstatement, promotion, and payment of lost wages and benefits.

Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 and the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to prohibit certain institutions of higher education and local educational agencies from requesting such password or account information from students or potential students. Prohibits denial of admission, suspension, expulsion, and other discipline or discrimination against students who decline to provide such information, file a complaint, institute a proceeding, or testify in any related proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
