<bill session="117" type="h" number="723" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:57Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reducing Fraud in Unemployment Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title III of the Social Security Act to require States to compare information regarding Federal inmates for purposes of combating fraud in unemployment compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Fraud in Unemployment Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-18T17:00:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Fraud in Unemployment Assistance Act

This bill sets forth provisions to combat fraud by federal inmates with respect to unemployment compensation.

The bill requires a state's unemployment compensation law to provide that the state's agency in charge of administering unemployment compensation must (1) enter into an agreement with the Attorney General under which the list of individuals receiving unemployment compensation within that state shall be regularly compared with a list of each prisoner in federal and state custody at a federal or state correctional facility within that state; and (2) use the results of each such comparison to investigate and prosecute fraud, waste, and abuse of unemployment compensation under the state's law.

The full federal share of payments to states for extended and regular unemployment compensation shall exclude any overpayment of pandemic unemployment assistance, federal pandemic unemployment compensation, and mixed earner unemployment compensation recovered by a state.</summary>
</bill>
