<bill session="112" type="h" number="5884" updated="2019-11-15T21:01:01Z">
  <state datetime="2012-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeownership Preservation Education Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Homeownership Preservation Education Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a 1-year pilot program to reduce up-front premiums on FHA mortgage insurance for first-time homebuyers who complete a homeownership counseling program and thereby help to reduce default rates on residential mortgages.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001270"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000613" joined="2012-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2012-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-07-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-29T20:27:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeownership Preservation Education Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to carry out a pilot program to evaluate the effectiveness, in reducing defaults on residential mortgages, of reducing up-front premiums for mortgage insurance made available by the Secretary pursuant to the National Housing Act for first-time homebuyers who complete a homeownership counseling program providing for one-on-one prepurchase counseling.

Requires reduced premiums for mortgages secured by a 1- to 4-family dwelling that is an obligation of the Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund for a first-time homebuyer who completes a HUD-approved program of counseling on the responsibilities and financial management involved in homeownership that provides for one-on-one prepurchase counseling of the homebuyer by a HUD-approved nonprofit housing counseling agency.</summary>
</bill>
