<bill session="118" type="s" number="433" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to convene a blue ribbon panel to review the forest inventory and analysis program of the Forest Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to convene a blue ribbon panel to review the forest inventory and analysis program of the Forest Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-28T01:51:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to convene a blue ribbon panel to review the forest inventory and analysis program (a program that accounts for public and private forests and their resources in the United States).

The panel shall conduct a review of the past progress, current priorities, and future needs of such program with respect to national monitoring of forest carbon, climate change, forest health, and sustainable wood products.

The review shall include consideration of

 the modernization of the program broadly and specifically relating to the integration of advanced remote sensing technologies and methods such as small area estimation; and the possibility of more public-private-academic partnerships under the program to help meet the goals of the program and external needs, particularly relating to research priorities, operational implementation of current or ongoing science, and decision support. The panel shall report to USDA, the Department of the Interior, and Congress describing the review by March 31, 2024.</summary>
</bill>
