<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1234</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T16:48:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T16:48:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-06-11</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2003-08-26T17:56:34Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2003-06-19T21:17:27Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-06-11T18:57:11Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 108-127</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <actionTime>12:21:53</actionTime>
        <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H15000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <actionTime>10:03:20</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent. (text: CR S9316-9321)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.(text: CR S9316-9321)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR S9316-9321)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-08-26</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 251.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-08-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/29/03 legislative day 07/21/03 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-127.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-08-26</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/29/03 legislative day 07/21/03 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-127.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7722-7725)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7721-7722)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000303</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. McCain, John [R-AZ]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>MCCAIN</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <middleName>SIDNEY</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001142</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Smith, Gordon H. [R-OR]</fullName>
        <firstName>GORDON</firstName>
        <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OR</state>
        <middleName>H.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-06-11</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000725</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hollings, Ernest F. [D-SC]</fullName>
        <firstName>ERNEST</firstName>
        <lastName>HOLLINGS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>SC</state>
        <middleName>FREDERICK</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-09-25</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-07-09T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1234, Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/14615</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on June 19, 2003&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2003-07-09T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1234, Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/14615</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on June 19, 2003</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative remedies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Antitrust law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Bank records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Canada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Common carriers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Confidential communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Conflict of interests</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer complaints</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Corporate corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Credit unions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime prevention</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electronic commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Evidence (Law)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Exchange of persons programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal Trade Commission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal employees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Freedom of information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Freight forwarders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gifts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government attorneys</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Independent regulatory commissions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International agencies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Interstate commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Liability (Law)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Negotiations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prosecution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Railroads</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Restrictive trade practices</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Savings and loan associations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State-sponsored terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trucking</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Volunteer workers</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-06-11</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-10-22T19:56:16Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to authorize appropriations for the Commission (FTC) through FY 2006. Authorizes the FTC to accept payment from a domestic or foreign law enforcement authority for expenses incurred in carrying out FTC activities; and (2) accept unconditional gifts, donations, bequests, and voluntary and uncompensated services if such acceptance would not create a conflict of interest. <p> <p>Authorizes the FTC: (1) to share material with a foreign law enforcement agency upon prior certification that the material will be maintained in confidence and used only for official law enforcement purposes; and (2) upon request from such an agency, to conduct an investigation and seek and accept appointment by a U.S. district court of FTC attorneys to assist foreign and international tribunals and litigants, if the requesting agency is investigating or enforcing possible prohibitions against fraudulent or unfair commercial conduct. <p>Includes the FTC among the agencies for which the exchange of records of and reports on financial institutions is permitted under RFPA. <p>Allows the FTC to designate FTC attorneys to assist the Department of Justice in connection with litigation in foreign courts in which the FTC has an interest. Makes remedies currently available to the FTC regarding unfair and deceptive acts applicable to such acts involving foreign commerce that cause injury within, or that involve material conduct occurring within, the United States. Allows the FTC to refer evidence involving foreign persons or corporations for criminal proceedings. Authorizes staff exchanges with, and expenditures for cooperative arrangements with, foreign government agencies.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-08-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-02-27T21:10:34Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003 - <b>Title I: Reauthorization</b> - (Sec. 101) Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to reauthorize appropriations for the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) through FY 2007. </p> <p>(Sec. 102) Authorizes the FTC to: (1) accept payment or reimbursement from or on behalf of a domestic or foreign law enforcement authority for expenses incurred in carrying out FTC activities; and (2) accept unconditional gifts, donations, bequests of property, and voluntary and uncompensated services if such acceptance would not create a conflict of interest.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Directs the FTC, as part of its existing consumer education programs, to educate consumers concerning the potential risks to their privacy and personal security, as well as about potentially inappropriate behavior resulting from purposeful or accidental misuse of peer-to-peer file sharing technology.</p> <p><b>Title II: International Consumer Protection </b>- (Sec. 202) Amends the Act to include the definition of &quot;foreign law enforcement agency.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 203) Authorizes the FTC to share material with a foreign law enforcement agency upon prior certification that the material will be maintained in confidence and used only for official law enforcement purposes, if: (1) such agency has set forth a legal basis for its authority to maintain the material in confidence; and (2) the materials are to be used for purposes of investigating, or engaging in enforcement proceedings related to, possible violations of foreign laws prohibiting fraudulent or deceptive commercial practices or other practices similar to those prohibited by any law administered by the FTC, law administered by the FTC if disclosure of the material would further an FTC investigation or enforcement proceeding, or (with the approval of the Attorney General) foreign criminal laws.</p> <p>(Sec. 204) Authorizes the FTC to conduct an investigation and seek and accept appointment by a U.S. district court of FTC attorneys to assist foreign and international tribunals and litigants at the request of an agency acting to investigate or pursue the enforcement of civil laws or when the Attorney General refers such a request to the FTC (without requiring that the conduct identified in the request also constitutes a violation of U.S. laws). Directs the FTC, in deciding whether to provide such assistance, to consider all relevant factors, including whether: (1) the requesting agency will provide reciprocal assistance to the FTC; (2) compliance with the request would prejudice the public interest of the United States; and (3) the requesting agency's investigation or enforcement proceeding concerns acts or practices that cause or are likely to cause injury to a significant number of persons.</p> <p>Authorizes the FTC, if a foreign law enforcement agency has set forth a legal basis for requiring execution of an international agreement as a condition for reciprocal assistance or as a condition for disclosure of materials or information to the FTC, to negotiate such an agreement.</p> <p>(Sec. 205) Provides that the FTC shall not be compelled to disclose material: (1) obtained from a foreign government agency if such agency has requested confidential treatment or has precluded such disclosure as a condition of disclosing the material; (2) reflecting consumer complaints obtained from any other foreign source that has requested confidential treatment; or (3) material reflecting a consumer complaint submitted to an FTC reporting mechanism sponsored in part by foreign government agencies. States that nothing in this section shall authorize the FTC to withhold information from Congress or prevent the FTC from complying with an order of a U.S. court in an action commenced by the United States or the FTC.</p> <p>(Sec. 206) Provides that the provisions for delay or prohibition of notice under the Right to Financial Privacy Act (RFPA) and the Electronic Communication Privacy Act shall be available to the FTC: (1) upon a finding by the presiding judge or magistrate judge pursuant to an ex parte application by the FTC that there is reason to believe that notification may cause an &quot;adverse result&quot; (as defined to mean the transfer of assets or records outside the United States, the intimidation of potential witnesses, and other specified consequences), or where notification is delayed pursuant to a finding by the FTC that there is reason to believe that notification may cause an adverse result. Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) ex parte application by the FTC; (2) immunity from liability for compliance by the recipient of compulsory process issued by the FTC; and (3) venue and procedure, including for applications for in camera proceedings. Makes this section inapplicable to an investigation or proceeding related to the administration of Federal or foreign antitrust laws.</p> <p>(Sec. 207) Shields from liability for disclosure certain listed entities (including a courier service, a provider of alternative dispute resolution services, a bank or thrift institution, and an Internet service provider or provider of telephone services) that voluntarily: (1) provide to the FTC material relevant to a possible unfair or deceptive act or practice or relevant to assets subject to recovery by the FTC, including assets located in foreign jurisdictions; and (2) disclose consumer complaints sent to them (does not provide any exemption from liability for the underlying conduct). Exempts material submitted with a request for confidential treatment from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act to the extent that it could reasonably be expected to disclose either the identity of persons, partnerships, or corporations or the identification of particular financial accounts, their ownership, or confidential records of account activity.</p> <p> <p>(Sec. 208) Includes the FTC among the agencies for which the exchange of financial records of and reports on financial institutions is permitted under RFPA.</p> <p>(Sec. 209) Allows the FTC to designate FTC attorneys to assist the Department of Justice in connection with litigation in foreign courts in which the FTC has an interest. Authorizes the FTC to expend appropriated funds for the retention of foreign counsel for consultation, litigation, and related expenses in foreign courts in which the FTC has an interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 210) Makes remedies currently available to the FTC regarding unfair and deceptive acts applicable to acts involving foreign commerce that cause injury within, or that involve material conduct occurring within, the United States. <p> (Sec. 211) Allows the FTC to refer evidence involving foreign persons or corporations to the Attorney General, who may institute criminal proceedings under appropriate statutes, whenever it obtains evidence that any person, partnership, or corporation, either domestic or foreign, has engaged in conduct that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law. <p>Directs the FTC to endeavor to ensure, with respect to memoranda of understanding and international agreements, that material it has obtained from foreign law enforcement agencies may be used for the purpose of investigation, prosecution, or prevention of violations of U.S. criminal laws.<n> <p>(Sec. 212) Authorizes staff exchanges with, and expenditures for cooperative arrangements with, foreign government agencies. Authorizes the FTC to expend appropriated funds not to exceed $100,000 per fiscal year for operating expenses and other costs of specified bilateral and multilateral cooperative law enforcement groups.]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>35</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed Senate amended</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-01-05T19:17:27Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>International Consumer Protection Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to include the definition of &quot;foreign law enforcement agency.&quot; </p> <p>(Sec. 3) Makes remedies currently available to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) regarding unfair and deceptive acts applicable to acts involving foreign commerce that cause or are likely to cause reasonably foreseeable injury within, or that involve material conduct occurring within, the United States. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Authorizes the FTC to make certain privileged or confidential information available to foreign law enforcement agencies.</p> <p>Authorizes the FTC to conduct an investigation and seek and accept appointment by a U.S. district court of FTC attorneys to assist foreign and international tribunals and litigants at the request of an agency acting to investigate or pursue the enforcement of civil laws, or when the Attorney General refers such a request to the FTC (without requiring that the conduct identified in the request also constitutes a violation of U.S. laws). Directs the FTC, in deciding whether to provide such assistance, to consider all relevant factors, including whether: (1) the requesting agency will provide reciprocal assistance to the FTC; (2) compliance with the request would prejudice the public interest of the United States; and (3) the requesting agency's investigation or enforcement proceeding concerns acts or practices that cause or are likely to cause injury to a significant number of persons.</p> <p>Authorizes the FTC to negotiate international agreements with the approval and oversight of the Secretary of State, if a foreign law enforcement agency has set forth a legal basis for requiring execution of such an agreement as a condition for reciprocal assistance or as a condition for provision of materials or information to the FTC.</p> <p>Limits the FTC's authority with respect to banks, savings and loan institutions, Federal credit unions, and common carriers.</p> <p>Prohibits the FTC from providing investigative assistance to foreign law enforcement agencies from countries determined to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism.</p> <p>Allows the FTC to refer evidence involving foreign persons or corporations to the Attorney General, who may institute criminal proceedings under appropriate statutes, whenever it obtains evidence that any person, partnership, or corporation, either domestic or foreign, has engaged in conduct that may constitute a violation of Federal criminal law. </p> <p>Directs the FTC to endeavor to ensure, with respect to memoranda of understanding and international agreements, that material it has obtained from foreign law enforcement agencies may be used for the purpose of investigation, prosecution, or prevention of violations of U.S. criminal laws.<n> <p>Authorizes the FTC to expend appropriated funds not to exceed $100,000 per fiscal year for operating expenses and other costs of specified bilateral and multilateral cooperative law enforcement agencies and organizations. <p>(Sec. 5) Allows the FTC to designate FTC attorneys to assist the Attorney General in connection with litigation in foreign courts in which the FTC has an interest. Authorizes the FTC, upon agreement with the Attorney General, to expend appropriated funds to reimburse the Attorney General for the retention of foreign counsel for litigation and related expenses in foreign courts in which the FTC has an interest. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Authorizes the FTC to share material with a foreign law enforcement agency upon prior certification that the material will be maintained in confidence and used only for official law enforcement purposes, if: (1) such agency has set forth a legal basis for its authority to maintain the material in confidence; (2) the material is to be used for purposes of investigating, or engaging in enforcement proceedings related to, possible violations of foreign laws prohibiting fraudulent or deceptive commercial practices or other practices substantially similar to those prohibited by laws administered by the FTC, laws administered by the FTC if disclosure of the material would further an FTC investigation or enforcement proceeding, or (with the approval of the Attorney General) other foreign criminal laws if such laws are offenses defined in or covered by a criminal mutual legal assistance treaty in force between the United States and the relevant foreign government; (3) the appropriate Federal banking agency or the National Credit Union Administration has approved the sharing of material (if requested in connection with an investigation or enforcement proceeding concerning possible violations of law by a bank, savings and loan institution, or Federal credit union); and (4) the foreign law enforcement agency is not from a country that is determined to have repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism. <p>Exempts material received by the FTC in any investigation from public disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). <p>Provides that the FTC shall not be compelled to disclose under FOIA or any other law material: (1) obtained from a foreign government agency if such agency has requested confidential treatment or has precluded such disclosure as a condition of receipt; (2) reflecting consumer complaints obtained from any other foreign source that has requested confidential treatment; or (3) reflecting a consumer complaint submitted to an FTC reporting mechanism sponsored in part by foreign government agencies. States that nothing in this section shall authorize the FTC to withhold information from Congress or prevent the FTC from complying with an order of a U.S. court in an action commenced by the United States or the FTC.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Requires application to the FTC of the Right to Financial Privacy Act (RFPA) and specified criminal laws concerning stored wire and electronic communications and transactional records access, except as otherwise provided by this section.</p> <p>Makes available to the FTC procedures for delay of notification or prohibition of disclosure under RFPA and the Electronic Communication Privacy Act, provided that: (1) a court may issue an order delaying notification or prohibiting disclosure upon a finding by the presiding judge or magistrate judge that there is reason to believe that notification may cause an adverse result (defined as the transfer of assets or records outside the United States, the intimidation of potential witnesses, and other specified consequences); or (2) if notice would otherwise be required, the FTC may delay notification upon the execution of a written certification if there is reason to believe notification may cause an adverse result. </p> <p>Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) ex parte application by the FTC; (2) immunity from liability for compliance by the recipient of compulsory process issued by the FTC; and (3) venue and procedure, including for applications for in camera proceedings. Makes this section inapplicable to an investigation or proceeding related to the administration of Federal or foreign antitrust laws.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Shields from liability for disclosure: (1) certain listed entities (including specified financial institutions, courier services, commercial mail receiving agencies, industry membership organizations, payment system providers, consumer reporting agencies, domain name registrars, and providers of alternative dispute resolution services) that voluntarily provide to the FTC material relevant to a possible unfair or deceptive act or practice, or relevant to assets subject to recovery by the FTC, including assets located in foreign jurisdictions; (2) financial institutions that make similar voluntary disclosures or disclosures regarding suspicious chargeback rates related to possibly fraudulent or deceptive commercial practices; and (3) any such entities that disclose consumer complaints sent to them (does not provide any exemption from liability for the underlying conduct). </p> <p>(Sec. 9) Authorizes staff exchanges with, and expenditures for cooperative arrangements with, foreign government agencies. </p> <p>(Sec. 10) Includes the FTC among the agencies for which the exchange of financial records of and reports on financial institutions is permitted under RFPA.</p> <p>(Sec. 11) Authorizes the FTC to: (1) accept payment or reimbursement from or on behalf of a domestic or foreign law enforcement authority for expenses incurred in carrying out FTC activities; and (2) accept unconditional gifts, donations, bequests of property, and voluntary and uncompensated services. Requires the FTC to establish written guidelines for determining whether the acceptance of such gifts, donations, or bequests would create a conflict of interest or the appearance of such a conflict.</p> <p>(Sec. 13) Requires the FTC to report to Congress on its use of and experience with the authority granted by this Act.</p> <p>(Sec. 14) Reauthorizes appropriations for the FTC through FY 2008.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>International Consumer Protection Act of 2004</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>International Consumer Protection Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reauthorize the Federal Trade Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Federal Trade Commission Reauthorization Act of 2003</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <title>International Consumer Protection Act of 2004</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>3662</number>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <purpose>To enhance Federal Trade Commission enforcement against cross-border fraud and deception and other consumer protection law violations.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T04:56:31Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment SA 3662 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>SA 3662</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/108th-congress/senate-amendment/3662</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>M000303</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. McCain, John [R-AZ]</fullName>
            <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
            <lastName>MCCAIN</lastName>
            <party>R</party>
            <state>AZ</state>
            <middleName>SIDNEY</middleName>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <cosponsors>
          <countIncludingWithdrawnCosponsors>2</countIncludingWithdrawnCosponsors>
          <count>2</count>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>H000725</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Hollings, Ernest F. [D-SC]</fullName>
            <firstName>ERNEST</firstName>
            <lastName>HOLLINGS</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>SC</state>
            <middleName>FREDERICK</middleName>
            <sponsorshipDate>2004-09-15</sponsorshipDate>
            <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
          </item>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>S001142</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Smith, Gordon H. [R-OR]</fullName>
            <firstName>GORDON</firstName>
            <lastName>SMITH</lastName>
            <party>R</party>
            <state>OR</state>
            <middleName>H.</middleName>
            <sponsorshipDate>2004-09-15</sponsorshipDate>
            <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
          </item>
        </cosponsors>
        <proposedDate>2004-09-15T04:00:00Z</proposedDate>
        <submittedDate>2004-09-15T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>108</congress>
          <type>S</type>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <number>1234</number>
          <title>International Consumer Protection Act of 2004</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T16:48:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>6</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3662 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 3662 proposed by Senator Frist for Senator McCain. (consideration: CR S9321) To enhance Federal Trade Commission enforcement against cross-border fraud and deception and other consumer protection law violations.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 3662 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>94000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3662 proposed by Senator Frist for Senator McCain.(consideration: CR S9321)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>93000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2004-09-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2003-08-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-06-11T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
      <actionTime>12:21:53</actionTime>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
