<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6359</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:46:58Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:46:58Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-08-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <constitutionalAuthorityStatementText><![CDATA[<pre>From the Congressional Record Online through the Government Publishing Office [<a href='http://www.gpo.gov'>www.gpo.gov</a>]By Mr. REYES:H.R. 6359.Congress has the power to enact this legislation pursuantto the following:The Congress enacts this bill pursuant to Article I,Section 8 of the United States Constitution.Text:Article I, Section. 8.Clause 1: The Congress shall have Power To lay and collectTaxes, Duties, Imposts and Excises, to pay the Debts andprovide for the common Defence and general Welfare of theUnited States; but all Duties, Imposts and Excises shall beuniform throughout the United States;Clause 2: To borrow Money on the credit of the UnitedStates;Clause 3: To regulate Commerce with foreign Nations, andamong the several States, and with the Indian Tribes;Clause 4: To establish an uniform Rule of Naturalization,and uniform Laws on the subject of Bankruptcies throughoutthe United States;Clause 5: To coin Money, regulate the Value thereof, and offoreign Coin, and fix the Standard of Weights and Measures;Clause 6: To provide for the Punishment of counterfeitingthe Securities and current Coin of the United States;Clause 7: To establish Post Offices and post Roads;Clause 8: To promote the Progress of Science and usefulArts, by securing for limited Times to Authors and Inventorsthe exclusive Right to their respective Writings andDiscoveries;Clause 9: To constitute Tribunals inferior to the supremeCourt;Clause 10: To define and punish Piracies and Feloniescommitted on the high Seas, and Offences against the Law ofNations;Clause 11: To declare War, grant Letters of Marque andReprisal, and make Rules concerning Captures on Land andWater;Clause 12: To raise and support Armies, but noAppropriation of Money to that Use shall be for a longer Termthan two Years;Clause 13: To provide and maintain a Navy;Clause 14: To make Rules for the Government and Regulationof the land and naval Forces;Clause 15: To provide for calling forth the Militia toexecute the Laws of the Union, suppress Insurrections andrepel Invasions;Clause 16: To provide for organizing, arming, anddisciplining, the Militia, and for governing such Part ofthem as may be employed in the Service of the United States,reserving to the States respectively, the Appointment of theOfficers, and the Authority of training the Militia accordingto the discipline prescribed by Congress;Clause 17: To exercise exclusive Legislation in all Caseswhatsoever, over such District (not exceeding ten Milessquare) as may, by Cession of particular States, and theAcceptance of Congress, become the Seat of the Government ofthe United States, and to exercise like Authority over allPlaces purchased by the Consent of the Legislature of theState in which the Same shall be, for the Erection of Forts,Magazines, Arsenals, dock-Yards, and other needfulBuildings;--AndClause 18: To make all Laws which shall be necessary andproper for carrying into Execution the foregoing Powers, andall other Powers vested by this Constitution in theGovernment of the United States, or in any Department orOfficer thereof.[Page H5728]</pre>]]></constitutionalAuthorityStatementText>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
        <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-08-07T14:00:43Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any prizes or awards won in competition in the Olympic Games.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>6250</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-08-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any prizes or awards won in competition in the Olympic Games.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>6252</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-08-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate the tax on Olympic medals won by United States athletes.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>6267</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-08-01</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>Tax Exemption for American Medalists Act</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>6287</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-08-02</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to eliminate the tax on Olympic medals won by United States athletes.</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>3471</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2012-08-01</actionDate>
          <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-07</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hswm00</systemCode>
            <name>Ways and Means Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-08-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000170</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Reyes, Silvestre [D-TX-16]</fullName>
        <firstName>SILVESTRE</firstName>
        <lastName>REYES</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <district>16</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Taxation</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Athletes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax exclusion</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Olympic games</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Taxation</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-08-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-08-25T14:31:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income, for income tax purposes, the value of any medal awarded in, or any prize money received from the U.S. Olympic Committee on account of, competition in the Olympic Games or Paralympic Games.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any prizes or awards won in competition in the Olympic Games and Paralympic Games.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any prizes or awards won in competition in the Olympic Games and Paralympic Games.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any prizes or awards won in competition in the Olympic Games and Paralympic Games.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2012-08-07T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112hr6359ih/xml/BILLS-112hr6359ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-08-07</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
