<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3693</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-31T21:14:37Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-31T21:14:37Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2006-07-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
        <congress>109</congress>
        <number>3402</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2006-01-05</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 109-162.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
      <item>
        <title>A concurrent resolution relating to correcting a clerical error in the enrollment of S. 3693.</title>
        <congress>109</congress>
        <number>112</number>
        <type>SCONRES</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
          <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
          <actionTime>01:50:19</actionTime>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 109-271.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E40000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
        <text>Became Public Law No: 109-271.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>E30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
        <text>Signed by President.</text>
        <type>BecameLaw</type>
        <actionCode>36000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-02</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>E20000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-08-02</actionDate>
        <text>Presented to President.</text>
        <type>President</type>
        <actionCode>28000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:51:00</actionTime>
        <text>Pursuant to the provisions of S. Con. Res. 112, enrollment corrections on S. 3693 have been made.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H1B000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:49:58</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:49:57</actionTime>
        <text>On passage Passed without objection. (text: CR 7/28/2005 H6222-6227)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:49:57</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On passage Passed without objection.(text: CR 7/28/2005 H6222-6227)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:49:29</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Cannon asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30200</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-29</actionDate>
        <actionTime>01:49:29</actionTime>
        <text>Considered by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR 7/28/2005 H6222-6227)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-20</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:41:05</actionTime>
        <text>Held at the desk.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H15000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-20</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-20</actionDate>
        <actionTime>10:04:58</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-19</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S7933-7934, S7936-7941; text as passed Senate: CR S7936-7941)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-19</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S7933-7934, S7936-7941; text as passed Senate: CR S7936-7941)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2006-07-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S000709</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Specter, Arlen [R-PA]</fullName>
        <firstName>ARLEN</firstName>
        <lastName>SPECTER</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>PA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000444</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Biden, Joseph R., Jr. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOSEPH</firstName>
        <lastName>BIDEN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>ROBINETTE</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2006-07-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <laws>
      <item>
        <type>Public Law</type>
        <number>109-271</number>
      </item>
    </laws>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Alaska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aliens</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arrest</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child safety</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child sexual abuse</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime prevention</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crimes against women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Deportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Family violence</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to Indians</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to law enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigrants</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Immigration</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian children</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian courts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian law enforcement</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indigenous peoples</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Landlord and tenant</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Legal services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Prosecution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rape</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rural crime</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Stalking</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Students</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Victims of crimes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2006-07-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-08-28T14:25:36Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Makes technical and other amendments to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 and other related federal legislation relating to grant conditions for violence against women programs, law enforcement, sexual assault services programs, violence on college campuses, housing for victims of domestic violence, aliens and Indian women who are victims of domestic violence, and Department of Justice crime control programs. Establishes as new short titles for specified provisions of such Act: (1) the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2005; and (2) the Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act of 2005.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>49</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Public Law</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-05-31T11:28:06Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Makes technical corrections and other amendments to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 (the Act) and other related federal legislation.</p> <p>(Sec. 1) Establishes as new short titles for specified provisions of the Act: (1) the Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2005; and (2) the Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act of 2005. </p> <p>Delays the effective date of specified provisions of the Act until FY2007. </p> <p>Makes certain definitions and grant conditions in the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 applicable to provisions of the Act relating to crimes on campuses, outreach to underserved populations, and cultural services.</p> <p>Defines &quot;tribal nonprofit organization&quot; for purposes of the Act.</p> <p>Modifies universal grant conditions of the Act to qualify states for waivers of matching fund requirements based on demonstrated financial need.</p> <p>(Sec. 2) Extends the authorization of appropriations for sex offender management programs through FY2011.</p> <p>Amends federal criminal code provisions relating to domestic violence and stalking to modify the definition of &quot;spouse or intimate partner.&quot;</p> <p>Eliminates provisions of the Act relating to training, technical assistance, and data collection for violence against women &quot;STOP&quot; grants and grants to encourage arrest.</p> <p>Modifies the reporting requirement for recipients of grants for outreach to underserved populations.</p> <p>Extends to three years the compliance period for making forensic medical exams available to victims of sexual assault.</p> <p>Expands grant purposes for community-based programs for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</p> <p>Modifies funding allocations under the grant program to combat violent crimes against women relating to law enforcement, prosecutors, and victims services.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Repeals the sexual assault services program enacted by the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005 and reestablishes such program in the Violence Against Women Act of 1994. </p> <p>(Sec. 4) Modifies: (1) grant purpose provisions relating to violent crimes on campuses; and (2) grantee reporting requirements to require annual rather than biennial reports on programs to combat such crime.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Makes technical amendments to housing provisions of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act, and the United States Housing Act of 1937.</p> <p>Amends the Housing Act of 1937 to: (1) prohibit the denial of assisted housing benefits to individuals who are victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking; and (2) allow the eviction of assisted housing tenants who engage in criminal acts of domestic violence against family members or others.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Amends the Immigration and Naturalization Act to modify provisions relating to admissibility, waivers, removal, and adjustment of status for Violence Against Women Act (VAWA) self-petitioners. Allows the Secretary of Homeland Security to waive inadmissibility for a VAWA self-petitioner if there is a connection between the alien's battering or subjection to extreme cruelty and the alien's removal, departure from the United States, or reentry or reentries into the United States.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (OCCSSA) to: (1) modify grant allocations to Indian tribal governments for programs to combat violence against women and to encourage arrests and enforce protection orders; and (2) authorize the Attorney General to make grants to such governments for free (or minimal cost) legal assistance to victims of domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, or sexual assault who are seeking legal relief.</p> <p>Amends the Safe Homes for Women Act of 1994, the Violence Against Women Act of 1994, and the Violence Against Women Act of 2000 to modify grant allocations for specified programs to combat violence against Indian tribal women.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Transfers grant authority for the organized retail theft national database and the juvenile and young adult witness assistance program from the Attorney General to the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance in the Office of Justice Programs.</p> <p>Repeals provisions of the Act relating to state grants and reporting requirements under OCCSSA.</p> <p>Extends restrictions on payments to private entities for Justice Department employee training facilities to include meals, lodging, or other expenses related to internal training or conference meetings.</p> <p>Extends the application period for grants under the Bureau of Justice Assistance Grant Programs (Byrne Grants) from 90 to 120 days after the date funds for such grants are appropriated.</p> <p>Transfers grant authority for the matching grant program for school security from the Attorney General to the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services.</p> <p>Increases FY2006 authorizations of appropriations for: (1) the U.S. Marshals Service; (2) the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives (ATF); (3) fees and expenses of witnesses; and (4) the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission.</p> <p>Transfers responsibility for Drug Courts technical assistance and training from the Community Capacity Development Office to the Bureau of Justice Assistance.</p> <p>Changes effective dates for various programs under the Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A bill to make technical corrections to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>A bill to make technical corrections to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Department of Justice Appropriations Authorization Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Violence Against Women Reauthorization Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to make technical corrections to the Violence Against Women and Department of Justice Reauthorization Act of 2005.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Enrolled Bill</type>
        <date/>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2006-07-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Considered and Passed Senate</type>
        <date>2006-07-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s3693cps/xml/BILLS-109s3693cps.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <date>2006-08-13T03:59:59Z</date>
        <formats/>
        <type>Public Law</type>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2006-08-12</actionDate>
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-271.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
