<bill session="109" type="s" number="3978" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:03Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Debit and Check Card Consumer Protection Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide consumer protections for lost or stolen check cards and debit cards similar to those provided with respect to credit cards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Debit and Check Card Consumer Protection Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10480-10481"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10481" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Debit cards"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-02T21:53:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Debit and Check Card Consumer Protection Act of 2006 - Amends the Electronic Funds Transfer Act regarding consumer liability for unauthorized electronic fund transfers to repeal the provision that financial institutions need not reimburse a consumer for losses that would not have occurred but for the consumer's failure to report an unauthorized electronic fund transfer or account error within a certain time period. Repeals the $500 consumer liability limit for such unauthorized transfers or account errors (thus applying the regular $50 maximum limit currently specified for timely reported unauthorized transfers or account errors).

Applies error resolution requirements to any charge for goods or services not accepted by the consumer (or designee), or not delivered to the consumer (or designee), in accordance with the agreement made at the time of a transaction.

Sets forth the rights of consumers with respect to issuers of accepted credit and debit cards.</summary>
</bill>
