<bill session="118" type="s" number="3494" updated="2025-10-14T22:43:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trusted Foreign Auditing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trusted Foreign Auditing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to provide for disclosure regarding foreign jurisdictions that hinder inspections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2024-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-12-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6769" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-01T15:49:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trusted Foreign Auditing Act of 2023

This bill expands a securities trading prohibition currently applicable to companies that use a foreign public accounting firm not subject to inspections by the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board.&#160;

Under the bill, a company&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s securities are prohibited from trade on a national securities exchange or through any other method regulated by the Securities and Exchange Commission if a company that is headquartered in a country of concern retains a compromised auditor to prepare an audit report. The bill defines a country of concern as North Korea, China, Russia, Iran, or a country identified as a threat to U.S. security in an annual report by the Office of the Director of National Intelligence. The bill defines a compromised auditor as an independent branch or office of a registered public accounting firm that is subject to the jurisdiction and laws of a country of concern, is controlled or influenced by a country of concern, or has entered into a particular type of relationship with a country of concern.

Further, board hearings to investigate and discipline registered public accounting firms must be public if a compromised auditor is a party to the hearing.</summary>
</bill>
