<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>6518</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:13Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:13Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-12-13</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-12-13T15:00:34Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-13</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsif00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Commerce Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-13</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000515</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rush, Bobby L. [D-IL-1]</fullName>
        <firstName>BOBBY</firstName>
        <lastName>RUSH</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>L.</middleName>
        <district>1</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Drug, alcohol, tobacco use</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor carriers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Product safety and quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science and engineering education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid and college costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation safety and security</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-12-13</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-10T22:08:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Research of Alcohol Detection Systems for Stopping Alcohol-related Fatalities Everywhere Act of 2010 or ROADS SAFE Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA), to carry out a collaborative research effort to continue to explore the feasibility and the potential benefits of, and the public policy challenges associated with, more widespread deployment of in-vehicle technology to prevent alcohol-impaired driving.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to initiate a rulemaking proceeding to prescribe certain performance standards to reduce commercial motor vehicle rollover and loss of control crashes and associated deaths and injuries for air-braked truck tractors and motorcoaches with a gross vehicle weight rating of more than 26,000 pounds.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress regarding the quality of data collected through the National Automotive Sampling System, including the Special Crash Investigations, as well as recommendation for improvements to the data collection program.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to establish and publicize a hotline for mechanics, passenger motor vehicle dealership personnel, and passenger motor vehicle manufacturer personnel to contact NHTSA confidentially regarding potential passenger motor vehicle safety defects.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to establish within NHTSA an honors program for the recruitment of engineering, computer science, and other students interested in training with engineers and other safety officials for a career in vehicle safety.</p> <p>Revises requirements for rules on early warning reporting by motor vehicle or motor vehicle equipment manufacturers about vehicle or equipment defects. Requires early warning reports to include information on consumer complaints, warranty claims, field reports, or technical service bulletins.</p> <p>Requires all early warning report information to be made available to the public, unless exempt from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA). Presumes that information shall not be exempt from disclosure, and thus must be made public, if it is: (1) vehicle safety defect information related to incidents involving death or injury; (2) aggregated numbers of property damage claims; or (3) aggregated numbers of consumer complaints related to potential vehicle defects.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to study the feasibility of more widespread use of in-vehicle technology to prevent alcohol-impaired driving, to require a Federal motor vehicle safety standard related to rollover prevention and crash mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to study the feasibility of more widespread use of in-vehicle technology to prevent alcohol-impaired driving, to require a Federal motor vehicle safety standard related to rollover prevention and crash mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To direct the Secretary of Transportation to study the feasibility of more widespread use of in-vehicle technology to prevent alcohol-impaired driving, to require a Federal motor vehicle safety standard related to rollover prevention and crash mitigation, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Research of Alcohol Detection Systems for Stopping Alcohol-related Fatalities Everywhere Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>ROADS SAFE Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2010-12-13T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr6518ih/xml/BILLS-111hr6518ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-12-13</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
