<bill session="114" type="h" number="6417" updated="2023-01-11T13:33:57Z">
  <state datetime="2016-12-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fair Calculations in Civil Damages Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit a court from awarding damages based on race, ethnicity, gender, religion, or actual or perceived sexual orientation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Calculations in Civil Damages Act of 2016</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000584" joined="2016-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2016-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000062" joined="2016-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution and Civil Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="3489" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Economic theory"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-12-07T19:17:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Fair Calculations in Civil Damages Act of 2016

This bill prohibits courts from awarding damages to plaintiffs in civil actions using a calculation for projected future earning potential that takes into account a plaintiff's race, ethnicity, gender, religion, or actual or perceived sexual orientation.

The Department of Labor must develop guidance for economists to develop future earnings tables that do not rely on such factors. Labor and the Department of Justice must develop guidance for states on how to calculate future earnings in state tort proceedings in a manner that is free of such biases.

The Judicial Conference of the United States must report on damages awarded under federal law for personal injury, employment discrimination, tort damages, and cases involving protected classes of individuals sharing a common characteristic or identity who are legally protected against discrimination. The Administrative Office of the United States Courts must submit recommendations to ensure that future earnings calculations that take into account age and disability do not conflict with federal equal protection laws.

The Federal Judicial Center must train federal judges on how to implement this bill.</summary>
</bill>
