<amendment session="112" chamber="s" number="3435" updated="2022-02-08T17:32:23Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5949" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-12-27">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-12-27"/>
  <description>To require the Attorney General to disclose each decision, order, or opinion of a Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court that includes significant legal interpretation of section 501 or 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 unless such disclosure is not in the national security interest of the United States.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-12-27" how="roll" result="fail" roll="233">
      <text>Amendment SA 3435, under the order of 12/21/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 54. Record Vote Number: 233.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 3435 proposed by Senator Merkley. (consideration: CR S8397-8407, S8427-8428; text: CR S8397-8398) To require the Attorney General to disclose each decision, order, or opinion of a Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court that includes significant legal interpretation of section 501 or 702 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 unless such disclosure is not in the national security interest of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 3435 proposed by Senator Merkley.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8397-8407, S8427-8428" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8397-8398" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 3435, under the order of 12/21/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 54. Record Vote Number: 233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 3435, under the order of 12/21/2012, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 37 - 54. Record Vote Number: 233.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-12-27">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
