<bill session="118" type="h" number="2990" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 to address sexual harassment involving National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration personnel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001278"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2023-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8862" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-25T17:28:21Z" status="Introduced in House">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Sexual Harassment and Assault Prevention Improvements Act of 2023

This bill addresses sexual harassment and sexual assault involving personnel of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

The bill specifies that NOAA's sexual harassment prevention and response policy applies to personnel such as observers, at-sea monitors, and voting members and staff of regional fishery management councils.

The bill removes the requirement that certain acts, such as assault, intimidation, and sexual harassment of an observer or a data collector, be forcible in nature to be unlawful.

The bill also requires NOAA's Office of Marine and Aviation Operations to establish a policy for reporting to the Coast Guard the names of NOAA personnel who are the subject of certain claims. Specifically, such reports must identify employees or contractors who are the subject of a claim of an act or offense detrimental to good discipline and safety at sea (e.g., a claim of sexual assault substantiated by an investigation) or any other substantiated claim of an act or offense for which suspension or revocation of a credential is either mandatory or sought pursuant to certain Coast Guard regulations.

Additionally, the bill directs NOAA to develop a restricted reporting system that allows employees and other personnel to confidentially report sexual harassment or assault and receive services without triggering an investigation.

Finally, the bill also expands reporting requirements on sexual harassment, sexual assault, and equal employment.</summary>
</bill>
