<bill session="110" type="h" number="2957" updated="2023-01-11T21:19:56Z">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to improve educational practices for limited English proficient students and immigrant students.</title>
    <title type="display">English Language Instruction Improvement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">English Language Instruction Improvement Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001234"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Language arts"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-09-11T21:27:41Z" status="Introduced in House">English Language Instruction Improvement Act of 2007 - Amends title III (Language Instruction for Limited English Proficient and Immigrant Students) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to raise, from 6.5% to 9%, the amount of title III appropriations devoted to the National Clearinghouse for English Language Acquisition and Language Instruction Educational Programs and a program providing competitive grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) for teacher training to improve classroom instruction for limited English proficient children.

Alters such grant program by allowing the provision of grants directly to states and local educational agencies (LEAs) and eliminating the requirement that IHE grantees be in consortia with states or LEAs.

Adds to allowable grant uses: (1) the development and dissemination of best practices in teaching individuals with limited English proficiency to high levels of achievement pursuant to challenging state academic performance standards or to high levels of multiligual proficiency; (2) research and evaluation of the education provided to such individuals; and (3) technical assistance to states and LEAs in meeting the requirements of title III.</summary>
</bill>
