<bill session="116" type="h" number="7553" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEFEND Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of National Intelligence to notify Congress if the Director determines, with high or moderate confidence, that a foreign government with which the United States is at peace is seeking to cause the death of, or serious bodily injury to, members of the United States Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deadly Escalation by Foreign Entities Notification and Disclosure Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEFEND Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001122" joined="2020-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2020-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2020-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-02T18:24:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Deadly Escalation by Foreign Entities Notification and Disclosure Act or the DEFEND Act

This bill requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) to brief Congress if ODNI determines with moderate or high confidence that a foreign government is deliberately seeking to kill or cause serious bodily injury to any member of the Armed Forces, either directly or indirectly.

The briefing shall include information such as a description of the nature and extent of the foreign government's efforts and an assessment of the foreign government's motivations. After giving an initial briefing, the ODNI shall give periodic updated briefings.</summary>
</bill>
