<bill session="118" type="s" number="3745" updated="2025-11-19T03:38:00Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BRIDGE for Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRIDGE for Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building on Reemployment Improvements to Deliver Good Employment for Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend reemployment services and eligibility assessments to all claimants for unemployment benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2024-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2024-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2024-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5861" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-29T15:56:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building on Reemployment Improvements to Deliver Good Employment for Workers Act or the BRIDGE for Workers Act

This bill permanently expands the allowable purposes for certain Department of Labor grants to states for reemployment services and eligibility assessments. Specifically, the bill permanently allows these grants to be used to fund reemployment services and eligibility assessments for all claimants for unemployment compensation.

(Under the current statute, the grants may only be used to provide such services to a subset of claimants who have been identified by the state as likely to exhaust unemployment benefits and need job search assistance to become employed. However, in recent years, annual appropriations acts have allowed the grants to be used for all claimants for unemployment compensation. This bill makes this authority permanent.) &#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
