<bill session="117" type="h" number="2429" updated="2023-05-11T15:43:11Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-15T14:38:46-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-06-15T14:38:46-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Police Improvement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Police Improvement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">VA Police Improvement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Police Improvement and Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the staffing, transparency, and accountability of the law enforcement operations of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000602"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2021-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000479" joined="2021-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T14:32:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T14:32:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2777-2778" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T14:33:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2429.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-06-15T14:38:46-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2777-2778" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15T14:38:50-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-29T12:49:40Z" status="Passed House">VA Police Improvement and Accountability Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to establish policies and procedures related to the accountability and staffing of its police force.

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to publish specified summaries, statistics, and contact information related to the activities of VA police officers from the previous five-year period. The VA must ensure that each of its police forces is able to provide VA employees and members of the public who contact the force with contact information to directly contact the police force regarding the arrest, ticketing, detainment, use of force, or other police matters pertaining to the individual.

The bill requires VA police officers to wear body cameras that record and store audio and video. Additionally, the VA's guidance on the use of body cameras must be made publicly available.

Under the bill, the VA is required to track and analyze the following information regarding its police force:

 arrests made and tickets issued; prosecutions, ticketing, and other actions relating to such arrests; the use of force and weapon discharges; and complaints, investigations, and disciplinary actions. The VA must ensure each incident of the use of force is promptly reported to the Assistant Secretary with responsibility for operations, preparedness, security, and law enforcement functions. The Assistant Secretary must review and investigate each incident (including allegations) of the use of force by a VA police officer, including such situations where any person receives medical attention.

The VA must develop a plan that establishes minimum standards for police staffing at its facilities.</summary>
</bill>
