<bill session="118" type="h" number="7377" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:03Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Royalty Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Royalty Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Royalty Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="short">Royalty Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="display">Royalty Resiliency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 to improve the management of royalties from oil and gas leases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2024-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2024-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001096" joined="2024-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2024-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2024-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2024-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 118-562.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-27" calendar="Union" number="464">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 464.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:14:15-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:14:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4650-4651" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:14:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7377.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-07-22T16:23:45-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4650" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T16:23:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2024-09-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6003" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-09-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-81" type="public" datetime="2024-09-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-81.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Energy revenues and royalties"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-22T16:30:11Z" status="Public Law">Royalty Resiliency Act

This act modifies the process under which oil and gas leaseholders who have entered into certain joint drilling agreements (i.e., a communitization agreement or a unit agreement, except agreements containing Indian lands) to drill wells on leased land pay royalties to the Department of the Interior under the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982.

Under current law, Interior must issue a determination of allocations of royalty payments for oil and gas production under a joint agreement within 120 days of a request for determination. Generally, the first leaseholder to drill must pay any royalties due to Interior for all oil and gas production on the land subject to the agreement until Interior determines the royalty allocations of each leaseholder. If Interior fails to issue the determination by that deadline, then it must waive interest due on royalty obligations until the end of the month following the month in which the determination was made.

Under the act, a leaseholder must pay royalties on oil and gas production based on the lessee's proposed allocation of production under the joint agreement until Interior issues a determination of royalty allocations. After Interior issues the determination, then the lessee must correct, if necessary, the amount of royalties paid by the end of the third month following the month in which the lessee received the determination from Interior. Subject to the full and timely payment of monthly royalties in accordance with the agreement,&#160;Interior must waive interest due on royalty obligations until the end of the third month.&#160;&#160;&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-562</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
