<bill session="115" type="s" number="3217" updated="2022-02-02T05:50:02Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to reauthorize the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000360"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Alexander. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-07-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="517">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 517.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-12-19">
      <text>By Senator Alexander from Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions filed written report. Report No. 115-434.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2353" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4387" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3137" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="653" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="790" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="3101" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-08T17:25:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Strengthening Career and Technical Education for the 21st Century Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2023 and increases funding levels for Department of Education (ED) grants to states, national programs, and tribally controlled postsecondary career and technical education (CTE) institutions under the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 to support CTE programs for secondary and postsecondary students. It repeals the authorization for certain occupational and information activities and the separate mandate for tech prep education.

 Beginning in FY2021, states must receive at least 90% of their previous year's allocation of basic state CTE grants.

The bill permits states to:

 reserve up to 15% (currently 10%) of their grant funds for innovative CTE activities in rural areas or areas with higher numbers of CTE students, and set their own annual targets on the core indicators of performance at both the secondary and postsecondary education levels without ED's approval. The bill modifies grant application processes for states and localities and performance measures for evaluating CTE programs. It prohibits ED from withholding funds from states that do not meet certain performance measures.

The bill amends the Wagner-Peyser Act to expand the duties of state agencies with respect to providing workforce and labor market information.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 115-434</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
