<bill session="109" type="s" number="1554" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:21Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Antiterrorism Capabilities Through International Cooperation Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an intergovernmental grant program to identify and develop homeland security information, equipment, capabilities, technologies, and services to further the homeland security of the United States and to address the homeland security needs of Federal, State, and local governments.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Promoting Antiterrorism Capabilities Through International Cooperation Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Collins with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="509">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 509.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-29T18:20:54Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Promoting Antiterrorism Capabilities Through International Cooperation Act of 2006 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Under Secretary for Science and Technology to establish the Science and Technology Homeland Security International Cooperative Programs Office.

Requires the Office's Director to: (1) be responsible for developing mechanisms, legal frameworks, and strategic priorities for international cooperative activity in support of homeland security research; (2) facilitate the matching of U.S. and foreign entities engaged in homeland security research so that they may partner in research activities; (3) ensure that the activities are coordinated with those of other relevant research agencies; and (4) hold periodic international homeland security technology workshops and conferences to improve contact among the international community of technology developers and help establish direction for future technology goals.

Requires the Director to ensure that funding and resources expended in international cooperative activity will be equitably matched by the foreign partner government or other entity through direct funding, the funding of complementary activities, or the provision of staff, facilities, material, or equipment. Authorizes the Director to require a grant recipient to: (1) match up to 50% of the cost of the proposed project; and (2) repay the grant amount (or a portion thereof), interest, and charges for grant administration.

Includes among partners Israel, the United Kingdom, Canada, Australia, Singapore, and other allies in the global war on terrorism.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
