<bill session="119" type="h" number="5851" updated="2025-11-18T17:56:33Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Keep America Flying Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keep America Flying Act of 2026</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making continuing appropriations for essential Federal Aviation Administration and Transportation Security Administration pay and operations in the event of a Federal Government shutdown, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000307"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001230" joined="2025-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="3031" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-30T13:20:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Keep America Flying Act of 2026

This bill provides continuing appropriations to pay air traffic controllers, other essential Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) employees, and certain Transportation Security Administration (TSA) employees during the period in which interim or full-year appropriations for FY2026 are not in effect (i.e., the government shutdown).

Specifically, the bill provides FY2026 continuing appropriations to&#160;pay and provide benefits to

air traffic controllers and other FAA essential operational personnel whose services are required for the safe and orderly operation of the national airspace system; andTSA employees engaged in screening operations, aviation security duties, or related mission-support functions necessary to carry out security screening.The bill also provides appropriations for payments to&#160;FAA and TSA contractors who are providing support to these employees.

The bill provides the continuing appropriations until the earlier of (1) the enactment into law of specified appropriations legislation, or (2) September 30, 2026.&#160;

The bill must take effect as if it had been enacted on September 30, 2025.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
