<bill session="117" type="h" number="6062" updated="2022-12-30T08:18:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hatch Act Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hatch Act Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to strengthen and enhance enforcement and penalties of the Hatch Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2021-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5314" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-19T21:03:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Hatch Act Accountability Act

This bill expands the jurisdiction of the Office of Special Counsel (OSC) to investigate and enforce Hatch Act violations. The Hatch Act prohibits civil service employees in the executive branch of the federal government from engaging in some forms of political activity (e.g., advocating for or against a partisan political party while on duty). The purpose of the act is to maintain a federal workforce free from partisan political influence or coercion.

Specifically, the bill allows OSC to investigate Hatch Act violations involving White House political appointees. If OSC determines that a White House political appointee has violated the Hatch Act, the bill allows OSC to refer a complaint to the Merit Systems Protection Board for imposition of a civil penalty of up to $50,000.

The bill also allows OSC to investigate Hatch Act violations regardless of whether a complaint has been filed.</summary>
</bill>
