<bill session="119" type="s" number="608" updated="2025-06-10T22:00:59Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IRS MATH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Internal Revenue Service Math and Taxpayer Help Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IRS MATH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require additional information on math and clerical error notices.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="998" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-09T13:04:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Internal Revenue Service Math and Taxpayer Help Act of 2025 or the&#160;IRS MATH Act of 2025

This bill requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to provide specific information on a notice related to a math or clerical error, send a notice related to an abatement of taxes assessed due to a math or clerical error, provide procedures for requesting such an abatement, and implement a pilot program for sending notices of a math or clerical error.

Under the bill, a notice sent by the IRS regarding&#160;a math or clerical error must include

a clear description of the error and the specific federal tax return line on which the error was made,an itemized computation of adjustments required to correct the error,the telephone number for the automated transcript service, andthe deadline for requesting an abatement of any tax assessed due to the error.Further, the bill requires the IRS to send a notice related to an abatement of tax assessed due to a math or clerical error that clearly describes the abatement and includes an itemized computation of adjustments to be made to the items described in the notice of the&#160;error.

The bill also requires the IRS to

provide procedures for requesting an abatement of tax assessed due to a math or clerical error,implement a pilot program to send notices of a math or clerical error by certified or registered mail, andreport to Congress certain information about the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
