<bill session="110" type="h" number="5828" updated="2019-11-15T21:10:13Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Exports Through Coordination and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="display">Securing Exports Through Coordination and Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the reliability of information in the Automated Export System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001138"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2008-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2008-04-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-06-10T18:33:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Exports Through Coordination and Technology Act - Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 2003 to revise filing requirements under the Automated Export System (AES).

Requires carriers obliged to file Shipper's Export Declarations to file them through AES (either directly or through intermediaries) before items are exported from any U.S. port, unless the Secretary of Commerce grants an exception. (Under current law such a filing may be made after departure of the carrier from the port or place of exportation or transportation.) Defines "intermediary" as a freight forwarder, a non-vessel operating common carrier, or an ATA (Admission Temporaire/Temporary Admission) Carnet and its service providers.

Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) the confidentiality and the sharing of Shipper's Export Declarations with the public and government agencies; and (2) conferences and seminars to educate exporters about U.S. export laws and the AES.

Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) grant licenses to persons to file information in the AES; and (2) deny, suspend, or revoke a license. Provides for administrative and judicial appeal of license denials, suspensions, or revocations.

Requires the Secretary to issue regulations to ensure that the AES will not accept filings with respect to exports that would violate U.S. export control laws or trade sanctions regulations.</summary>
</bill>
