<bill session="116" type="h" number="7157" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLIGHT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require pilot programs in connection with Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps units at Historically Black Colleges and Universities and minority institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLIGHT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fostering Leadership and Inclusion by Growing HBCU Training Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000371" joined="2020-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2020-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001210" joined="2020-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6395" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3953" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-24T15:10:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Fostering Leadership and Inclusion by Growing HBCU Training Act of 2020 or the FLIGHT Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense to carry out five-year pilot programs to

 assess the feasibility and advisability of mechanisms to reduce barriers to participation in the Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps at certain historically Black colleges and universities and certain other minority institutions of higher education (covered institutions) by creating partnerships between satellite or extension Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps units at such institutions and military installations, and assess the feasibility and advisability of providing financial assistance to members of the Senior Reserve Officers' Training Corps and members of the Coast Guard College Student Pre-Commissioning Initiative at covered institutions for participation in flight training.</summary>
</bill>
