<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="181" updated="2022-02-03T06:07:50Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2410" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-06-10T17:45:31-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000410"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <description>Amendment (1) makes a number of minor, technical and conforming changes, including changes to address concerns of other Committees that have jurisdiction over certain provisions of H.R. 2410 and making changes to certain authorizations; (2) adds the relevant text from H.R. 2828, 110th Congress, as passed by the House, relating to compensation of Foreign Service victims of terrorism; (3) adds a provision relating to streamlining export controls to better serve the scientific and research community, consistent with the protection of U.S. national security interests; (4) adds a provision on monitoring and evaluating certain provision U.S. overseas activities; (5) adds a provision to improve the stabilization and reconstruction activities of the Department of State; (6) adds a provision on implementation of an international nuclear fuel bank; (7) adds a provision relating to the development of a food security strategy; (8) adds certain other sense of congress provisions; and (9) adds a new subsection to section 334 providing that nothing in that section shall be construed as affecting existing statutory prohibitions relating to abortion.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in part C of House Report 111-143 to (1) make a number of minor, technical and conforming changes, including changes to address concerns of other Committees that have jurisdiction over certain provisions of H.R. 2410 and making changes to certain authorizations; (2) add the relevant text from H.R. 2828, 110th Congress, as passed by the House, relating to compensation of Foreign Service victims of terrorism; (3) add a provision relating to streamlining export controls to better serve the scientific and research community, consistent with the protection of U.S. national security interests; (4) add a provision on monitoring and evaluating certain provision U.S. overseas activities; (5) add a provision to improve the stabilization and reconstruction activities of the Department of State; (6) add a provision on implementation of an international nuclear fuel bank; (7) add a provision relating to the development of a food security strategy; (8) adds certain other sense of congress provisions; and (9) add a new subsection to section 334 providing that nothing in that section shall be construed as affecting existing statutory prohibitions relating to abortion.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-06-10T17:45:31-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="320">
      <text>On agreeing to the Berman amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 257 - 171 (Roll no. 320).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T13:37:27-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Berman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6477-6483, H6509-6510" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6477-6481" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T13:37:27-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Berman.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6477-6483, H6509-6510" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6477-6481" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:45:31-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:45:31-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:45:31-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Berman amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 257 - 171 (Roll no. 320).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
