<bill session="118" type="h" number="7023" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-21T17:13:42-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-21T17:13:42-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Creating Confidence in Clean Water Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Creating Confidence in Clean Water Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nationwide Permitting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short">Creating Confidence in Clean Water Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="display">Creating Confidence in Clean Water Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 404 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to codify certain regulatory provisions relating to nationwide permits for dredged or fill material, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to provide regulatory and judicial certainty for regulated entities and communities, increase transparency, and promote water quality, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-375.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-02-06" calendar="Union" number="306">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 306.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T20:07:21-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1085 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, H. Con. Res. 86, H. Res. 98and H.R. 7023. The resolution provides for consideration H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, H. Con. Res. 86, and H. Res. 987 under a closed rule, and H.R. 7023 under a structured rule, each with one hour of general debate. The rule provides for one motion to recommit each on H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, and H.R. 7023.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20T14:09:43-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1085 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:44:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1085.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1322-1340" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1331-1332" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:44:13-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, H. Con. Res. 86, H. Res. 987 and H.R. 7023. The resolution provides for consideration H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, H. Con. Res. 86, and H. Res. 987 under a closed rule, and H.R. 7023 under a structured rule, each with one hour of general debate. The rule provides for one motion to recommit each on H.R. 1023, H.R. 1121, H.R. 6009, and H.R. 7023.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:44:39-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1085 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:44:40-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Daniel Meuser to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T14:45:06-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 7023.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T15:36:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bergman amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T15:42:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garamendi amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T15:48:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Houlahan amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T15:53:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the James amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T15:58:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moolenaar amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:06:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bean (FL) amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:12:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1085, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:56:45-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 7023.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:58:24-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:58:37-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T16:59:49-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Scholten moved to recommit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1328" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T17:06:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 205 - 213 (Roll no. 100).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="101" datetime="2024-03-21T17:13:42-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 213 - 205 (Roll no. 101).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T17:13:44-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-21T17:13:49-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1085" relation="procedurally related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h874"/>
    <amendment number="h873"/>
    <amendment number="h872"/>
    <amendment number="h871"/>
    <amendment number="h870"/>
    <amendment number="h869"/>
    <amendment number="h868"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-03-26T22:46:40Z" status="Passed House">Creating Confidence in Clean Water Permitting Act

This bill modifies requirements under the Clean Water Act, including requirements concerning water quality criteria, the National Pollutant Discharge Elimination System (NPDES) program, the permit program for discharging dredged or fill material into waters of the United States, and the meaning of waters of the United States. It also limits the issuance of permits under the act.

First, the bill directs the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to develop any new or revised water quality criteria for states through a rule.

Next, the bill modifies the NPDES program, including by providing statutory authority for provisions that shield NPDES permit holders from liability under certain circumstances. It also provides statutory authority for the EPA to issue general permits under the program. The EPA must also provide written notification two years before the expiration of a general permit. If notice is not provided by that deadline, then discharges under the expired permit may continue until a new permit is issued. Finally, the bill extends the maximum term for NPDES permits issued to states or municipalities from 5 to 10 years.

Additionally, the bill modifies the permitting program of the EPA and the U.S. Corps of Engineers that regulates the discharge of dredged or fill material into waters of the United States. For example, the bill limits the EPA's veto authority to restrict, prohibit, deny, or withdraw the specification by the Corps of a site for the discharge of dredged or fill material into waters of the United States. The bill also modifies requirements for general permits to discharge dredge or fill material that are issued on a nationwide, regional, or state basis for particular categories of activities, including by extending the maximum term for a general permit from a period of 5 years to 10 years. It also exempts the Corps from certain consultation and environmental review requirements when reissuing nationwide general permits.

Further, the bill also provides statutory authority for the EPA's decision to approve Florida's request to assume permitting authority from the Corps for the discharge of dredged or fill material. The decision, which was issued in 2020, was subsequently vacated in 2024 by the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia.

The bill also directs the EPA and the Corps to begin a process to issue guidance on the implementation of the 2023 final rule titled Revised Definition of "Waters of the United States"; Conforming and stipulates the guidance must comply with the decision of the Supreme Court in Sackett v. EPA.

Finally, the bill prohibits permits from being issued under Title IV of the Clean Water Act for any discharges from a point source that is owned or operated by certain foreign counties of concern and any subsidiaries of entities that are subject to the jurisdiction of such countries.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-375</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
