<bill session="118" type="h" number="5688" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bipartisan HSA Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bipartisan HSA Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bipartisan HSA Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to improve health savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2023-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-26">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 118-401.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-02-26" calendar="Union" number="330">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 330.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5716" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5777" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-13T22:14:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Bipartisan HSA Improvement Act of 2023

This bill allows an individual to contribute to a health savings account (HSA), as part of a high deductible health plan (HDHP), while also participating in a primary care service arrangement, receiving qualified items or services at an employer-sponsored on-site clinic, or if covered under a spouse&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s flexible spending arrangement (FSA). Further, the bill allows individuals to rollover amounts in an FSA or health reimbursement arrangement (HRA) into an HSA.

The bill defines a primary care service arrangement as one in which an individual is provided primary care services by a primary care practitioner for a periodic fixed fee of no more than $150 a month for an individual (or no more than $300 a month for an arrangement that covers more than one individual).

Additionally, under the bill, qualified items or services received at an employer-sponsored, on-site clinic include physical exams, immunizations, nonprescription drugs or biologicals, treatment for injuries related to an individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s employment, preventative care for chronic conditions, and vision and hearing screenings.

The bill allows an individual to contribute to an HSA, as part of an HDHP, even if covered by a spouse&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s FSA. However, amounts in the spouse&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s FSA must be used to reimburse the spouse&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s eligible medical expenses for the plan year before being rolled over into the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s HSA.

Finally, individuals may be able to rollover up to the annual FSA contribution limit from an FSA or HRA into an HSA upon enrolling in an HDHP.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-401</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
