<bill session="118" type="s" number="3580" updated="2025-11-19T03:40:45Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require institutions of higher education participating in Federal student aid programs to share information about title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, including a link to the webpage of the Office for Civil Rights where an individual can submit a complaint regarding discrimination in violation of such title, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2024-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2024-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2024-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2024-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2024-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2024-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2024-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7735" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-05T13:16:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Students on Campus Act of 2024

This bill requires the Department of Education (ED) and institutions of higher education (IHEs) participating in federal student aid programs to distribute information on how to report alleged violations of civil rights under Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964. (Title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 prohibits discrimination based on race, color, or national origin in federally funded programs or activities.)

Specifically, the bill requires ED's Office for Civil Rights (OCR) to conduct a public awareness campaign regarding the rights&#160;of individuals under Title VI. This campaign must be updated annually and distributed to IHEs.

The bill requires an IHE to post a link on its website on how to file a Title VI complaint with OCR. Additionally, the&#160;IHE must annually post the materials from OCR's public awareness campaign. The information must be posted in high-traffic public places on campus (e.g., student centers) and high-traffic websites (e.g., the website for student services).&#160;

OCR must give monthly congressional briefings on (1) the number of complaints filed with OCR, (2) how OCR plans to address those complaints and the investigations opened in response to those complaints, and (3) how long those complaints remain open.&#160;Additionally, the bill prohibits OCR from closing or dismissing a complaint due to resolution via another agency or avenue.&#160;

The bill also requires annual reporting by IHEs on discrimination complaints. Further, the bill directs ED's Office of Inspector General to audit and study discrimination complaints.</summary>
</bill>
