<bill session="117" type="s" number="3031" updated="2023-07-31T14:00:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Water Allotment Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Water Allotment Modernization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to modify certain allotments under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2021-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5653" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-31T13:54:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Water Allotment Modernization Act of 2021

This bill revises the formula the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) uses to determine how to distribute funds from the Clean Water State Revolving Fund (SRF) program. Under the program, the EPA allocates funding to states for water quality infrastructure projects, such as wastewater systems and stormwater management projects.

In FY2022-FY2026, the EPA must provide an initial allotment to each state that is equal to the amount the state received in FY2023. The EPA must also provide an additional allotment to each state that is based on its share of the U.S. population.

In FY2027 and each subsequent fiscal year, the EPA must use an updated allotment formula, which is based on the needs of states as identified in the most recently available clean watersheds needs survey.

Beginning in FY2022, the formula must also provide allotments for Indian tribes and territories. In addition, the formula must provide an allotment for EPA's oversight of SRF projects to ensure they use American iron and steel.</summary>
</bill>
