<bill session="118" type="s" number="965" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Success for Rural Students and Communities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Success for Rural Students and Communities Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a rural postsecondary and economic development grant program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S934-935" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-05T18:39:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Success for Rural Students and Communities Act of 2023

This bill establishes a grant program through which the Department of Education may award funds to eligible partnerships to support rural postsecondary education and economic growth and development in rural communities.

A grant recipient must be a partnership whose members represent at least three designated types of organizations, specifically (1) a local educational agency or educational service agency serving a rural area, (2) an institution of higher education (IHE), (3) a regional economic development entity, or (4) a rural community-serving organization with demonstrated success supporting rural students in accessing higher education and attaining degrees.

A grant recipient must use awarded funds to carry out no fewer than two specified activities, namely (1) improving postsecondary enrollment rates for rural secondary school students, (2) increasing enrollment and completion rates of rural nontraditional students in degree programs at IHEs, (3) creating or strengthening academic programs at rural-serving IHEs to prepare graduates to enter into high-need occupations in the regional and local economies, or (4) generating local and regional economic development that creates employment opportunities for rural students with postsecondary degrees.</summary>
</bill>
