<bill session="111" type="s" number="956" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:58Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preserve Patient Access to Reputable DMEPOS Providers Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to exempt unsanctioned State-licensed retail pharmacies from the surety bond requirement under the Medicare Program for suppliers of durable medical equipment, prosthetics, orthotics, and supplies (DMEPOS).</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserve Patient Access to Reputable DMEPOS Providers Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001071" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2009-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2009-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2009-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1970" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-20T14:57:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserve Patient Access to Reputable DMEPOS Providers Act of 2009 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to declare that the surety bond requirement under the Medicare program for suppliers of durable medical equipment, prosthetics, orthotics, and supplies (DMEPOS) shall apply only to a state-licensed retail pharmacy if there has been a final adverse action that is not subject to administrative or judicial appeal taken against such pharmacy during the 10-year period preceding the issuance (or renewal) of the provider number involved.

(Thus exempts from the surety bond requirement any state-licensed retail pharmacy that has not been subject to such an adverse action for at least 10 years. Such adverse actions refer to: (1) a Medicare-imposed revocation of any Medicare billing privileges; (2) suspension or revocation of a license to provide health care by any state licensing authority; (3) revocation or suspension by an accreditation organization; (4) conviction of a federal or state felony offense within the last 10 years preceding enrollment, revalidation, or re-enrollment; or (5) an exclusion or debarment from participation in a federal or state health care program.)</summary>
</bill>
