<bill session="116" type="h" number="3719" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CTPAT Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Security and Accountability for Every Port Act of 2006 to reauthorize the Customs Trade Partnership Against Terrorism Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CTPAT Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2019-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2019-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8309" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-29T20:31:24Z" status="Introduced in House">CTPAT Reauthorization Act of 2019

This bill revises and permanently reauthorizes the Customs Trade Partnership Against Terrorism (CTPAT), a voluntary, public-private partnership program for expediting the movement of secure cargo through the international supply chain.

Specifically, the bill allows an eligible entity (e.g., importer, exporter, customs broker, or carrier) that meets certain security measures and supply chain practices to apply to participate in the CTPAT program at a defined tier, pursuant to which it will receive tier-specific benefits such as fewer inspections at ports of entry, priority examination of cargo, and other accelerated trade mechanisms. The bill authorizes U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to suspend or remove a participant that fails to meet minimum security criteria, provides false or misleading information, or poses a threat to national security.

Additionally, the bill revises the process for an eligible entity's recertification and revalidation, and it allows CBP to recognize a revalidation conducted by a foreign government under a Mutual Recognition Agreement.</summary>
</bill>
