<bill session="118" type="h" number="185" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-08T16:59:34-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-08T16:59:34-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To terminate the requirement imposed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for proof of COVID-19 vaccination for foreign travelers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To terminate the requirement imposed by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention for proof of COVID-19 vaccination for foreign travelers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000377" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2023-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2023-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2023-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000626" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000478" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000590" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000596" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001095" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000596" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2023-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2023-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2023-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000929" joined="2023-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2023-01-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2023-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000067" joined="2023-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07T09:32:05-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 97 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 185, H.J. Res. 24 and H.J. Res. 26 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:02:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 97.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H747-757" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H752-753" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:02:31-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 185, H.J. Res. 24 and H.J. Res. 26 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:03:03-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 97 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:03:05-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Kevin Kiley to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:04:13-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 185.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:45:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 97, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McGovern amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:52:49-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McGovern amendment No. 1, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:53:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 97, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T14:58:40-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Boebert demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:00:05-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 97, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Golden (ME) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:00:06-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Golden (ME) amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:04:07-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 97, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rose amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:12:01-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rose amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:13:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 97, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Torres (CA) amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:16:53-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Torres (CA) amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Pallone demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:17:11-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Bucshon moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:17:33-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T15:18:05-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 185 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:00:32-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H757-762" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:00:48-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:01:04-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINES - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on the question of agreeing to amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:45:09-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 185.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:45:49-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:46:00-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:46:54-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Schrier moved to recommit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H760" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:47:03-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:53:10-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by recorded vote: 208 - 220 (Roll no. 115).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="116" datetime="2023-02-08T16:59:34-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 201 (Roll no. 116).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08T16:59:36-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-02-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="14">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 14.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="455" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="97" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3094" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h84"/>
    <amendment number="h83"/>
    <amendment number="h82"/>
    <amendment number="h81"/>
    <amendment number="h80"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-02-13T20:57:44Z" status="Passed House">This bill nullifies the order issued by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) titled Amended Order Implementing Presidential Proclamation on Advancing the Safe Resumption of Global Travel During the COVID-19 Pandemic and published on April 7, 2022. (The order restricts the entry of noncitizens who are not immigrants into the United States by air travel unless they are fully vaccinated against COVID-19 or otherwise attest that they will take public health measures to prevent the spread of the disease.)

The bill also nullifies any successor or subsequent orders that require foreign persons traveling by air to show proof of a COVID-19 vaccination as a condition of entry and prohibits the use of federal funds to administer or enforce such a requirement. However, the bill does not affect the CDC order published on January 5, 2023, that governs COVID-19 testing or documentation of COVID-19 recovery for certain individuals traveling from China to the United States by aircraft.

In addition, the CDC must report to Congress about the number of visitors who were denied entry into the United States from April 7, 2022, until the date of the bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
