<bill session="117" type="h" number="2267" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving State and Local Government Access to Performance Contracting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to provide Federal financial assistance to States to implement expanded energy savings performance contracting programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving State and Local Government Access to Performance Contracting Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2021-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2021-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-10T22:02:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving State and Local Government Access to Performance Contracting Act

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to provide financial assistance to states for the implementation, improvement, or expansion of a state energy savings performance contracting program. Energy savings performance contract means a contract that provides for the performance of services for the design, acquisition, installation, testing, operation, maintenance, or repair of an energy conservation measure, water conservation measure, resiliency-related measure, utility cost savings measure, or series of measures.

Upon the request of a state, DOE must provide information and technical assistance in the development and implementation of such a state program.

Further, DOE must establish a national project facilitator certification program to expand the availability of individuals who are trained and certified to work on behalf of the state and local government as project facilitators who will assist with the oversight of projects under state programs.</summary>
</bill>
