<bill session="111" type="s" number="1086" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:00Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Livestock Marketing Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921, to prohibit the use of certain anti-competitive forward contracts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Livestock Marketing Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2009-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5702-5703"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5703" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-15T15:15:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Livestock Marketing Fairness Act - Amends the Packers and Stockyards Act, 1921 to prohibit a livestock sale forward contract (with an exception for specified cooperatives) that: (1) does not contain a firm base price that may be equated to a fixed dollar amount on the contract day; (2) is not offered for open public bid; (3) is based on a formula price; or (4) provides for the sale of more that 40 cattle, 30 swine, or other livestock in a quantity as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture.

Defines: (1) "firm base price" as a transaction using an external source reference price; (2) "formula price" as any price term that establishes a base from which a purchase price is calculated on the basis of a price that will not be determined or reported until a date after the forward price is established (with specified exclusions); and (3) "forward contract" as a livestock purchase contract that provides for livestock delivery to a packer at a date that is more than seven days after the date on which the contract is entered into, without regard to whether the contract is for a specified lot of livestock or a specified number of livestock over a certain period of time.</summary>
</bill>
