<bill session="117" type="s" number="2671" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-06">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DISCLOSE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Democracy Is Strengthened by Casting Light On Spending in Elections Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DISCLOSE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for additional disclosure requirements for corporations, labor organizations, Super PACs and other entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5946-5951" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-08-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="120">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 120.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1279" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1334" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="443" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2093" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5746" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4822" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-03T20:02:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Democracy Is Strengthened by Casting Light On Spending in Elections Act of 2021 or the DISCLOSE Act of 2021

This bill addresses campaign finance, including by expanding the prohibition on campaign spending by foreign nationals and requiring additional disclosures of campaign expenditures.

First, the bill prohibits foreign nationals from participating in the decision-making process regarding an election expenditure.

Additionally, the bill expands existing foreign money prohibitions to include disbursements for paid web-based or digital communications and federal judicial nomination communications. It also prohibits foreign nationals from contributing to campaigns related to ballot initiatives and referenda.

The Federal Election Commission (FEC) must conduct an audit after each federal election cycle to determine the incidence of illicit foreign money.

Next, the bill makes it unlawful to establish or use a corporation, company, or other entity with the intent to conceal an election contribution or donation by a foreign national. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to five years, or both.

 Covered organizations (e.g., corporations, labor organizations, and political organizations) must, within 24 hours, file reports with the FEC to disclose campaign expenditures of more than $10,000 during an election cycle.</summary>
</bill>
