<bill session="117" type="h" number="4029" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to establish an interagency national security review process, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">TEAM TELECOM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEAM TELECOM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Timely Evaluation of Acquisitions, Mergers, or Transactions with External, Lawful Entities to Clear Owners and Management Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-10T18:15:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Timely Evaluation of Acquisitions, Mergers, or Transactions with External, Lawful Entities to Clear Owners and Management Act or the TEAM TELECOM Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the interagency working group at the National Telecommunications and Information Administration that assesses and addresses the law enforcement and national security policy implications arising from foreign ownership in an applicant for certain telecommunications licenses and permits.

Such applications are those for (1) authorization to construct or extend, acquire or operate, or engage in transmission by means of a line (i.e., any channel of communication established by the use of appropriate equipment); (2) a submarine cable landing license or its assignment or transfer; or (3) a new construction permit or station license (or for the transfer, assignment, or disposal of an existing permit or license).</summary>
</bill>
