<bill session="114" type="s" number="1603" updated="2023-04-24T19:48:51Z">
  <state datetime="2015-09-09">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to actively recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as Customs and Border Protection Officers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Born-Alive Abortion Survivors Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2015-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2015-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2015-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2015-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2015-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2015-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2015-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000461" joined="2015-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2015-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-06-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-08-05">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-116.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-08-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="196">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6539-6040" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6539" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-09">
      <text>The committee reported substitute amendment was withdrawn by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6539" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2015-09-09" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10T10:54:56-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Homeland Security, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-18T12:56:22-04:00">
      <text>Passed House with amendment pursuant to H. Res. 421.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-21">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="2835" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="114" type="hr" number="421" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="3504" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2648"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2015-09-22T20:07:25Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Border Jobs for Veterans Act of 2015

(Sec. 3) Directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS): (1) in conjunction with the Department of Defense (DOD), to identify Military Occupational Specialty Codes and Officer Branches, Air Force Specialty Codes, Naval Enlisted Classifications and Officer Designators, and Coast Guard Competencies (qualifications) that are transferable to the requirements and duties assigned to Customs and Border Protection (CBP) Officers; and (2) to consider hiring qualified candidates with such qualifications who are eligible for veterans recruitment appointment.

(Sec. 4) Directs DHS, in conjunction with DOD, acting through existing programs, authorities, and agreements, to enhance DHS efforts to recruit members of the Armed Forces who are separating from military service to serve as CBP Officers. Requires such enhanced efforts to:

 include CBP Officer opportunities in relevant job assistance efforts under the Transition Assistance Program; place CBP officials or other relevant DHS officials at recruiting events and jobs fairs involving separating members of the Armed Forces; provide opportunities for local CBP field offices to partner with military bases in the region; include outreach efforts to educate members of the Armed Forces with qualifications that are transferable to CBP Officer requirements; require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to identify shared activities and opportunities for reciprocity related to steps in hiring CBP officers with the goal of minimizing the time required to hire qualified applicants; require DOD and DHS to work cooperatively to ensure the streamlined interagency transfer of relevant background investigations and security clearances; and include other elements to ensure that separating members of the Armed Forces are aware of opportunities to fill vacant CBP Officer positions. (Sec. 5) Directs DHS and DOD, within 180 days after enactment of this Act and by December 31 of each of the three successive years, to jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees on DHS efforts to hire separating service members as CBP Officers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-116</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
