<bill session="116" type="h" number="8526" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:34Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HSAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Smart Air Travel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HSAT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to carry out a health smart air travel pilot program to improve the application of public health risk mitigation measures related to the public health risks presented by COVID-19 in airports and on passenger aircraft.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000133"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Energy and Commerce, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-04T19:12:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Smart Air Travel Act or the HSAT Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish a pilot program to improve the application of public health risk mitigation measures related to the public health risks presented by COVID-19 (i.e. coronavirus disease 2019) in airports and on passenger aircraft.

DOT may provide grants under the program to states, commercial airlines, airports, public health institutions, and other entities to to carry out development, testing, or evaluation of such public health risk mitigation measures.

DOT, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), and the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must each designate federal facilities for receiving, processing, and analyzing data collected and experience gained by recipients of grants under the program.

DOT, DHS, and HHS must use the data collected and experience gained to (1) jointly identify technical, regulatory, or policy challenges to the integration of public health risk mitigation measures related to the public health risks created by COVID-19 in airports and on passenger aircraft; and (2) inform ongoing initiatives by the Federal Aviation Administration, the Transportation Security Administration, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention to develop operational standards and procedures to mitigate such public health risks.</summary>
</bill>
