<bill session="108" type="s" number="716" updated="2023-01-15T23:03:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Power Act Amendments Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Power Act to improve the electricity transmission system of the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Power Act Amendments Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000447" joined="2003-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4442-4443"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Power marketing administrations"/>
    <term name="Public utility regulation"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-25T19:06:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Federal Power Act Amendments Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal Power Act to provide that Federal regulation of electric energy transmission and sales shall not extend to those matters which are subject to regulation by the States, including the retail sale of electric energy and any component service.

Denies the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) jurisdiction over: (1) bundled retail sales of electric energy (sales of electric energy to retail customers where generation, transmission, distribution, and other services necessary to supply electric energy to such customers are sold as a single delivered service by a single seller); and (2) the transmission component of sales of electric energy to retail customers.

Requires FERC, upon request of a Regional Transmission Organization or any FERC-authorized transmission entity, to authorize the recovery of costs on a participant-funding basis of transmission facilities that increase the transfer capability of the transmission system.

Directs FERC to establish technical standards and procedures for the interconnection of facilities used for the transmission of electric energy in interstate commerce with facilities used for the generation of electric energy.

Instructs FERC to ensure, in setting rates for transmission services, that all jurisdictional uses of transmission facilities bear an allocation of the embedded costs of the facilities, as well as the costs of other services ancillary to the transmission of electric energy.

Directs FERC to promulgate pricing policies and standards to promote expansion and improvement of interstate transmission networks through incentive-based, performance-based, participant-funded and cost of service-based rate treatments to ensure reliability of the electric system, to support interstate wholesale markets for electric power, and to expand transmission transfer capacity needed to sustain wholesale competition.

Directs FERC to convene regional discussions with State and other retail regulatory commissions to address whether wholesale electric markets in each region (especially regions without a regional transmission organization) are working effectively to provide reliable service to electric consumers in the region at the lowest reasonable cost.

Authorizes FERC to require an unregulated transmitting utility to provide open access transmission services.</summary>
</bill>
