<bill session="119" type="s" number="622" updated="2025-10-16T17:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe Reservation Restoration Act to provide for the transfer of additional Federal land to the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-14">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Murkowski without amendment. With written report No. 119-78.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-10-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="187">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 187.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-27T14:35:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Leech Lake Reservation Restoration Amendments Act of 2025

This bill transfers certain federal land located in the Chippewa National Forest in Cass County, Minnesota, to the Department of the Interior for the benefit of the Leech Lake Band of Ojibwe.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to transfer for the benefit of the tribe land in the Chippewa National Forest that records maintained by the Bureau of Indian Affairs show was sold without the unanimous consent of the rightful landowners.

Upon agreement between USDA and the tribe, USDA shall substitute alternative National Forest System land located in Cass County, Minnesota, on an acre-for-acre basis for those parcels of federal land to be transferred in a manner that avoids inholdings and provides a preference for land adjacent to or near existing Leech Lake trust lands and lands of cultural importance to the tribe, to the maximum extent practicable.

USDA may transfer land to Interior on a rolling basis as that land is identified and surveys are completed.

USDA, acting through the&#160;U.S. Forest Service, must&#160;provide for public engagement and comment to implement this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-78</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
