<bill session="116" type="s" number="4243" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Children of Immigrant Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Children of Immigrant Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect children of certain immigrant workers from detention and removal and aging out of lawful status, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4354-4355" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-11T19:04:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Children of Immigrant Workers Act

This bill provides protections for an alien minor whose parent is the principal beneficiary of an employment-based immigrant petition.

Specifically, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall not detain or remove such a minor. The minor shall be eligible for nonimmigrant status, either dependent on the parent's status or otherwise, until a decision has been made on the minor's application for lawful permanent resident status.

Such a minor shall also qualify as a derivative beneficiary child for immigrant visa purposes starting from the approval of the parent's employment-based immigration petition until a decision has been made on the minor's application for permanent resident status, even if the parent is deceased.

These protections shall not apply if DHS determines that the minor poses a threat to public safety or national security.</summary>
</bill>
