<bill session="111" type="h" number="1938" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:35Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting Wellness for Individuals with Disabilities Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 and the Public Health Service Act to set standards for medical diagnostic equipment and to establish a program for promoting good health, disease prevention, and wellness and for the prevention of secondary conditions for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Wellness for Individuals with Disabilities Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-18T16:06:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Wellness for Individuals with Disabilities Act of 2009 - Amends the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to require the Architectural and Transportation Barriers Compliance Board to issue and periodically review standards setting forth the minimum technical criteria for medical diagnostic equipment used in medical settings, to ensure that such equipment: (1) is accessible to and usable by individuals with disabilities; and (2) allows independent entry to, use of, and exit from the equipment by such individuals to the maximum extent possible. Applies such standards to examination tables and chairs, weight scales, mammography equipment, x-ray machines, and other radiological equipment commonly used for diagnostic purposes by health professionals. Sets forth interim standards for such equipment.

Amends the Public Health Service Act to allow the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for programs to promote good health, disease prevention, and wellness for individuals with disabilities and prevent secondary conditions in such individuals. Requires the Secretary to establish a National Advisory Committee on Wellness for Individuals With Disabilities to set priorities to carry out such programs, review grant proposals, make recommendations for funding, and annually evaluate the progress of such programs in implementing the priorities.

Provides for training programs to improve competency and clinical skills for providing health care and communicating with patients with disabilities through training integrated into the core curriculum and patient interaction in community-based settings.</summary>
</bill>
