<bill session="110" type="h" number="182" updated="2021-06-07T19:40:58Z">
  <state datetime="2007-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TEAM up for Energy Independence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">To Encourage Alternatively fueled vehicle Manufacturing up for Energy Independence Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="display">TEAM up for Energy Independence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on automobiles sold in the United States that are not alternative fueled automobiles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-01-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E19"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobiles"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-01-19T22:04:44Z" status="Introduced in House">To Encourage Alternatively fueled vehicle Manufacturing up for Energy Independence Act of 2007 or the TEAM up for Energy Independence Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax on the first retail sale of each passenger automobile sold by manufacturers, producers, or importers. Exempts alternative fueled automobiles from such tax.

Amends federal transportation law to revise the definitons of "automobile" and "passenger automobile" to increase the gross vehicle weight limit from 6,000 to 10,000 pounds.

Directs the Secretary of Energy to make grants for alternative fuel refueling infrastructure projects from a trust fund into which revenues from the excise tax on passenger automobiles shall be deposited.

Amends the Automobile Information Disclosure Act to require labeling for new automobiles to indicate: (1) whether a new automobile is an alternative fueled automobile; and (2) the types of fuel on which such automobile can operate.</summary>
</bill>
