<bill session="112" type="h" number="3721" updated="2019-11-15T21:31:57Z">
  <state datetime="2011-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALUTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember Assistance for Lawful Understanding, Treatment, and Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize veterans' treatment courts and encourage services for veterans through drug courts under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</title>
    <title type="display">SALUTE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000210" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2012-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2012-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000807" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000063" joined="2011-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-07T22:24:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Servicemember Assistance for Lawful Understanding, Treatment, and Education Act or the SALUTE Act - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Attorney General to make grants for veterans' treatment courts and programs for continuing judicial supervision over offenders who are veterans.

Requires such grants to be used for: (1) developing, implementing, or enhancing veterans' treatment courts or expanding operational mental health or drug courts to serve veterans to ensure that such courts effectively integrate substance abuse treatment, mental health treatment, sanctions and incentives, and transitional services in a judicially supervised court setting with jurisdiction over offenders that have served in the U.S. military; and (2) programs that involve continuing judicial supervision over offenders with substance abuse or mental health problems who have served in the U.S. military and the integrated administration of other sanctions and services, which shall include substance abuse and mental health treatment for each participant and diversion, probation, or other supervised release involving the possibility of prosecution, confinement, or incarceration based on noncompliance with program requirements or failure to show satisfactory progress.

Requires an evaluation report submited by a state, Indian tribal government, or local government that receives funds under such Act to include data on and an evaluation of the effectiveness of veterans' treatment courts and programs.</summary>
</bill>
