<bill session="116" type="h" number="1740" updated="2022-11-01T17:47:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Workforce for an Expanding Economy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide for an H-2C nonimmigrant classification, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce for an Expanding Economy Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2019-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2019-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2019-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001088" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000611" joined="2019-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000607" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001187" joined="2019-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2019-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-19T20:56:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Workforce for an Expanding Economy Act

This bill establishes a new nonimmigrant visa for temporary nonagricultural workers (H-2C visa) to fill jobs that have remained open for a certain amount of time and are located in an area where the unemployment rate is 4.9% or less. This visa shall only be available for certain occupations, and those requiring a bachelor's degree or higher level of education shall not be eligible.

The bill imposes various requirements related to H-2C positions, such as requiring that the employer make certain efforts to recruit a U.S. worker beforehand. The employer must register the opening before filling it with an H-2C worker, and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall maintain a publicly available registry of registered positions.

For the first fiscal year after the bill's enactment, no more than 65,000 positions may be registered. For subsequent fiscal years, the number shall be increased or decreased depending on how many positions were registered the previous year and how quickly the allotment was filled. A certain number of allocations shall be reserved for small businesses.

An employer seeking to hire H-2C workers shall register with DHS and provide documentation establishing that the employer meets various qualifications. An employer may become ineligible for registration for certain actions, such as having been penalized for a pattern of willful violation of wage and hour laws.

H-2C workers shall not be entitled to certain federal public benefits.

The Bureau of the Census shall report to Congress on the impact of the H-2C program.</summary>
</bill>
