<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1504</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T06:17:47Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T06:17:47Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-07-30</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <number>2122</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2003-07-17</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 214.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-09-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 265.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-30</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-30</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000445</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Gregg, Judd [R-NH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Judd</firstName>
        <lastName>Gregg</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000105</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kennedy, Edward M. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>EDWARD</firstName>
        <lastName>KENNEDY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>MOORE</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-07-30</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Chemical warfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>EBB Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear warfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Radiation safety</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Weapons of mass destruction</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-07-30</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-10-30T22:42:18Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Project BioShield Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act regarding preparations for public health emergencies affecting national security, including a bioterrorist attack.</p> <p>Grants the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary), through the National Institutes of Health (NIH), certain authority with respect to the research and development of qualified biomedical countermeasures, including: (1) expedited procurement authority; (2) expedited peer authority; and (3) authority for personal services contracts.</p> <p>Directs: (1) the Secretary of Homeland Security to assess current and emerging chemical, biological, radiological, and nuclear threats, and determine which present a material risk to the United States; and (2) the Secretary to assess the public health consequences of such threats, and the availability and appropriateness of countermeasures. Authorizes the Secretaries to jointly propose to the President appropriate countermeasures and procurement. Directs the Secretaries, upon presidential approval, to procure the necessary countermeasures for stockpiling.</p> <p>Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to allow the Secretary to declare a national emergency under specified conditions and authorize the release into interstate commerce of a drug or device intended for use in an emergency. Directs the Secretary, as feasible, to: (1) impose requirements on such authorization, including emergency product labeling and ensuring that health care professionals administering the product and persons to whom the product is administered are informed about benefits, risks, and alternatives; and (2) periodically review, or revoke as circumstances warrant, an authorization. Provides civil monetary penalties for violations of such provisions. Allows the President, under specified circumstances involving the Armed Forces, to waive the requirement that individuals be allowed to refuse administration of a countermeasure.</p> <p>Amends the Social Security Act to revise the Secretary's authority to waive specified requirements during a national emergency. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide protections and countermeasures against chemical, radiological, or nuclear agents that may be used in a terrorist attack against  the United States.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Project BioShield Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Popular Titles</titleType>
        <title>Vaccine Compensation bill</title>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2003-09-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-07-30T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-09-02</actionDate>
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 265.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
