<bill session="118" type="h" number="2895" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:00Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Time Is Up Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Time Is Up Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to announce whether action will be taken with respect to a covered transaction under the Defense Production Act of 1950 that has passed the CFIUS transaction review deadline, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000569"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000594" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001204" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000816" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-14T20:14:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Time Is Up Act of 2023

This bill sets time limits for the President to make certain decisions and take certain actions related to Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) national security reviews and investigations that are incomplete as of this bill's enactment date. (CFIUS is an interagency committee that oversees the national security risk of certain foreign direct investments in the U.S. economy. It may recommend that the President suspend or prohibit certain transactions.)

For certain transactions that are pending CFIUS review on the date of this bill's enactment, the President must announce a decision on whether to suspend or prohibit the transaction no later than 15 days after the bill's enactment. Specifically, this requirement applies to transactions where on the date of the bill's enactment (1) more than 105 days have passed since CFIUS accepted written notice of the transaction from one or more parties to the transaction, (2) more than 105 days have passed since CFIUS unilaterally initiated a review, or (3) more than 60 days have passed since a national security investigation was initiated based on the recommendation of a designated lead agency.

The President must complete any suspensions or prohibitions announced as a result of this bill's requirements within 30 days of the announcement. Additionally, the President must complete within 30 days of the bill's enactment any suspensions or prohibitions announced prior to the bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
