<bill session="108" type="s" number="1639" updated="2023-01-15T07:02:58Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to extend certain protections to franchised refiners or distributors of lubricating oil.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to extend certain protections to franchised refiners or distributors of lubricating oil.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000146"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001126" joined="2003-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2003-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11756"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11756" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-22T20:37:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to extend to contracts between refiners (franchisors) and franchised distributors of trademarked lubricating oil the protections of the Act. Permits termination or non-renewal of such franchise relationships by the franchisor in good faith and in the normal course of business if the franchisor decides to withdraw from the marketing of the lubricating oil in the relevant geographic market in which the oil is distributed, and: (1) the decision is made after the date on which the franchise is entered into or renewed, and on the basis of a change in relevant facts or circumstances relating to the franchise that occurs after such date; and (2) the termination or nonrenewal is not for the purpose of converting any accounts subject to the franchise to the franchisor's account.</summary>
</bill>
