<bill session="117" type="s" number="4796" updated="2023-08-24T19:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local News and Broadcast Media Preservation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local News and Broadcast Media Preservation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the limitations on multiple ownership of radio and television stations imposed by the Federal Communications Commission, to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission from limiting common ownership of daily newspapers and full-power broadcast stations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1735" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="673" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-24T19:08:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Local News and Broadcast Media Preservation Act of 2022

This bill modifies ownership rules and limitations related to media such as newspapers and broadcast stations.

Specifically, the bill repeals specified media ownership limitations and prohibits the Federal Communications Commission from disallowing multiple ownership of radio and television stations. It also prohibits the Federal Trade Commission from considering whether certain media mergers will substantially lessen competition or tend to create a monopoly.

Further, the bill creates a four-year safe harbor from antitrust laws for print, broadcast, or digital news companies to collectively negotiate with online content distributors (e.g., social media companies) regarding the terms on which the news companies' content may be distributed by online content distributors.</summary>
</bill>
