<bill session="116" type="s" number="2577" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:47Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require data brokers to establish procedures to ensure the accuracy of collected personal information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6675" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-13T15:18:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Data Broker Accountability and Transparency Act of 2019

This bill places requirements on an entity that collects, assembles, or maintains the personal data of an individual in order to sell or provide third-party access to the information (data brokers).

Specifically, the bill requires a data broker to ensure the accuracy of personal information it collects, and it prohibits a data broker from obtaining an individual's personal information by false pretenses. A data broker must provide an individual with access to their personal information and a means to correct inaccuracies. Additionally, a data broker shall not use an individual's personal information for unreasonable purposes, such as profiting from biometric information or processing personal information in a manner that is discriminatory.

Further, the bill requires a data broker to maintain a website with clear and conspicuous instructions for how an individual may (1) review their personal information, and (2) express a preference on the sharing of their data for marketing purposes. If an individual indicates a preference to not have their information used for marketing purposes, a data broker is required to abide by that preference.

The bill also directs a data broker to facilitate the retracing of access to an individual's personal information and implement a consumer privacy and data security program to protect against data breaches. If the personal information of an individual has been breached, the data broker must notify the individual.

The Federal Trade Commission is authorized to establish a website that lists covered data brokers and provides consumers with information about their rights.</summary>
</bill>
