<bill session="117" type="h" number="5367" updated="2022-12-31T05:45:52Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to award grants for qualifying advanced energy projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Advancing Energy Manufacturing in Coal Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advancing Energy Manufacturing in Coal Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2021-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-12T21:58:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Advancing Energy Manufacturing in Coal Communities Act

This bill requires the Department of Energy to establish a program to award grants to certain manufacturing firms for qualifying advanced energy projects. To qualify for a grant, a project must (1) re-equip, expand, or establish a manufacturing or recycling facility for the production or recycling of advanced energy property (e.g., property designed to produce renewable energy); or (2) re-equip an industrial or manufacturing facility with equipment designed to reduce the greenhouse gas emissions of that facility substantially below the greenhouse gas emissions under current best practices. Further, the project must have a reasonable expectation of commercial viability and be located near or in an area where a coal mine has closed or coal-fired plant that produced electricity has been retired.</summary>
</bill>
