<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2726</number>
    <updateDate>2025-05-27T14:16:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2025-05-27T14:16:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2023-09-05</introducedDate>
    <congress>118</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred To</name>
            <date>2023-09-05T22:58:50Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-09-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2023-09-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000575</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lankford, James [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Lankford</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
        <updateDate>2023-10-04T14:30:40Z</updateDate>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2023-09-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2024-11-14T21:27:24Z</updateDate>
        <cdata>
          <text>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Countering Adversarial and Malicious Partnerships at Universities and Schools Act of 2023 or CAMPUS Act&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This bill limits certain interactions with Chinese entities. Specifically, the bill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;requires the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to identify institutions of higher education in China providing support to the People's Liberation Army;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;prohibits the Department of Defense from providing research, development, testing, and evaluation (RDT&amp;amp;E) funds to entities that maintain contracts with such identified Chinese institutions of higher education;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;prohibits the Defense Counterintelligence and Security Agency from granting eligibility to host or store classified information to those entities with an active research partnership with such identified Chinese institutions of higher education;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;authorizes the Department of State to deny entry visas to students and employees of such identified Chinese institutions of higher education;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;prohibits the Department of Education (ED) from providing funds for K-12 education to an elementary or secondary school that maintains a contract with entities in China;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;prohibits federal&amp;nbsp;RDT&amp;amp;E funds from being provided to an entity that maintains a contract with such identified Chinese institutions of higher education or a Chinese entity on the Entity List maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security in the Department of Commerce; and&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;lowers the minimum amount of foreign gifts or contracts benefiting an institution of higher education that must be reported to ED by the institution.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The bill also authorizes ED to provide grants to K-12 schools and institutions of higher education to support Mandarin language instruction and Chinese cultural programming provided by certain Taiwanese entities.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;</text>
        </cdata>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>CAMPUS Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>45</titleTypeCode>
        <title>CAMPUS Act</title>
        <updateDate>2024-07-24T15:20:34Z</updateDate>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>CAMPUS Act</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:36:48Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>101</titleTypeCode>
        <title>Countering Adversarial and Malicious Partnerships at Universities and Schools Act of 2023</title>
        <updateDate>2024-05-24T13:36:48Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <titleTypeCode>6</titleTypeCode>
        <title>A bill to prohibit the use of funds for universities that provide support to the People's Liberation Army, and for other purposes.</title>
        <updateDate>2023-09-09T04:14:09Z</updateDate>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2023-09-05T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-118s2726is/xml/BILLS-118s2726is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2023-09-05</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
