<bill session="118" type="s" number="2589" updated="2025-11-19T03:57:02Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AG RESEARCH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AG RESEARCH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Augmenting Research and Educational Sites to Ensure Agriculture Remains Cutting-Edge and Helpful Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Research Facilities Act and the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 to address deferred maintenance at agricultural research facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-09-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4135" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-09T16:23:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Augmenting Research and Educational Sites to Ensure Agriculture Remains Cutting-Edge and Helpful Act or the AG RESEARCH Act 

This bill provides funding for maintenance at agricultural research facilities.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) must (1) revise its review process for evaluating proposals for agricultural research facilities to include consulting with representatives of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture (NIFA) peer review panels; and (2) establish a grant program within NIFA to provide agricultural research facilities with a federal share of the cost for the construction, alteration, acquisition, modernization, renovation, or remodeling of the research facilities or the equipment necessary for agricultural research.

Additionally, the bill provides funding for the grant program and for USDA to provide direct payments to research facilities of the Agricultural Research Service for addressing deferred maintenance. USDA must give priority to the most critical structures in accordance with the Agricultural Research Service Capital Investment Strategy (April 2012).</summary>
</bill>
