<bill session="117" type="h" number="6424" updated="2022-12-30T03:49:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HIGHER ED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Individuals Get a Higher Education while Reducing Education Debt Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HIGHER ED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve loans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4563" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4631" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="603" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2442" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2976" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-12T20:10:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Individuals Get a Higher Education while Reducing Education Debt Act or the HIGHER ED Act

This bill makes various changes to student loan forgiveness and loan repayment programs.

First, the bill authorizes graduate and professional students to receive subsidized Stafford Loans. These students have been ineligible to receive subsidized Stafford Loans since July 1, 2012.

Next, the bill allows student loans to be discharged in bankruptcy proceedings.

The bill also establishes refinancing programs for student loans. It allows certain borrowers to refinance their federal student loans down to lower interest rates, and it creates the Federal Direct Refinanced Private Loan to allow certain borrowers to refinance their private student loans.

Additionally, the bill revises the Public Service Loan Forgiveness (PSLF) program, such as by (1) allowing certain part-time faculty to participate in the PSLF program, (2) directing the Department of Education (ED) to annually cancel 10% of the amount a borrower owes after satisfying 12 qualifying monthly payments, (3) revising the process for certification of employment, and (4) requiring ED to establish a dispute resolution process.

Further, the bill revises federal student loan repayment programs, including by (1) replacing existing student loan repayment plans with one income-based repayment plan and one standard 10-year repayment plan, and (2) allowing existing borrowers to lower their payments by switching to these new plans. It also establishes a process for ED to enroll a delinquent borrower in a new repayment plan.

The bill also requires ED to provide certain notifications to borrowers.</summary>
</bill>
