<bill session="118" type="s" number="2756" updated="2025-11-19T02:58:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Streamlining Organic Research Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Streamlining Organic Research Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 and the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to direct the Agricultural Research Service to expand organic research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2720" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2317" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-31T18:13:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Streamlining Organic Research Act of 2023

This bill expands Department of Agriculture (USDA) support for organic agricultural&#160;research.

USDA must establish the Coordinating and Expanding Organic Research Initiative for USDA resources dedicated to organic agricultural research. Every five years, the initiative must survey USDA's organic agricultural research and produce a report, including findings and recommendations on expanding research and increasing coordination. USDA must take the findings and recommendations into consideration when preparing USDA's annual budget recommendations.

The bill also reauthorizes&#160;the&#160;National Institute of Food and Agriculture&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s&#160;Organic Agriculture Research and Extension Initiative through FY2028. Further, eligible grant projects are expanded to include (1) facilitating the identification and adoption of traditional ecological knowledge; (2) developing cultural practices and other allowable alternatives to substances recommended for removal from the National List of approved and prohibited substances for organic production; and&#160;(3) identifying how organic agriculture can reduce greenhouse gas emissions, build landscape resiliency, and facilitate other related ecosystem services.

The bill also reauthorizes, and extends funding for, organic production and market data initiatives of the Economic Research Service (ERS) through FY2028. ERS must conduct an economic impact analysis of organic agricultural management conducted in accordance with the National Organic Program and submit a report to Congress.

USDA may make competitive grants to support research, education, and extension activities relating to the transition from nonorganic into organic agricultural production systems.&#160;

Further, the Agricultural Research Service must submit a report to Congress on the resources needed to increase the research conducted on certified organic agricultural land.</summary>
</bill>
