<bill session="117" type="h" number="7974" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Endometriosis CARE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Endometriosis CARE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Endometriosis Coverage, Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To advance research, promote awareness, and provide patient support with respect to endometriosis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2022-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2022-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-14T15:59:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Endometriosis Coverage, Awareness, Research, and Education Act of 2022 or the Endometriosis CARE Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to address endometriosis through increasing awareness, research, and other means. Endometriosis is a condition in which tissue similar to the inner lining of the uterus grows outside of the uterus, which may result in pain, infertility, and other symptoms.

Specifically, HHS must

 report on barriers (e.g., issues related to health insurance coverage and costs) to accessing endometriosis care and treatments; disseminate information about endometriosis, such as its symptoms and treatments, to both the public and health care providers; and seek to contract with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to study racial, ethnic, and other disparities in endometriosis prevalence, diagnosis, treatment, and outcomes. The National Institutes of Health must also conduct or support data collection, surveillance, and research related to endometriosis.</summary>
</bill>
