<bill session="116" type="s" number="4206" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 to authorize the interest rate to be used on a secured loan to be the interest rate for United States Treasury securities of a similar maturity on the date of first disbursement of the loan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 to authorize the interest rate to be used on a secured loan to be the interest rate for United States Treasury securities of a similar maturity on the date of first disbursement of the loan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-05T23:20:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill modifies statutory requirements related to the minimum interest rate for a secured loan provided under a federal program to help finance water infrastructure projects (i.e., the program established under the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014).

Specifically, the interest rate for such a loan shall not be less than the yield of U.S. Treasury securities of similar maturity to the loan, either on the date the loan agreement was executed or the date of the loan's first disbursement, whichever is lower. Currently, the statute only takes into consideration the yield of comparable U.S. Treasury securities on the execution date of the loan agreement.</summary>
</bill>
