<bill session="108" type="h" number="2115" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:35Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Vision 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to reauthorize programs for the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Flight 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flight 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Vision 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Aviation Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Aviation Investment and Revitalization Vision Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Arming Cargo Pilots Against Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Flight 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="popular">Aviation Administration FY2004-2006 Authorization bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000006" joined="2003-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Aviation Consideration and Markup Held Prior to Introduction and Referral (May 14, 2003).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Mr. Mica asked unanimous consent that the Committee on Transportation have until midnight on June 6 to file a report on H.R. 2115. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation. H. Rept. 108-143.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-06" calendar="Union" number="72">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 72.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10T20:12:41-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 265 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2115 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against the bill are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, as modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:12:23-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 265 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:37:43-04:00">
      <text>ORDER OF PROCEDURE - Mr. Mica asked unanimous consent that during consideration of H.R. 2115 in the Committee of the Whole pursuant to H. Res. 265, the amendment numbered 5 printed in House Report 108-146 be considered first and out of order. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:38:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 265.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5201-5239" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:38:17-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2115 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. All points of order against the bill are waived. It shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure now printed in the bill, as modified by the amendment printed in part A of the report of the Committee on Rules accompanying this resolution. Measure will be considered read. Specified amendments are in order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:38:35-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 265 and Rule XXIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:38:36-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Charles F. Bass to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T13:38:42-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T14:55:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 265, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Manzullo amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T14:59:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Manzullo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the yeas had prevailed. Mr. Manzullo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T15:02:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 265, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Mica amedment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T15:15:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 265, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T15:28:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 265, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peterson (PA) amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T15:40:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to H. Res. 265, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pitts amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T15:51:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED VOTE - At the conclusion of debate on the Pitts amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the yeas had prevailed. Mr. Mica demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T16:20:24-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="264" datetime="2003-06-11T16:37:54-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 418 - 8 (Roll no. 264).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T16:37:55-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-11T16:37:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="134">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 134.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7820" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.824 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="225" datetime="2003-06-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 94 - 0. Record Vote Number: 225.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 6/13/2003 S7884-7902" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendment, asks for a conference, appoints conferees McCain; Stevens; Burns; Lott; Hutchison; Hollings; Inouye; Rockefeller; Breaux.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>See also S.824.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:34:29-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica asked unanimous consent that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:35:04-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendment, and agree to a conference Agreed to without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6825-6826" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:35:27-04:00">
      <text>Mr. DeFazio moved that the House instruct conferees.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:35:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the DeFazio motion to instruct conferees. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the managers on the part of the House to insist upon a total level of funding of not less than $59 billion for fiscal years 2004 through 2007 for programs authorized pursuant to secs. 101 through 103 of the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:19-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:23-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House instruct conferees Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:24-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:47-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure for consideration of the House bill and the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Young (AK), Mica, Ehlers, Hayes, Rehberg, Isakson, Oberstar, DeFazio, Boswell, and Holden.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:48-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Energy and Commerce for consideration of sec. 521 of the House bill and sec. 508 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Tauzin, Barton (TX), and Dingell.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:49-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Government Reform for consideration of secs. 404 and 438 of the House bill and sec. 108 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Davis, Tom, Shays, and Waxman.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:50-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on the Judiciary for consideration of secs. 106, 301, 405, 505 and 507 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Sensenbrenner, Coble, and Conyers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:51-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Resources for consideration of secs. 204 and 409 of the House bill and sec. 201 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Pombo, Gibbons, and Rahall.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:52-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees Provided that Mr. Renzi is appointed in lieu of Mr. Pombo for consideration of sec. 409 of the House bill, and modifications committed to conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:53-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Science for consideration of sec. 102 of the House bill and secs. 102, 104, 621, 622, 641, 642, 661, 662, 663, 667, and 669 of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Boehlert, Rohrabacher, and Costello.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-15T18:41:54-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees - from the Committee on Ways and Means for consideration of title VI of the House bill and title VII of the Senate amendment, and modifications committed to conference: Thomas, Camp, and Rangel.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24T19:28:13-04:00">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T11:41:50-04:00">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T19:30:43-04:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-240 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7718-7764" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-28">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-24T18:40:25-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 377 Reported to House. Upon the adoption of this resolution, the conference report to accompany H.R. 2115 is hereby recommitted to the committee of conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T19:25:09-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 377 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-28T19:26:00-05:00">
      <text>House recommitted conference report pursuant to H. Res. 377.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T13:24:29-05:00">
      <text>Conference report H. Rept. 108-334 filed.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10008-10054" label="text of conference report"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and manager's statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29T18:37:39-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 422 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of the conference report to H.R. 2115. All points of order against the conference report and against its consideration are waived. The conference report shall be considered as read when called up for consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T15:59:05-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 422 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T16:15:40-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Mica brought up conference report H. Rept. 108-334 for consideration under the provisions of H. Res. 422.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10163-10170, CR 10/31/2003 H10176-10189" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T16:16:00-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T17:17:07-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House continued with debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T17:47:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed debate on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T18:22:58-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T18:23:24-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Oberstar moved to recommit with instructions to the conference committee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/31/2003 H10187-10188" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 10/31/2003 H10187-10188" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T18:24:41-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T18:46:25-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions to conference committee Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 219 (Roll no. 591).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="592" datetime="2003-10-30T18:56:31-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:HOUSE">
      <text>On agreeing to the conference report Agreed to by recorded vote: 211 - 207 (Roll no. 592).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30T18:56:31-05:00">
      <text>Motions to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Conference papers: and message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-14">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14858" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-14">
      <text>Cloture motion on the conference report to accompany H.R. 2115 presented in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14940-14952" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Cloture not invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 43. Record Vote Number: 453.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Motion by Senator Frist to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the conference report was not invoked (Roll Call Vote No. 453) was entered in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15385-15390" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Motion by Senator Frist to reconsider the vote by which cloture on the conference report was not invoked (Roll Call Vote No. 453) was withdrawn in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="conference" datetime="2003-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-12-02">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-12-12" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-176" type="public" datetime="2003-12-12">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-176.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest, Legislative Interest, Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="824" relation="related document"/>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1618" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="265" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="377" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="422" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2734" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Air cargo"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aircraft construction"/>
    <term name="Aircraft engines"/>
    <term name="Aircraft industry"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Aviation insurance"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer discounts"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Decision making"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dismissal of employees"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Flight crews"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="Gulf of Mexico"/>
    <term name="Helicopters"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Military aircraft"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Natural gas vehicles"/>
    <term name="Navigation (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Navigational aids (Aeronautics)"/>
    <term name="Newspapers"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential commissions"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Product counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Reinsurance"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="September 11, 2001"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Subcontractors"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Taxicabs"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation rates"/>
    <term name="Transportation workers"/>
    <term name="Travel agents"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Victims"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h165"/>
    <amendment number="h164"/>
    <amendment number="h163"/>
    <amendment number="h162"/>
    <amendment number="h161"/>
    <amendment number="h160"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Flight 100--Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act - Amends Federal transportation law to authorize appropriations for FY 2004 through 2007 for the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), including: (1) air navigation facilities and equipment; and (2) airport and noise compatibility planning and development. Extends the current authority of the Secretary of Transportation to provide air carrier insurance and reinsurance through calendar 2007, after which limits are imposed.Airport Streamlining Approval Process Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary to develop and implement a coordinated review process for airport capacity enhancement projects at congested airports.Directs the FAA Administrator to convert the Air Traffic Services Subcommittee of the Federal Aviation Management Advisory Council into an independent Air Traffic Services Board.Establishes in the FAA a Small Business Ombudsman.Revises requirements with respect to airline service improvements, involving among other things: (1) data on incidents and complaints involving passenger and baggage security screening; (2) conversion of ground support equipment or airport-owned vehicles to low-emission technology; (3) the passenger facility fee program; (4) overflights of national parks; (5) a collaborative decision-making pilot program; (6) availability of aircraft accident site information; (7) slot exemptions at Ronald Reagan Washington National Airport; (8) small community air service and the essential air service program, including a community and regional choice alternate essential air service pilot program; (9) action for de novo review in U.S. district court of a discrimination complaint by an employee providing air safety information; (10) agreements to permit use of type certificates by other persons; (11) design organization certificates; (12) runway safety standards; (13) availability of maintenance information; (14) flight attendant certification; (15) a civil penalty for closure of an airport without providing sufficient notice; (16) improvement of curriculum standards for aviation maintenance technicians; (17) a task force on future of air transportation system; (18) air quality in aircraft cabins; (19) a task force on enhanced transfer of applications of technology for military aircraft to civilian aircraft; (20) reimbursement for losses incurred by general aviation entities; (21) impasse procedures for national association of air traffic specialists; (22) FAA inspector training; (23) a prohibition on air traffic control privatization; and (24) reduced airfares for members of the Armed Forces on commercial U.S. flights.Revises requirements relating to airport development and involving among other things: (1) security costs at small airports; (2) runway safety areas; (3) proceeds from disposition of land acquired for noise compatibility purposes; (4) hangar construction grant assurances; (5) costs of construction or modification of public parking facilities for security purposes; (6) formulae for apportionments to primary airports and cargo airports; (7) considerations in making discretionary grants; (8) flexible funding for nonprimary airport apportionments; (9) use of apportioned amounts for noise mitigation projects; (10) increased funding for the military airport program and air traffic control contract towers; (11) 100 percent Federal share of the cost of airport safety data collection by a private contractor; (12) the use of revenues in the airport privatization pilot program; (13) further limitations on innovative financing techniques for airport development projects; (14) emission credits for air quality projects and an airport ground support equipment emissions retrofit pilot program; (15) compatible land use planning and projects by State and local governments; and (16) funding for Midway Island Airport.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-143</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-240</report>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-334</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
