<bill session="117" type="h" number="9516" updated="2023-08-15T17:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AACCENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AACCENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Augmentative and Alternative Communication Centers to Establish National Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support national training, technical assistance, and resource centers, to ensure that all individuals with significant expressive communication disabilities have access to the augmentative and alternative communication the individuals need to interact with others, in order to learn, work, socialize, and take advantage of all aspects of life in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001202"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-15T16:59:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Augmentative and Alternative Communication Centers to Establish National Training Act or the AACCENT Act

This bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to award three grants in geographically diverse regions to establish a network of resource centers to improve access to tools, technologies, strategies, training, and other methods used to supplement or replace speech (i.e., augmentative and alternative communication) for individuals with significant expressive communication disabilities. These are communication disabilities (other than communication disabilities that are primarily visual or auditory in nature) that prevent or significantly limit an individual from understanding or being understood using spoken words, resulting in the need for or benefit from augmentative and alternative communication.</summary>
</bill>
