<bill session="117" type="s" number="4366" updated="2022-12-29T17:33:53Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEFEND Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEFEND Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deterring Enemy Forces and Enabling National Defenses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to seek to cooperate with allies and partners in the Middle East to identify an architecture and develop an acquisition approach for  certain countries in the Middle East to implement an integrated air and missile defense capability to protect the people, infrastructure, and territory of such countries from cruise and ballistic missiles, manned and unmanned aerial system, and rocket attacks from Iran, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2022-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2022-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2022-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2022-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7987" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4543" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-06T15:59:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deterring Enemy Forces and Enabling National Defenses Act of 2022 or the DEFEND Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Defense to seek to cooperate with Middle East allies and partners (i.e., countries of the Gulf Cooperation Council, Iraq, Israel, Jordan, Egypt, and other countries in the region as appropriate) to identify and develop an approach for such allies and partners to implement an integrated air and missile defense capability to protect against attacks from Iran and groups linked to Iran.</summary>
</bill>
