<bill session="116" type="h" number="1054" updated="2022-11-01T15:47:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HBCU PARTNERS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the capacity and competitiveness of historically Black colleges and universities through robust public-sector, private-sector, and community partnerships and engagement, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HBCU PARTNERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HBCU Propelling Agency Relationships Towards a New Era of Results for Students Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2019-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001304" joined="2019-08-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2019-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2019-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2019-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2020-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2019-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000819" joined="2019-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="461" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-20T14:36:33Z" status="Introduced in House">HBCU Propelling Agency Relationships Towards a New Era of Results for Students Act or the HBCU PARTNERS Act

This bill addresses the capacity of historically Black colleges and universities (HBCUs) to participate in federal programs.

Specifically, the bill requires agencies that regularly interact with HBCUs to submit annual plans for strengthening the capacity of HBCUs to participate in federal programs. Among other things, the plans must establish how the agencies intend to increase the capacity of HBCUs to compete effectively for grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements.

Agencies that do not work regularly with HBCUs must submit annual plans to identify specific HBCU initiatives and resources that could benefit the HBCU community.

The agencies may provide technical assistance and information to the initiative to enhance communication with HBCUs concerning their program activities and applications for grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements.

In addition, the bill provides statutory authority for the President's Board of Advisors on HBCUs.</summary>
</bill>
