<bill session="109" type="hr" number="895" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:44Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-29T19:27:44-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-29T19:27:44-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting intelligence and law enforcement programs to track terrorists and terrorist finances conducted consistent with Federal law and with appropriate Congressional consultation and specifically condemning the disclosure and publication of classified information that impairs the international fight against terrorism and needlessly exposes Americans to the threat of further terror attacks by revealing a crucial method by which terrorists are traced through their finances.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting intelligence and law enforcement programs to track terrorists and terrorist finances conducted consistent with Federal law and with appropriate Congressional consultation and specifically condemning the disclosure and publication of classified information that impairs the international fight against terrorism and needlessly exposes Americans to the threat of further terror attacks by revealing a crucial method by which terrorists are traced through their finances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000163"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T00:26:01-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 896 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 895 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T14:38:40-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 896 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T17:14:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 896.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4875-4890" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T17:14:30-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 895 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T17:15:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 895.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T18:32:56-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T18:34:10-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the resolution the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Oxley demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the resolution until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T19:21:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4892-4893" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="357" datetime="2006-06-29T19:27:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 227 - 183 (Roll no. 357).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4875-4876" label="text as passed House"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-06-29T19:27:45-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="sr" number="524" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="896" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Journalistic ethics"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-25T17:13:11Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses support for efforts to identify, track, and pursue suspected foreign terrorists and their financial supporters by tracking terrorist money flows and uncovering terrorist networks, including through the Terrorist Finance Tracking Program.

Condemns the unauthorized disclosure of classified information and expresses concern that such disclosure may endanger the lives of Americans as well as individuals and organizations that support U.S. efforts.

Declares that the House of Representatives: (1) finds that the Program has been conducted in accordance with all applicable laws, that appropriate safeguards and reviews have been instituted to protect civil liberties, and that Congress has been appropriately informed and consulted and will continue Program oversight; and (2) expects the cooperation of all news media organizations in protecting American lives and the government's capability to identify, disrupt, and capture terrorists by not disclosing classified intelligence programs, such as the Program.</summary>
</bill>
