<bill session="116" type="h" number="1125" updated="2022-11-01T16:03:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Accountability for Quality VA Healthcare Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on physical security at Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities, to direct the Secretary to make certain improvements relating to inspections of Department of Veterans Affairs medical facilities and improving care for women, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accountability for Quality VA Healthcare Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001284" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2019-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001202" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2019-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000608" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2019-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2019-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-07T15:56:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Accountability for Quality VA Healthcare Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to address functionality and accountability in regard to its facilities and provision of care.

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to carry out a two-year pilot program to enhance the physical security of five selected VA medical facilities.

The VA must submit a report that includes its plan and time frame to address specified findings and recommendations of the Government Accountability Office report titled VA Real Property: VA Should Improve Its Efforts to Align Facilities with Veterans' Needs.

The bill requires the VA to update its Planning and Activating Community Based Outpatient Clinics handbook at least once every five years to reflect current policies and clarify the responsibilities of VA leasing project personnel.

The VA must strengthen its medical facility inspection process and monitor women veterans' access to gender-specific care services under community care contracts, including appointment scheduling and completion times.

Finally, the bill requires the VA to (1) clarify measures for medical appointment wait times in a manner that reduces the likelihood of misinterpretation, (2) ensure that patient indicated date (the earliest date the patient needs to be seen) is clearly defined for purposes of Veterans Health Administration scheduling and related training documents, (3) improve recruitment and retention of scheduling staff and require facilities to routinely assess scheduling and resource needs, and (4) improve telephone access at its medical facilities.</summary>
</bill>
