<bill session="109" type="h" number="6198" updated="2023-01-31T21:41:36Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-30">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Iran Freedom Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To hold the current regime in Iran accountable for its threatening behavior and to support a transition to democracy in Iran.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Iran Freedom Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Iran Freedom Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Iran Freedom Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Iran Freedom Support Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000022" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001022" joined="2006-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2006-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28T13:02:33-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Ros-Lehtinen moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28T13:03:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7695-7706" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28T13:03:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6198.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-09-28T13:51:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7695-7697" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28T13:51:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2006-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 9/29/2006 S10769-10770" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-09-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-09-30" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="109-293" type="public" datetime="2006-09-30">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-293.</text>
    </enacted>
    <action datetime="2006-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and Central Asia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Middle East, North Africa, and Central Asia" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="3971" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="282" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Equality before the law"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Middle East and North Africa"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Reactor fuel reprocessing"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-09T13:44:26Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 28, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Iran Freedom Support Act - Title I: Codification of Sanctions Against Iran - (Sec. 101) States that U.S. sanctions with respect to Iran imposed pursuant to sections 1 and 3 of Executive Order 12957, sections 1(e), 1(g), and 3 of Executive Order 12959, and sections 2, 3, and 5 of Executive Order 13059 (relating to exports and certain other transactions with Iran), as in effect on January 1, 2006, shall remain in effect. Authorizes the President to terminate such sanctions in whole or in part: (1) upon congressional notification; and (2) without prior notification under exigent circumstances (but within three days of such action).

Prohibits anything in this Act from affecting sanctions, controls, or regulations relating to Iranian support of international terrorism.

Title II: Amendments to the Iran and Libya Sanctions Act of 1996 and Other Provisions Related to Investment in Iran - (Sec. 201) Amends the Iran and Libya Sanctions Act of 1996 to authorize case-by-case waiver of sanctions (up to six months with renewable six-month periods) against nationals of a country if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the waiver is vital to U.S. security interests.

States that the President should initiate an investigation leading to the possible imposition of sanctions against a person upon receipt of credible information that such person is engaged in prohibited petroleum investment activity in Iran.

(Sec. 202) Imposes (two or more) mandatory sanctions on a person or entity that knowingly helps Iran acquire or develop chemical, nuclear, or biological weapons of mass destruction or destabilizing types and numbers of conventional weapons. Makes such provision effective with respect to actions taken on or after June 6, 2006.

(Sec. 203) Adds a requirement that Iran be determined to pose no significant threat to U.S. national security, interests, or allies in order to lift sanctions against entities investing in Iran's petroleum industry.

(Sec. 204) Extends such Act's sunset provision to December 31, 2011.

(Sec. 205) Renames the the Iran and Libya Sanctions Act of 1996 as the Iran Sanctions Act of 1996.

Title III: Promotion of Democracy for Iran - (Sec. 301) Declares that it should be U.S. policy to support: (1) efforts by the Iranian people to exercise self-determination over their country's form of government; and (2) independent human rights and peaceful pro-democracy forces in Iran.

States that nothing in this Act shall be construed as authorizing the use of force against Iran.

(Sec. 302) Authorizes the President to provide financial and political assistance to eligible foreign and domestic individuals and groups that support democracy in Iran, including assistance for radio and television broadcasting into Iran. Prohibits assistance from being used to support the use of force against Iran.

States that assistance may be provided only to an individual, organization, or entity that: (1) officially opposes the use of violence and terrorism and has not been designated as a foreign terrorist organization during the preceding four years; (2) advocates Iran's adherence to nonproliferation regimes for nuclear, chemical, and biological weapons and materiel; (3) supports adoption of a democratic government in Iran; (4) is dedicated to respect for human rights, including equality of women; (5) works to establish equality of opportunity for people; and (6) supports freedoms of press, speech, association, and religion.

Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) support for a transition to democracy in Iran should be expressed by U.S. representatives and officials in all appropriate international fora; and (2) U.S. officials and representatives should support indigenous efforts in Iran calling for democratic elections and draw international attention to Iran's violations of human rights, freedom of religion, freedom of assembly, and freedom of the press.

Authorizes appropriations.

Terminates authority to provide assistance under this section on December 31, 2011.

Title IV: Policy of the United States to Facilitate the Nuclear Nonproliferation of Iran - (Sec. 401) Expresses the sense of Congress that it should be U.S. policy to not bring into force an agreement for cooperation with the government of any country that is assisting Iran's nuclear program or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to Iran unless the President has determined that: (1) Iran has suspended and will end all enrichment-related and reprocessing-related activity (except uranium conversion exclusively for export to foreign nuclear fuel production facilities pursuant to internationally agreed arrangements); or (2) such other country has suspended all nuclear assistance to Iran and all transfers of advanced conventional weapons and missiles to Iran, and is committed to maintaining that suspension until Iran has implemented measures that would permit such presidential determination.

Title V: Prevention of Money Laundering for Weapons of Mass Destruction - (Sec. 501) Includes money laundering activities involved in the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or missiles in the federal provisions regulating certain monetary transactions.</summary>
</bill>
