<bill session="117" type="h" number="6417" updated="2023-08-07T14:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Free Peng Shuai Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Free Peng Shuai Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the imposition of sanctions pursuant to the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act to combat the perpetuation of human rights violations in the People's Republic of China by certain members of the International Olympic Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-07T14:23:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Free Peng Shuai Act

This bill directs the President to impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on any foreign individual associated with the International Olympic Committee (IOC) who has materially assisted China's government in the disappearance of Peng Shuai, including the president of the IOC. (Peng is a Chinese tennis star who raised allegations of sexual coercion against a retired senior Chinese leader.)

The sanctions shall not apply to acts related to U.S. intelligence activities. The President may waive application of the sanctions if (1) doing so would be in U.S. national security interests, or (2) Peng has been released and may travel freely and her well-being has been independently confirmed by the U.S. government.</summary>
</bill>
