<bill session="115" type="h" number="6365" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:04Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo Land Claims Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo Land Grant-Merced Claims Commission and other Federal policies for the restoration of land for hardships resulting from the incomplete and inequitable implementation of the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, to affirm Land Grant-Merced property rights protected by the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo Land Claims Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo Land Claims Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water, Power and Oceans Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 19 - 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-27">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 115-1052.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-11-27" calendar="Union" number="819">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 819.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-06T17:43:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Treaty of Guadalupe-Hidalgo Land Claims Act of 2018

This bill establishes the Treaty of Guadalupe Hidalgo Land Grant-Merced Claims Commission to conduct a hearing on each qualifying petition that shows the claimed boundaries of a land grant-merced.

A "land grant-merced" is a specified community land grant, or a community, village, town, or settlement, the land of which was granted by Spain or Mexico between 1689 and 1854 within the Territory of New Mexico, which now includes New Mexico, Colorado, and Arizona, to the community, village, town, or pueblo, or to a person to found or establish a community, village, town, or settlement.

After a hearing, the Commission may recommend as restitution any one of the following possible restitutions:

 convey federal land; grant stewardship rights to all or part of federal land; grant priority access and use rights to such lands for the harvesting of natural resources, such as timber and minerals, grazing and watering of livestock, or hunting and fishing; grant priority rights to leases, special use permits, and easements on federal land, to acquire federal lands that may become available for disposal, or to obtain new, unused, or unrenewed grazing allotments on federal lands. The bill prohibits the impairment of the rights of any acequia located on federal land as the result of enactment of this bill, including the right to the use of water by valid water right owners and access to the acequia for maintenance and improvements to its easement and infrastructure.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-1052</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
