<bill session="118" type="h" number="1400" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Territories Statistics Collection Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Territories Statistics Collection Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy to develop a plan to collect and publish statistics regarding the Territories of the United States in the same manner as statistics are collected and reported by Federal agencies for the several States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2023-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2023-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2023-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2023-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2023-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Indian and Insular Affairs .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-27T19:58:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Territories Statistics Collection Equity Act

This bill requires implementation of a plan for federal agencies to collect and publish statistics regarding the U.S. territories in the same manner as statistics are collected and reported for the states.

Specifically, the bill directs the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy to publish a list and assessment of existing federal statistical programs that collect and publish data for the U.S. territories comparable to the states.

The council must submit to Congress a plan to collect and publish statistics regarding the territories in the same manner as statistics are collected and reported by federal agencies for the states.

The council, in coordination with agencies, must implement the plan no later than four years after enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
