<bill session="110" type="h" number="7307" updated="2021-06-07T20:07:24Z">
  <state datetime="2008-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowner Assistance and Taxpayer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Homeowner Assistance and Taxpayer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To help struggling families stay in their homes and to ensure that taxpayers are protected when the Secretary of the Treasury purchases equity shares in financial institutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001043"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001037" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2008-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2008-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2008-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3690" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Bank employees"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Dividends"/>
    <term name="Estates (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-12-19T21:14:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Homeowner Assistance and Taxpayer Protection Act - Amends the Emergency Economic Stabilization Act of 2008 (EESA), with respect to mortgages acquired by the Secretary of the Treasury, to direct the Secretary to use authority to require (currently, encourage) the servicers of the underlying mortgages to take advantage of the HOPE for Homeowners Program under the National Housing Act or other available programs to minimize foreclosures. Requires federal property managers holding, owning, or controlling mortgages, mortgage backed securities, and other assets secured by residential real estate to do likewise.

Directs a federal property manager to require (currently, encourage) loan servicers to implement specified loan modifications in any case in which the property manager does not own a residential mortgage loan, but holds an interest in obligations or pools of obligations secured by residential mortgage loans.

Requires lenders to participate in HOPE for Homeowners Program when homeowners elect to participate.

Amends Chapter 13 (Adjustment of Debts of an Individual with Regular Income) of the federal bankruptcy code to allow a debtor's plan to modify an allowed secured claim secured by the debtor's principal residence (mortgage), if, after deduction of permitted expenses, the debtor has insufficient remaining current monthly income to retain possession of the residence by curing a default and maintaining payments while the case is pending.

Waives the credit counseling requirement for a debtor whose home is in foreclosure.

Waives the liaibility of the debtor and the debtor's estate for certain fees arising in connection with a claim secured by the debtor's principal residence.

Amends EESA to prohibit financial institutions from which troubled assets are purchased by the Secretary from paying increased dividends until such time as the troubled assets are no longer owned by the Secretary.

Requires that dividends be reduced to pay for excessive executive compensation in the case of any such financial institution.</summary>
</bill>
