<bill session="108" type="hc" number="382" updated="2023-01-15T10:18:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affirming that the intent of Congress in passing the National Wildlife Refuge System Improvement Act of 1997 was to allow hunting and fishing on public lands within the National Wildlife Refuge System and declaring that the purpose of reserving certain lands as public lands is to make them available to the public for reasonable uses.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Affirming that the intent of Congress in passing the National Wildlife Refuge System Improvement Act of 1997 was to allow hunting and fishing on public lands within the National Wildlife Refuge System and declaring that the purpose of reserving certain lands as public lands is to make them available to the public for reasonable uses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-27T20:22:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses that: (1) in passing the National Wildlife Refuge System Improvement Act of 1997, Congress demonstrated its clear intent to allow hunting and fishing on public lands within the National Wildlife Refuge System (the System); (2) the intent of Congress has not changed in any way since such Act was enacted, and any assumptions to the contrary are misguided and misinterpret the clear intent of Congress; and (3) the general purpose of reserving certain lands as public lands, including lands within the System, is to make them available to the public for reasonable uses, which include hunting, fishing, other wildlife-dependent sports, and other outdoor purposes.</summary>
</bill>
