<bill session="109" type="h" number="679" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:37Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey a parcel of real property to Beaver County, Utah.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey a parcel of real property to Beaver County, Utah.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000116"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-285.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-11-10" calendar="Union" number="155">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 155.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="52" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-06T19:18:51Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to convey to Beaver County, Utah, for public recreational use all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the approximately 200 acres identified as "Minersville State Park."

Permits the County to sell, for not less than fair market value, a part of the property conveyed to the County under this Act, if the proceeds of such sale are used by the County solely for maintenance of public recreation facilities located on the remainder of the conveyed property. Provides that, if the County does not comply with such requirements in the conveyance of such property: (1) the County shall pay to the United States the proceeds of the conveyance; and (2) the Secretary may require the reversion of all the property conveyed under this Act (other than property sold by the County under this Act).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-285</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
