<bill session="109" type="h" number="435" updated="2022-02-03T05:28:49Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Access to Justice Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Equal Access to Justice Reform Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the provisions of titles 5 and 28, United States Code, relating to equal access to justice, award of reasonable costs and fees, and administrative settlement offers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001138"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2017" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-22T21:27:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Equal Access to Justice Reform Act of 2005 - Includes within the functions and duties of the Small Business Administration's (SBA's) Office of Advocacy ensuring that the justice system remains accessible to small businesses for the resolution of disputes with the Federal Government.

Directs the Office to advise, cooperate with, and consult with the President and Attorney General regarding provisions concerning the awarding of Federal contracts to small businesses and minority-, female-, and veteran-owned businesses.

Requires the Attorney General to report to specified congressional committees on: (1) the effectiveness of the Equal Access to Justice Act (EAJA) in achieving its purpose of easing the burden upon small businesses of engaging in dispute resolution with the Federal Government; (2) variations in the frequency and amounts of fee awards paid by specified Federal entities; and (3) recommendations for congressional oversight or legislative changes.

Eliminates the EAJA's: (1) substantial justification standard whereby the Government can deny attorney's fees to prevailing parties if the agency's position was substantially justified; and (2) rate cap on expert witness and attorney's fees.

Sets forth provisions regarding settlement offers, declarations of intent to seek a fee award, payments from agency appropriations, and taxpayer eligibility for fee awards.

Defines "prevailing party" in EAJA cases to include a party whose pursuit of a non-frivolous claim or defense was a catalyst for a voluntary or unilateral change in position by the opposing party that provides any significant part of the relief sought.</summary>
</bill>
