<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1449</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T06:17:49Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T06:17:49Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-07-23</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
        <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-07-23T23:16:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003</title>
        <congress>108</congress>
        <number>1904</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2003-12-03</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 108-148.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssaf00</systemCode>
            <name>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-23</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S9799-9801)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-07-23</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000880</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Crapo, Mike [R-ID]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Crapo</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ID</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Lincoln, Blanche L. [D-AR]</fullName>
        <firstName>BLANCHE</firstName>
        <lastName>LINCOLN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>AR</state>
        <middleName>LAMBERT</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2003-07-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see H.R. 1904, which became Public Law 108-148 on 12/3/2003.]]></text>
        <links>
          <link>
            <name>H.R. 1904</name>
            <url>https://www.congress.gov/bill/108th-congress/house-bill/1904</url>
          </link>
        </links>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative procedure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Biomass energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Citizen participation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Ecosystem management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electronic government information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency Management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental monitoring</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to water resources development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forest conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forest fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forest health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Local laws</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maps</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National forests</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Newspapers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Non-native species</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Old growth forests</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Planning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Potable water</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public meetings</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Reforestation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research centers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of petition</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology transfer</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Timber sales</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water supply</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Watersheds</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-07-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2003-10-17T18:52:19Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>America's Healthy Forests Restoration and Research Act of 2003 - Permits the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System lands, and the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands administered by the Bureau of Land Management, to plan and conduct hazardous fuels reduction projects (fuels projects) on specified types of Federal lands.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary concerned to give priority to fuels projects that provide for the protection of communities and watersheds.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary concerned to plan and conduct fuels projects in accordance with the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and other applicable laws, with an exemption from specified provisions of such Act pertaining to analysis of alternative options to proposed agency actions. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary concerned to provide for collaboration among governments, Indian tribes, and interested persons during the formulation of each fuels project. </p> <p>Sets forth special requirements regarding judicial review of fuels projects. Provides injunctive relief for agency actions on Federal lands, including fuels projects, to restore fire-adapted forests or rangeland systems.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary concerned to make grants to: (1) improve the commercial value of forest biomass to produce electric energy, sensible heat, transportation fuels, substitutes for petroleum-based products, wood-based products, pulp, or other commercial products; and (2) offset the cost of projects to add value to biomass. </p> <p>Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to permit the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Forest Service, to provide assistance to State foresters and officials for the purpose of expanding State forest capacities and activities to address watershed issues on non-Federal forested lands and potentially forested lands. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop a technical assistance program to protect water quality; and (2) establish a watershed forestry cost-share program. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary concerned to establish an accelerated program to conduct, and promote comprehensive information gathering on the effects to forests of insect and disease infestation and severe weather. Allows the Secretary concerned to conduct applied silvicultural assessments on threatened Federal lands. </p> <p>Directs the Secretary concerned to: (1) inventory and monitor Federal and private (with consent) forest stands to identify environmental threats; and (2) develop a comprehensive early warning system for potential catastrophic forest threats. </p> <p>Amends the Biomass Research and Development Act of 2000 to increase Biomass Research and Development Initiative grant uses.</p> <p>Amends the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out biomass and small-diameter-based rural revitalization programs.</p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an Upland Hardwood Research Center which shall, in conjunction with the Southern Forest Research Station of the Department of Agriculture, provide a broad research and development program for the upland hardwood resources of the Ozark Mountains and the South.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish the healthy forests reserve program for the purpose of restoring and enhancing private forest ecosystems to promote the recovery of threatened and endangered species as well as improve biodiversity and enhance carbon sequestration. </p> <p> Directs the Secretaries to jointly establish a program for the emergency treatment and reduction of nonnative invasive plants.</p> <p> Expresses congressional reaffirmation of the enhanced community fire protection program. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>America's Healthy Forest Restoration and Research Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>America's Healthy Forest Restoration and Research Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to improve the capacity of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to prepare and conduct hazardous fuels reduction projects on National Forest System land and Bureau of Land Management land that are aimed at protecting communities, watersheds, and certain other at-risk land from catastrophic wildfire, to enhance efforts to protect watersheds and address threats to forest and rangeland health on public and private land, including catastrophic wildfire, to increase research on forest health and forest-damaging agents, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>America's Healthy Forest Restoration and Research Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-07-23T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-07-23</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
