<bill session="117" type="h" number="4729" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 to allow the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of the Department of the Interior and other agencies to provide grants, assistance, studies, Federal coordination, and essential restoration and protection of the Mississippi River Corridor for the purpose of sustaining critical environmental services and the major U.S. economies that depend on them and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Andy&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andrew J. Young Safeguarding the Mississippi River Together Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andrew J. Young SMRT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andy&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Bill</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Andy&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Mississippi River Bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2022-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-20T12:02:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Andrew J. Young Safeguarding the Mississippi River Together Act or the Andrew J. Young SMRT Act or Andy's Mississippi River Bill or Andy's Bill.

This bill establishes a National Mississippi River Program for the preservation of the Mississippi River Corridor.

The Environmental Protection Agency, coordinating with specified federal departments, may enter into agreements with a state or local government to develop a National Mississippi River Program Office, provide grants, assistance, studies, coordination, and essential restoration and protection of the Mississippi River Corridor to

 sustain essential environmental services; maintain the ecological integrity, health, and biodiversity of federal lands as well as lands managed under federal programs; protect critical national infrastructure, habitat, fish and wildlife resources; and support the major U.S. economies that depend on the Mississippi River. The Program Office shall develop a comprehensive Mississippi River Restoration Plan to guide implementation of projects to sustain the corridor.

In order to support the plan and for other purposes, the bill establishes a series of ongoing studies and investigations to sustain the corridor.

Once every five years the Program Office shall complete an updated economic profile of the corridor.</summary>
</bill>
