<bill session="117" type="h" number="9556" updated="2023-03-01T14:01:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote innovation in financial services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-27T17:45:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Services Innovation Act of 2022 

This bill addresses the regulation of financial products and services. Specifically, the bill allows persons intending to offer a financial innovation to petition specified financial regulatory agencies regarding existing areas of regulation. A petitioner may request a modification or waiver of an agency regulation. The bill sets forth requirements regarding the petition process, a safe harbor for petitioners from enforcement, and enforceable compliance agreements. Agencies must biannually publish a list of financial regulatory areas the agency would consider modifying or waiving through the petition process.

The bill also establishes Financial Services Innovation Offices at these agencies to assist petitioners. These offices must also generally support the development of financial innovations and coordinate with other offices to share data.</summary>
</bill>
