<bill session="117" type="h" number="3846" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NSF Technology Research Institutes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the National Science Foundation to create a program that plans for, establishes, and supports Technology Research Institutes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NSF Technology Research Institutes Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2021-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-21T23:09:06Z" status="Introduced in House">NSF Technology Research Institutes Act

This bill authorizes the National Science Foundation (NSF) to awards grants and cooperative agreements to institutions of higher education, or consortia thereof, for the planning, establishment, and support of Technology Research Institutes in key technology areas, as determined by the NSF.

Funds awarded may be used by an institute to, among other things

 conduct fundamental research to advance innovation in a key technology area; conduct research involving a key technology area to solve challenges with social, economic, health, scientific, and national security implications; and further the development, adoption, and commercialization of innovations in key technology areas. In making awards, the NSF shall ensure the focus areas of an institute do not substantially and unnecessarily duplicate the efforts of any other institute or any other similar effort at another federal agency.</summary>
</bill>
