<bill session="109" type="s" number="1059" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:07Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to specify procedures for the conduct of preliminary damage assessments, to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to vigorously investigate and prosecute instances of fraud, including fraud in the handling and approval of claims for Federal emergency assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to specify procedures for the conduct of preliminary damage assessments, to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to vigorously investigate and prosecute instances of fraud, including fraud in the handling and approval of claims for Federal emergency assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-18">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 109-161.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Losses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-20T21:42:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relielf and Emergency Assistance Act to: (1) specify procedures for the conduct of preliminary disaster damage assessments; and (2) increase the associated penalties for fraud.

Directs the President to: (1) investigate vigorously any allegations and instances of fraud, including fraud relating to the handling and approval of claims for federal emergency assistance; and (2) refer to the Attorney General appropriate allegations, instances, and investigation results.

Requires the Attorney General to: (1) give serious consideration to any allegation or instance of fraud and begin an investigation into it not later than 10 days after the receipt of such a referral; and (2) report on investigation progress and results to the Secretary of Homeland Security within 45 days.

Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to propose new inspection procedures that: (1) more accurately identify disaster-related losses of household items for which applicants should be compensated; (2) modify guidelines for individual and housing inspections to require inspectors to specify any item that was not available for inspection; and (3) develop eligibility criteria for funding vehicle damage, taking into consideration damage to a vehicle sustained as a result of a disaster.</summary>
</bill>
