<bill session="111" type="h" number="6127" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:36Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Extension of Health Care Eligibility for Veterans Who Served at Qarmat Ali Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the continued provision of health care services to certain veterans who were exposed to sodium dichromate while serving as a member of the Armed Forces at or near the water injection plant at Qarmat Ali, Iraq, during Operation Iraqi Freedom.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Extension of Health Care Eligibility for Veterans Who Served at Qarmat Ali Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001235" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1619-1620"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-08T17:06:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Extension of Health Care Eligibility for Veterans Who Served at Qarmat Ali Act - Makes eligible for hospital and nursing home care and medical services for any disability, notwithstanding sufficient medical evidence to conclude that such disability is associated with exposure to sodium dichromate (or other toxic substances), a veteran who: (1) served on active duty at or near the water injection plant at Qarmat Ali, Iraq, during Operation Iraqi Freedom; (2) is notified by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (VA) of possible exposure to sodium dichromate during such service; and (3) enrolls in the VA patient enrollment system within five years after such notification.

Authorizes the Secretary to base a notification of possible exposure to sodium dichromate (or other toxic substances) on information received from the Secretary of Defense (DOD).</summary>
</bill>
