<bill session="117" type="s" number="5222" updated="2022-12-23T05:25:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maintaining and Enhancing Hydroelectricity and River Restoration Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maintaining and Enhancing Hydroelectricity and River Restoration Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to support upgrades at existing hydroelectric dams in order to increase clean energy production, improve the resiliency and reliability of the United States electric grid, enhance the health of the Nation's rivers and associated wildlife habitats, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2022-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-21T12:03:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maintaining and Enhancing Hydroelectricity and River Restoration Act of 2022

This bill allows a new investment tax credit for 30% of the basis of any hydropower improvement property. The bill defines such property as property that, amount other things (1) adds or improves fish passage at a qualified dam (i.e., a hydroelectric dam licensed by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission or legally operating without such a license before the enactment of this bill); (2) maintains or improves the quality of the water retained or released by such a dam; (3) promotes downstream sediment transport processes and habitat maintenance for such a dam; (4) removes an obsolete river obstruction; or (5) places into service an approved remote dam (i.e., a hydroelectric dam that services certain communities and does not contribute to atmosphere pollution).</summary>
</bill>
