<bill session="118" type="s" number="5649" updated="2025-09-18T19:29:11Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Our Seas 2.0 Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Save Our Seas 2.0 Amendments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Marine Debris Act to improve the administration of the Marine Debris Program of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, to improve the administration of the Marine Debris Foundation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2024-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7315-7316" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7315-7316" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:12:13-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-18T19:28:38Z" status="Passed Senate">Save Our Seas 2.0 Amendments Act

This bill expands the administrative requirements of the Marine Debris Program and the Marine Debris Foundation. Both the program and the foundation work to remove, reduce, and prevent marine debris on oceans, waterways, and the Great Lakes.

First, the bill modifies the program to allow the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to (1) enter into other agreements, outside of contracts; and (2) make in-kind contributions for certain projects in an amount that represents the benefit&#160;NOAA derives from the project.

Next, the bill modifies the requirements for the foundation, including by modifying the process for approving or removing members of the foundation's board of directors. It directs&#160;NOAA to obtain the approval from the Department of Commerce before appointing or removing a member of the foundation's board of directors. The bill expands the list of governmental entities that NOAA must consult with before removing a board member to include the U.S. Agency for International Development.

The board must&#160;appoint and review the performance of a chief executive officer (CEO) for the foundation. The board may also remove the CEO.

The bill also directs the foundation to locate its principal office in the National Capital Region or a city or county directly adjacent to the open ocean, a major estuary, or one of the Great Lakes.

The foundation must also develop best practices for conducting outreach to Indian tribes.

The bill expands existing matching fund sources to allow the&#160;foundation to match contributions made to the foundation, or recipients of the foundation's grants, by nongovernmental organizations, regional organizations, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and foreign government entities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
