<bill session="117" type="h" number="4781" updated="2022-12-30T14:02:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">POWER Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to reauthorize a program to address orphaned, abandoned, or idled wells on Federal land, to establish a program to provide grants to States and Tribes to address orphaned wells, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plugging Orphan Wells and Environmental Restoration Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POWER Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000467"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000395" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2021-08-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2021-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000610" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2021-09-29" withdrawn="2021-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-07T17:20:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Plugging Orphan Wells and Environmental Restoration Act of 2021 or the POWER Act of 2021

This bill addresses orphaned, abandoned, or idled oil and gas wells on federal, tribal, state, or private lands.

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes through FY2026 the program to remediate, reclaim, and close orphaned, abandoned, or idled oil and gas wells located on federal land.

Additionally, the Department of the Interior must establish a program to provide grants to states and Indian tribes to remediate, reclaim, and close orphaned oil and gas wells located on state, tribal, or private lands. In providing grants, priority must be given to states and Indian tribes that already have an established program to carry out such activities.

Finally, the Department of Energy must provide technical assistance to oil and gas producing states and Indian tribes to ensure practical and economical remedies for environmental problems caused by orphaned or abandoned oil and gas well sites on state, tribal, or private land.</summary>
</bill>
