<bill session="116" type="h" number="6207" updated="2022-02-09T00:10:46Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coronavirus Worker Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for unemployment benefits to workers affected by the 2019 Novel Coronavirus.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coronavirus Worker Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000381"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2020-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3476" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-27T14:47:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Coronavirus Worker Relief Act

This bill provides for unemployment benefits to workers affected by the coronavirus (i.e., the virus that causes COVID-19).

If the President issues an emergency declaration or major disaster declaration due to the coronavirus&#160;for a state or Indian tribe, the declaration shall be deemed to be a major disaster for the purpose of carrying out provisions regarding unemployment assistance.

An individual in an area for which such a declaration is declared shall be eligible for unemployment assistance if he or she

 has experienced a week of unemployment in such area as a result of the coronavirus; has good cause to voluntarily reduce regular work hours or refuse a bona fide offer of employment, or, in the case of an unemployed self-employed individual, refuses to resume or commence suitable self-employment, for a reason such as illness or incapacity, family crises, or changed individual or family circumstances in the area, as a result of the coronavirus; or is unable to work due to the immediate federal, state, tribal, or local government response to the coronavirus. The assistance authorized for a week of unemployment shall be not less than the weekly amount authorized under the unemployment compensation law of the state for which the disaster declaration was issued.

The state unemployment compensation requirement that an individual be able to work, available to work, and actively seeking work shall not apply. Compensation shall be made to an individual otherwise eligible without any waiting period.</summary>
</bill>
