<bill session="116" type="h" number="232" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:27Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Landlord Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Housing Act, to prohibit discrimination based on use of section 8 vouchers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Landlord Accountability Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000081"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-31T15:05:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Landlord Accountability Act of 2019

This bill provides protections to tenants of certain federally assisted housing and establishes a low-income housing maintenance tax credit for eligible landlords.

Specifically, the bill prohibits discrimination, in the context of rental housing, against individuals who possess a housing choice voucher. Additionally, landlords may not take, or fail to take, certain actions with the intent to make a unit ineligible to receive assistance from the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). Landlords that violate this prohibition shall be fined by HUD for each violation and may be sued by tenants who are harmed.

In addition, the bill allows HUD to provide grants to states, Indian tribes, local governments, and affordable housing organizations to develop, expand, and assist tenant harassment prevention programs.

The bill also provides protections to tenants of multifamily housing projects by requiring HUD to (1) increase the staffing level for the Multifamily Housing Complaint Line, (2) create a Multifamily Housing Complaint Resolution Program, and (3) publicly disclose on its website information regarding each complaint received under the program. Landlords must also display in certain multifamily housing projects information about the complaint line and the phone number of the regional or local HUD office.

In addition, the bill provides a tax credit to qualifying landlords that is equal to the landlord's low-income housing maintenance expenses for the year. To qualify, landlords must have addressed within 30 days any complaints filed against them under the complaint resolution program.</summary>
</bill>
