<bill session="117" type="sr" number="465" updated="2022-12-30T03:33:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States should prioritize within the Government and emphasize with allies the need to provide continued support to, and maintain legal pathways for the emigration out of Afghanistan of, individuals who do not wish to be governed by the Taliban.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the United States should prioritize within the Government and emphasize with allies the need to provide continued support to, and maintain legal pathways for the emigration out of Afghanistan of, individuals who do not wish to be governed by the Taliban.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8913" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T18:22:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution expresses that it is the sense of the Senate that the Department of State should lead a coordinated effort to

 extract U.S. citizens and lawful permanent residents from Afghanistan, support Afghan citizens in their efforts to safely leave Afghanistan, and maintain open lines of contact and help with individuals remaining in Afghanistan under the Taliban. The resolution urges the United States to work with the United Nations (U.N.) to establish humanitarian corridors from and to countries bordering Afghanistan and work with such countries to ensure the efficient and safe reception and processing of Afghan refugees.

 The resolution urges the U.N. to appoint an independent, nongovernmental human rights monitor, who should

 have continued free access throughout Afghanistan to ensure the Taliban is not brutalizing individuals and families living in Afghanistan, and report to the U.N. Security Council in an ongoing fashion on the human rights and humanitarian situation on the ground in Afghanistan. The resolution urges the United States to convene a high-level summit to identify and consult with countries willing and able to receive Afghan refugees.

Finally, the resolution discourages the U.S. government from engaging with the Taliban in any way that would grant the Taliban benefits typically afforded to legitimate governments or would otherwise legitimize the Taliban.</summary>
</bill>
