<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="165" updated="2022-02-18T20:00:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4521" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-02-03T18:51:03-05:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000298"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 124 printed in Part D of House Report 117-241 to require the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct and present to Congress and analysis of the humanitarian impact of the confiscation of the assets of Afghanistan's central bank, its impact on the political power of the People's Republic of China and other entities in the region, and any increase in illicit financial activities between the People's Republic of China and affiliated entities that may have occurred as a result.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to require the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct and present to Congress an analysis of the humanitarian impact of the confiscation of the assets of Afghanistan's central bank, its impact on the political power of the People's Republic of China and other entities in the region, and any increase in illicit financial activities between the People's Republic of China and affiliated entities that may have occurred as a result.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-02-03T18:51:03-05:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="25">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jayapal amendment (A009) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 175 - 255 (Roll no. 25).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:18:51-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A009) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:11:44-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A009) offered by Ms. Jayapal.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H932-933" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H932" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T13:11:44-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A009) offered by Ms. Jayapal.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H932-933" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H932" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T18:51:03-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T18:51:03-05:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Jayapal amendment (A009) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 175 - 255 (Roll no. 25).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03T18:51:03-05:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Jayapal amendment (A009) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 175 - 255 (Roll no. 25).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
