<bill session="118" type="h" number="2612" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gig Worker Equity Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gig Worker Equity Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to extend exemptions for securities offered as part of employee pay to other individuals providing goods for sale, labor, or services for remuneration, to preempt certain provisions of State law with respect to wage rates and benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-29T17:20:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Gig Worker Equity Compensation Act

This bill preempts any state law that classifies an individual providing labor or services for remuneration (i.e., an independent contractor) as an employee for purposes of wage-rate and benefit requirements.

The bill also&#160;broadens the existing Securities and Exchange Commission registration exemption for the issuance of securities as part of an employee-compensation package. Specifically, the bill applies this exemption to the issuance of securities&#160;as compensation for&#160;independent contractors.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the&#160;bill's effects.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
