<bill session="119" type="s" number="1637" updated="2025-08-26T20:21:36Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MVP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid VBPs for Patients Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MVP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to codify value-based purchasing arrangements under the Medicaid program and reforms related to price reporting under such arrangements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2025-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T20:20:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medicaid VBPs for Patients Act or the MVP Act

This bill provides statutory authority for regulations that allow for the use of varying best price points under value-based purchasing arrangements for purposes of the Medicaid Drug Rebate Program. (Value-based purchasing arrangements refer to arrangements in which the price of a drug is linked to clinical outcomes; such arrangements are particularly used for new high-cost treatments, such as gene therapies.)

The Government Accountability Office must study the impact of value-based purchasing arrangements on federal health care programs, including with respect to the bill's changes.

Additionally, the bill (1) exempts sales of drugs that are made under value-based purchasing arrangements from calculations of the manufacturer average sales price for purposes of payments under Medicare medical services, if the manufacturer reports multiple best prices under Medicaid in accordance with the bill's changes; and (2) requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to issue guidance on how&#160;state Medicaid programs may cover drugs in inpatient settings via value-based purchasing arrangements.</summary>
</bill>
