<bill session="117" type="h" number="4064" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, and the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to provide increased protections for election workers and voters in elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001168"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000376" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001312" joined="2021-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000273" joined="2021-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2021-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2021-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2021-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2155" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5746" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T17:40:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Election Subversion Act of 2021

This bill establishes certain federal criminal offenses related to voting and sets forth additional requirements for federal elections.

The bill makes it a crime to (1) intimidate, threaten, coerce, or harass an election worker (i.e., an election official, a poll worker, or an election volunteer) with the intent to interfere with the official duties of, or retaliate against, the worker; or (2) publicly disclose restricted personal information about an election worker or an immediate family member with the intent to threaten or cause harm to the worker or the family member.

In addition, the bill restricts the ability of a statewide election administrator to remove a local election administrator. A statewide election administrator may suspend, remove, or relieve the duties of a local election administrator only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance while in office.

 Further, the bill establishes certain requirements for challenging an individual's eligibility to register to vote or vote in federal elections.

The bill also sets a minimum distance for poll observers.</summary>
</bill>
