<bill session="118" type="h" number="7528" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-06T16:34:38-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-06T16:34:38-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 206 of the E-Government Act of 2002 to improve the integrity and management of mass comments and computer-generated comments in the regulatory review process, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001077"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 31 - 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06T16:25:03-04:00">
      <text>Mr. LaTurner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06T16:25:07-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2844-2846" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06T16:25:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 7528.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-05-06T16:34:38-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2844-2845" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06T16:34:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-306.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="712">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 712.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-14T15:11:09Z" status="Passed House">Comment Integrity and Management Act of 2024

This bill establishes requirements with respect to the submission of mass comments and computer-generated comments in the federal rulemaking process.

Specifically, the bill requires federal agencies to verify, to the greatest extent possible at the time a public comment is submitted, whether the comment has been submitted by a human being.

An agency also must determine whether comments are mass comments and may publish on the docket only a single representative copy of such comments or a single copy of one variation of mass comments that use standardized but not identical language. If the agency publishes only a single copy of a mass comment, the agency also must indicate the number of mass comments submitted that were identical or substantively identical to the representative copy or variation that the agency published.

Additionally, each agency must establish a policy with respect to the posting and consideration of computer-generated comments and mass-comments during the agency's rulemaking process.

The Office of Management and Budget must issue guidance for implementing the requirements of this bill, and the Government Accountability Office must report on the identification and effect of computer-generated comments in the rulemaking process.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-306</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
