<bill session="117" type="s" number="2710" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Open App Markets Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote competition and reduce gatekeeper power in the app economy, increase choice, improve quality, and reduce costs for consumers.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open App Markets Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Open App Markets Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2022-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2021-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2021-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2022-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-17">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Durbin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-02-17" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="275">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 275.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5017" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7030" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-16T14:19:59Z" status="Reported to Senate">Open App Markets Act

This bill establishes rules related to the operation of an app store by a covered company (i.e., the owner or controller of an app store with more than 50 million U.S. users).

An app is a software application or electronic service that may be run or directed by a user on a computer or mobile device. An app store is a publicly available website, software application, or other electronic service that distributes apps from third-party developers to users.

The bill prohibits a covered company from (1) requiring developers to use an in-app payment system owned or controlled by the company as a condition of distribution or accessibility, (2) requiring that pricing or conditions of sale be equal to or more favorable on its app store than another app store, or (3) taking punitive action against a developer for using or offering different pricing terms or conditions of sale through another in-app payment system or on another app store.

A covered company may not interfere with legitimate business communications between developers and users, use non-public business information from a third-party app to compete with the app, or unreasonably prefer or rank its own apps (or those of its business partners) over other apps.

The bill provides for enforcement of its provisions by the Federal Trade Commission and the Department of Justice, as well as through suits brought by developers that are injured by reason of anything prohibited by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
