<bill session="116" type="s" number="3185" updated="2022-02-08T23:22:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bogus Bonus Ban Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bogus Bonus Ban Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the payment of bonuses to contractors for unsatisfactory performance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2145" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-13T20:13:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bogus Bonus Ban Act of 2020

This bill directs the Office of Management and Budget, in coordination with federal departments and agencies, to issue guidance, with detailed implementation instructions, on the appropriate use of award and incentive fees in department or agency programs.

The guidance shall, among other things

 ensure that all new contracts using award fees link such fees to outcomes (which shall be defined in terms of program cost, schedule, and performance); establish criteria for identifying the appropriate level of officials authorized to approve the use of award and incentive fees in new contracts; ensure that no award fee may be paid for contractor performance that is judged to be below satisfactory performance or performance that does not meet the basic requirements of the contract; and provide for the development of performance measures to evaluate the effectiveness of award and incentive fees as a tool for improving contractor performance and achieving desired program outcomes. Any funds intended to be awarded as incentive fees that are not paid due to the inability of a contractor to meet the criteria established by this bill shall be deobligated and made available for purposes for which the funds are otherwise allowable.

The Department of the Treasury shall include award fee as a filter on USAspending.gov.</summary>
</bill>
