<bill session="117" type="h" number="6765" updated="2023-09-15T20:59:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FUELS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers Undertake Environmental Land Stewardship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FUELS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 with respect to the application of the Spill Prevention, Control, and Countermeasure rule to certain farms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000565" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2022-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-06T15:28:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Farmers Undertake Environmental Land Stewardship Act or the FUELS Act

This bill increases thresholds for requiring a farm to have a plan to address oil spills.

Currently, regulations require a farm to have an oil spill control and prevention plan that is certified by a professional engineer if the farm's aboveground oil storage capacity is above a certain threshold or if the farm has a reportable oil discharge history. A farm with lower aboveground storage capacity and no reportable history is either allowed to self-certify its plan or not required to have a plan at all, depending on the farm's storage capacity.&#160;&#160; &#160;

Under the bill, the Environmental Protection Agency must require a farm to have a professionally certified plan if the farm has an aggregate aboveground oil storage capacity of 40,000 gallons or more, whereas the current threshold is 20,000 gallons. The bill also raises the aggregate capacity thresholds at which a farm with no reportable oil discharge history may self-certify its plan or is not required to have a plan.

The bill also limits when a farm's aboveground oil storage containers on separate parcels shall count toward the farm's oil storage capacity for the purposes of these thresholds.</summary>
</bill>
