<bill session="116" type="s" number="1683" updated="2022-11-01T06:02:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildland Firefighter Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildland Firefighter Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to correct problems pertaining to human resources for career and volunteer personnel engaged in wildland fire and structure fire.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2019-07-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="National and community service"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-06T18:02:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wildland Firefighter Fairness Act

 This bill requires the Departments of the Interior and Agriculture to work with states and the Workforce Development Committee of the National Wildfire Coordinating Group to merge the Incident Qualification System and the Incident Qualification and Certification System into a single system by September 30, 2027.

The Office of Personnel Management shall establish a pilot program to expand, when necessary, a service year limitation for seasonal or temporary federal employees whose duties primarily involve being a firefighter. The bill allows wildland firefighters of the Forest Service or Interior who sustained injuries in the performance of their duties that prevent them from performing the physical duties of a firefighter, but who commence an equivalent federal position after receiving compensation for their work injuries, to retain the same retirement benefits they would have received in their former position had they not been injured or disabled, without requiring them to complete any more years of service.

Compensation for disability or death of Forest Service and Interior wildland firefighters must include overtime pay received for wildfire suppression activity.</summary>
</bill>
