<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>693</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:56:06Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:56:06Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-04-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-04-04T20:59:56Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-04-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3155)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-04-04</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3154-3155)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-04-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001056</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cornyn, John [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Cornyn</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Labor and Employment</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Air force</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aircraft pilots</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency Management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military civic action</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rescue work</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Survivors' benefits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Volunteer forces</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Labor and Employment</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-04-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-04-19T15:00:06Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Electronic Communications Privacy Judicial Review and Improvement Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal criminal code to authorize wire or electronic communication service providers (service providers) who receive national security letters (NSLs) from the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) requesting subscriber information and toll billing records in connection with an authorized investigation concerning international terrorism or clandestine intelligence activities to: (1) challenge the NSL in U.S. district court; and (2) challenge the statutory requirement that the receipt of an NSL may not be disclosed to any person. </p> <p>Authorizes the court to: (1) modify or set aside an NSL if compliance would be unreasonable or oppressive; and (2) set aside the nondisclosure requirement if there is no reason to believe that disclosure may endanger U.S. national security, interfere with specified investigations or diplomatic relations, or endanger the life or physical safety of any person. States that the Government's certification that disclosure may endanger national security or interfere with diplomatic relations shall be treated as conclusive unless made in bad faith.</p> <p>Authorizes the Attorney General to seek enforcement of an NSL in U.S. district court if the recipient refuses to comply.</p> <p>States that disclosure of information in proceedings under this Act may be limited consistent with the Classified Information Procedures Act.</p> <p>Modifies the NSL nondisclosure requirement to create exceptions for: (1) disclosure to an attorney for the purpose of seeking advice; or (2) disclosure to other persons as necessary to comply with the request. Makes the nondisclosure requirement applicable to such parties.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Electronic Communications Privacy Judicial Review and Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Electronic Communications Privacy Judicial Review and Improvement Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Electronic Communications Privacy Judicial Review and Improvement Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for judicial review of national security letters issued to wire and electronic communications service providers.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2005-04-04T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s693is/xml/BILLS-109s693is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-04-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3155)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
