<bill session="117" type="h" number="7246" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Athlete Opioid Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use to award grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements for planning, establishing, or administering programs to prevent and address the misuse of opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, by students and student athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2022-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000588" joined="2022-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3940" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-14T19:23:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act or the Student Athlete Opioid Prevention Act

This bill authorizes a program through which the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration may award grants or other assistance for preventing and addressing the misuse of opioids and other medications used for treating pain or injury recovery among students and student athletes. Entities eligible for the grants include states, nonprofits, and drug-free community coalitions.</summary>
</bill>
