<bill session="109" type="s" number="3888" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:06Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fix And Improve Reimbursement (FAIR) for Physicians Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to sunset the sustainable growth rate formula as of January 1, 2009, in order to expedite Congressional action in establishing a new physician payment system that would appropriately reimburse physicians by keeping pace with increases in medical practice costs and providing stable, positive Medicare updates.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fix And Improve Reimbursement (FAIR) for Physicians Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9363-9364"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-16T19:53:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fix And Improve Reimbursement (FAIR) for Physicians Act of 2006 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to repeal the sustainable growth rate (SGR) formula.

Establishes the Physician Payment Update Commission to study and report to the appropriate congressional committees and the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission (MEDPAC) on all matters relating to payment rates under the Medicare physician fee schedule. Requires the Commission to develop recommendations for establishment of a new Medicare physician payment system that would keep pace with increases in medical practice costs and provide stable, positive Medicare updates.</summary>
</bill>
