<bill session="119" type="h" number="907" updated="2025-11-19T02:30:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northern Montana Water Security Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern Montana Water Security Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Fort Belknap Indian Community Water Rights Settlement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the settlement of the water rights claims of the Fort Belknap Indian Community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Z000018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000634" joined="2025-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="241" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Missouri River"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-28T00:22:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Northern Montana Water Security Act of 2025

This bill modifies and ratifies a specified water rights settlement agreement entered into by the United States, Montana, and the Fort Belknap Indian Community of the Fort Belknap Reservation of Montana (i.e., the Gros Ventre and Assiniboine Tribes). The bill also authorizes&#160;wastewater infrastructure on the Blackfeet Indian Reservation in Montana.

The bill requires the community's water rights to be held in trust for the benefit of the community and its allottees. The community must enact a tribal water code to regulate its water rights.

Additionally, the bill authorizes the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (as applicable) to enter negotiations with Montana to exchange certain state lands for federal lands to be held in trust for the benefit of the community.&#160;The bill prohibits gaming on the land taken into trust.

The bill also

establishes the Aaniiih Nakoda Settlement Trust Fund (and specified accounts) for purposes of carrying out this bill,establishes the Fort Belknap Indian Community Water Settlement Implementation Fund (and specified accounts) for purposes of carrying out this bill, andprovides funding for specified accounts established by the bill.The bill also authorizes Interior to plan, design, construct, operate, maintain, and replace community water distribution and wastewater treatment facilities for the Blackfeet Tribe of the Blackfeet Indian Reservation of Montana.</summary>
</bill>
