<bill session="111" type="s" number="1103" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:00Z">
  <state datetime="2009-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voter Fraud Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish standards for the distribution of voter registration application forms and to require organizations to register with the State prior to the distribution of such forms.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voter Fraud Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001066" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000560" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000595" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000352" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001141" joined="2009-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-10T21:37:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Voter Fraud Prevention Act - Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prescribe standards for paid distribution of voter registration application forms and registration requirements for organizations.

Prohibits any individual from distributing, for compensation, a voter registration application form for federal elections in a state if the individual: (1) has been convicted of a felony under any state or federal law; (2) does not sign and print legibly the individual's name on the form; (3) does not provide identifying information to the proper election official; or (4) does not certify, under penalty of perjury, that he or she has not received financial compensation based on the number of voter registration application forms submitted by the individual to an election official upon completion by the applicant, and that the information provided by the individual is accurate to the best of the individual's knowledge.

Excepts from this prohibition the distribution of a voter registration application form by an individual who is not compensated directly or indirectly for it.

Imposes criminal penalties upon: (1) individuals not meeting such standards; and (2) anyone who employs such an individual knowingly, or who should reasonably be expected to know the individual is ineligible.</summary>
</bill>
