<bill session="117" type="s" number="517" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:13Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for joint reports by relevant Federal agencies to Congress regarding incidents of terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">REPORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2021-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-26">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters without amendment. With written report No. 117-31.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-07-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="106">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 106.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-08T18:26:16Z" status="Reported to Senate">Reporting Efficiently to Proper Officials in Response to Terrorism Act of 2021 or the REPORT Act

This bill requires the primary government agency investigating an act of terrorism to submit to Congress an unclassified report within one year after the agency completes its investigation. The agency shall conduct such investigation in collaboration with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of Justice (DOJ), the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), and the National Counterterrorism Center. Such requirement shall not apply in instances in which DHS, DOJ, the FBI, or the center determines that the information required to be reported could jeopardize an ongoing investigation or prosecution, in which case the principal agency making such determination must notify Congress.

Such a report shall (1) identify any gaps in national security that could be addressed to prevent future acts of terrorism, and (2) include any recommendations for additional measures that could be taken to improve homeland security.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-31</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
