<bill session="112" type="h" number="6497" updated="2019-11-15T21:28:19Z">
  <state datetime="2012-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Mining Townsite Conveyance Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Nevada Mining Townsite Conveyance Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the conveyance of certain public lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management in and around historic mining townsites in Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-11-14T22:07:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Nevada Mining Townsite Conveyance Act of 2012 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), to convey, to the counties in which they are situated, all interest of the United States in certain mining townsites in Esmeralda and Nye Counties, Nevada.

 Requires a county receiving a site to reconvey the property to anyone with a valid interest in the site. Requires, for purposes of proving a valid interest, that anyone making the claim must have occupied the site for a least 15 years immediately before enactment. Prohibits a county from recognizing a claim submitted more than 10 years after enactment.

Requires the preservation and protection of all historic and cultural resources on conveyed or reconveyed sites.</summary>
</bill>
