<bill session="118" type="s" number="3543" updated="2025-08-26T12:43:48Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-17">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Historic Greenwood District-Black Wall Street National Monument in the State of Oklahoma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2024-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2024-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2024-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2024-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="602">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 602.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7079" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7079" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T18:01:57-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-18T18:25:58-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T12:42:35Z" status="Passed Senate">Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument Establishment Act

This bill establishes the Historic Greenwood District&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Black Wall Street National Monument in Tulsa, Oklahoma. The monument is established within the National Park System to preserve, protect, and interpret resources associated with Black Wall Street, the Historic Greenwood District, and the Tulsa Race Massacre of 1921.&#160;

(The Tulsa Race Massacre of 1921 occurred in the neighborhood of Greenwood in Tulsa, Oklahoma, referred to as America's Black Wall Street. Racial violence resulted in the deaths of hundreds of Black residents and the displacement of thousands, in what came to be known as one of the worst racial attacks in U.S. history.)

Under the bill, the Department of the Interior may acquire land within a specified area by donation, purchase, or exchange to constitute the monument.&#160;

Interior may enter into cooperative agreements with public or private entities to provide and facilitate interpretive and educational services, administrative support, and technical assistance related to the monument. Interior may also enter into agreements to mark or interpret significant historical or cultural resources or locations within the monument.&#160;

The bill also establishes a commission to advise Interior on the development and management of the monument, including the construction of visitor facilities and infrastructure. Members of the commission must serve without compensation. Interior must consult with the commission to prepare a management plan for the monument.</summary>
</bill>
