<bill session="117" type="s" number="4674" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:37Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Credit Card Competition Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Card Competition Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Electronic Fund Transfer Act to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve system to prescribe regulations relating to network competition in credit card transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8874" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-18T18:47:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Credit Card Competition Act of 2022 

This bill addresses network access and competition in electronic credit transactions.

The bill generally prohibits credit card issuers from restricting the number of payment card networks on which an electronic credit transaction may be processed. Specifically, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System must prohibit certain credit card issuers with assets of over $100 billion from restricting the number of networks on which credit card transactions may be processed to

 one network, two or more networks operated by affiliated networks or persons, or the two networks with the largest market share of credit cards issued. Additionally, credit card issuers are prohibited from imposing certain limitations on the routing of electronic credit transactions, such as through penalties for failure to meet a specified threshold of transactions on a particular payment card network.

The board must also provide for the designation of payment card networks that pose a security risk to the United States or are owned, operated, or sponsored by a foreign state entity.</summary>
</bill>
