<bill session="108" type="h" number="2315" updated="2023-01-15T16:18:34Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Badge Security Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to certain prohibitions relating to police badges, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Badge Security Enhancement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000792"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-15T18:08:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Badge Security Enhancement Act of 2003 - Amends the Federal criminal code to: (1) eliminate as a defense to a prosecution for violating prohibitions against transporting, transferring, or possessing a police badge the intention that such a badge is to be used for decorative or recreational purposes; and (2) provide that prohibitions shall not apply to the use of a badge in the fictitious or historical visual depiction of either a public officer or employee.

Requires a person to: (1) provide certification of the intended use of a genuine or counterfeit badge in order to receive one in interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) obtain written permission from the agency represented on the badge before knowingly transferring or transporting one in interstate or foreign commerce.

Directs the Attorney General to establish additional procedures for the transfer or transportation of genuine and counterfeit police badges to assure that a badge is not acquired under false pretenses to be used for illegal purposes.</summary>
</bill>
