<bill session="116" type="h" number="3906" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DONE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the expansion of immigration detention facilities, to improve the oversight of such facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Detention Oversight, Not Expansion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DONE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2019-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2019-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2221" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-14T11:18:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Detention Oversight, Not Expansion Act or the DONE Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from using any federal funds to construct or expand immigration detention facilities and requires additional oversight of such facilities.

The DHS Inspector General shall conduct various oversight activities into immigration detention facilities, including (1) periodic unannounced inspections; (2) audits to ensure compliance with various legal requirements; and (3) investigations into issues such as deaths in custody, detainee access to medical and mental health care, and sexual assault and harassment. DHS may not continue a contract with any facility deemed less than adequate in two of the most recent inspector general inspections, audits, or investigations.

The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties within DHS shall (1) investigate civil rights and civil liberties complaints in immigration detention facilities, and (2) periodically release on a public website data about such complaints and investigations.

The bill requires various reports to Congress, including a DHS plan for decreasing the number of immigration detention beds and implementing community-based alternatives to detention.</summary>
</bill>
