<bill session="108" type="s" number="1160" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:17Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Millennium Challenge Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Millennium Challenge Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Millennium Challenge Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize Millennium Challenge assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-29">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Lugar under authority of the order of the Senate of May 23 2003. With written report No. 108-55.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="115">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 115.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1240" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Capital movements"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Free trade"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Pluralism (Social sciences)"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-13T13:01:27Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Declares that the purposes of this Act are to provide U.S. assistance for global development through Millennium Challenge Contracts in a manner that: (1) promotes economic growth and the elimination of extreme poverty; and (2) strengthens good governance, economic freedom, and investments in people.

Title I: Millennium Challenge Assistance - (Sec. 101) Directs the Secretary of State to designate an appropriate Department of State officer, with the advice and consent of the Senate, to be Coordinator for the Millennium Challenge Account (established by this Act), who shall be responsible, among other things, for ensuring that assistance under this Act is coordinated with other U.S. economic assistance programs.

(Sec. 102) Authorizes the Secretary to provide assistance (excluding military assistance or training) to an eligible entity (government of an eligible country, a nongovernmental organization (NGO) or other private entity) to carry out projects aimed at reducing extreme poverty in an eligible developing country that enters into a Millennium Challenge Contract with the United States establishing a multiyear plan for achieving economic growth, good governance, economic freedom, and investments in its people.

(Sec. 104) Defines "eligible country" in terms of a country's commitment to democratic governance, economic freedom, and investment in its people (including educational opportunities and health care for all its citizens).

(Sec. 107) Sets forth certain information disclosure requirements.

(Sec. 108) Directs the President to report annually to Congress on the assistance provided under this Act during the prior fiscal year.

(Sec. 109) Authorizes the Secretary to provide assistance to a candidate country that meets certain conditions for the purpose of assisting it in becoming an eligible country.

Defines "candidate country" as a country that: (1) during FY 2004 is eligible to receive loans from the International Development Association (IDA); (2) during FY 2005 has a per capita income less than the historical per capita income cutoff of the IDA for that year; (3) is classified as a lower-middle-income country by the World Bank on the first day of a fiscal year after 2005 in which more than $5 billion has been appropriated to the Millennium Challenge Account; or (4) has a per capita income less than the historical per capita income cutoff of the IDA for any fiscal year after 2005 in which $5 billion or less has been appropriated to such Account.

Title II: The Millennium Challenge Account and Authorization of Appropriations - (Sec. 201) Establishes a Millennium Challenge Account for receipt of funds authorized to carry out this Act.

(Sec. 202) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2004 through 2006.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-55</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
