<bill session="114" type="h" number="3503" updated="2023-01-11T13:29:29Z">
  <state datetime="2015-11-02T16:46:37-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-11-02T16:46:37-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-09-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Support to Fusion Centers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require an assessment of fusion center personnel needs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Support to Fusion Centers Act of 2015</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Support to Fusion Centers Act of 2015</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001269" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2015-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2015-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Counterterrorism and Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 114-322.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2015-11-02" calendar="Union" number="245">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 245.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02T16:36:03-05:00">
      <text>Ms. McSally moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02T16:36:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7357-7360" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02T16:36:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3503.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2015-11-02T16:46:37-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7357-7358" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2015-11-02T16:46:39-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-11-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-02-02T20:02:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Homeland Security Support to Fusion Centers Act of 2015

This bill directs the Under Secretary of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in coordination with the homeland security advisors of the states, to conduct a needs assessment of DHS personnel assigned to fusion centers established under the Homeland Security Act of 2002. (A fusion center serves as a focal point within the state and local environment for the receipt, analysis, gathering, and sharing of threat-related information between the federal government and state, local, tribal, territorial, and private sector partners.)

The assessment must include information on:

 the current deployment of DHS personnel to each fusion center; the roles and responsibilities of Office of Intelligence and Analysis intelligence officers, intelligence analysts, senior reports officers, reports officers, and regional directors deployed to fusion centers; federal resources, in addition to personnel, provided to each fusion center; whether deploying additional personnel would enhance intelligence and information sharing between DHS and federal, state, local, tribal, and territorial partners; fusion centers located in jurisdictions along land and maritime borders of the United States and the degree to which deploying personnel from the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, and the Coast Guard to such centers would enhance the integrity and security at such borders; and fusion centers located in jurisdictions with large and medium hub airports and the degree to which deploying personnel from the Transportation Security Administration to such centers would enhance aviation security. The Under Secretary must submit such assessment to specified congressional committees, together with a report on:

 the number of personnel assigned to fusion centers from the Office of Intelligence and Analysis; the number of personnel assigned to the National Network of Fusion Centers from components and offices of DHS and the methodology for determining the fusion centers to which such personnel are assigned; and an implementation plan for determining how DHS's personnel resources will be allocated to fusion centers in the future. The Under Secretary, in collaboration with the Chief Security Officer of DHS, shall: (1) establish a program to provide eligibility for access to certain information classified as Top Secret for state and local analysts located in fusion centers, and (2) report on the effects of such program and the cost for providing additional training and providing Top Secret clearances for such analysts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-322</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
