<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1542" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that Members' official websites include congressional earmark requests and video presentations for requests submitted to committees.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that Members' official websites include congressional earmark requests and video presentations for requests submitted to committees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Ethics" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-27T18:23:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner (Member) to maintain an official website and include on it a comprehensive, sortable, and searchable database comprising all congressional earmark requests for the current fiscal year and for the budget year, including for each such request: (1) the name and address of any recipient; (2) the purpose of the earmark; (3) its merits; (4) whether it meets applicable eligibility requirements (if any); (5) the amount requested; and (6) in the case of the Committee on Appropriations, a video presentation by the intended recipient with a link for public comment.

Authorizes each Member to waive the requirement for a video presentation by the intended recipient of a congressional earmark if the Member: (1) determines that the video presentation is unnecessary; and (2) places that determination on the Member's official website.</summary>
</bill>
