<bill session="117" type="h" number="1830" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PURE Executive Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to establish a 5-year post-employment ban on lobbying by former senior executive branch personnel and to prohibit such personnel from lobbying at any time on behalf of foreign clients, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting the Unbiased Role of Employees in the Executive Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PURE Executive Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2021-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2021-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2021-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-05T18:21:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting the Unbiased Role of Employees in the Executive Act or the PURE Executive Act

This bill expands restrictions on post-employment lobbying for senior executive branch personnel.

Specifically, the bill prohibits senior personnel (e.g., deputy secretaries) and very senior personnel (e.g., cabinet members) from lobbying agencies for five years after their employment ends. The bill also prohibits such personnel from lobbying on behalf of foreign entities, including foreign corporations, at any time after their employment ends. Currently, senior and very senior personnel may not lobby agencies for one year and two years post-employment, respectively, and may not lobby on behalf of foreign governments or political parties for one year post-employment.</summary>
</bill>
