<bill session="116" type="s" number="1207" updated="2022-11-01T19:47:15Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve the settlement of the water rights claims of the Navajo Nation in Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2019-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-09">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Hoeven without amendment. With written report No. 116-79.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-09-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="182">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 182.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="644" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="886" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-23T15:53:39Z" status="Reported to Senate">Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Act of 2019

This bill ratifies and modifies the Navajo Utah Water Rights Settlement Agreement negotiated between the Navajo Nation, the United States, and Utah. The agreement gives the Navajo Nation the right to use water from sources located within Utah and adjacent to or encompassed within the boundaries of the Navajo Reservation resulting in depletions not to exceed a specified amount annually.

The Navajo water rights shall be held in trust by the United States for the use and benefit of Navajo Nation and shall not be subject to forfeiture or abandonment.

The Navajo Nation shall have authority to allocate, distribute, and lease the water rights for any use on or off its reservation in accordance with the agreement.

The Department of the Interior shall establish and manage the Navajo Utah Settlement Trust Fund, with amounts available for withdrawal by the Navajo Nation for planning, designing, constructing, operating, maintaining, and replacing Navajo water development projects.

The bill also specifies waivers and releases that must be executed in order for the settlement to be binding and effective.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-79</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
