<bill session="117" type="s" number="2776" updated="2022-12-31T05:35:16Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify that the Secretary of Health and Human Services has authority to implement a residential eviction moratorium under the quarantine authority vested by the Public Health Service Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Keeping Renters Safe Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Renters Safe Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-09-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5307" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-01T16:40:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping Renters Safe Act

This bill expressly authorizes the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to place a moratorium on residential evictions to prevent the spread of communicable diseases. The bill also requires HHS to implement a moratorium nationwide to reduce the spread of COVID-19. This moratorium must remain in effect for at least 60 days following the termination of the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Current law authorizes HHS to take measures to prevent the spread of communicable diseases. As part of the COVID-19 response, HHS delegated this authority to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), which then issued (and extended) several orders banning residential evictions. Whether these orders exceed the CDC's statutory and constitutional authority has been the subject of multiple legal challenges; the Supreme Court blocked enforcement of the most recent order on August 26, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
