<bill session="117" type="s" number="2060" updated="2022-12-30T13:03:12Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Funding Accountability Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend disclosure requirements of foreign gifts and contracts under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Funding Accountability Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2021-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2021-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-04T22:33:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Foreign Funding Accountability Act of 2021

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disclose additional information related to gifts and contracts from foreign sources.

Under current law, an IHE is required to disclose in a report to the Department of Education (ED) a gift or contract that is from a foreign source and is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with a foreign source. The bill instead requires the IHE to disclose such a gift or contract that is valued at $25,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts or contracts. In-kind gifts, gifts to foundations, and gifts to other legal entities that operate substantially for the benefit of the IHE are included in this limit.

An IHE must disclose additional information in its report, including the intended purpose and function of the gift or contract.

Further, an IHE must disclose gifts and contracts from foreign agents.

 Next, the bill authorizes ED to impose civil penalties on an IHE for failing to comply with disclosure requirements. An IHE that has violated these disclosure requirements three or more times shall be ineligible to enroll foreign students under the Student and Exchange Visitor Program and shall lose its tax-exempt status.

An IHE must submit to ED a report for every qualifying event (e.g., each time it received a gift or contract valued at $25,000 or more) that occurred since October 7, 1998.</summary>
</bill>
