<bill session="109" type="s" number="288" updated="2022-02-03T05:35:33Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">State High Risk Pool Funding Extension Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State High Risk Pool Funding Extension Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">State High Risk Pool Funding Extension Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend Federal funding for operation of State high risk health insurance pools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000445"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2005-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2005-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2005-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2005-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2005-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-10">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-02-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="2">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 2.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2005-07-29">
      <text>By Senator Enzi from Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions filed written report. Report No. 109-121.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3204" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3297" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4519" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-14T20:32:46Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">State High Risk Pool Funding Extension Act of 2005 - Reauthorizes funds to provide grants to States to create and operate qualified high risk health insurance pools.

Amends provisions requiring the Secretary to award grants to States with existing qualified high risk pools to cover losses incurred by a State in connection with the operation of such a pool to: (1) remove the limit that provided that such grants would cover up to 50 percent of such losses; and (2) allow such grants to be made to entities that operate such a pool under applicable State law; and (3) change the allocation of such grants to give one-half of the funds to eligible States equally and apportion the other half based on the number of uninsured individual in each State and the number of enrollees in a State's qualified high risk pool. (Currently all funds are allotted based solely on the number of uninsured individuals in a State.)

Requires the Secretary to award grants to States with established qualified high risk pools for the provision of supplemental consumer benefits, which must include one or more of the following benefits: (1) low-income premium subsidies; (2) a reduction in premium trends, actual premiums, or other cost-sharing requirements; (3) an expansion or broadening of the pool of individuals eligible for coverage; (4) less stringent rules or additional waiver authority with respect to coverage of preexisting conditions; (5) increased benefits; or (6) establishment of disease management programs.

Authorizes appropriations.

Defines "qualified high risk pools" to allow States to provide for enrollment through: (1) a combination of a qualified high risk pool and an acceptable alternative mechanism; (2) health insurance coverage that meets the requirements for a high risk pool, limits rates, is available to all eligible individuals, and does not exceed the rate limit allowed for high risk pools; or (3) health insurance coverage that provides first dollar coverage, limits on cost-sharing, and comprehensive medical, hospital, and surgical coverage if the rate limits do not exceed 125 percent of the rate limit otherwise allowable for qualified high risk pools.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-121</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
