<bill session="118" type="h" number="1772" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WHEELChairs on Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WHEELChairs on Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working to Help Ensure Equity for Lithium-ion-powered Chairs on Airplanes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to prevent discrimination against airline passengers with disabilities who use lithium-ion-powered wheelchairs and mobility aids that are safe for air travel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2023-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2023-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-22T19:26:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Working to Help Ensure Equity for Lithium-ion-powered Chairs on Airplanes Act or the WHEELChairs on Airplanes Act

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to conduct an annual survey of all air carriers and foreign air carriers to compile each of their policies regarding lithium-ion battery-powered wheelchairs and mobility aids and determine whether any of the policies are more restrictive than FAA safety standards.

The bill requires air carriers with more restrictive policies than the FAA and those that do not have a policy in effect to update their policies. The FAA must assess a civil penalty for any policy of the air carrier that remains noncompliant.</summary>
</bill>
