<bill session="117" type="h" number="4706" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-08T21:03:12-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-12-08T21:03:12-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Blackwell School National Historic Site in Marfa, Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000132" joined="2021-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 117-198.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2021-12-01" calendar="Union" number="142">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 142.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01T13:42:09-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Leger Fernandez moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01T13:42:21-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6740-6741" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6740" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01T13:42:22-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4706.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-01T13:50:38-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T20:56:11-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7546" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="429" datetime="2021-12-08T21:03:12-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 8 (Roll no. 429).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08T21:03:13-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2490" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-17T16:36:41Z" status="Passed House">Blackwell School National Historic Site Act

This bill establishes the Blackwell School National Historic Site in Texas as a unit of the National Park System to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations the Blackwell School, its role as both an academic and cultural cornerstone in the community in Marfa, Texas, and its function within a segregated system of education in Texas and the United States from 1885-1965.

The historic site shall not be established until the date on which the Department of the Interior has (1) entered into a written agreement with the Marfa Unified School District providing that the Blackwell School shall be donated to or placed by agreement into comanagement with the United States for inclusion in a national historic site to be managed consistently with the purposes of such a site, and (2) acquired sufficient land or interests in land within the boundaries of the historic site to constitute a manageable unit.

Interior may only acquire by donation, purchase with donated funds, or exchange any land or interest in land located within the boundary of the historic site.

The bill prohibits any private property or nonfederal public property from being included within the boundaries of the historic site or managed as part of such site without the written consent of the owner.

Interior shall prepare a general management plan for the historic site.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-198</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
