<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3614</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:09Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:09Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-07-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-12-14T22:02:20Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2010-07-22T23:40:41Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-07-19T21:03:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Oil Spill Response Improvement Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>3643</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-07-26</actionDate>
          <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 483.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-14</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 697.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-14</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-12-14</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-22</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-07-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H001016</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hutchison, Kay Bailey [R-TX]</fullName>
        <firstName>KAY</firstName>
        <lastName>HUTCHISON</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>TX</state>
        <middleName>BAILEY</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000572</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. LeMieux, George S. [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>LeMieux</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-07-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3614, Oil Spill Response Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/21890</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on July 22, 2010&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 3614, Oil Spill Response Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/21890</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on July 22, 2010</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accidents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arctic and polar regions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Atlantic Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coast guard</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency planning and evacuation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental technology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Gulf of Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes and toxic substances</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and inland water transportation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine pollution</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oil and gas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pacific Ocean</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technology assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water quality</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Environmental Protection</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-07-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-08-31T20:23:48Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oil Spill Response Act - Requires the Commandant of the Coast Guard to establish a Maritime Center of Expertise for Maritime Oil Spill and Hazardous Substance Release Response.</p> <p>Requires the Coast Guard to maintain a National Strike Force to facilitate preparedness for, and response to, maritime oil spill and hazardous substance release incidents. Requires the National Strike Force to consist of: (1) a National Strike Force Coordination Center; (2) strike force teams, including one each for the Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, and the Gulf of Mexico; (3) a public assistance team; and (4) if the Commandant so directs, one or more teams for the northwest Pacific Ocean and the Arctic Ocean.<br> </p> <p>Requires the Commandant to maintain district preparedness response teams.</p> <p>Requires each maritime oil spill response organization that is listed under the oil spill response plan of a vessel or facility regulated under the National Response System to be certified by the Coast Guard and inspected at least once a year.</p> <p>Requires each certified oil spill response organization and any facility that is not using a maritime oil spill response organization to meet the facility oil spill response plan requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to maintain a current list of its response equipment and to submit a copy to the National Strike Force Coordination Center. </p> <p>Directs the Commandant to establish a research and development program for oil spill and hazardous substance release response to prevent or mitigate oil discharges and hazardous substances releases.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-12-14</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-23T14:30:25Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Oil Spill Response Act - (Sec. 2) Requires the Commandant of the Coast Guard to establish a Maritime Center of Expertise for Maritime Oil Spill and Hazardous Substance Release Response to perform specified functions, including: (1) serving as the primary facility for Coast Guard personnel to obtain qualifications to perform specified regional response and on-scene coordination duties; (2) training first responders in the incident command system structure, maritime oil spill and hazardous substance release response techniques and strategies, and public affairs; (3) working with academic and private sector response training centers; (4) conducting research, development, testing, and demonstration for response equipment, technologies, and prevention and mitigation techniques; (5) maintaining at least two incident management and assistance teams, one of which must be ready to deploy anywhere in the continental United States within 24 hours after an incident or event; (6) administering Coast Guard participation in the National Preparedness for Response Exercise Program; and (7) establishing Coast Guard marine environmental response doctrine.</p> <p>(Sec. 3) Requires the Coast Guard to maintain a National Strike Force (NSF) to facilitate preparedness for, and response to, maritime oil spill and hazardous substance release incidents. Requires the NSF to consist of: (1) a National Strike Force Coordination Center (NSFCC); (2) strike force teams, including one each for the Atlantic Ocean, Pacific Ocean, and the Gulf of Mexico; (3) a public information assist team; and (4) if the Commandant so directs, one or more teams for the northwest Pacific Ocean and the Arctic Ocean. Sets forth the duties required of the NSFCC and related NSF teams.</p> <p>(Sec. 4) Requires the Commandant to maintain district preparedness response teams to administer area contingency plans and the National Preparedness for Response Exercise Program, coordinate district participation with the Federal Emergency Management Agency's (FEMA) regional interagency steering committee, and perform related enumerated activities.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Requires each maritime oil spill response organization that is listed under the oil spill response plan of a vessel or facility regulated under the National Response System to be certified by the Coast Guard and inspected at least once a year.</p> <p>Directs the Commandant to develop criteria for certifying and classifying maritime oil spill response organizations. </p> <p>Requires each certified oil spill response organization and any facility that is not using a maritime oil spill response organization to meet the facility oil spill response plan requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to maintain a current list of its response equipment and to submit a copy to the NSFCC. </p> <p>(Sec. 6) Directs the Commandant to establish a research and development program for oil spill and hazardous substance release response to prevent or mitigate oil discharges and hazardous substances releases. Requires such program to include research and development related to: (1) containment, recovery, removal, and disposal methods; (2) vessel designs; (3) private industry and U.S. government response; (4) a public list of approved technology; and (5) a process for private industry, academic institutions, nongovernmental organizations, and federal, state, and local governments to submit systems, equipment, and technologies for testing and evaluation.</p> <p>Authorizes the Commandant to make grants to or enter into cooperative agreements with academic institutions for related research and development. Requires the Commandant to carry out such program by: (1) coordinating with the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Oil Pollution Research; and (2) using sums as may be necessary for FY2010-FY2015 from funds appropriated to the Coast Guard's research, development, and testing program account for those years.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Oil Spill Response Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Oil Spill Response Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize the establishment of a Maritime Center of Expertise for Maritime Oil Spill and Hazardous Substance Release Response, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Oil Spill Response Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Oil Spill Response Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-12-14T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-07-19T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-12-14</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 697.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
