<bill session="119" type="h" number="2247" updated="2025-09-11T14:41:08Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pilot Certificate Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pilot Certificate Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to authorize the use of physical or digital copies of certain certificates for certain Federal Aviation Administration inspections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2025-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-11T14:35:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Pilot Certificate Accessibility Act

This bill allows a pilot to present a digital copy of certain certificates (e.g., an airman certificate or a&#160;medical certificate) when required to present such documentation by a&#160;Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) inspector or other official.

Under current FAA regulations, a pilot must present for inspection a physical copy of an airman certificate and other paperwork upon a request from the FAA; a federal, state, or local law enforcement officer; or an authorized representative of the Transportation Security Administration or the National Transportation Safety Board. This bill allows a pilot to present a&#160;certificate such as an airman certificate or a medical&#160;certificate as (1) a physical, original copy; or (2) a digital copy stored on an electronic device or cloud storage platform.

The FAA must update current regulations to implement this change.</summary>
</bill>
