<bill session="111" type="h" number="2761" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:52Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To sever United States' government relations with the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma until such time as the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma restores full tribal citizenship to the Cherokee Freedmen disenfranchised in the March 3, 2007, Cherokee Nation vote and fulfills all its treaty obligations with the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To sever United States' government relations with the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma until such time as the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma restores full tribal citizenship to the Cherokee Freedmen disenfranchised in the March 3, 2007, Cherokee Nation vote and fulfills all its treaty obligations with the Government of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000794"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2009-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2009-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-08T19:29:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Severs the United States relations with the Cherokee Nation of Oklahoma until the Cherokee Nation is meeting all of its treaty obligations and other federal statutory obligations, including all obligations with the Treaty of 1866 and has restored the rights of Cherokee Freedmen disenfranchised from the Cherokee Nation in the March 3, 2007, Cherokee Nation vote to remove them from the Cherokee Nation.

Requires a report from the Government Accountability Office (GAO) on the Cherokee Nation's expenditure of federal funds, as well as other specified reports from federal agencies, the Secretary of the Interior, and the National Indian Gaming Commission.

Suspends the Cherokee Nation's authority to conduct gaming operations until it is in compliance with all treaty and other obligations with the United States.

Grants any Cherokee Freedman a private right to bring actions for injunctive relief, declaratory relief, or monetary damages against the Cherokee Nation, officials of the Cherokee Nation, or federal officials.

Directs the Attorney General to issue a finding on whether the federal civil rights of the Cherokee Freedmen have been violated by the Cherokee Nation and/or the Department of the Interior.</summary>
</bill>
