<bill session="117" type="h" number="8516" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Response Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Response Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to conduct a review of the benefit cost analysis criteria for mitigation projects under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-23T15:38:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildfire Response Improvement Act

This bill requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to take specified actions to address issues related to wildfire and drought.

Specifically, FEMA must

 issue such regulations as necessary to update the categories of eligibility and timelines for the fire management assistance program under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to be the same as such categories and timelines under the Public Assistance Program; issue such regulations as necessary to update the Public Assistance Program and Policy Guide to include guidance on the wildfire-specific challenges, including debris removal, emergency protective measures, and the resulting toxicity of drinking water resources; and conduct a review of the benefit cost analysis criteria for mitigation projects under the Stafford Act to consider a broader range of factors, including carbon sequestration, improved water quality, and lessening disaster impact on traditionally underserved communities.</summary>
</bill>
