<bill session="119" type="h" number="159" updated="2025-02-28T16:10:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CLEAN Public Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Legislature Anti-Corruption Reform of Public Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN Public Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to terminate pensions for Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-28T16:10:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Citizen Legislature Anti-Corruption Reform of Public Service Act or the CLEAN Public Service Act

This bill excludes Members of Congress from further retirement coverage under the Civil Service Retirement System or the Federal Employees Retirement System following the enactment of the bill. It also prohibits further government contributions or deductions from a Member's basic pay for deposit in the Treasury to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund.

This exclusion does not affect a Member's eligibility to participate in the Thrift Savings Plan.</summary>
</bill>
