<bill session="117" type="s" number="1981" updated="2022-12-30T16:02:27Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify rules relating to donor advised funds, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Accelerating Charitable Efforts Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACE Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2022-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6595" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-05T13:14:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Accelerating Charitable Efforts Act or the ACE Act

This bill modifies tax rules relating to donor advised funds (DAFs) (separately identified funds maintained and operated by a tax-exempt charitable organization for which a donor retains advisory privileges with respect to the distribution of funds and the investment of assets).

Specifically, the bill places certain restrictions on charitable contribution deductions for gifts made to a nonqualified DAF. It also sets forth rules for the treatment of private foundation administrative expenses paid to disqualified persons and for the treatment of distributions to DAFs from private foundations.

The bill imposes a 50% penalty on contributions held in a DAF that are not timely distributed.

The bill also sets forth special rules for the treatment of contributions from DAFs for purposes of meeting the public support test (the requirement that charitable organizations receive a certain percentage of their support from public sources).

The bill exempts from the tax on the investment income of a private foundation (1) distributions to a DAF of not less than 7% of the foundation's assets, and (2) for foundations that have a duration, specified in their governing documents, of not more than 25 years.</summary>
</bill>
