<bill session="109" type="s" number="3064" updated="2018-02-04T00:22:38Z">
  <state datetime="2006-05-25">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="display">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to express the policy of the United States regarding the United States relationship with native Hawaiians and to provide a process for the recognition by the United States of the Native Hawaiian governing entity.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2006-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-05-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="459">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 459.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="309" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="147" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Directories"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Homestead law"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Referendum"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Statehood (American politics)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-06-05T17:25:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native Hawaiian Government Reorganization Act of 2006 - Establishes the U.S. Office for Native Hawaiian Relations within the Office of the Secretary of the Interior.

Establishes the Native Hawaiian Interagency Coordinating Group.

Recognizes the right of the Native Hawaiian people to reorganize the single Native Hawaiian governing entity to provide for their common welfare and to adopt appropriate organic governing documents.

Establishes a Commission to: (1) prepare and maintain a roll of the adult members of the Native Hawaiian community who elect to participate in such reorganization; and (2) certify that the adult members of the Native Hawaiian community proposed for inclusion on the roll meet the definition of Native Hawaiian.

Outlines the process for the reorganization, which includes forming a Native Hawaiian Interim Governing Council.

Reaffirms the special political and legal relationship between the United States and the Native Hawaiian governing entity upon certification required by the Secretary regarding the organic governing documents and the election of the entity's officers. Extends federal recognition to the governing entity as the representative governing body of the Native Hawaiian people.

Authorizes the United States, upon the reaffirmation of such political and legal relationship, together with the state of Hawaii, to enter into negotiations with the governing entity to lead to an agreement addressing specified matters, including the transfer of lands, natural resources, and other assets, and the protection of existing rights related to such lands or resources.</summary>
</bill>
