<bill session="110" type="h" number="3899" updated="2023-01-11T20:23:37Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a civil action for a minor injured by exposure to an entertainment product containing material that is harmful to minors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Parents' Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parents' Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000981"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000453" joined="2008-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000280" joined="2008-01-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2182"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Sex-oriented businesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-10-26T21:36:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Parents' Empowerment Act - Authorizes a minor, through a person acting on his or her behalf under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure, to bring a civil action in U.S. district court for compensatory and punitive damages for the knowing sale or distribution in interstate or foreign commerce of an entertainment product containing material harmful to minors, if: (1) a reasonable person would expect a substantial number of minors to be exposed to the material; and (2) the minor as a result of such exposure is likely to suffer personal or emotional injury or injury to mental or moral welfare.

Makes it an affirmative defense to such an action that: (1) a parent or guardian of the minor owned or possessed the entertainment product containing the material to which the minor was exposed; and (2) an act of that parent or guardian was the proximate cause of the minor&#146;s exposure.</summary>
</bill>
