<bill session="117" type="h" number="5689" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-05T15:54:59-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-05T15:54:59-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Resilient AMERICA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resilient AMERICA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resilient Assistance for Mitigation for Environmentally Resilient Infrastructure and Construction by Americans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Resilient AMERICA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Resilient Assistance for Mitigation for Environmentally Resilient Infrastructure and Construction by Americans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Resilient AMERICA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Resilient Assistance for Mitigation for Environmentally Resilient Infrastructure and Construction by Americans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the provision of Federal resources to help build capacity and fund risk-reducing, cost-effective mitigation projects for eligible State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments and certain private nonprofit organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000546" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2021-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 63 - 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 117-277.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-03-24" calendar="Union" number="204">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 204.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T13:22:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. DeFazio moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T13:22:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4170-4175" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T13:22:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5689.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T13:40:53-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T15:46:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4182-4183" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="113" datetime="2022-04-05T15:54:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 383 - 41 (Roll no. 113).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4170-4172" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T15:55:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-07T16:25:05Z" status="Passed House">Resilient Assistance for Mitigation for Environmentally Resilient Infrastructure and Construction by Americans Act or the Resilient AMERICA Act

This bill addresses disaster resilience issues and expands coverage for hazard mitigation.

The bill

 increases from 6% to 15% the estimated aggregate amount of grants that may be set aside for national public infrastructure pre-disaster hazard mitigation assistance; makes private nonprofit facilities eligible for technical and financial assistance for implementing cost-effective pre-disaster hazard mitigation measures; provides funding for water resources development projects; and expands the use of hazard mitigation assistance to cover certain activities pertaining to wildfires, tsunamis, and ice storms. Additionally, the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must set aside 10% of funds made available for any given year to further the implementation and enforcement of the latest published editions of relevant consensus-based building codes.

FEMA must require as a condition of providing nonemergency financial assistance for construction projects costing at least $1 million that the steel and iron used in the projects be produced in the United States, with certain exceptions.

FEMA must carry out a residential resilience pilot program to provide grants for residential resilience retrofits (e.g., elevation of homes, floodproofing measures, wildfire retrofit and mitigation measures, and wind retrofits).

The Government Accountability Office must study the challenges to states and territories in obtaining funds under public assistance alternative procedures.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-277</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
