<bill session="117" type="h" number="3429" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHOP SAFE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Trademark Act of 1946 to provide for contributory liability for certain electronic commerce platforms for use of a counterfeit mark by a third party on such platforms, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHOP SAFE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Harmful Offers on Platforms by Screening Against Fakes in E-commerce Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2021-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1843" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5374" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-23T20:49:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Stopping Harmful Offers on Platforms by Screening Against Fakes in E-commerce Act of 2021 or SHOP SAFE Act of 2021

This bill makes an electronic commerce platform liable for infringement of a registered trademark by a third-party seller of goods that implicate health and safety unless the platform takes certain actions.

Specifically, the platform may be contributorily liable if the seller uses a counterfeit mark in connection with selling, offering, or advertising such goods on the platform. The platform may avoid such liability by taking certain actions before the infringing act, including (1) requiring the seller to have a registered agent or a verified address for service of process in the United States, (2) verifying the seller's identity and contact information, (3) requiring the seller to agree to not use counterfeit marks with goods sold on the platform, (4) implementing technical measures to prescreen listings on the platform and remove listings for goods being sold with a counterfeit mark, and (5) implementing policies to remove and ban repeat offenders.</summary>
</bill>
