<bill session="116" type="s" number="1503" updated="2022-11-01T05:32:24Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Defense Ethics and Anti-corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Defense Ethics and Anti-corruption Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote ethics and prevent corruption in Department of Defense contracting and other activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4277" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military command and structure"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-09T13:52:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Department of Defense Ethics and Anti-corruption Act of 2019

This bill addresses the conduct of Department of Defense (DOD) officials regarding relationships with military contractors.

With respect to certain DOD officials involved in contracting, the bill increases the following: (1) the period during which an official leaving DOD and seeking compensation from a contractor must obtain an ethics opinion concerning post-employment restrictions, (2) the length of time such requests must be retained in a central repository, and (3) the frequency of Inspector General reviews of providing and retaining opinions.

Each procurement contract of a value exceeding $10 million must require the contractor to annually report information (including concerning lobbying activities) about former officials and military officers who received compensation within four years after leaving service. Such a contract shall include a clause prohibiting the contractor from receiving the compensation.

Contracts with contractors that received an average of more than $1 billion in revenue in the previous three years from DOD or the Department of Energy (related to the U.S. nuclear program) shall prohibit the employment or payment of certain DOD officials within four years of leaving DOD service.

In addition, the bill includes restrictions and conditions concerning:

 lobbying by former officials and officers; stock ownership and trading; employment that is subject to the emoluments clause of the Constitution; work by certain senior officials for a foreign entity (including work that conflicts with U.S. national security interests); financial disclosure by large prospective contractors; and public disclosure of information regarding the identification of general or flag officers and their finances and conduct.</summary>
</bill>
