<bill session="118" type="h" number="6260" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-03-19T17:05:08-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-03-19T17:05:08-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FOCUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Oversight of Construction Use and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FOCUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Oversight of Construction Use and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FOCUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Oversight of Construction Use and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FOCUS Act</title>
    <title type="short">Federal Oversight of Construction Use and Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short">FOCUS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for certain reviews of the use and safety of Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2024-01-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-410.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-03-06" calendar="Union" number="337">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 337.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T16:56:07-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Johnson (SD) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T16:56:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1209-1211" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T16:56:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6260.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-03-19T17:05:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1209-1210" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-03-19T17:05:10-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-02T13:32:45Z" status="Passed House">Federal Oversight of Construction Use and Safety Act or FOCUS Act This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to limit scope or size escalations for public building projects. GSA must also report to Congress on certain project scope and cost changes, public safety, and utilization of public buildings.

Specifically, GSA must not allow the scope or size of a project to increase or decrease by more than 10% without congressional approval.

GSA must report (1) when the estimated maximum cost increases by more than 5%, (2) when the scope or size of a project increases or decreases by more than 5%, (3) any safety incidents as a result of criminal or other activity impacting public safety in and around public buildings, and (4) public building utilization rates and locations of tenant agency activities near such buildings.

GSA must notify Congress upon accomplishing certain milestones for all congressionally approved projects.

GSA must also share space utilization information among federal agencies to coordinate consolidation and sharing of facilities.

The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office to review and report on special use spaces (e.g., conference centers and fitness centers) in federal buildings to determine levels of utilization, opportunities for sharing, and other efficiencies.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-410</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
