<bill session="111" type="h" number="4688" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:35Z">
  <state datetime="2010-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Reintegration and Crime Prevention Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Second Chance Act of 2007 to reauthorize the grants program carried out by the Secretary of Labor to provide mentoring, job training and job placement services, and other comprehensive transitional services to assist eligible offenders in obtaining and retaining employment, and to require a study on best practices by nonprofit organization participating in such grants program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Reintegration and Crime Prevention Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-23T21:05:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Reintegration and Crime Prevention Act of 2010 - Amends the Second Chance Act of 2007 to reauthorize appropriations for FY2011 and FY2012 to the Secretary of Labor to carry out the reintegration of offenders grants program through the award of grants to nonprofit organizations to provide mentoring, job training and job placement services, and other comprehensive transitional services to assist eligible offenders in obtaining and retaining employment.

Directs the Attorney General, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor, to prepare a report identifying the best practices of nonprofit organizations receiving grants under the Act. Directs the Attorney General to make such report available to the public.

Requires nonprofit organization grantees, for grants awarded on or after January 1, 2012, to comply with the best practices identified in the report.</summary>
</bill>
