<bill session="116" type="h" number="2546" updated="2022-08-10T23:26:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-12T17:01:53-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-02-12T17:01:53-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting America's Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain lands in the State of Colorado as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting America's Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Central Coast Heritage Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Northwest California Wilderness, Recreation, and Working Forests Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Rim of the Valley Corridor Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Rim of the Valley Corridor Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">San Gabriel Mountains Foothills and Rivers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Wild Olympics Wilderness and Wild and Scenic Rivers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2019-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 116-387.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-02-04" calendar="Union" number="310">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 310.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-02-10T19:15:37-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 844 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2546 and H.J. Res. 79. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each measure. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2546 under a structured rule and consideration of H.J.Res. 79 under a closed rule with a motion to recommit with or without instructions for each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T12:22:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 844.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1058-1104" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1066-1089" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T12:22:36-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 2546 and H.J. Res. 79. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each measure. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2546 under a structured rule and consideration of H.J.Res. 79 under a closed rule with a motion to recommit with or without instructions for each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T12:23:19-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 844 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T12:23:20-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James P. McGovern to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T12:23:56-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 2546.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:30:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeGette amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:37:18-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeGette amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Tipton demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:38:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:45:49-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McClintock demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:46:50-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:55:34-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McClintock amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. McClintock demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:56:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brown (MD) amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T13:59:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Panetta amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:06:18-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Panetta amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Panetta demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:06:43-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westerman amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:15:30-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westerman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westerman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:16:07-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westerman amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:24:28-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Westerman amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Westerman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:25:06-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cunningham amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:29:50-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Cunningham amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Cunningham demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:30:29-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tipton amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:42:18-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tipton amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Tipton demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:42:54-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tipton amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:48:40-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kilmer amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T14:55:23-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 844, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schrier amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:02:00-05:00">
      <text>Ms. DeGette moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:02:12-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:02:21-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 2546 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:32:13-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1104-1112" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:32:23-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T15:32:26-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:35:46-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 2546.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:36:47-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:36:58-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:37:43-05:00">
      <text>Mr. McClintock moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1110" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:37:56-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McClintock motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment to allow mechanical wildfire mitigation in wilderness areas designated under the bill to protect life, property or the environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:48:24-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T16:55:55-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 199 - 215 (Roll no. 68).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="69" datetime="2020-02-12T17:01:53-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 231 - 183 (Roll no. 69).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12T17:01:55-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="844" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1708" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2215" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2250" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2199" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2642" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5714" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1109" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1110" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1111" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1382" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3288" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Archaeology and anthropology"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military readiness"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h800"/>
    <amendment number="h799"/>
    <amendment number="h798"/>
    <amendment number="h797"/>
    <amendment number="h796"/>
    <amendment number="h795"/>
    <amendment number="h794"/>
    <amendment number="h793"/>
    <amendment number="h792"/>
    <amendment number="h791"/>
    <amendment number="h790"/>
    <amendment number="h789"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-02-26T20:34:25Z" status="Reported to House">Colorado Wilderness Act of 2019

This bill designates specified lands in Colorado managed by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the Forest Service as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill designates specified lands in Colorado administered by the BLM, the National Park Service, and Bureau of Reclamation as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Such lands shall be incorporated into the West Elk Wilderness.

The Department of the Interior may continue authorizing competitive running events currently permitted in the Redcloud Peak Wilderness and Handies Peak Wilderness Areas.

The Colorado Army National Guard, through the High-Altitude Army National Guard Aviation Training Site, may conduct aerial navigation training maneuver exercises over the wilderness areas designated by this bill.

The bill designates specified lands managed by the BLM as (1) potential wilderness areas, and (2) the Pisgah East Wilderness and the Pisgah West Wilderness upon publication by Interior of a notice in the Federal Register that all nonconforming uses of such lands authorized by this bill have ceased.

The bill provides for the securing, adjudication, and use of U.S. water rights for certain of the wilderness areas designated by this bill.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-387</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
