<bill session="111" type="h" number="5457" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:05Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Nursing Home Patient and Medicaid Assistance Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide supplemental payments to nursing facilities serving Medicare and Medicaid patients and to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to assure adequate Medicaid payment levels for services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Home Patient and Medicaid Assistance Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2010-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000559" joined="2010-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001173" joined="2010-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2010-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-21T21:25:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Nursing Home Patient and Medicaid Assistance Act of 2010 - Makes appropriations to the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), who, acting through the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicare Services, shall pay an amount directly to an eligible dually-certified facility to reimburse it for furnishing quality care to Medicaid-eligible individuals.

Defines "dually-certified facility" as one meeting several requirements, including participation as a nursing facility under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) and as a skilled nursing facility under SSA title XVIII (Medicare) during the entire year.

Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to prohibit a state Medicaid plan from being considered to meet the requirement for methods and procedures relating to the utilization of care and services unless, by April 1 before the beginning of any plan year (beginning with 2011), the state submits to the Secretary a plan amendment specifying the payment rates for such services, including data on how rates for payments to Medicaid managed care organizations take such payment rates into account.

Requires the Secretary to review each such plan amendment and approve or disapprove it.

Requires a state participating in the Medicaid program to submit to the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services: (1) information on the determination of payment rates for service providers; and (2) an explanation of the process used to allow providers, beneficiaries and their representatives, and other concerned state residents a reasonable opportunity to review and comment on such rates, methodologies, and justifications before the state made such rates final.</summary>
</bill>
