<bill session="119" type="s" number="909" updated="2025-10-09T17:05:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain land to La Paz County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2025-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1043" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-01T20:37:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, after receiving a request from La Paz County, Arizona, to convey approximately&#160;3,400 acres of identified land managed by the Bureau of Land Management to the county for fair market value.

Interior must exclude from the conveyance any federal land that contains significant cultural, environmental, wildlife, or recreational resources.

As a condition of the conveyance, La Paz County and any subsequent owner must

make good faith efforts to avoid disturbing tribal artifacts;minimize impacts on tribal artifacts if they are disturbed;coordinate with the Colorado River Indian Tribes Tribal Historic Preservation Office to identify artifacts of cultural and historic significance; andallow tribal representatives to rebury unearthed artifacts at, or near, where they were discovered.The federal land is withdrawn from the operation of U.S. mining and mineral leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
