<bill session="117" type="s" number="4458" updated="2023-09-05T17:28:36Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-26">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-08-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines whether an educational institution meets requirements relating to the percentage of students who receive educational assistance furnished by the Secretary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2022-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2022-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-04">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4034" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-08-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4034" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-08-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09T13:03:09-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-09T13:16:35-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12T17:43:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7704-7705" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12T17:43:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano asked unanimous consent to take from the Speaker's table and consider.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="without objection" type="vote2" datetime="2022-08-12T17:44:44-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On passage Passed without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7704-7705" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-08-12T17:44:46-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-08-23">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2022-08-26" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-174" type="public" datetime="2022-08-26">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-174.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8198" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-09T12:58:50Z" status="Public Law">Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022

This act makes adjustments to the process by which the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) evaluates programs of education for violations of the 85/15 Rule.

The rule generally prohibits the VA from approving the enrollment of a veteran in any course at an educational institution where more than 85% of the students are having all or part of their tuition or other charges paid by the institution or the VA.

The act adds an exception for tuition or charges paid under a payment plan at an educational institution with a history of offering payment plans that are completed within 180 days after the end of the applicable term, quarter, or semester.

The act also requires the VA to establish a process by which an educational institution may request a review of a determination that the institution has more than 85% of enrolled students that have all or part of their tuition or other charges paid by the institution or the VA.

The act adjusts the existing 35% exemption by exempting courses from the 85/15 Rule if the majority of courses at the institution are approved by the state approving agency, and the total number of veterans, reservists, or eligible beneficiaries who are enrolled at the institution equals 35% or less of the total student enrollment at the institution.

Additionally, the 85/15 Rule does not apply with respect to the enrollment of a veteran in a program of education with fewer than 10 students who are having all or part of their tuition or other charges paid to or for them by the educational institution or the VA.</summary>
</bill>
