<bill session="117" type="s" number="758" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combating Global Poverty Through Energy Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support financing of affordable and reliable energy projects by international financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Poverty Through Energy Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2021-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-24T16:57:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Global Poverty Through Energy Development Act

This bill supports the elimination of restrictions that limit support for certain energy projects at specified international financial institutions.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. executive directors of certain financial institutions (e.g., the International Finance Corporation, the International Monetary Fund, and the Inter-American Development Bank) to (1) oppose any restriction or prohibition on the financing of coal, oil, natural gas, or civil nuclear energy projects; and (2) seek to rescind current restrictions or prohibitions on this financing.

Further, not more than 50% of amounts made available for the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development may be used until Treasury certifies that the bank (1) has rescinded any restrictions or prohibitions on the financing of coal, oil, natural gas, or civil nuclear energy projects; and (2) has in effect a policy promoting the financing of these projects.

 Treasury must coordinate with designated agencies to identify steps the United States can take to promote international financing of these energy projects in order to help developing countries access affordable and reliable power.</summary>
</bill>
