<bill session="117" type="h" number="1930" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Advisory Committee Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Advisory Committee Act to increase the transparency of Federal advisory committees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Advisory Committee Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001108" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-04T20:02:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Advisory Committee Transparency Act

This bill revises provisions regarding federal advisory committees, including to (1) require designation of committee members as special government employees or representatives, (2) apply the Federal Advisory Committee Act (FACA) to subcommittees and subgroups, and (3) require publication of certain information about advisory committees.

The bill requires appointments to advisory committees to be made without regard to political affiliation or campaign activity, unless required by federal statute. Each agency, prior to appointing members to an advisory committee, must solicit nominations for potential committee members. The agency shall solicit nominations at least once every two years.

The bill provides statutory authority for the designation of advisory committee members as special government employees (if they are appointed to exercise their individual best judgement) or representatives (if they are appointed to represent a nongovernment entity). Agencies may not designate committee members as representatives to avoid federal ethics rules.

Each agency shall make available on its website specified information about each of the agency's advisory committees, including membership, meeting minutes, and notices of future meetings. The General Services Administration must also publish this information.

The bill revises requirements for Advisory Committee Management Officers, including to require them to be senior officials with expertise in implementing FACA.

The Government Accountability Office shall report on agency compliance with FACA.</summary>
</bill>
