<bill session="111" type="h" number="4634" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:36Z">
  <state datetime="2010-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency in Job Loss from Fishery Closures Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit the authority of the Secretary of Commerce to implement certain fishery closures unless the Secretary certifies that closure is the only option available for maintaining a fishery at a sustainable level, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency in Job Loss from Fishery Closures Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001239" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000370" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000485" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2010-02-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2010-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2010-02-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-04T18:04:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency in Job Loss from Fishery Closures Act of 2010 - Prohibits the Secretary of Commerce from implementing a closure of a fishery pursuant to the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act that would have a direct or indirect effect of at least $50,000 on each of more than 25 small businesses that do business related to the recreational, charter, or commercial fishing industries involved in the fishery being closed, unless the Secretary has certified that: (1) the closure is the only option available for maintaining the fishery at a sustainable level; (2) the stock assessment of the fishery has been updated and peer reviewed within the preceding three years; and (3) such assessment was developed using at least two models that were subjected to outside peer review. Requires the Secretary to review, in order to meet such requirements, any fishery closure for which notice was published within 12 months prior to the date of enactment of this Act, and to include in such review the effects of the closure on coastal communities.

Directs the Secretary to report to Congress on fishery closures established within five years prior to the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
