<bill session="109" type="h" number="5547" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:50Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a Gulf Coast Long-Term Recovery Office to administer amounts available to the Department for providing assistance to the residents of the Gulf Coast region for recovering from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a Gulf Coast Long-Term Recovery Office to administer amounts available to the Department for providing assistance to the residents of the Gulf Coast region for recovering from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Integration, and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Church and social problems"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-08-02T15:00:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to establish a Gulf Coast Long-Term Recovery Office to administer assistance to the residents of the Gulf Coast region for recovering from Hurricanes Katrina and Rita.

Requires the Office's Director to work with state and local governments and non-governmental organizations, including to: (1) assess social and economic consequences and coordinate federal efforts to address community recovery issues; (2) advise the Secretary on the long-term recovery implications of response activities; (3) conduct comprehensive market disruption and loss analysis and develop a market-based comprehensive long-term recovery plan for the affected areas; (4) identify federal programs and agencies to support plan implementation, ensure coordination among federal agencies, and identify gaps in available resources; (5) avoid duplication of assistance, coordinate program application processes and planning requirements, and identify and coordinate the resolution of policy and program issues; (6) determine responsibilities for recovery activities, provide a method of maintaining continuity in the delivery of federal assistance, and oversee coordination with governments and other involved parties regarding recovery and hazard mitigation efforts; and (7) encourage implementation of mitigation measures during recovery.

Terminates the Office at the Secretary's discretion.</summary>
</bill>
