<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2202</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T23:26:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-23T23:34:46Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-03-15</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-03-15T20:42:27Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-15</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S1738-1740)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-15</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S1737-1738)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-03-15</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Emergency Management</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Disaster relief and insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Homeland security</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Natural disasters</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Emergency Management</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-03-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-07-11T15:24:22Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Preparedness and Resilience Foundation Act - Establishes the Preparedness and Resilience Foundation as a nonprofit, private corporation to support and carry out activities that: (1) promote the resilience of individuals, communities, structures, and systems against natural disasters and terrorist attacks and other human caused disasters; and (2) build and sustain capabilities of the public, private, and civic sectors to work together to prepare for, prevent, protect against, respond to, recover from, and mitigate all such hazards.</p> <p>Directs the Foundation to establish an Endowment Fund for providing endowments for positions that are associated with the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) and dedicated to the Foundation's purpose. Includes among Foundation activities providing for: (1) fellowship programs among state, local, and tribal officials to work and study in association with each other and FEMA or the Department of Homeland Security (DHS); (2) international exchange programs for voluntary or reciprocal service by officials engaged in preparedness or resilience activities; and (3) programs to improve the collection and analysis of data on preparedness and resilience programs, practices, activities, and events. </p> <p>Authorizes the FEMA Administrator to: (1) accept any gift or devise of property and any voluntary service provided by the Foundation for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of FEMA; and (2) provide to the Foundation facilities, utilities, and support services as determined to be advantageous to FEMA or DHS programs. </p> <p>Establishes a committee to incorporate, provide for initial operation of, and appoint the initial Board of Directors of, the Foundation. </p> <ul> <ul> <ul> </ul> </ul> </ul>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Preparedness and Resilience Foundation Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Preparedness and Resilience Foundation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Preparedness and Resilience Foundation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the establishment of a private, nonprofit entity to assist the Government in providing disaster assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2012-03-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s2202is/xml/BILLS-112s2202is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-03-15</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S1738-1740)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
