<bill session="117" type="h" number="5185" updated="2022-12-31T09:00:09Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a credit for qualified environmental justice programs.</title>
    <title type="display">CORE Justice Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CORE Justice Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Creating Opportunities in Research for Environmental Justice Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000296"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2021-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="848" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5376" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-22T18:56:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Creating Opportunities in Research for Environmental Justice Act of 2021 or the CORE Justice Act of 2021

This bill allows certain educational institutions a tax credit for up to 30% of amounts paid that are necessary for a qualified environmental justice program. The bill defines qualified environmental justice program as a program conducted by educational institutions that is designed to address, or improve data about, qualified environmental stressors (e.g., contaminations of air, water, soil, or food) for the primary purpose of improving health and economic outcomes of individuals residing in low-income areas or areas at risk of experiencing multiple exposures to environmental stressors.

The bill requires (1) the allocation of credit amounts to educational institutions over a five-year period, and (2) public disclosure of the identity of educational institutions receiving allocations and the amount of each allocation.</summary>
</bill>
