<bill session="111" type="s" number="1276" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:37Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Private Fund Transparency Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require investment advisers to private funds, including hedge funds, private equity funds, venture capital funds, and others to register with the Securities and Exchange Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Private Fund Transparency Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6653-6654"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6654" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-21T19:48:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Private Fund Transparency Act of 2009 - Amends the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to: (1) repeal the exemption from its registration requirements for private investment advisers; and (2) continue to exempt from such requirements only foreign private advisers.

Authorizes the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to require any registered investment adviser to maintain and submit records for federal supervision of systemic risk.

Shields the SEC from any compulsion to disclose any supervisory report or information that is required to be filed with the SEC.

Repeals the general disclaimer that no provision of the Act shall be construed to require, or to authorize the SEC to require any investment adviser engaged in rendering investment supervisory services to disclose the identity, investments, or affairs of any of its clients.

Empowers the SEC to ascribe different meanings to terms (including the term "client") used in different sections of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
