<bill session="117" type="s" number="2570" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Border Health Security Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish grant programs to improve the health of residents along the United States-Mexico and United States-Canada borders and for all hazards preparedness in the border areas, including with respect to bioterrorism, infectious disease, and other emerging biothreats, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Border Health Security Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4812" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-30T13:59:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Border Health Security Act of 2021

This bill modifies the duties and activities of the United States-Mexico Border Health Commission and the Canada-United States Pan-Border Public Health Preparedness Council and makes other changes to address health issues along the U.S. border.

Specifically, the commission must cooperate with the council where appropriate, and both the commission and the&#160;council must develop strategic plans, work plans, evaluations, and reports concerning their activities.

The Department of Health and Human Services must award grants to&#160;(1) eligible entities in border areas to address recommendations of the commission and the council to improve the health of border area residents; and (2) trauma centers, public health entities, and state, local, or tribal entities for infectious disease surveillance activities in border areas. In addition, the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response may coordinate with the Department of Homeland Security in establishing a system that alerts clinicians and public health officials to emerging health threats in border areas.

The Government Accountability Office must evaluate commission and council activities every two years.</summary>
</bill>
