<bill session="117" type="s" number="5048" updated="2023-02-14T14:25:47Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Tax Parity and Relief Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Tax Parity and Relief Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat Indian tribal governments in the same manner as State governments for certain Federal tax purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2022-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-09T19:57:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native American Tax Parity and Relief Act of 2022 

This bill makes changes to the Internal Revenue Code to treat Indian tribal governments in the same manner as their state counterparts for tax purposes. Among other changes, the bill

 treats Indian tribes as states for purposes of the issuance of tax-exempt bonds, equalizes the tax treatment of charities funded by Indian tribal governments, enhances the ability of tribal governments to enforce child support orders, expands the special-needs adoption tax credit to apply to adoptions ratified by a tribal court, designates certain Indian areas as difficult development areas for purposes of the low-income housing tax credit, increases the amount of wages and benefits taken into account for purposes of determining the Indian employment tax credit, and creates an annual $175 million New Markets Tax Credit for low-income tribal communities and for projects that serve or employ Tribe members.</summary>
</bill>
