<bill session="111" type="h" number="6369" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:29Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MyCAA Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to codify the Military Spouse Career Advancement Account program (MyCAA) conducted by the Department of Defense to assist spouses of members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty to pursue educational opportunities and career training, to ensure that such educational opportunities and training are available to all military spouses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MyCAA Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-08T13:51:46Z" status="Introduced in House">MyCAA Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense, as one of the programs established by the Department of Defense (DOD) to assist spouses of members of the Armed Forces serving on active duty, to continue to carry out the current Military Spouse Career Advancement Account (MyCAA) program, under which such spouses may receive up to $6,000 in tuition assistance for education and training courses and licensing and credentialing fees.

Requires the Secretary to establish such assistance programs.

Prohibits the Secretary from restricting MyCAA program participation to spouses of members serving in particular grades.</summary>
</bill>
