<bill session="117" type="s" number="939" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">IMAGINE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage the research and use of innovative materials and associated techniques in the construction and preservation of the domestic transportation and water infrastructure system, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">IMAGINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Innovative Materials for America's Growth and Infrastructure Newly Expanded Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2197" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-19T14:26:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Innovative Materials for America's Growth and Infrastructure Newly Expanded Act of 2021 or the IMAGINE Act

This bill encourages the use of innovative construction materials and techniques to accelerate the deployment, extend the service life, improve the performance, and reduce the cost of domestic transportation and water infrastructure projects.

Among other things, the bill

 establishes an Interagency Innovative Materials Standards Task Force to assess existing standards and test methods for the use of innovative materials in infrastructure, identify key barriers in the standards area that inhibit broader market adoption, and develop new methods and protocols to better evaluate innovative materials; requires the Department of Transportation to enhance the development of innovative materials in the United States by providing awards to entities for establishing and operating new innovative material innovation hubs; directs the Federal Highway Administration to provide grants to states' departments of transportation, tribal governments, public toll authorities, and units of local government for coastal or rural infrastructure bridge projects and value engineering projects to enhance the performance of bridges through the use of innovative materials; and provides grants for the design and installation of water infrastructure projects.</summary>
</bill>
