<bill session="118" type="h" number="2710" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ocean Shipping Competition Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean Shipping Competition Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 46, United States Code, to allow the Federal Maritime Commission to provide injunctive relief without a court order, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E329-330"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-20T21:04:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Ocean Shipping Competition Enforcement Act

This bill establishes procedures for the Federal Maritime Commission (FMC) to enjoin, without obtaining a court order, the operation of any ocean shipping agreement it determines is likely to have certain anticompetitive effects.&#160;

The FMC monitors agreements by ocean common carriers and marine terminal operators and otherwise&#160;regulates the U.S. international ocean transportation system.&#160;

Under current law, the FMC must obtain a court order to enjoin the operation of an agreement it determines is likely, by a reduction in competition, to (1) produce an unreasonable reduction in transportation service, (2) cause an unreasonable increase in transportation cost, or (3) substantially lessen competition in the purchasing of certain covered services.&#160;

The bill authorizes the FMC to issue such&#160;an injunction without a court order. For such an injunction, the&#160;FMC must provide the person filing the agreement with notice and an opportunity to be heard under expedited procedures established by the FMC. The FMC may allow a third party to intervene in a proceeding relating to such an injunction.

An injunction issued under this bill shall constitute a final order of the FMC.

&#160;



&#160;

&#160;

&#160;</summary>
</bill>
