<bill session="116" type="s" number="1001" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Veterans Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Veterans Health Care Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to allow the Indian Health Service to cover the cost of a copayment of an Indian or Alaska Native veteran receiving medical care or services from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2019-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2241-2242" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-20">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 116-183.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-04T15:15:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Veterans Health Care Enhancement Act

This bill authorizes the Indian Health Service (IHS) to pay copayments owed to the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) by Indian veterans for medical services authorized under the Purchased/Referred Care program and administered at a VA facility.

The IHS, the VA, and tribal health programs, in consultation with impacted tribes, must enter into a memorandum of understanding that authorizes the IHS or a tribal health program to pay such copayments unless it would decrease the quality of, or access to, health care for individuals receiving care from the IHS or the VA.

The IHS and the VA must report on veterans who are eligible for IHS assistance and have received care from the VA.</summary>
</bill>
