<bill session="111" type="s" number="1188" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:39Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Mental Health Services Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to mental health services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Mental Health Services Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6201-6202"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6202-6204" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1011" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-08T15:59:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Community Mental Health Services Improvement Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration (SAMHSA), to award grants for demonstration projects to provide coordinated and integrated services to individuals with mental illnesses who have co-occurring primary care conditions and chronic diseases through the co-location of primary and specialty care services in community-based mental and behavioral health settings.

Requires the Secretary to make funds available for the development or expansion of programs to provide integrated treatment services for individuals with a serious mental illness and a co-occurring substance abuse disorder.

Deems certain community mental health centers to be automatically designated as having health professional shortage areas for purposes of the National Health Service Corps.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, to award matching grants to states, territories, and Indian tribes or tribal organizations for programs to address behavioral and mental health workforce needs of designated mental health professional shortage areas.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of SAMHSA, to award grants for: (1) establishing or expanding accredited behavioral and mental health education programs; and (2) providing tele-mental health services in medically-underserved areas.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) implement a plan for ensuring that various components of the National Health Information Infrastructure address the needs of mental health and substance abuse treatment providers; and (2) finance related infrastructure improvements, technical support, personnel training, and ongoing quality improvements.</summary>
</bill>
