<bill session="108" type="h" number="949" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To prohibit certain transfers or assignments of franchises, and to prohibit certain fixing or maintaining of motor fuel prices, under the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain transfers or assignments of franchises, and to prohibit certain fixing or maintaining of motor fuel prices, under the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000784"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Franchises (Retail trade)"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act to prohibit a franchisor from transferring or assigning its interest in the franchise during the term of the franchise unless the franchisor, at least 45 days before the proposed transfer or assignment, has first: (1) made a bona fide offer to the franchisee to sell, transfer, or assign to the franchisee the franchisor's interests in the leased marketing premises; or (2) offered the right of first refusal (of at least 45 days' duration) to the franchisee regarding an offer made by another to acquire the franchisor's interest in the premises.Declares null, void, and unenforceable a franchise or marketing agreement that, in the event of litigation, calls for payment by either party of the prevailing party's legal expenses.States that it shall be a violation of the Act for a refiner or distributor to fix or maintain motor fuel retail prices at a retail outlet supplied by that refiner or distributor, unless the refiner or distributor also operates such outlet.</summary>
</bill>
