<bill session="111" type="h" number="2793" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:51Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Auto Dealers' Pension Fairness Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a report to the Congress from the Presidential Task Force on the Auto Industry regarding closings of vehicle dealerships in connection with the bankruptcies of Chrysler Corporation and General Motors Corporation, and to suspend imposition of withdrawal liability to multiemployer plans in connection with the closing of such dealerships (and to suspend the requirement for payment of existing withdrawal liability in connection with such closings) until 60 days after submission of such report.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Auto Dealers' Pension Fairness Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000363"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001256" joined="2009-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2009-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001148" joined="2009-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2009-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-15T15:51:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Auto Dealers' Pension Fairness Act of 2009 - Requires the Presidential Task Force on the Auto Industry to report to Congress on the closing of vehicle dealerships in connection with the commencement of bankruptcy proceedings for Chrysler Corporation and General Motors Corporation in 2009.

Declares that during a specified period no withdrawal liability to a multiemployer pension benefit plan under the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA), in connection with bankruptcy proceedings commenced in 2009, may be imposed on any contributing sponsor by reason of the closing of a Chrysler or General Motors vehicle dealership the sponsor owned or operated.

Declares further that any payment of existing withdrawal liability imposed before such period as a result of a dealership closure shall not be payable.</summary>
</bill>
