<bill session="110" type="h" number="1996" updated="2023-01-11T19:43:18Z">
  <state datetime="2007-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify the applicability of State law to national banks and Federal savings associations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Preservation of Federalism in Banking Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preservation of Federalism in Banking Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000535"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000191" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2007-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2007-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-04-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Affiliated corporations"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank examination"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government statistics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mortgage banks"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-06-07T17:36:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Preservation of Federalism in Banking Act - Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States and the Home Owners' Loan Act to declare applicable to either a national bank or federal savings association any consumer protection in state consumer law of general application (including unfair or deceptive acts or practices, consumer fraud law and repossession, foreclosure, and collection).

Declares that when a national bank or federal savings association avails itself of state law for its benefit, all related consumer protections in such state law shall apply.

Declares applicable to a national bank or federal savings association: (1) state banking or thrift laws enacted pursuant to federal law; and (2) state laws providing greater protection in high cost mortgage loans (predatory mortgage loans).

Permits the Comptroller of the Currency to preempt state law only when a comparable federal statute or regulation pursuant to a federal statute, other than this Act, expressly governs the activity.

States that any federal law relating to visitorial powers or which otherwise limits or restricts the supervisory, examination, or regulatory authority to which a national bank or federal savings association is subject shall not be construed as restricting the authority of any chief state law enforcement officer to bring an action on behalf of state residents to enforce federal or state law, or to seek relief and recover damages for violations by a national bank or federal savings association.

Prescribes procedural guidelines requiring the Comptroller and the Director of the Office of Thrift Supervision to record and monitor consumer complaints regarding either a national bank or a federal savings association, respectively.</summary>
</bill>
