<bill session="117" type="s" number="4521" updated="2022-12-29T18:33:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">KESSLER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Keeping Everyone Safe and Securing Lives by Emergency Readiness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">KESSLER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the President to develop a strategy to ensure the health, safety, and general welfare of the civilian population of the United States in case of catastrophic incidents disabling 1 or more critical infrastructure sectors or significantly disrupting the critical functions of modern society, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2022-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4488" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8574" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4888" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-16T15:11:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Keeping Everyone Safe and Securing Lives by Emergency Readiness Act or the KESSLER Act

This bill directs the President to develop a national strategy to ensure the health and safety of the U.S. civilian population in case of catastrophic incidents.

Specifically, the President must develop and submit to Congress a strategy to

 provide for the basic needs of the civilian population that is impacted by catastrophic incidents in the United States; coordinate response efforts with state and local governments, the private sector, and nonprofit relief organizations; promote personal and local readiness and non-reliance on government relief during periods of heightened tension or after catastrophic incidents; and develop international partnerships with allied nations for the provision of relief services and goods. The President must issue a plan to implement and operationalize the strategy.

The Department of Homeland Security shall lead a national exercise to test and enhance the operationalization of the implementation plan.

The President must provide recommendations for (1) actions that should be taken to prepare the United States to implement the strategy, increase readiness, and address preparedness gaps; and (2) additional authorities that should be considered to more effectively implement the strategy.</summary>
</bill>
