<bill session="117" type="h" number="5758" updated="2022-12-30T07:34:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COMFORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COMFORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comforting Our Military Families through On-base or Remote Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize non-medical counseling services, provided by certain mental health professionals, to military families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2021-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3021" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-13T21:44:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Comforting Our Military Families through On-base or Remote Treatment Act or the COMFORT Act

This bill authorizes the Office of Military Family Readiness Policy within the Department of Defense (DOD) to coordinate programs and activities for the provision of nonmedical counseling services to military families through the DOD Military and Family Life Counseling Program. Under the bill, nonmedical counseling services means mental health care services that are nonclinical, short-term, and solution-focused to address topics related to personal growth, development, and positive functioning.

The bill authorizes mental health professionals to provide non-medical counseling services regardless of where the provider or recipient is located so long as the provision of service is within the scope of the authorized duties of the provider. For purposes of the bill, mental health professionals include licensed or certified mental health professionals or members of the uniformed services, civilian DOD employees, or DOD contractors.</summary>
</bill>
