<bill session="118" type="h" number="3437" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Colorado Outdoor Recreation and Economy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colorado Outdoor Recreation and Economy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the designation of certain wilderness areas, recreation management areas, and conservation areas in the State of Colorado, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1634" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-21T00:48:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Colorado Outdoor Recreation and Economy Act

This bill provides for the conservation of specified lands in Colorado.

Specifically, the bill designates

 specified federal lands within the White River National Forest as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System, the proposed Williams Fork Mountains Wilderness as a potential wilderness area, the Spraddle Creek Wildlife Conservation Area, the Porcupine Gulch Wildlife Conservation Area, the Williams Fork Mountains Wildlife Conservation Area, the Sheep Mountain and Liberty Bell East Special Management Areas, the Curecanti National Recreation Area, and the interpretive site located beside U.S. Route 24 as the Sandy Treat Overlook. The bill adjusts the boundary of the White River National Forest and the Rocky Mountain National Park Potential Wilderness.

The bill provides for the inclusion of additional federal lands in the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The bill provides for the cancellation of all Thompson Divide oil or gas leases.

The bill establishes the Greater Thompson Divide Fugitive Coal Mine Methane Use Pilot Program to promote the capture, beneficial use, mitigation, and sequestration of fugitive methane emissions to reduce methane emissions, improve air quality, and improve public safety, among other things.</summary>
</bill>
