<bill session="115" type="s" number="3627" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:56Z">
  <state datetime="2018-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VET Extension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional entitlement to Post-9/11 Educational Assistance to certain veterans and members of the Armed Forces who require extra time to complete remedial and deficiency courses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Extension Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education and Transfer Extension Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-03T21:19:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Education and Transfer Extension Act or the VET Extension Act

This bill makes changes to Post-9/11 educational assistance for veterans or active duty military service members. Specifically, the bill increases the number of months of educational assistance available under the Post-9/11 GI Bill by (1) 15 months, or (2) the amount of months needed to complete remedial and deficiency courses that may be needed prior to beginning a program of education.

Under the bill, individuals who do not currently have a dependent, but wish to elect to transfer educational assistance to a dependent, may do so at such a time when they do have a dependent. Additionally, the Department of Defense may not prescribe any additional limitation on the time period in which a member of the Armed Forces may make an election.</summary>
</bill>
