<bill session="108" type="s" number="1767" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:18Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Auditor Independence and Tax Shelters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent corporate auditors from providing tax shelter services to their audit clients.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Auditor Independence and Tax Shelters Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2003-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2003-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12976-12978"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12978" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Corporate accountability"/>
    <term name="Corporate governance"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Executives"/>
    <term name="Financial planning"/>
    <term name="Financial services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment advisers"/>
    <term name="Securities fraud"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-27T21:16:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Auditor Independence and Tax Shelters Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit a registered public accounting firm from providing tax shelter services to their audit clients.

Defines tax shelter services as services provided by a registered public accounting firm (or by an associated person of that firm) to an issuer, or an officer or director of an issuer, to design, organize, promote, assist, or execute any investment, entity, plan, arrangement, or transaction for which a significant purpose is the avoidance or evasion of Federal income tax by such issuer, or an officer or director of such issuer, whether acting as a direct or indirect participant, and for which such firm may receive fees in excess of $100,000 in the aggregate.

Requires an audit committee, as a prerequisite to its approval of a non-audit service, to determine whether a reasonable likelihood exists that the service would impair the independence of the registered public accounting firm by resulting in the firm's: (1) auditing its own work for the issuer; (2) performing a management function for the issuer; (3) advocating in a public forum for the issuer; or (4) promoting the stock or other financial interest of the issuer.

Prohibits the audit committee from providing advance approval of such service if it determines that such a reasonable likelihood exists.</summary>
</bill>
