<bill session="110" type="h" number="4847" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:01Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-03T12:56:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-04-03T12:56:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the United States Fire Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001167"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001232" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000461" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001058" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000794" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000172" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000226" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000549" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000550" joined="2007-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000472" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001154" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2008-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001174" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000801" joined="2008-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000793" joined="2008-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-28">
      <text>Hearing Held by Subcommittee by Technology and Innovation Prior to Introduction and Referral (October 2, 2007).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-31">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science and Technology. H. Rept. 110-559.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-03-31" calendar="Union" number="342">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 342.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02T16:52:03-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1071 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4847 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science and Technology now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the committee Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:33:31-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1071 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:40:35-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1071.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1979-1991" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:40:40-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4847 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. A specified amendment is in order. All points of order against consideration of the bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. In lieu of the amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Science and Technology now printed in the bill, it shall be in order to consider as an original bill for the purpose of amendment under the five-minute rule the amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in part A of the report of the committee Rules accompanying this resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:41:09-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1071 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:41:11-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Eni F.H. Faleomavaega to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T10:41:23-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4847.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T11:41:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Pascrell amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T11:53:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sali amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:02:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1071, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Langevin amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:12:00-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4847.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:12:17-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1989" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:12:38-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendment in the nature of a substitute as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1985-1986" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:13:01-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. McMorris Rodgers moved to recommit with instructions toScience and Technology.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1989-1991" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1989" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:13:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McMorris Rodgers motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment inserting a new paragraph stating that State of local government that provide fire service training for fire fighters, or any rescue personnel shall not be liable for any act or omission in connection with providing such service or advice that results in harm to an infant or child.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:22:30-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1990" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:46:34-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 205 - 209 (Roll no. 159).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1990-1991" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="160" datetime="2008-04-03T12:56:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 412 - 0 (Roll no. 160).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-04-03T12:56:53-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY19" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2606" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="hr" number="1071" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine terminals"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h979"/>
    <amendment number="h978"/>
    <amendment number="h977"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2008-04-07T19:08:19Z" status="Passed House amended">United States Fire Administration Reauthorization Act of 2008 - (Sec. 3) Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for the U.S. Fire Administration (USFA) for FY2009-FY2012.

(Sec. 4) Authorizes the Superintendent of the National Academy for Fire Prevention and Control to include within fire service personnel training: (1) response, tactics, and strategies for dealing with non-terrorist-caused national catastrophes and incidents that involve weapons of mass destruction; (2) applying new technology and developing strategies and tactics for fighting wildfires; (3) response, tactics, and strategies for fighting large-scale or multiple fires in a general area that cross jurisdictional boundaries, fires occurring at the wildland-urban interface, and fires involving hazardous materials; and (4) advanced emergency medical services (EMS) training.

Requires the Administrator of USFA to: (1) include in triennial reports information about changes made to the National Fire Academy curriculum; and (2) consolidate and integrate into that curriculum a course on incident command training for fire service personnel for fighting fires at U.S. ports and in marine environments, including fires on the water and aboard vessels. Provides that such course shall not relate to border and port security.

Authorizes the Administrator to contract with one or more nationally recognized organizations that have established on-site training programs that prepare fire service personnel to meet national voluntary consensus standards for fire service personnel and that facilitate delivery of education and training programs, provided that such an organization: (1) provides training that leads to certification by a program accredited by a nationally recognized accreditation organization; or (2) provides training under such a program pursuant to a cooperative agreement with a federal agency. Limits the amounts that may be expended by the Administrator to carry out this provision to 4% of the amount authorized to be appropriated in that fiscal year to facilitate the delivery of education and training programs directly to fire service personnel.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator to use specified funds during FY2009-FY2011 to update the National Fire Incident Reporting system to an Internet-based, real-time incident reporting database.

(Sec. 6) Authorizes the Administrator to assist the nation's fire services for activities and equipment to improve fire prevention and control in the wildland-urban interface. Directs the Administrator to make available to the public information regarding USFA funded activities, to advance new knowledge and best practices in firefighting through a regularly updated Internet database.

(Sec. 7) Requires the Administrator to: (1) promote adoption by fire services of voluntary national consensus standards for firefighter health and safety; and (2) develop and provide information and training to relevant federal departments on the importance of clearing biomass in wildland areas of federal lands to promote firefighter safety.

(Sec. 8) Directs the Administrator to provide liaison to assure coordination of fire service-based EMS programs. Authorizes the Administrator to conduct studies of the operations and management aspects of fire service-based EMS and coordination between EMS and fire services, including the optimum protocols for on-scene care, the allocation of resources, and the training requirements for fire service-based EMS.

(Sec. 10) Expresses support for USFA recommendations regarding the adoption of fire sprinklers in commercial buildings and educational programs to raise awareness of the importance of installing fire sprinklers in residential buildings.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-559</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
