<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1957</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T09:03:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T09:03:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-11-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2004-09-20T21:22:46Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2004-09-17T16:31:32Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg07</systemCode>
            <name>Water and Power Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Hearings by</name>
                <date>2004-05-19T21:02:22Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2004-07-07T20:33:22Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2004-06-16T21:45:53Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-11-25T17:03:52Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 108-297</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-17</actionDate>
        <actionTime>10:03:32</actionTime>
        <text>Received in the House.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent. (consideration: CR S93340-9342; text as passed Senate: CR S9340-9342)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in Senate: Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.(consideration: CR S93340-9342; text as passed Senate: CR S9340-9342)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>17000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-07-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 616.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-07-07</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-297.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-07-07</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-297.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-06-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-05-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg07</systemCode>
            <name>Water and Power Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-618.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. (text of measure as introduced: CR S15982-15983)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-25</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S15982)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000468</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Bingaman, Jeff [D-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>JESSE</firstName>
        <lastName>BINGAMAN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>FRANCIS</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000407</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Domenici, Pete V. [R-NM]</fullName>
        <firstName>PETE</firstName>
        <lastName>DOMENICI</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NM</state>
        <middleName>VICHI</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-05-17</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000352</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kyl, Jon [R-AZ]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Kyl</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <middleName>Llewellyn</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-05-19</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2004-06-22T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1957, United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/15755</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on June 16, 2004&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2004-06-22T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1957, United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/15755</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources on June 16, 2004</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Aquifers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arizona</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Boundaries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Communication in science</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Data banks</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-state relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Geographic information systems</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Governmental investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Groundwater</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hydrology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indian lands</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International cooperation in science</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Laboratories</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Latin America</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maps</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Native Americans</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Regional planning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research grants</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Texas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Treaties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water supply</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Water Resources Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-11-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-02-15T19:04:08Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act - Establishes a United States-Mexico transboundary aquifer assessment program to characterize, map, and model groundwater resources along the border. Describes as the program's objectives: (1) to develop and implement an integrated scientific approach to assess transboundary groundwater resources, including identifying fresh and saline aquifers, prioritizing the aquifers for further analysis, and creating a geographic information system database to characterize the spatial and temporal aspects of each priority aquifer; (2) to expand existing agreements between the United States Geological Survey, the Border States, the Water Resources Research Institutes and appropriate authorities in the United States and Mexico to conduct joint scientific investigations, archive and share relevant data, and carry out other activities; and (3) to produce scientific products for each priority aquifer to provide water managers and natural resource agencies with the information needed to effectively accomplish their missions.</p> <p>Designates the Hueco Bolson and Mesilla aquifers as priority transboundary aquifers.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary of the Interior to develop partnerships with, and receive input from, relevant organizations in Mexico and to coordinate program activities with appropriate water resource agencies in the Border States and any affected Indian tribes. Prohibits the Secretary from initiating any field studies before consulting and coordinating with the Border State water resource agency with jurisdiction over the aquifer.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>35</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-09-15</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed Senate amended</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-03-15T21:13:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b></b></p> <p>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the U.S. Geological Survey, to carry out a United States-Mexico transboundary aquifer assessment program to characterize, map, and model transboundary groundwater resources along the U.S.-Mexico border, in consultation and cooperation with the States of Arizona, California, New Mexico, and Texas (border States), the water resources research institutes (WRRIs) within the border States established under the Water Resources Research Act of 1984, Sandia National Laboratories, and other appropriate entities in the United States and Mexico. </p> <p>Sets forth as the objectives of the program to: (1) develop and implement an integrated scientific approach to assess transboundary groundwater resources, including by prioritizing aquifers for further analysis; (2) expand existing agreements between the U.S. Geological Survey, the border States, the WRRIs, and appropriate authorities in the United States and Mexico to conduct joint scientific investigations, archive and share relevant data, and carry out any other activities consistent with the program; and (3) produce scientific products for each priority aquifer that are capable of being broadly distributed and that provide the scientific information needed by water managers and natural resource agencies on both sides of the border to effectively accomplish their missions.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to designate priority aquifers, including: (1) the Hueco Bolson and Mesilla aquifers underlying parts of Texas, New Mexico, and Mexico; and (2) the Santa Cruz River Valley aquifers underlying Arizona and Sonora, Mexico. . Directs the Secretary to work with appropriate Federal agencies and other organizations to develop partnerships with, and receive input from, relevant organizations in Mexico to carry out the program. Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants or enter into cooperative and other agreements with the WRRIs and other border State entities to carry out the program.</p> <p>(Sec. 5) Directs the Secretary to coordinate the activities carried out under the program with: (1) the appropriate water resource agencies in the border States; (2) any affected Indian tribes; and (3) any other appropriate entities that are conducting monitoring and metering activity with respect to a priority aquifer. Prohibits the Secretary from initiating any new field studies or analyses under the program before consulting and coordinating with any border State water resource agencies with jurisdiction.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to work with appropriate border State water resource agencies, WRRIs, and other relevant entities to develop a study plan, timeline, and cost estimate for each priority aquifer to be studied. Directs that such study plan: (1) integrate existing data collection and analyses; (2) improve and strengthen existing groundwater flow models; and (3) be consistent with appropriate State guidelines and goals.</p> <p>(Sec. 6) Declares that nothing in this Act affects: (1) the jurisdiction or responsibility of a border State to manage surface or groundwater resources in the State; or (2) the water rights of any person or entity using water from an aquifer.</p> <p>(Sec. 7) Directs the Secretary, not later than five years after this Act's enactment and on completion of the program in FY 2014, to submit to the appropriate water resource agencies in the border States an interim and final report that describes activities carried out, conclusions relating to the status of aquifers, and participation of entities in Mexico.</p> <p>(Sec. 8) Authorizes appropriations for FY 2005 through 2014. Directs that 50 percent of such amounts be made available to the WRRIs to provide funding to appropriate entities in the border States and Mexico to conduct activities under the program, including the binational collection and exchange of scientific data.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to cooperate with the States on the border with Mexico and other appropriate entities in conducting a hydrogeologic characterization, mapping, and modeling program for priority transboundary aquifers, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed Senate</titleType>
        <title>United States-Mexico Transboundary Aquifer Assessment Act</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Referred in House</type>
        <date>2004-09-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in Senate</type>
        <date>2004-09-15T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2004-07-07T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-11-25T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-09-20</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
