<bill session="117" type="h" number="5229" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the President to establish the Civilian Conservation and Climate Corps as a means of providing gainful employment to unemployed and underemployed youth through the performance of useful public work, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">21st Century Civilian Conservation and Climate Corps Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Civilian Conservation and Climate Corps Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2021-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2021-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2021-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-14T19:19:58Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Civilian Conservation and Climate Corps Act

This bill temporarily authorizes and provides funding for the President to establish and operate a Civilian Conservation and Climate Corps to employ young adults (ages 16-25) in connection with public conservation and climate projects.

If available funds are insufficient to employ every eligible individual seeking employment with the corps, preference must be given, in order, to (1) unemployed veterans, (2) unemployed individuals who have exhausted their unemployment benefits, (3) individuals who are otherwise eligible for unemployment benefits, (4) members of groups determined to have suffered economic or social disadvantages to finding decent work, and (5) other unemployed individuals.

The corps must pay employees wages comparable to wages paid to public-sector employees. The corps may also provide room, board, and clothing for employees, but the cost of these accommodations must be deducted from wages.</summary>
</bill>
