<bill session="117" type="h" number="8001" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Countering Atrocities through Currency Accountability Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Countering Atrocities through Currency Accountability Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to ensure the United States currency market does not support egregious human rights violations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001309" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001104" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2022-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000469" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001082" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000576" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2022-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-06T13:55:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Countering Atrocities through Currency Accountability Act of 2022 

This bill requires financial institutions and agencies to take specified special measures regarding foreign financial activity if the Department of the Treasury concludes that the measures are necessary to address human rights violations. These measures are applied upon a finding that a jurisdiction (or a financial institution, transaction, or type of account involving a jurisdiction) is of primary humanitarian concern.

The measures include additional recordkeeping and reporting of transactions, beneficial ownership information, and information relating to payable-through accounts and correspondent accounts. If Treasury finds a payable-through or correspondent account involves foreign human rights violations, then Treasury is allowed to prohibit or impose conditions on that account.

The bill establishes additional due diligence requirements for financial institutions managing a bank account or a correspondent account of a foreign person.

Finally, Treasury must determine if the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region in China qualifies as a jurisdiction subject to the additional measures established by the bill.</summary>
</bill>
