<bill session="111" type="h" number="5778" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:55Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Renewable Fuels Marketing Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the implementation of the Renewable Fuel Standard, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Fuels Marketing Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000573"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001244" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001030" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000285" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000365" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000567" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000568" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000265" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000571" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000572" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2010-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001179" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2010-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001155" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000413" joined="2010-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2010-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-23T22:51:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Renewable Fuels Marketing Act of 2010 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue guidelines for determining whether underground storage tanks and associated dispensing equipment are compatible with any fuel or fuel additive that is authorized by the Administrator or by statute for use in a motor vehicle, nonroad vehicle, or engine.

Deems tanks and equipment that have been listed by a nationally recognized testing laboratory as compatible with such a fuel or fuel additive as of the date of enactment of this Act to be compatible under the guidelines. Declares that no person shall be liable under any federal or state law, and no provider of financial assurance may deny payment for a claim, on the basis that a tank (or associated dispensing equipment) is not compatible with such fuel or fuel additive if such tank or equipment has been determined to be compatible pursuant to the guidelines issued under this Act.

Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator to promulgate regulations that establish requirements for the labeling of associated dispensing equipment to prevent the introduction into a motor vehicle, nonroad vehicle, or engine of transportation fuel that contains a fuel or fuel additive that is authorized, after January 1, 2010, by the Administrator or by statute for use in motor vehicles, nonroad vehicles, or engines but that is not compatible with such vehicle or engine. Shields a person selling such fuel who complies with such regulations from liability for: (1) a self-service purchaser's introduction of such a fuel into a vehicle or engine that is not compatible with such fuel; or (2) the voiding of the manufacturer's warranty of such vehicle or engine from introduction of such fuel. Sets penalties for violation of such regulations.</summary>
</bill>
