<bill session="116" type="s" number="4768" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:39Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Intelligence Measures Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIM Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Office of Intelligence in the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8238" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-02T18:52:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agricultural Intelligence Measures Act or the AIM Act 

This bill establishes the Office of Intelligence in the Department of Agriculture (USDA) under the National Intelligence Program.

The office must

 leverage the capabilities of the intelligence community and the intelligence-related research of the National Laboratories to ensure that USDA is fully informed of threats by foreign actors to U.S. agriculture; focus on understanding foreign efforts to steal U.S. agriculture knowledge and technology, and develop or implement biological warfare attacks, cyber or clandestine operations, or other means of sabotaging and disrupting U.S. agriculture; prepare, conduct, and facilitate intelligence briefings for USDA; operate as the liaison between USDA and the intelligence community, with the authority to request intelligence collection and analysis on matters related to U.S. agriculture; collaborate with the intelligence community to downgrade intelligence assessments for broader dissemination within USDA; and facilitate the sharing of information on foreign activities related to agriculture with the intelligence community.</summary>
</bill>
