<bill session="112" type="h" number="6349" updated="2019-11-15T21:32:37Z">
  <state datetime="2012-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 11 of the United States Code to increase the maximum amount that may be paid to trustees for services rendered; to repeal provisions relating the trustee administration of certain employee pension plans; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2012-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2012-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-28T16:08:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Bankruptcy Administration Improvement Act of 2012 - Amends federal bankruptcy law to: (1) round to the nearest $5 any Consumer Price Index (CPI) increase in the trustee fee for services rendered in a case under chapter 7 (Liquidation); (2) increase that fee from $15 to $75; and (3) authorize the court, in determining the amount of reasonable compensation to be awarded to a trustee under chapter 7, to treat such compensation as a commission.

Prohibits the waiver of the trustee fee if an individual debtor is able to pay in installments in chapter 7 cases.

Repeals the requirement that, when a trustee is not serving a chapter 7 case involving an employee benefit plan, the debtor continue to perform the obligations required of the plan administrator if at the time of the commencement of the case the debtor (or a designee entity) served as the administrator. Repeals the duty of a trustee, in such a circumstance, to continue to perform such administrative obligations.</summary>
</bill>
