<bill session="118" type="s" number="4249" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:36Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FUEL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FUEL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Utilization for Enhanced Logistics Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to conduct a study on access to operational energy by the Armed Forces in the Indo-Pacific region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2024-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-13T14:27:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fuel Utilization for Enhanced Logistics Act or the FUEL Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to study the energy supply, logistics networks, and infrastructure that support access to operational energy by the Armed Forces in the Indo-Pacific region. Under the bill, operational energy means the energy required for training, moving, and sustaining military forces and weapons platforms for military operations (including energy used by tactical power systems and generators and weapons platforms).

Based on the findings of the study, DOD must develop a strategy to secure access to operational energy for the Armed Forces in the Indo-Pacific region.

DOD must report to Congress on the findings of the study, the strategy developed as a result of the study, and any recommendations for legislative or administrative actions to support such strategy.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
