<bill session="116" type="h" number="8404" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Housing Solar Equity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Housing Solar Equity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require sales and leases of assets of public housing projects in connection with solar energy projects to financially benefit the residents of such public housing project and the budget of the public housing agency that owns such public housing project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5455" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-12T13:40:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Housing Solar Equity Act of 2020

This bill requires public housing agencies (PHAs) to take certain actions when selling or leasing assets in connection with a solar energy project.

Specifically, a PHA must ensure that such a sale or lease financially benefits the residents of the public housing project as well as the budget of the PHA. Further, if a buyer or lessee intends to derive a product or service from the asset, the PHA must require that the product or service be offered and provided to residents of the public housing project before being offered and provided to nonresidents.

Additionally, a PHA must include certain information regarding assets it intends to sell or lease in the upcoming year in its annual plan.</summary>
</bill>
