<bill session="111" type="h" number="1920" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:35Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United Nations Durban Review Conference (Durban II) Funding Prohibition Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit United States funding for the 2009 United Nations Durban Review Conference ("Durban II Conference") or any other activity relating to the planning, preparation, or implementation of a follow-up meeting to the 2001 United Nations World Conference Against Racism, Racial Discrimination, Xenophobia and Related Intolerance ('Durban I Conference') in Durban, South Africa.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United Nations Durban Review Conference (Durban II) Funding Prohibition Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000548"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2009-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001179" joined="2009-04-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-04-20T18:51:02Z" status="Introduced in House">United Nations Durban Review Conference (Durban II) Funding Prohibition Act of 2009 - Prohibits making any funds available to support the 2009 United Nations Durban Review Conference (Durban II Conference) or any other activity relating to the planning, preparation, or implementation of a follow-up meeting to the 2001 United Nations World Conference Against Racism, Racial Discrimination, Xenophobia and Related Intolerance (Durban I Conference).

Requires the United States to withhold from its assessed contributions to the U.N. regular budget the proportional amount allocated for the Durban II Conference and any other activity relating to the planning, preparation, or implementation of a follow-up meeting to the Durban I Conference.</summary>
</bill>
