<bill session="118" type="s" number="3660" updated="2024-07-24T15:19:19Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BARCODE Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BARCODE Efficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require electronically prepared tax returns to include scannable code when submitted on paper, and to require the use of optical character recognition technology for paper documents received by the Internal Revenue Service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2024-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-07T21:34:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Barcode Automation for Revenue Collection to Organize Disbursement and Enhance Efficiency Act or the BARCODE Efficiency Act

This bill requires federal tax returns that are prepared electronically, but printed and filed on paper, to bear a code that when scanned converts the data in such return to an electronic format. It also requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to use optical character recognition technology to transcribe returns and correspondence that are not prepared electronically and are printed on paper.

The IRS may decline to use such technology if it determines that it is slower or less reliable than manual transcription.</summary>
</bill>
