<bill session="118" type="s" number="434" updated="2025-11-18T21:45:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAID OFF Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAID OFF Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Adversary Influence, Disinformation, and Obscured Foreign Financing Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended, to modify requirements under that Act relating to exemptions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S427" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1099" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-29T14:09:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preventing Adversary Influence, Disinformation, and Obscured Foreign Financing Act of 2023 or the PAID OFF Act of 2023

This bill requires certain persons to register as agents of a foreign principal if the foreign principal in question is China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Cuba, or Syria.

Currently, the Foreign Agents Registration Act exempts certain agents from the act's registration requirements, including agents (1) engaged only in private and nonpolitical activities to advance a foreign principal's bona fide trade or commerce interests, or (2) engaged in certain lobbying activities and where the agent has registered as a lobbyist. Under this bill, these exemptions shall not apply if the foreign principal is one of the countries specified in this bill.

The changes made by this bill shall expire on October 1, 2026.</summary>
</bill>
