<bill session="118" type="s" number="890" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Screening Partnership Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Screening Partnership Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the program providing for private screening companies to conduct security screening at airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-08T16:27:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Screening Partnership Reform Act

This bill revises the Screening Partnership Program of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA). Under the program, the TSA contracts with qualified private companies for security screening services at commercial airports.

Specifically, the bill requires the TSA to provide the operator of an airport with the opportunity to (1) select a preferred qualified private screening company for the screening services contract, or (2) request that the TSA select the screening company for the contract.

A private screening company may use screening supervisors who have been trained and certified at a Federal Law Enforcement Training Center to administer comparable on-site training and certification to private security screeners at an airport that is participating in the Screening Partnership Program.

The bill also removes a requirement that a qualified private screening company provide employees compensation and other benefits that are not less than the level provided to federal government personnel.</summary>
</bill>
