<bill session="119" type="h" number="1592" updated="2025-09-09T08:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SOLAR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Our Lands and Resources Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOLAR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To limit USDA funding for ground-mounted solar energy systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2025-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001189" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000490" joined="2025-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-23T14:24:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing Our Lands and Resources Act or the SOLAR Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Agriculture from providing financial assistance for certain projects that would result in the conversion of covered farmland for solar energy production.

Under the bill, covered farmland generally refers to prime farmland, unique farmland, and farmland that is of statewide or local importance. Conversion means any activity that results in the covered farmland no longer meeting certain requirements for agricultural production, activity, or use.

The bill includes an exception for certain smaller projects that&#160;result in&#160;the conversion of (1) less than 5 acres of covered farmland, or (2)&#160;less than 50 acres of covered farmland if the majority of the energy produced by the project is for on-farm use.

The bill also includes an exception for projects that have the approval or support from the local county and municipality. For these projects, the applicant must (1) develop a farmland conservation plan for the project (e.g., implementing best practices to protect future soil health and productivity), and (2) ensure that sufficient funds are provided for the decommissioning of the solar energy production system and the remediation and restoration of the farmland.</summary>
</bill>
