<bill session="118" type="h" number="4624" updated="2025-11-19T02:50:18Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Algorithmic Justice and Online Platform Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Algorithmic Justice and Online Platform Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the discriminatory use of personal information by online platforms in any algorithmic process, to require transparency in the use of algorithmic processes and content moderation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001163"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2024-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2024-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000476" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2024-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2023-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2024-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2325" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-04T17:55:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Algorithmic Justice and Online Platform Transparency Act

This bill establishes requirements for certain commercial online platforms (e.g., social media sites) that withhold or promote content through algorithms and related computational processes that use personal information.

The platforms must

 make disclosures about their collection and use of personal information and their content moderation practices; retain specified records that describe how the algorithms use personal information and assess whether the algorithms produce disparate outcomes based on race and other demographic factors in terms of access to housing, employment, financial services, and related matters; employ algorithms safely and effectively; and allow users to access and transfer their personal information. If a platform uses algorithms to publish or sell advertising, it must maintain a library of the advertisements. The Federal Trade Commission must also adopt rules concerning deceptive advertising.

A platform's chief executive officer or other senior officer must certify compliance with disclosure requirements.

Additionally, platforms may not (1) employ algorithms or other design features that result in discrimination or similar harms based on demographic or biometric factors, or (2) process information such that it impairs voting rights. Further, users of a platform may not violate civil rights laws using the platform's algorithms.

The bill prohibits waivers or other methods that limit rights under the bill; provides whistleblower protections for individuals who report violations; and authorizes enforcement by specified federal agencies, states, and private individuals.

The bill also provides funding for an interagency task force to study the discriminatory use of personal information by platforms' algorithms.</summary>
</bill>
