<bill session="117" type="h" number="3231" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the recognition of certain Alaska Native communities and the settlement of certain claims under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20T14:21:06-04:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mr. Stauber asked unanimous consent that he may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 3231, a bill originally introduced by Representative Young, for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3269" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9116" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-03T19:42:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Unrecognized Southeast Alaska Native Communities Recognition and Compensation Act

This bill allows five Alaska Native communities in Southeast Alaska to form urban corporations and receive land entitlements.

Specifically, the bill allows the Alaska Native residents of each of the Alaska Native villages of Haines, Ketchikan, Petersburg, Tenakee, and Wrangell, Alaska, to organize as Alaska Native urban corporations and to receive certain settlement land.

The bill directs the Department of the Interior to convey specified land to each urban corporation. Further, Interior must convey the subsurface estate for that land to the regional corporation for Southeast Alaska.

Interior must also convey to each urban corporation any U.S. interest in all roads, trails, log transfer facilities, leases, and appurtenances on or related to the land conveyed to the urban corporation.

The bill also allows each urban corporation to establish a settlement trust to (1) promote the health, education, and welfare of the trust beneficiaries; and (2) preserve the Alaska Native heritage and culture of their communities.</summary>
</bill>
