<bill session="111" type="h" number="128" updated="2019-11-15T21:35:16Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Respect for the Law Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to strengthen the criminal consequences for certain violations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Respect for the Law Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000021"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-29T22:54:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Respect for the Law Act of 2009 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to establish criminal penalties for an alien who is permitted to depart voluntarily and subsequently enters, attempts to enter, or is present in the United States unlawfully.

Revises criminal penalties for an alien subject to an order of removal who fails to depart or to appear for removal to include a one-year minimum prison sentence.

Revises criminal criminal penalties for an alien who reenters the United States after having been removed to include a one-year minimum prison sentence.

Revises criminal penalties for the reentry of certain aliens who were removed from the United States for specified criminal-related grounds.

Revises exclusion provisions for an alien who has been unlawfully present in the United States for: (1) more than 180 days and less than one year; and (2) at least one year.</summary>
</bill>
