<bill session="108" type="h" number="1060" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:37Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an exchange of lands with the United Water Conservation District of California to eliminate private inholdings in the Los Padres National Forest, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000021"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation engineering"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Los Padres National Forest Land Exchange Act of 2003 - Authorizes an exchange of approximately 340 acres held by the United Water Conservation District of California and approximately 420 acres of National Forest System lands. Allows the Secretary of Agriculture to reserve easements in the conveyance of National Forest System lands for access roads and trails, including perpetual unrestricted rights of pedestrian access to the Potholes trailhead of Los Padres National Forest. Requires the Secretary to provide reasonable access to privately owned inholdings in the District lands acquired under this Act. Stipulates that the District must construct a gravel parking area for the Potholes trailhead. Exempts water rights from this land exchange. Permits the District and the Secretary to equalize this exchange through a cash payment. Adds the District lands acquired under this Act to the Los Padres National Forest.</summary>
</bill>
