<bill session="116" type="s" number="4405" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Neighborhood Economic Development and Opportunity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Neighborhood Economic Development and Opportunity Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a pilot program to provide grants to nongovernmental entities, including nonprofit organizations and faith-based organizations, to provide economic support in urban areas of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T21:11:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Neighborhood Economic Development and Opportunity Act of 2020

This bill establishes, and provides emergency funding for, grants to support the revitalization of opportunity zones and areas with long-term poverty, including in Baltimore, Maryland.

The bill designates the funding as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits.

The Department of Commerce shall provide grants to qualifying nongovernmental, nonprofit, faith-based, or charitable organizations to carry out in these areas programs that help individuals acquire or improve skills. Such a program may include a development project that revitalizes physical infrastructure.

For qualifying projects in Baltimore, Maryland, Commerce may also provide grants to the city or to the state.</summary>
</bill>
