<bill session="116" type="h" number="6172" updated="2022-08-10T23:26:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-14">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to prohibit the production of certain business records, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2020-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), Oversight and Reform, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), Oversight and Reform, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), Oversight and Reform, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Intelligence (Permanent Select), Oversight and Reform, and Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10T19:39:24-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 891 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 68, H.R. 2486 and H.R. 6172. Resolution provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 68, the Senate amendment to H.R. 2486, and H.R. 6172. For S.J. Res. 68, the resolution provides for 1 hour of debate and 1 motion to commit. For the Senate amendment to H.R. 2486, the question will be divided and each portion will have 1 hour of debate. H.R. 6172 will have 1 hour ofdebate and 1 motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T14:00:45-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 891 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T15:14:39-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 891.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1622-1637" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T15:14:44-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 68, H.R. 2486 and H.R. 6172. Resolution provides for consideration of S.J. Res. 68, the Senate amendment to H.R. 2486, and H.R. 6172. For S.J. Res. 68, the resolution provides for 1 hour of debate and 1 motion to commit. For the Senate amendment to H.R. 2486, the question will be divided and each portion will have 1 hour of debate. H.R. 6172 will have 1 hour ofdebate and 1 motion to recommit with or without instructions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T15:15:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 6172.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T15:47:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House resumed with debate on H.R. 6172.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T16:22:13-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="98" datetime="2020-03-11T17:05:19-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 278 - 136 (Roll no. 98).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1622-1627" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T17:05:24-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11T17:15:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-03-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="440">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 440.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1735"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure presented in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1735"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-16">
      <text>Motion to proceed to measure considered in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1748"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-16">
      <text>Cloture motion on the motion to proceed to the measure withdrawn by unanimous consent in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1753"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-13">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2388, S2396-2400, S2409-2412, S2414" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2432-2441" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="92" datetime="2020-05-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate, under the order of 5/12/20, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 80 - 16. Record Vote Number: 92.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28T13:24:46-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Nadler moved that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and request a conference.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2340-2346" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2340-2342" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28T13:24:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the motion to disagree to the Senate amendments and request a conference on H.R. 6172.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28T15:12:49-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the House disagree to the Senate amendments, and request a conference Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 284 - 122 (Roll no. 115).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-28T15:12:50-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker appointed conferees: Nadler, Schiff, Lofgren, Jordan, and Nunes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-01">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="981" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="891" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3421" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h814"/>
    <amendment number="h813"/>
    <amendment number="s1586"/>
    <amendment number="s1584"/>
    <amendment number="s1583"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-10-28T19:33:02Z" status="Passed Senate">USA FREEDOM Reauthorization Act of 2020

This bill reauthorizes through December 1, 2023, provisions related to intelligence gathering under the Foreign Intelligence and Surveillance Act (FISA) and amends FISA-related provisions.

The Federal Bureau of Investigation may not seek certain FISA-authorized orders to obtain (1) call detail records on an ongoing basis, (2) a tangible thing where a person has a reasonable expectation of privacy and a warrant would typically be required, or (3) cellular or GPS location information.

A tangible thing obtained under&#160;FISA may be retained for no longer than five years&#160;except in certain instances, such as&#160;when&#160;a tangible thing is reasonably believed to be evidence of a crime.&#160;If the government intends to use information from a&#160;tangible thing obtained under FISA in a trial or other proceeding, it shall be treated as information obtained through electronic surveillance, unless a U.S. authority finds that notifying the person targeted would harm national security. (There are existing protections related to electronic surveillance, such as allowing the targeted person to move to suppress the disclosure of the obtained information in court.)

In applications for certain FISA-authorized orders to obtain information or conduct surveillance, the applicant must certify that the Department of Justice (DOJ) has received any information that might raise doubts about the application. The bill imposes additional requirements on FISA-authorized orders targeting (1) a U.S. person, or (2) a federal elected official or candidate.

The bill increases criminal penalties for violations related to electronic surveillance conducted under color of law or false statements made to the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Court (FISA court). A U.S. government employee, officer, or contractor who&#160;engages in deliberate&#160;misconduct before a FISA court shall be subject to adverse actions, such as removal from the individual's position.

The bill broadens the criteria for when a FISA court decision shall be declassified and requires the declassification review and release of such opinions within 180 days of an opinion being issued.

The bill broadens the FISA court's authority to appoint an amicus curiae (an outside party that assists in consideration of a case) and expands such amici's powers, such as the power to ask the court to review a decision. An amicus may also seek the court's permission to address any novel or significant privacy or civil liberties issues arising in a case, even if the court did not ask for assistance on that issue. The FISA court may employ legal advisors to assist in considering any matter.

Each agency that submits applications to the FISA court shall appoint an officer responsible for compliance with FISA requirements.

An application for a FISA court order shall include all information in the government's possession that (1) is material to a ruling on the application, including any exculpatory information; or (2) calls into question the accuracy of the application or the accuracy of an assessment in the application, or otherwise raises doubts about a finding that is a required part of the application.

An application for a FISA court order shall include (1) a description of the procedures in place to ensure the accuracy and completeness of the application, and (2) a certification by the applying officer (or designee) that the officer or designee has reviewed the application and accompanying documentation for accuracy and completeness. A judge may not enter a FISA court order unless the described accuracy and completeness procedures comply with requirements prescribed by this bill.</summary>
</bill>
