<bill session="117" type="h" number="5448" updated="2022-12-30T11:33:16Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BIDEN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Believe In Delaware Election Nobility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BIDEN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote integrity in elections for Federal office by prohibiting automatic voter registration and requiring voter identification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2021-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7270" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-04T19:11:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Believe In Delaware Election Nobility Act or the BIDEN Act

This bill prohibits states from taking certain actions related to voting in federal elections, particularly with respect to absentee voting.

Specifically, the bill prohibits states from (1) using automatic voter registration systems, (2) providing absentee ballots to individuals unless they meet specified application requirements and are unable to vote in person, (3) using drop boxes to collect completed absentee ballots unless the box is located within a building that serves as an office for an election official, (4) accepting completed absentee ballots that are received after the polls close on election day, and (5) allowing individuals to vote at a polling place during an early voting period.

Additionally, the bill places certain restrictions on the delivery of completed absentee ballots and requirements for collecting these ballots. In particular, the bill prohibits a completed absentee ballot that is delivered by an individual other than the voter from being counted unless the individual who delivers the ballot is acting within the individual's official duties as authorized by law, such as an employee of the U.S. Postal Service.

The bill also requires individuals to provide proof of identification to vote.</summary>
</bill>
