<bill session="116" type="s" number="2175" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Acting on the Annual Duplication Report Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acting on the Annual Duplication Report Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address recommendations made to Congress by the Government Accountability Office and detailed in the annual duplication report, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000603" joined="2019-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-03T18:21:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Acting on the Annual Duplication Report Act of 2019

This bill requires specified federal agencies to address recommendations made to Congress by the Government Accountability Office and detailed in the annual duplication report.

Specifically

 the Defense Security Cooperation Agency shall review options for expanding the use of administrative surcharges under the foreign military sales program; the Department of Energy shall review options for a long-range target for the optimal size and configuration of the Strategic Petroleum Reserve; the U.S. Mint may modify the composition of circulating coins in accordance with a study and analysis conducted by the Mint if such modification will reduce costs incurred by taxpayers, be seamless, and have no impact on the public and stakeholders; and the Department of the Treasury shall require that any tax return which is prepared electronically, but is printed and filed on paper, bear a code which can, when scanned, convert such return to electronic format. Regarding student loan debt, among other things, an institution of higher education may not include placing students in forbearance as a means of reducing the cohort default rate of the institution.</summary>
</bill>
