<bill session="116" type="h" number="6621" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:06Z">
  <state datetime="2020-04-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-04-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-04-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Open Technology Fund Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 to authorize the Open Technology Fund of the United States Agency for Global Media, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Open Technology Fund Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2020-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2020-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2020-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2020-04-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001209" joined="2020-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2020-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-04-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-04-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3820" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-06T17:19:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Open Technology Fund Authorization Act

This bill authorizes the existing Open Technology Fund (OTF) as an independent grantee within the U.S. Agency for Global Media (USAGM).

The OTF is an independent nonprofit organization within the purview of the USAGM that supports the development of internet freedom technologies that create ways to counter censorship efforts.

As an independent grantee authorized by this bill, the OTF shall seek to advance freedom of the press and unrestricted internet access in repressive environments through functions such as

 researching, developing, implementing, and maintaining secure communications tools and technologies that circumvent censorship techniques used to limit or block access to the internet; advancing internet freedom by supporting private and public sector efforts to provide secure and uncensored access to the internet; and developing, acquiring, and distributing internet freedom technologies and techniques to fully enable the creation and distribution of digital content between and to all users and audiences. To advance freedom of the press and unrestricted internet access, the OTF shall use methods that include

 supporting fully open-source tools, code, and components that are as secure, transparent, and accessible as possible; supporting technologies that undergo comprehensive security audits; and establishing safeguards to mitigate the use of supported technologies for illicit purposes. The Department of State must report on the effectiveness of the OTF and the extent to which U.S. interests are being served by its work, and the Government Accountability Office shall have access to all information pertaining to financial transactions as may be necessary to facilitate an audit.</summary>
</bill>
