<bill session="119" type="h" number="3645" updated="2025-10-28T20:20:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACCESS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Act of 1933 to raise the offering amount threshold for when issuers using the crowdfunding exemption are required to file financial statements reviewed by a public accountant who is independent of the issuer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACCESS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amendment for Crowdfunding Capital Enhancement and Small-business Support Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">ACCESS Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Amendment for Crowdfunding Capital Enhancement and Small-business Support Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001204"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000594" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001136" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2025-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2025-05-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 51 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-15">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 119-203.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-07-15" calendar="Union" number="166">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 166.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-03T15:31:10Z" status="Reported to House">Amendment for Crowdfunding Capital Enhancement and Small-business Support Act of 2025 or the ACCESS Act of 2025 

This bill expands the exemption from certain disclosures applicable to crowdfunding issuers with specified target offering amounts. (Crowdfunding is used to raise capital through a large number of individuals investing potentially small amounts of money.) Under current law, crowdfunding issuers that have target offering amounts of $100,000 or less are not required to make available financial statements reviewed by an independent public accountant. The bill increases that amount to $250,000 and allows the Securities and Exchange Commission to increase this amount to no more than $400,000 upon recommendation of the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and the Office of the Investor Advocate.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-203</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
