<bill session="118" type="h" number="4244" updated="2025-11-19T02:46:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SERVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Servicemember Enrollment and Readmission for Valuable Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To adjust the definition of service in the uniformed services with respect to readmission requirements for servicemembers under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000307" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000388" joined="2023-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2076" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-14T14:06:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Servicemember Enrollment and Readmission for Valuable Education Act or the SERVE Act

This bill revises the definition of service in the uniformed services as the term relates to readmission requirements for servicemembers.

Current law requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to readmit students who take a leave of absence to perform active military service at the same academic status they had attained prior to such service. This readmission requirement currently applies to servicemembers who perform service in the uniformed services for a period of more than 30 days under a call or order to active duty of more than 30 days. This bill removes the 30-day requirement, thereby allowing a student who is serving for less than 30 days to be readmitted to their IHE.</summary>
</bill>
