<bill session="116" type="h" number="5564" updated="2022-02-09T03:56:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enhancing Broadcaster DIVERSITY Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for certain requirements with respect to ownership and diversity reporting for television broadcast stations and cable operators, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Broadcaster Diversity and Inclusion by Verifying and Ensuring the Reporting required by Statute Is Transpiring and Yielding Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Broadcaster DIVERSITY Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2020-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2020-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-20T16:18:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing Broadcaster Diversity and Inclusion by Verifying and Ensuring the Reporting required by Statute Is Transpiring and Yielding Data Act or the Enhancing Broadcaster DIVERSITY Data Act

This bill requires the collection of certain broadcast and cable ownership data to inform the analysis of barriers to market entry.

Specifically, the bill directs the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to complete the rulemaking on broadcast and cable equal employment opportunity rules and policies. The bill also prohibits the FCC from making certain revisions to the reporting requirements on commercial broadcast station ownership.

In addition, the bill requires the FCC to include such ownership data in its biennial communications marketplace report and to analyze how such data relates to market entry barriers that prevent diversity in media ownership. The FCC must also create a public, searchable database of media ownership information.</summary>
</bill>
