<bill session="118" type="h" number="4675" updated="2025-01-15T18:51:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to clarify the organization and duties of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2023-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T21:32:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards Reform Act or the ACRS Reform Act

This bill modifies requirements concerning the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards. Among other duties, the committee currently advises the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) on the hazards of certain nuclear facilities and reviews safety studies and reactor facility license applications.&#160;

The bill limits the committee's review of such applications to those that present novel issues or issues of significant safety concern, based on a risk-informed determination by the NRC.

The bill also prohibits the NRC from assessing and collecting fees for costs associated with any reviews conducted by the committee.

Additionally, the bill requires the committee's chairman to be designated by a majority of the members of the NRC.

Finally, the bill prohibits the committee from forming any subcommittees.</summary>
</bill>
