<bill session="117" type="s" number="1594" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the congressional intent behind the requirements relating to immediate suspension orders and corrective action plans under the Controlled Substances Act that were added by the Ensuring Patient Access and Effective Drug Enforcement Act of 2016.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001183"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-28T15:47:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DEA Enforcement and Authority Act of 2021

This bill modifies enforcement authorities of the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA).

First, the bill modifies the required elements of an order to show cause issued by the DEA before it denies, revokes, or suspends a registration due to a violation of the Controlled Substances Act. Specifically, the bill eliminates the requirement that an order to show cause must notify the registrant of the opportunity to submit a corrective action plan.

Second, the bill modifies the standard of review for an immediate suspension order. Currently, the DEA may immediately suspend the registration of a controlled substances manufacturer, distributor, or dispenser to prevent imminent danger to the public health or safety. This bill lowers the standard for determining imminent danger to the public health or safety&#8212;from substantial likelihood of an immediate threat of harm to probable cause that harm will occur.</summary>
</bill>
