<bill session="109" type="h" number="2125" updated="2019-11-15T20:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continued Benefits for Injured Military Spouses Act</title>
    <title type="display">Continued Benefits for Injured Military Spouses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that unremarried former spouses of retired and career members of the Armed Forces shall be entitled to military health care and commissary and exchange benefits if married for at least 10 years during the member's military service and if the former spouse left the marriage due to domestic violence or unbearable conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2005-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E898"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Post exchanges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-01T21:34:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Continued Benefits for Injured Military Spouses Act - Entitles to military health care and commissary and exchange benefits the former spouse of a member of the armed forces who performed at least 20 years of service creditable for retired pay if such spouse: (1) has not remarried; (2) had been married to such member for at least 20 years on the date of divorce or annulment, of which at least 10 years were during the period when the member was performing such service; and (3) sought a divorce or annulment due in whole or part to domestic violence involving that person or a child of that person that is substantiated by counseling or medical records, or to other circumstances that constitute unbearable conditions.</summary>
</bill>
