<bill session="117" type="h" number="6856" updated="2023-09-08T13:15:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing Air Travel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Air Travel Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Securing Air Travel Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reduce the number of firearms at Transportation Security Administration passenger screening checkpoints by directing the Administrator to carry out a range of activities to inform the public about restrictions regarding the carrying of firearms in sterile areas of airports and to strengthen enforcement of such restrictions and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2022-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 21 - 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 117-641.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-14" calendar="Union" number="461">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 461.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-08T15:29:16Z" status="Reported to House">Securing Air Travel Act

This bill addresses penalties for, and other matters pertaining to, carrying firearms beyond airport security checkpoints or on aircraft.

Specifically, the bill establishes minimum civil monetary penalties for repeat or egregious violations of prohibitions against carrying unauthorized firearms at airports or on aircraft. It also makes individuals who violate the prohibitions ineligible for programs that expedite security screenings at airports.

Additionally, the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) must display signage and carry out a campaign to inform travelers of the prohibitions and of the penalties for violating them.

The bill also requires the TSA and the Government Accountability Office to report to Congress about the bill's implementation and related issues.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-641</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
