<bill session="115" type="h" number="6252" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:17Z">
  <state datetime="2018-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lead-Safe Housing for Kids Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Lead-Based Paint Poisoning Prevention Act to provide for additional procedures for families with children under the age of 6, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lead-Safe Housing for Kids Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2018-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000464" joined="2018-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2018-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2018-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2018-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2018-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2018-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2018-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2018-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1845" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-19T15:12:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Lead-Safe Housing for Kids Act of 2018

This bill amends the Lead-Based Paint Poisoning Prevention Act to direct the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to promulgate regulations that:

 require owners of certain housing to initiate a lead-based paint hazard risk assessment before a family with a child under age six occupies such housing, unless lead-based paint has already been removed; state that a visual assessment alone is not sufficient for these purposes; and require owners to control lead-based paint hazards identified in the assessment within 30 days and provide certain notices to residents of the housing. These regulations shall apply to housing receiving federal assistance that was constructed before 1978, but exclude:

 single-family housing covered by an application for mortgage insurance under the National Housing Act, or multi-family housing that is covered by such an application but does not receive any other federal housing assistance. HUD regulations shall also require emergency relocation of such families, without placement on a waitlist, penalty (including rent payments to be made for that dwelling unit), or lapse in assistance, to a unit that was constructed in 1978 or later or to another unit of covered housing that has no lead-based paint hazards.</summary>
</bill>
