<bill session="117" type="h" number="3129" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing Endless Armed Conflict and Engagement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the War Powers Resolution to require an annual report and assessment with respect to each specific statutory authorization of the use of military force, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing Endless Armed Conflict and Engagement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001115"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2021-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000614" joined="2021-10-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2205-2206"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-04T17:04:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing Endless Armed Conflict and Engagement Act

This bill establishes requirements related to an authorization for the use of military force.

Specifically, the bill provides for the termination of any specific statutory authorization (or reauthorization thereof) not later than two years after the enactment of the authorization (or reauthorization). Further, a specific statutory authorization must specify (1) each nation, organization, or force engaged in active hostilities against the United States; (2) each country in which military force is authorized; and (3) the objective for such authorization.

The Department of Defense must submit an annual report that includes (1) a list of each authorization for the use of military force, and (2) specified information related to each authorization (e.g., the number of military personnel deployed and the expected scope and duration of operations).</summary>
</bill>
