<bill session="108" type="s" number="1551" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Excellence through Choice to Elevate Learning Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide educational opportunities for disadvantaged children, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Excellence through Choice to Elevate Learning Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10683-10684"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10684-10685" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational vouchers"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School choice"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student transportation"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Waste in government spending"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-17T19:44:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Excellence through Choice to Elevate Learning Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to States for private or public school choice vouchers for children from low-income families who are enrolled in low-performing elementary or secondary public schools.

Requires each grantee State to provide scholarships (at $2,000 per year, but with continuing awards) to the parents of eligible children through a lottery system administered for all eligible schools by the State educational agency. Requires that a child eligible for such a scholarship be: (1) enrolled in an eligible public elementary or secondary school; and (2) a member a family with income not more than 200 percent of the poverty line.Allows the use of such funds for: (1) payment of tuition and fees at the school selected by the scholarship child's parents, plus reasonable transportation costs; (2) up to $500 of supplementary academic services, if the parents choose a provider (with an appropriate refund policy) which the State determines capable of rendering such services; and (3) educational programs that help the child achieve high levels of academic excellence, if the child chooses to attend a public school.Requires: (1) a grantee State to allow lawfully operating public and private elementary and secondary schools serving the area involved, including religious schools, to participate in the program; (2) participating schools or providers of supplementary academic services to comply with specified antidiscrimination requirements; and (3) national evaluation of the program by the Comptroller General.Directs specified congressional committees to identify, and report to certain congressional leaders on, wasteful Federal spending (including loopholes to revenue raising tax provisions) as a means of providing funding for this Act.</summary>
</bill>
