<bill session="117" type="h" number="3705" updated="2022-12-30T17:32:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to include a safe harbor for communication of information with respect to a vaccine authorized for emergency use under such Act that is provided or distributed to a health care provider, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to include a safe harbor for communication of information with respect to a vaccine authorized for emergency use under such Act that is provided or distributed to a health care provider, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-27T19:21:31Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prohibits using certain communications to establish that a vaccine authorized for emergency use violates specified laws relating to drug safety, such as laws concerning drug misbranding and the authorization of new drugs.

Specifically, the bill applies to certain communications about the use of such a vaccine that has been provided to certain health care entities. Such a communication must be (1) neither false nor misleading when measured objectively against the available information at the time; (2) accompanied by certain disclaimers, if required, including a statement identifying any differences between the communicated information and the vaccine's authorized labeling; and (3) based on competent and reliable scientific evidence.</summary>
</bill>
