<bill session="117" type="s" number="3253" updated="2023-07-06T14:00:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALING Mothers and Fathers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALING Mothers and Fathers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping with Equal Access to Leave and Investing in Needs for Grieving Mothers and Fathers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Family and Medical Leave Act of 1993 to provide leave for the spontaneous loss of an unborn child, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6031" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-01T14:30:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping with Equal Access to Leave and Investing in Needs for Grieving Mothers and Fathers Act or the HEALING Mothers and Fathers Act This bill revises the family and medical leave entitlement and limits funding to certain family planning programs. Specifically, the bill provides family and medical leave due to the spontaneous loss of an unborn child of an employee or spouse of the employee. It also establishes a tax credit for an individual who experiences, during the taxable year, the stillbirth of a child who would have been a qualifying child of the individual for the taxable year if the child had been born live. The bill further prohibits the Office of Population Affairs within the Department of Health and Human Services from providing federal assistance to voluntary family planning programs that (1) perform abortions, (2) provide funding to another entity that performs abortions, or (3) refer patients to abortion providers.</summary>
</bill>
