<bill session="117" type="s" number="3708" updated="2023-03-29T15:04:02Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trading System Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trading System Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide the President with authority to enter into certain plurilateral trade agreements with benefits only applying to signatories of those agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2022-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive branch relations"/>
    <term name="Free trade and trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Normal trade relations, most-favored-nation treatment"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-08T14:35:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trading System Preservation Act

This bill authorizes the President to enter into covered plurilateral trade agreements. Covered plurilateral trade agreement refers to a sector-specific agreement within the framework of the World Trade Organization (WTO) involving foreign countries or foreign territories that form a subset of the members of the WTO that does not extend benefits on a most-favored-nation basis.

Specifically, the bill requires the U.S. Trade Representative to provide a classified briefing to specified congressional committees on the feasibility and advisability of pursuing and adopting covered plurilateral trade agreements.

After the congressional briefing, the bill directs the President to initiate negotiations for a covered plurilateral trade agreement when the President determines it is in the national interest to do so.

The bill authorizes the President to enter into these agreements in specified sectors of the economy (e.g., digital services and pharmaceuticals), with such authority expiring on July 1, 2027. Further, the President may proclaim a modification or continuance of any existing duty or continuance of existing excise or duty-free treatment to carry out an agreement.</summary>
</bill>
