<bill session="108" type="s" number="2691" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:27Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-11">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Long Island Sound Stewardship Initiative.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2004-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2004-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2004-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-11">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11327" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-10-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16T14:03:08-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4876" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Connecticut"/>
    <term name="Conservation easements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental justice"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landowners"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Long Island Sound"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Open space lands"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Shore protection"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4064"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-11-23T16:08:43Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Long Island Sound Stewardship Act of 2004 - (Sec. 4) Establishes the Long Island Sound Stewardship Initiative Region in Connecticut and New York.

(Sec. 5) Establishes the Long Island Sound Stewardship Advisory Committee to: (1) evaluate applications from government or nonprofit organizations qualified to hold conservation easements for funds to purchase land or development rights for designated stewardship sites; (2) evaluate applications to develop and implement management plans to address threats; (3) evaluate applications to act on opportunities to protect and enhance stewardship sites; (4) recommend that the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency award grants to qualified applicants; (5) recommend guidelines for evaluating information to identify stewardship sites; (6) publish a list of sites that further the purposes of this Act; (7) raise awareness of the values of and threats to these sites; and (8) leverage additional resources for improved stewardship of the Region.

(Sec. 8) Requires the Committee to identify 20 initial Long Island Sound stewardship sites that are natural resource-based recreation areas or exemplary natural areas with ecological value, and that best promote the purposes of this Act. States that such initial sites are exempt from the site identification process established by this Act.

Requires the Committee to use due diligence to recommend an equal distribution of funds between States for the initial sites.

Authorizes owners of sites to submit applications to the Committee to have sites identified as stewardship sites. Sets forth a site identification process and related selection criteria for natural resource-based recreation areas and natural areas with ecological value.

Directs the Committee to publish notice of the list of sites identified pursuant to the site identification process with prior notice to site owners.

Authorizes the Committee to deviate from the site identification process in certain circumstances.

Requires the Committee to use an adaptive management framework to identify the best policy initiatives and actions and to use that framework to update the list of recommended stewardship sites.

(Sec. 9) Requires the Committee to submit annual reports to the Administrator. Requires the Administrator to: (1) review the recommendations contained in such reports and take action on those recommendations (unless the Administrator finds that action is not warranted by the facts) within 90 days; and (2) develop and publish a report within one year of enactment of this Act that provides an assessment of current resources and threats to Long Island Sound and information on various aspects of the Initiative.

(Sec. 10) Protects the existing legal rights of private property owners. States that nothing in this Act requires private property owners located within the Region to participate in the Initiative.

(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations. Requires the Administrator to use appropriated funds for land acquisition, development and implementation of site management plans, site enhancements, and administrative expenses of the Committee. Limits the Federal share of costs associated with activities carried out using assistance or grants under this Act to 75 percent of the total.

(Sec. 12) Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize appropriations for the Office of Management Conference of the Long Island Sound Study and implementation of the Long Island Sound Comprehensive Conservation and Management Plan through FY 2009.

(Sec. 13) Provides for the Committee's termination on December 31, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
