<bill session="117" type="h" number="1189" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Deepwater Port Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Deepwater Port Act of 1974 to permit the construction of deepwater ports in Federal water adjacent to certain coastal States that do not have an active Coastal Zone Management Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deepwater Port Parity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-29T17:30:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Deepwater Port Parity Act

This bill authorizes the Maritime Administration (MARAD) to allow the construction of a deepwater port in federal waters off the state to which the port is to be directly connected by pipeline if the state developed an approved coastal zone management program and withdrew the program prior to January 1, 2012. Currently, a deepwater port may only be licensed by MARAD if the state developed, or is making reasonable progress toward developing, such a program. Alaska is the only state that withdrew its program before 2012. A deepwater port is any man-made structure other than a vessel that is located beyond state seaward boundaries and that is used or intended for use as a port or terminal for the transportation, storage, or further handling of oil or natural gas.</summary>
</bill>
