<bill session="116" type="s" number="4845" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:22Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agricultural Emissions Data Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Emissions Data Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct surveys to collect data regarding the prevention, reduction, and mitigation of greenhouse gas emissions, soil carbon sequestration, and forest wood and tree carbon sequestration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000307"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-16T19:06:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Agricultural Emissions Data Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to conduct surveys and data analysis to collect agricultural subsector-specific information and data regarding (1) the prevention, reduction, and mitigation of greenhouse gas emissions, including livestock emissions reductions; (2) soil carbon sequestration; and (3) forest wood and tree carbon sequestration.

Additionally, the establishment of federal agricultural baselines for the prevention, reduction, and mitigation of greenhouse gas emissions, soil carbon sequestration, and forest wood and tree carbon sequestration must be determined by modeling based on the information and data collected by USDA.

USDA must submit to the Environmental Protection Agency and other appropriate federal agencies, and make publicly available, the results of the surveys.</summary>
</bill>
