<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2999</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:32Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:32Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-02-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-02-04T21:46:40Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>To provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public lands under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>4589</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-06-22</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S493-494)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>U000038</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Udall, Mark [D-CO]</fullName>
        <firstName>MARK</firstName>
        <lastName>UDALL</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CO</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crimes against animals and natural resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Agriculture</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forests, forestry, trees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land use and conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-02-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-04-13T15:36:16Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966, and other federal law to provide that: (1) any person who knowingly violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of such an Act or any regulation issued under such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of Bureau of Land Management (BLM) lands, National Park System lands, National Wildlife Refuge lands, and National Forest lands shall be guilty of a Class A misdemeanor, subject to fine and/or imprisonment as provided under federal criminal law; and (2) any person who otherwise violates or fails to comply with any of the provisions of such an Act or any regulation issued under such an Act concerning the management, use, and protection of such lands shall be guilty of a Class B misdemeanor, subject to fine and/or imprisonment as provided under federal criminal law. Permits requiring persons adjudged guilty of a: (1) Class B misdemeanor on BLM or National Park System lands to pay all costs of the proceedings; and (2) a Class A or Class B misdemeanor on National Wildlife Refuge or National Forest lands to pay all costs of the proceedings. </p> <p> <p>Amends the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, the National Park Service Organic Act, and other federal law to set a minimum fine of $500 for certain fire usage violations on BLM, National Park System, and National Forest lands.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>A bill to provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public lands under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public lands under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide consistent enforcement authority to the Bureau of Land Management, the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, and the Forest Service to respond to violations of regulations regarding the management, use, and protection of public lands under the jurisdiction of these agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-02-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s2999is/xml/BILLS-111s2999is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-02-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
