<bill session="116" type="s" number="1152" updated="2022-11-01T19:47:17Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of Federal land in Arlington, Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain parcels of Federal land in Arlington, Virginia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001236"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2019-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2019-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-308.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-12-20T16:07:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill transfers administrative jurisdiction from the Department of the Interior to the Department of the Army over the 16.09-acre parcel of federal land in Arlington, Virginia, adjacent to and comprising Memorial Avenue from the western side of the Route 110 overpass, west to and including the hemicycle used by the Women in Military Service for America Memorial. Such land shall be administered as part of Arlington National Cemetery.

The bill also transfers administrative jurisdiction from Army to Interior over the 1.04-acre parcel of federal land in Arlington adjacent to the Chaffee parking lot, comprising one structure, and bounded on the northeast by Sherman Drive. Such land shall be included within the boundary of Arlington House and the Robert E. Lee Memorial, and administered by Interior as part of such memorial.

The land transfers of this bill&#160;shall be made without reimbursement nor consideration.

The use of a bicycle trail or recreational access in the transferred lands may continue after&#160;transfer.</summary>
</bill>
