<bill session="118" type="h" number="6419" updated="2025-10-08T00:28:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ending Subsidies for Pro-Terrorist Activity on Campus Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ending Subsidies for Pro-Terrorist Activity on Campus Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require institutions of higher education to include reporting regarding campus anti-Semitism in the annual security report required under the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act, to ensure that institutions of higher education do not support terrorist activity of foreign terrorist organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2023-11-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3184" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-21T17:20:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Ending Subsidies for Pro-Terrorist Activity on Campus Act

This bill requires certain actions related to preventing terrorism and antisemitism on campus.

Specifically, the bill requires each institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs to include in its annual security report (1) a statement of current campus policies regarding antisemitism; and (2) a statement of current campus policies regarding procedures to prevent and respond to speech, fighting words, or true threats by students, employees, or other individuals related to foreign terrorist organizations.

Additionally, each IHE that receives federal funds must (1) carry out procedures to identify applicants for faculty and staff positions or applicants for student enrollment who have engaged in certain terrorist-related activity; and (2) ensure that federal funds are not used for any activity that urges support for, endorses, espouses, encourages, organizes for, or promotes a foreign terrorist organization or its terrorist activities.

The bill prohibits a student that has been convicted of a criminal offense involving terrorist activity from receiving federal student aid.

The bill requires IHEs that participate in the Student and Exchange Visitor Program to report antisemitic and terrorist-related activity committed by foreign students to the Department of Homeland Security and the Department of State.

Each IHE receiving federal financial assistance must report information to the Department of Education (ED) on its efforts to prevent and respond to discrimination that is based on an individual's Jewish lineage or ethnic characteristics. ED must annually submit a report to Congress containing this information.</summary>
</bill>
