<bill session="118" type="s" number="2943" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Addressing Digestive Distress in Stomachs of Our Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Addressing Digestive Distress in Stomachs of Our Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to require schools to provide fluid milk substitutes upon request of a student or the parent or guardian of such student, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-09-27" withdrawn="2023-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1539" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1619" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-10T11:08:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Addressing Digestive Distress in Stomachs of Our Youth Act or the ADD SOY Act

This bill requires schools to substitute a nondairy beverage for fluid milk in the National School Lunch Program upon the request of a student or their parent or guardian. Under current law, schools participating in the program may provide a substitute at the request of a medical authority or the student's parent or guardian.

The bill also removes current requirements that (1) the substitute request be based on an identified medical or other special dietary need that restricts the student's diet, and (2) the school food authority pay for any additional expenses resulting from providing the substitute that exceed the covered reimbursement amounts.</summary>
</bill>
