<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2285" updated="2022-02-03T05:38:07Z">
  <amends type="s" number="1072" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-02-12">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-02-10"/>
  <description>To provide a complete substitute.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-02-12" how="Voice Vote" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 2285 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Point of order fell when the motion to waive the Budget Act was agreed to in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to amendment SA 2285 and S. 1072 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 72 - 24. Record Vote Number: 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to amendment SA 2285 and S. 1072 made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Point of order under the Budget Act raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 2285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Cloture on amendment SA 2285 invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 11. Record Vote Number: 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1195, S1242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-11">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S964" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Cloture motion on SA 2285 presented in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Amendment SA 2285 proposed by Senator Inhofe. (consideration: CR S769) To provide a complete substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to amendment SA 2285 and S. 1072 agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 72 - 24. Record Vote Number: 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 2285 agreed to in Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Cloture on amendment SA 2285 invoked in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 86 - 11. Record Vote Number: 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2285 proposed by Senator Inhofe.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S769" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-10">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
