<amendment session="109" chamber="s" number="4986" updated="2022-02-25T17:32:11Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4954" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-09-14">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000243"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-09-13"/>
  <description>To require that as part of the annual performance plan required in the budget submission of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection under section 1115 of title 31, United States Code, the Commissioner of Customs establish performance indicators relating to the seizure of methamphetamine and methamphetamine precursor chemicals in order to evaluate the performance goals of the Bureau with respect to the interdiction of illegal drugs entering the United States, and for other purposes.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-09-14" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 4986 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9585" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Amendment SA 4986 proposed by Senator Collins for Senator Baucus. (consideration: CR S9585) To require that as part of the annual performance plan required in the budget submission of the Bureau of Customs and Border Protection under section 1115 of title 31, United States Code, the Commissioner of Customs establish performance indicators relating to the seizure of methamphetamine and methamphetamine precursor chemicals in order to evaluate the performance goals of the Bureau with respect to the interdiction of illegal drugs entering the United States, and for other purposes.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 4986 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9585" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4986 proposed by Senator Collins for Senator Baucus.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9585" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
