<bill session="108" type="h" number="831" updated="2023-01-15T22:03:58Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for and approve the settlement of certain land claims of the Bay Mills Indian Community.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for and approve the settlement of certain land claims of the Bay Mills Indian Community.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2003-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E254"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-24">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of the Interior to take specified land into trust for the benefit of the Bay Mills Indian Community of Michigan (the Community), with such land becoming part of the reservation of the Community. States that the Secretary's action shall be considered part of the settlement and extinguishment of the Charlotte Beach land claims of the Community, in accordance with the agreement reached between the Community and the Governor of Michigan on August 23, 2002. Classifies the land taken into trust as land obtained in a settlement of a land claim under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act.Approves the Charlotte Beach land claim settlement on behalf of the United States, except for one specified sentence, which this Act hereby deletes. Declares that the provisions contained in such settlement shall not be considered precedent for any future agreement between any tribe and State.</summary>
</bill>
