<bill session="116" type="s" number="1128" updated="2022-11-01T19:32:18Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emission fees, provide tax credits to workers, deliver additional benefits to retired and disabled Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sales and excise taxes"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-25T16:43:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Opportunity Carbon Fee Act of 2019

This bill imposes fees on carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gas emissions, establishes a tax credit for workers, provides payments to retired and disabled individuals, and provides cost mitigation grants to states.

Specifically, the bill imposes fees on (1) fossil fuel products producing carbon dioxide emissions, including coal, petroleum products, and natural gas; (2) fluorinated greenhouse gases; (3) facilities that emit greenhouse gases; and (4) associated emissions (attributable to venting, flaring, and leakage across the supply chain).

The bill directs the Department of the Treasury to

 establish, implement, and report on a program to identify all major source categories of associated emissions and collect data on associated emissions from the coal, petroleum products, and natural gas supply chains; make specified adjustments to the new fees for importers and exporters of energy-intensive manufactured goods; make a specified payment each calendar year to certain Social Security beneficiaries and other retired and disabled individuals; make cost mitigation grants to states for assisting low-income and rural households in reducing energy expenses, providing job training and worker transition assistance, or assisting in dealing with climate change or the transition to a low-carbon economy; and establish a website to make regular disclosures concerning revenue, tax savings, and benefits attributable to this bill. The bill also allows a new carbon fee offset tax credit for the lesser of 6.2% of earned income or $900.</summary>
</bill>
