<bill session="118" type="s" number="3595" updated="2025-11-19T03:35:10Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to award grants to States to establish or improve, and carry out, Seal of Biliteracy programs to recognize high-level student proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in both English and a second language, and early language programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2024-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2024-01-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2024-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7007" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-08T18:50:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Biliteracy Education Seal and Teaching Act or the BEST Act

This bill directs the Department of Education to award renewable two-year grants to states to establish or improve, and carry out, Seal of Biliteracy programs and early language programs&#160;to recognize student proficiency in both English and a second language. Student proficiency shall be demonstrated through proficiency in speaking and writing in both languages and may also be demonstrated through reading and listening in both languages.&#160; &#160;

Further, these programs must allow speakers of any official Native American language to use equivalent proficiency in speaking, reading, and writing in such language in lieu of proficiency in English.</summary>
</bill>
