<bill session="117" type="h" number="1499" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain Federal land in Arizona to La Paz County, Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2021-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001183" joined="2021-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="528" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-22T18:21:02Z" status="Introduced in House">La Paz County Solar Energy and Job Creation Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of the Interior, after receiving a request from La Paz County, Arizona, to convey approximately 4,800 acres of identified land managed by the Bureau of Land Management to the county.

Interior shall exclude from the conveyance any federal land that contains significant cultural, environmental, wildlife, or recreational resources.

As a condition of the conveyance, La Paz County and any subsequent owner shall

 make good faith efforts to avoid disturbing tribal artifacts; minimize impacts on tribal artifacts if they are disturbed; coordinate with the Colorado River Indian Tribes Tribal Historic Preservation Office to identify artifacts of cultural and historic significance; and allow tribal representatives to rebury unearthed artifacts at, or near, where they were discovered. The federal land is withdrawn from the operation of U.S. mining and mineral leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
