<bill session="118" type="h" number="3309" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Standard FEES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard FEES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Fees to Expedite Evaluation and Streamlining Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Middle Class Tax Relief and Job Creation Act of 2012 to establish a uniform fee schedule applicable to the processing of forms for the consideration of applications for the placement of communications facilities on certain buildings and other property owned by the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000609"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000590" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000579" joined="2023-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 50 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-245, Part I.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-17T22:19:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Standard Fees to Expedite Evaluation and Streamlining Act or the Standard FEES Act

This bill requires the General Services Administration (GSA) to establish, and federal agencies to adopt, a common schedule of fees for processing certain applications to use buildings or property owned or managed by the federal government for locating or modifying transmitting devices, support structures, or other communications facilities.

The fees must be competitively neutral and based on direct and actual costs. GSA may provide exceptions to the fees if the exceptions (1) are competitively neutral with respect to the categories of individuals or entities that are granted exceptions, and (2) serve a public benefit and the interest of expanding broadband deployment. The bill limits an agency's use of the fees to amounts made available in advance through appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-245</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
