<bill session="117" type="h" number="7164" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CFO Vision Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CFO Vision Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the governmentwide financial management plan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-02T17:04:46Z" status="Introduced in House">CFO Vision Act of 2022

This bill establishes or modifies provisions to provide for standardized government-wide financial management requirements.

Each agency Chief Financial Officer must oversee and provide leadership in the areas of budget formulation and execution, planning and performance, risk management, internal controls, financial systems, accounting, and other areas as the Office of Management and Budget may designate.

The bill requires the government-wide financial management plan to include actions for improving financial management systems, strengthening the federal financial management workforce, and linking performance and cost information to budget decision-making.

The bill requires (1) the development of financial management performance-based metrics, and (2) an assessment of performance by such metrics to be included in the government-wide and agency-level financial management plans and status reports.</summary>
</bill>
