<bill session="118" type="s" number="1547" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to implement policies to end preventable maternal, newborn, and child deaths globally.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1606-1607" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-20T13:38:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2023

This bill requires or authorizes certain actions for the purpose of ending preventable child and maternal deaths by 2030.

The bill requires the President to establish and implement a comprehensive five-year strategy focused on ending preventable child and maternal deaths by 2030. Requirements for the strategy include identifying priority countries in which the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID) will implement international maternal and child health and nutrition programs. The bill authorizes the President to provide assistance to implement this strategy.

The bill also requires the President to designate a USAID employee to serve as the child and maternal survival coordinator. The duties of the coordinator shall include primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of such international maternal and child health and nutrition program resources and activities as USAID determines to be appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
