<bill session="117" type="h" number="21" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-05T12:17:14-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-01-05T12:17:14-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Authorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Authorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Authorization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FedRAMP Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the innovation, security, and availability of cloud computing products and services used in the Federal Government by establishing the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program within the General Services Administration and by establishing a risk management, authorization, and continuous monitoring process to enable the Federal Government to leverage cloud computing products and services using a risk-based approach consistent with the Federal Information Security Modernization Act of 2014 and cloud-based operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001108" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001071" joined="2021-01-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05T12:05:23-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Maloney, Carolyn B. moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05T12:05:38-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H58-62" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05T12:05:39-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-01-05T12:17:14-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H58-60" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05T12:17:16-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3099" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-09T20:56:05Z" status="Passed House">Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program Authorization Act of 2021 or the FedRAMP Authorization Act

This bill provides statutory authority for the Federal Risk and Authorization Management Program (FedRAMP) within the General Services Administration (GSA).

The GSA must establish a government-wide program that provides the authoritative standardized approach to security assessment and authorization for cloud computing products and services that process unclassified information used by agencies. Agencies must ensure that their cloud computing services meet GSA requirements.

The bill establishes the Joint Authorization Board to conduct security assessments of cloud computing services and issue provisional authorizations to operate to cloud service providers that meet FedRAMP security guidelines.

The GSA shall (1) publish a report that includes an assessment of the cost incurred by agencies and cloud service providers related to the issuance of FedRAMP authorizations and provisional authorizations, (2) determine the requirements for certification of independent assessment organizations, and (3) establish the Federal Secure Cloud Advisory Committee.</summary>
</bill>
