<bill session="111" type="h" number="5559" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:54Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Flood Insurance Fairness Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise the National Flood Insurance Program to more fairly treat homeowners who purchase insurance under the program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Insurance Fairness Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000627"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2010-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001178" joined="2010-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-08T15:12:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Flood Insurance Fairness Act of 2010 - Amends the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 to delay, for certain areas not previously designated as having special flood hazards, the effective date for the mandatory purchase of flood insurance until the expiration of the five-year period beginning upon the date that revisions to certain flood insurance maps become available.

Prohibits this Act from being construed to authorize or require any payment or refund for flood insurance coverage purchases that covered any period during which such coverage is not required for the insured property.

Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to prescribe a five-year phase-in schedule for flood insurance rates for areas newly mapped as having special flood hazards.

Requires the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to reimburse property owners for costs incurred in requests to remove property from base flood elevations.

Instructs the FEMA Administrator to submit to Congress a community outreach plan updating floodplain areas and flood-risk zones.

Instructs the FEMA Administrator to notify the appropriate Members of Congress of actions taken regarding any modernization of a floodplain area or flood-risk zone in their respective states or districts.</summary>
</bill>
