<bill session="110" type="h" number="5620" updated="2021-06-07T20:01:49Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fresh Produce Safety Act</title>
    <title type="display">Fresh Produce Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a program to assure the safety of fresh produce intended for human consumption, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2008-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2008-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Horticulture and Organic Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2077" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-14T19:46:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Fresh Produce Safety Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to establish standards for good manufacturing practices for the minimal processing of produce, including standards related to sanitation and water.

Requires the Secretary to provide for unannounced inspections of processing facilities to determine if produce processed in the facilities is in compliance with the requirements of this Act.

Directs the Secretary to establish general standards for good agricultural practices for the production of raw agricultural commodities, including requirements related to manure, animals, water, and environmental conditions.

Gives officers and employees duly designated by the Secretary the authority to inspect appropriate facilities to determine compliance with the standards for good agricultural practices.

Directs the Commissioner of Food and Drugs to establish and maintain an active surveillance system to assess the frequency and sources of human illness in the United States associated with the consumption of fresh produce.

Directs the Commissioner and the Secretary of Agriculture to design and implement a national public education program on food safety relating to produce.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct research to assist in the implementation of this Act and the requirements of the FFDCA that relate to produce.

Requires the Secretary to establish procedures for equivalency with foreign countries that intend to export raw agricultural commodities and minimally processed produce to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
