<bill session="117" type="h" number="2956" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Limos Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish safety standards for certain limousines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Limos Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safety, Accountability, and Federal Enforcement of Limos Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2021-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2016" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1529" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-01T18:35:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Safety, Accountability, and Federal Enforcement of Limos Act of 2021 or the SAFE Limos Act

This bill sets out requirements to improve the safety of limousines.

Within two years of the bill's enactment, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must apply to newly manufactured limousines specified motor vehicle safety standards related to the installation of seat belts and other occupant crash protections. In addition, DOT must report on the feasibility, benefits, and costs of retrofitting limousines to meet those standards.

DOT must also develop additional motor vehicle safety standards to improve limousine safety. This includes standards related to (1) side impact protection, roof crush resistance, and other aspects of crashworthiness; (2) evacuation in the event the exit in the passenger compartment is blocked; and (3) the use of event data recorders.

Additionally, the bill requires that individuals who remodel new limousines submit to DOT and annually update a plan for mitigating limousine safety risks. The plan must include, among other topics, verification that the remodeled limousines meet applicable safety standards. Further, individuals who modify used vehicles into limousines must certify that the modified vehicles meet such standards.

The bill also requires limousine operators to disclose the date of, results of, and any corrective action needed to pass the most recent vehicle inspection. The Federal Trade Commissions shall enforce the disclosure requirements.</summary>
</bill>
