<bill session="111" type="h" number="485" updated="2019-11-15T21:51:26Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Security through Termination Of Proliferation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Security through Termination Of Proliferation Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen existing legislation sanctioning persons aiding and facilitating nonproliferation activities by the Governments of Iran, North Korea, and Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, the Judiciary, Oversight and Government Reform, and Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-13">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Taxation of foreign income"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-02-03T17:13:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Security through Termination Of Proliferation Act of 2009 or the STOP Act of 2009 - States that specified U.S. sanctions with respect to Iran, North Korea, or Syria shall remain in effect until the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that such country has verifiably dismantled its weapons of mass destruction programs.

Amends the Iran, North Korea, and Syria Nonproliferation Act to include within the scope of such Act (including identification/reporting and sanction provisions) persons involved in the transshipment (as defined by this Act) of certain goods, services, or technology.

Establishes restrictions on nuclear cooperation with a country that is assisting the nuclear program of, or transferring advanced conventional weapons or missiles to, Iran, North Korea, or Syria.

Provides for exclusion from the United States (with a discretionary national security waiver by the President) of an alien who is a senior government official of a foreign government or a corporate principal or significant shareholder of a foreign person identified as involved in proliferation activities respecting Iran, North Korea, or Syria.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) deny a foreign tax credit to a taxpayer engaged in business activity with Iran that is prohibited by U.S. law; and (2) set forth income tax provisions respecting a foreign corporation engaged in business activity with Iran that is prohibited by U.S. law.

Establishes the Compensation for Former United States Hostages in Iran Fund.</summary>
</bill>
