<bill session="118" type="s" number="94" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Investing in State Energy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Investing in State Energy Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain information and financial assistance under the State energy program and the Weatherization Assistance Program to be distributed without undue delay to support State and local high-impact energy efficiency and renewable energy initiatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-23T16:12:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Investing in State Energy Act of 2023

This bill revises requirements concerning the distribution of funds under the Weatherization Assistance Program (WAP) and the State Energy Program (SEP) to state agencies and local partners that implement energy initiatives. Under WAP, the Department of Energy (DOE) reduces energy costs for low-income households by increasing the energy efficiency of their homes. Under SEP, DOE supports state energy conservation plans and energy security.

This bill requires DOE, upon receiving state or area plans under WAP or SEP, to distribute funds to the recipients of the funding as quickly as practicable.

Within 60 days of Congress making the funds available for WAP and SEP, DOE must (1) provide application guidance for financial assistance, and (2) publish the allocation of financial assistance to be provided to states under the programs.</summary>
</bill>
