<bill session="109" type="s" number="235" updated="2020-01-29T20:28:03Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada National Forest Land Disposal Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Nevada National Forest Land Disposal Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to sell certain parcels of Federal land in Carson City and Douglas County, Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2005-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 109-104.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="816" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-22T19:31:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Nevada National Forest Land Disposal Act of 2005 - Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to sell any right, title, or interest of the United States in and to certain parcels of National Forest System lands in Carson City and Douglas County, Nevada. Declares that the Secretary and the relevant unit of local government shall jointly decide whether land is to be offered for sale under this Act. Sets forth percentages of the gross proceeds from sales under this Act that shall be earmarked for: (1) the State of Nevada general education program; (2) the Carson Water Subconservancy District in Nevada; (3) the fund established in the Sisk Act, to be used for land sales costs and for the development and maintenance of parks, trails, and natural areas in specified Nevada counties; and (4) the Minden Interagency Dispatch Center in Minden, Nevada. Declares that the lands authorized to be sold under this Act shall not be subject to specified Federal law pertaining to property management.</summary>
</bill>
