<bill session="118" type="s" number="5258" updated="2025-08-15T14:43:33Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Archie Cavanaugh Migratory Bird Treaty Amendment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Archie Cavanaugh Migratory Bird Treaty Amendment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Migratory Bird Treaty Act to clarify the treatment of authentic Alaska Native articles of handicraft containing nonedible migratory bird parts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-15T14:43:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Archie Cavanaugh Migratory Bird Treaty Amendment Act

This bill states that nothing in the Migratory Bird Treaty Act of 1918 (MBTA) prohibits possessing, selling, bartering, purchasing, shipping, or transporting any authentic Alaska Native handicraft, clothing, or art on the basis that it contains a nonedible migratory bird part, so long as the bird was not taken in a wasteful or illegal manner. (The MBTA implements four international treaties that the United States entered into with Canada, Mexico, Japan, and Russia. The MBTA prohibits the taking of protected migratory bird species without prior authorization.)

The bill directs the Department of&#160;State to work with the Department of the Interior to enter into appropriate bilateral procedures with countries that are parties to the treaties under the MBTA&#160;to clarify the treatment of Alaska Native handicraft containing nonedible migratory bird parts from the species of migratory birds listed in those treaties. Further, Interior must modify any regulations implementing the MBTA to implement this bill.</summary>
</bill>
