<bill session="111" type="h" number="3558" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Fair Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To allow incumbent contractors to be eligible to re-compete for Government contracts as small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Fair Competition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000557"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Contracting and Technology .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Small Business</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM23" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="Contracting and Infrastructure" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-10-05T19:56:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Fair Competition Act - Allows an incumbent contractor to recompete for a proposed contract in the case of a government solicitation for bids or proposals for goods or services that are substantially the same as under a current contract, provided the contractor currently performing the contract represents in good faith that it is a small business.

Permits such representation to be made if the incumbent contractor: (1) meets the definition of a small business concern applicable to the solicitation and has not been determined by the Small Business Administration (SBA) to be other than a small business; or (2) was a small business when the current contract was awarded, is no longer a small business at the time of the solicitation, and will revert to being a small business if not awarded the proposed contract.

Allows the government to qualify a contract being awarded to the incumbent contractor as a small business set-aside for the duration of the contract.

Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be revised to implement this Act.</summary>
</bill>
