<bill session="111" type="h" number="1374" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:43Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elder Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="display">Elder Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prevent the abuse and exploitation of older individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001058"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-18T19:33:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Elder Abuse Prevention Act - Requires a state that is receiving funds for certain law enforcement assistance programs under the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to adopt laws and policies that prohibit parole for: (1) any individual who is convicted of a criminal sexual offense against a victim who is elderly; or (2) a sexually violent predator. Grants states three years to implement such laws and policies (with one additional two-year extension for states making good faith efforts at implementation). Renders any state that does not implement such laws and policies within the required period ineligible for 10% of funding for its law enforcement assistance programs.

Requests the U.S. Sentencing Commission to promptly review its guidelines for sexual offenses committed against the elderly and to consider new guidelines for enhanced sentencing for such crimes.</summary>
</bill>
