<bill session="109" type="h" number="5932" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:34Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farm Risk Management Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to authorize agricultural producers to establish and contribute to tax-exempt farm risk management accounts in lieu of obtaining federally subsidized crop insurance or noninsured crop assistance, to provide for contributions to such accounts by the Secretary of Agriculture, to specify the situations in which amounts may be paid to producers from such accounts, and to limit the total amount of such distributions to a producer during a taxable year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Risk Management Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000268"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001244" joined="2006-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000868" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000187" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2006-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Crop insurance"/>
    <term name="Farm income"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax penalties"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-05T18:07:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Farm Risk Management Act of 2006 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) establish tax-exempt farm risk management accounts to allow taxpayers engaged in the business of farming or ranching to use distributions from such accounts to offset operational losses in lieu of receiving, after a specified transitional period, federal subsidies to purchase crop insurance; (2) allow a tax deduction for cash contributions to such accounts; (3) specify minimum levels of contributions to, and maximum levels of distributions from, such accounts; (4) require the Secretary of Agriculture to make matching contributions to such accounts; and (5) set forth tax rules relating to account distributions, excess contributions, and prohibited transactions.</summary>
</bill>
