<bill session="118" type="h" number="3718" updated="2025-11-19T04:16:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Processing Claims Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Processing Claims Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to take certain actions to improve the processing by the Department of Veterans Affairs of claims for disability compensation for post-traumatic stress disorder, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2023-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001091" joined="2023-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2023-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000194" joined="2023-10-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2024-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1635" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-05T11:14:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Veterans Affairs Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Processing Claims Improvement Act of 2023

This bill requires the Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) within the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to update an ongoing, national training program for claims processors who review compensation claims for service-connected post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Such claims processors will be required to participate in the training at least once a year starting in their second year of being a VA claims processor.

The training program must be standardized at regional offices of the VBA and include instruction on stressor development and verification.

The VBA must establish a formal process to annually analyze training needs based on identified processing error trends. Additionally, the VBA must establish a formal process to conduct annual studies to help guide the national training program for claims processors.

Finally, the VBA must evaluate the guidance relating to PTSD to determine if updates are warranted to provide claims processors with better resources regarding best practices for claims processing, including specific guidance regarding development of claims involving compensation for service-connected PTSD.</summary>
</bill>
