<bill session="117" type="h" number="9190" updated="2023-07-27T14:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PAYSTUB Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAYSTUB Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Accountability for Yearly Submission of The United States&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Budget Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 31, United States Code, to limit the use of Federal funds for the salaries or expenses of political employees if the President's annual budget submission to Congress is late, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001103"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2022-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2022-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-10-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9191" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-27T13:53:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Presidential Accountability for Yearly Submission of The United States' Budget Act or the PAYSTUB Act

This bill restricts the use of federal funds for the salaries or expenses of political employees if the President's budget is not submitted to Congress by the first Monday in February as required by law.

Specifically, if the President's budget is not submitted to Congress on or before the first Monday in February of a year, federal funds may not be used for the salary or expenses of any political employee during the period beginning on the first Tuesday of February of that year and ending on the date the budget is submitted.

On the earliest possible date after the President's budget is submitted, political employees whose salaries or expenses were not paid during a period in which the President's budget had not yet been submitted must be paid for that period.</summary>
</bill>
