<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1837</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T08:48:04Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T08:48:04Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2003-11-06</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2003-11-07T01:03:24Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-06</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-06</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S14179)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2003-11-06</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000386</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Grassley, Chuck [R-IA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Charles</firstName>
        <lastName>Grassley</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>IA</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Bank fraud</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime prevention</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>EBB Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Financial institutions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Forfeiture</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licenses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Money laundering</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Organized crime</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2003-11-06</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-03-01T23:23:14Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2003 - Amends the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations Act (RICO) to expand its scope to cover acts or threats involving burglary, embezzlement, and fraud in the purchase of securities.</p> <p>Modifies provisions regarding: (1) the laundering of monetary instruments to include violations of the Social Security Act relating to obtaining funds through misuse of a social security number, to grant authority to the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Commissioner of Social Security over offenses within their jurisdictions, and to cover certain informal transfers of the proceeds of specified unlawful activity; and (2) engaging in monetary transactions in property derived from specified unlawful activity to grant authority to the Secretary over offenses within his jurisdiction.</p> <p>Changes the name of a money transmitting business the operation of which is prohibited from an &quot;unlicensed&quot; to an &quot;illegal&quot; money transmitting business. Specifies that such a business shall be illegal if it fails to to comply with money transmitting business registration requirements (current law), whether or not the defendant knew that the operation was required to comply with such requirements. Authorizes the Attorney General, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Secretary of Homeland Security to investigate violations regarding such businesses.</p> <p>Amends the Federal criminal code to provide for civil forfeiture of the assets of individuals or entities engaging in planning or perpetrating any act of international terrorism against any international organization or foreign government.</p> <p>Reauthorizes the Money Laundering and Financial Crimes Strategy Act of 1998.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2003</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to combat money laundering and terrorist financing and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2003</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2003-11-06T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2003-11-06</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
