<bill session="115" type="h" number="599" updated="2023-01-11T13:34:20Z">
  <state datetime="2017-01-23T17:25:51-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2017-01-23T17:25:51-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to consolidate the reporting obligations of the Federal Communications Commission in order to improve congressional oversight and reduce reporting burdens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2017-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000791" joined="2017-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T17:15:32-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Lance moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T17:15:44-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H586-588" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T17:15:45-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 599.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2017-01-23T17:25:51-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H586-587" label="text of measure as passed"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2017-01-23T17:25:53-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-01-24">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="4986" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="174" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2017-02-15T21:07:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Communications Commission Consolidated Reporting Act of 2017

This bill amends the Communications Act of 1934 to replace various reporting requirements with a communications marketplace report that the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) must publish on its website and submit to Congress every two years.

The report must describe the FCC's actions in the marketplace and its agenda for the next two years. The FCC must: (1) compile a list of geographic areas that are not served by any provider of advanced telecommunications capability; and (2) consider market entry barriers for entrepreneurs and small businesses in accordance with national policy favoring diversity of media voices, competition, technological advancement, and promotion of the public interest, convenience, and necessity.

The FCC's competition assessments must include the aggregate average total amount paid by cable systems for retransmission consent.

The Telecommunications Act of 1996 is amended to require the FCC to determine from the communications marketplace report every two years (currently, in an inquiry initiated each year) whether it must act immediately to accelerate deployment of advanced telecommunications capabilities, particularly in elementary and secondary schools, by removing barriers to infrastructure investment and promoting competition.</summary>
</bill>
