<bill session="119" type="h" number="1720" updated="2025-09-02T19:13:07Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hospice Recertification Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospice Recertification Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend certain telehealth flexibilities with respect to hospice care under the Medicare program, and to establish a modifier for recertifications of hospice care eligibility conducted through telehealth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000134" joined="2025-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-18T21:19:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Hospice Recertification Flexibility Act

This bill extends until December 31, 2027, the ability of physicians and nurse practitioners to fulfill certain requirements for hospice care recertification under Medicare via telehealth.

Specifically, physicians and nurse practitioners may continue to fulfill the requirement of a face-to-face encounter with the hospice patient via telehealth. Such telehealth encounters must be identified with a specialized claims modifier for purposes of billing.

The bill's authorization does not apply (1) in areas in which there has been a moratorium for at least six months on the enrollment of new hospice programs under Medicare, Medicaid, or the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP) due to fraud, waste, or abuse; (2) to providers who are subject to enhanced oversight under Medicare, Medicaid, or CHIP; and (3) to practitioners who are not enrolled as Medicare providers and who have private contracts with Medicare patients that do not meet applicable opt-out requirements.</summary>
</bill>
