<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3966</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:16Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:16Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-11-18</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-11-18T21:21:29Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>GEDI Act</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>5354</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-11-15</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-11-18</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-11-18</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001181</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Shaheen, Jeanne [D-NH]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeanne</firstName>
        <lastName>Shaheen</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NH</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Collins, Susan M. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Susan</firstName>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-11-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Digestive and metabolic diseases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health information and medical records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health programs administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests and diagnostic methods</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sex and reproductive health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women's health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-11-18</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-01-25T21:23:46Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010 or the GEDI Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to develop a multisite gestational diabetes research project within the diabetes program of the CDC to expand and enhance surveillance data and public health research on gestational diabetes.&nbsp; Requires such research project to address: (1) procedures to establish accurate and efficient systems for the collection of gestational diabetes data; (2) the progress of collaborative activities with the National Vital Statistics System, the National Center for Health Statistics, and state health departments to improve surveillance of gestational diabetes; (3) postpartum methods of tracking women with gestational diabetes after delivery and targeted interventions to&nbsp;lower the incidence of type 2 diabetes in such women; (4) variations in the distribution of diagnosed and undiagnosed gestational diabetes; and (5) factors and culturally sensitive interventions that influence risks and reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and related complications during childbirth. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary to expand and intensify public health research on gestational diabetes, including; (1) developing and testing novel approaches for improving postpartum testing or screening and for preventing type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) conducting research to&nbsp;further understanding of the&nbsp;factors and health systems that influence the risk&nbsp;of gestational diabetes and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the CDC, to: (1) award grants for demonstration projects that implement evidence-based interventions to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes, the recurrence of such disease in subsequent pregnancies, and the development of type 2 diabetes in women with a history of gestational diabetes; and (2) work with state and Indian tribal-based diabetes prevention and control programs assisted by the CDC to encourage postpartum follow-up after gestational diabetes to reduce the incidence of gestational diabetes and its recurrence, the development of type 2 diabetes in at-risk women, and&nbsp;related complications.</p> ]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title III of the Public Health Service Act to provide for increased gestational diabetes research and to lower the rate of gestational diabetes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Gestational Diabetes Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>GEDI Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-11-18T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3966is/xml/BILLS-111s3966is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-11-18</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
