<bill session="116" type="s" number="2787" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Opportunity Zone Reporting and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunity Zone Reporting and Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require reporting for qualified opportunity funds, to make modifications to opportunity zones, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2019-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5042" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation facilities"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-12-04T15:12:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Opportunity Zone Reporting and Reform Act

This bill establishes annual reporting requirements for qualified opportunity funds and requires certain identifying information on persons investing in such funds. It also provides for penalties for failing to file reports or filing reports with incorrect information, and requires public online disclosure of information in the reports.

The bill expands prohibitions of investments in certain luxury assets, including private planes, sports stadiums, self-storage facilities, and luxury rental properties. It also terminates designations of contiguous communities that are not low-income as opportunity zones.

The Internal Revenue Service must provide a publicly available list of investment vehicles that are certified as qualified opportunity funds.

The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on the effectiveness of the Opportunity Zone program in the fifth and tenth year after the enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
