<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1486" updated="2022-02-03T05:57:34Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3409" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-09-21T11:03:49-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000376"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <description>Amendment requires the Secretary of Transportation to submit a report to Congress estimating the number of jobs, the fatalities and injuries, and the cost to the economy caused by the "2017 and Later Model Year Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards" rule and also requires that the Secretary shall not consult with the EPA or the California Air Resources Board to complete the report.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 4 printed in House Report 112-680 to require the Secretary of Transportation to submit a report to Congress estimating the number of jobs, the fatalities and injuries, and the cost to the economy caused by the "2017 and Later Model Year Light-Duty Vehicle Greenhouse Gas Emissions and Corporate Average Fuel Economy Standards" rule. Would require that the Secretary shall not consult with the EPA or the California Air Resources Board to complete the report.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-09-21T11:03:49-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="594">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kelly amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 242 - 168 (Roll no. 594).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6249" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T18:49:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Kelly.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6214-6216" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6214" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21T11:03:49-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Kelly amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 242 - 168 (Roll no. 594).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6249" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21T11:03:49-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-21T11:03:49-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20T18:49:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. Kelly.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6214-6216" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6214" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
