<bill session="116" type="s" number="1459" updated="2022-03-02T16:13:00Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to control the export to the People's Republic of China of certain technology and intellectual property important to the national interest of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2019-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3532" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-14T18:13:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">China Technology Transfer Control Act of 2019

This bill controls exports of certain national interest technology and intellectual property to China.

Specifically, covered technology or intellectual property includes items that (1) would contribute significantly to the Chinese military to the detriment of U.S. national security, (2) are necessary to protect the U.S. economy from the drain of scarce materials by demand from China, (3) are included in a designated list of product components compiled by the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), or (4) are used by China to violate human rights or religious liberties.

The bill requires the President to control exports to China of any covered technology or intellectual property. Additionally, the President must sanction (1) any foreign person who sells to, or purchases from, China any covered item; and (2) any Chinese person who knowingly uses a covered item provided to them in violation of U.S. export control law.

In addition to a specified list of industries subject to the bill, the USTR must identify products manufactured or produced in, or exported from, China that either receive certain support from China or are used by China to violate human rights or religious liberties.</summary>
</bill>
