<bill session="119" type="s" number="982" updated="2025-09-08T19:27:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to disclose campus policies relating to responding to certain incidents of civil disturbance, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">No Tax Dollars for College Encampments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Tax Dollars for College Encampments Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-08T19:26:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">No Tax Dollars for College Encampments Act of 2025

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student aid programs to report incidents of civil disturbance.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires each&#160;IHE to include in its annual security report its current campus policies for responding to incidents of civil disturbance occurring on campus, including with respect to coordination of such response with state, local, and campus law enforcement. The bill defines the term incident of civil disturbance to mean a civil unrest activity (e.g., a demonstration, riot, or strike) that disrupts the community in which it is taking place and requires intervention to maintain public safety and prevent the disruption of learning.

Additionally, the bill requires accrediting agencies to monitor an IHE's compliance with these reporting requirements. (Under current law, an IHE must be accredited by an accrediting agency to participate in federal student aid programs.)</summary>
</bill>
