<bill session="118" type="s" number="3123" updated="2025-11-19T04:39:42Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing Access to Our Public Waters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Access to Our Public Waters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Modernizing Access to Our Public Waters Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Modernizing Access to Our Public Waters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the standardization, consolidation, and publication of data relating to public outdoor recreational use of Federal waterways among Federal land and water management agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2023-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="595">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 595.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7145" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7145-7146" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T17:27:18-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6127" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-26T13:06:04Z" status="Passed Senate">Modernizing Access to Our Public Waters Act

This bill directs the Forest Service and the Department of the Interior to standardize and publish data on public access to&#160;federal waterways for recreational use.

Specifically, the Forest Service and Interior must jointly develop and adopt interagency standards for the collection and dissemination of geospatial data relating to federal fishing restrictions and public recreational use of federal waterways. The standards must ensure compatibility and interoperability among applicable federal databases with respect to the collection and dissemination of such data.

Within five years of the bill's enactment, the Forest Service and Interior&#160;must also digitize and make publicly available online, as applicable, certain geographic information system data about (1) federal waterway restrictions, (2) federal waterway access and navigation information, and (3) federal fishing restrictions. Data on waterway restrictions, waterway access, and navigation must be updated at least annually, and data on fishing restrictions must be updated in real time as changes take effect.

Finally, the&#160;Forest Service and Interior&#160;must develop a process to allow members of the public to submit questions or comments about waterway restrictions,&#160;waterway access, and navigation.</summary>
</bill>
