<bill session="116" type="h" number="6256" updated="2022-02-08T23:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Five-Stars for Safe Cars Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration to update the motor vehicle information required to be submitted to the Administration to assist a consumer in buying a passenger motor vehicle.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Five-Stars for Safe Cars Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2020-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-08T18:28:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Five-Stars for Safe Cars Act

This bill addresses consumer information related to passenger motor vehicles.

Among other requirements, the Department of Transportation must

 publish a report on efforts over the next five-year period to improve passenger motor vehicle information, including damage susceptibility; finalize its New Car Assessment Program which provides comparative information on the safety of new vehicles to assist consumers with vehicle purchasing decisions and encourages motor vehicle manufacturers to make vehicle safety improvements; update and create crash avoidance tests and ratings such as forward automatic emergency braking (i.e., forward collision warning, crash imminent braking, and dynamic brake support); establish tests and ratings for pedestrian, bicyclist, and other vulnerable road users crashworthiness, including the potential risks of injuries to the head, pelvis, upper and lower leg, and crash avoidance; create a combined overall five-star vehicle rating and separate five-star ratings for crashworthiness for adults, crashworthiness for elderly occupants and children, crash avoidance, and pedestrian and bicycling crashworthiness and crash avoidance; complete research into the development of tests for safety features, including automatic collision notification, lane keeping assistance, traffic jam assist, and passive drunk driving prevention systems; and update passenger motor vehicle information to expand consumer access to vehicles with improved safety.</summary>
</bill>
