<bill session="118" type="h" number="5570" updated="2024-11-25T22:42:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish and implement a multi-year Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Strategy to reduce the negative environmental and social impacts of illicit gold mining in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000400" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2023-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-19">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="797" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-25T22:41:00Z" status="Introduced in House">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act

This bill requires the Department of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to combat illicit gold mining in the Western Hemisphere, with a focus on artisanal and small-scale mining (ASM), a form of mining typified by labor-intensive techniques, dangerous working conditions, and limited regulation.

The required strategy shall include policies, programs, and initiatives to (1) interrupt the linkages between ASM and illicit actors such as drug traffickers and foreign terrorist organizations; (2) deter ASM in protected indigenous lands and environmentally protected areas; (3) build the capacity of foreign civilian law enforcement to counter linkages between illicit gold mining and money laundering, forced labor, sex work, child labor, and hazardous material trafficking; and (4) support efforts by foreign governments to increase regulation of the ASM sector.

This bill also requires the U.S. Agency for International Development to coordinate with democratically elected governments in the region to establish a public-private partnership to improve transparency and traceability in the international gold trade.</summary>
</bill>
