<bill session="118" type="s" number="2063" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BOONDOGGLE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Banning Overspending On Non-Defense Objectives at Gratuitous Gatherings and Learning Events Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BOONDOGGLE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the payment of a travel or transportation allowance for a member of the uniformed services to travel to obtain professional development training only if such training relates to the military occupational specialty of the member and not to the sex, sexual orientation, race, or religion of the member.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-16T17:06:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Banning Overspending On Non-Defense Objectives at Gratuitous Gatherings and Learning Events Act or the BOONDOGGLE Act

This bill limits the authorization of travel or transportation allowances for members of the uniformed services in connection with professional development training. Specifically, the bill provides that such allowances may only be provided if the training (1) relates to the military occupational specialty of the member; and (2) does not include activities or events related to the sexual orientation of the member or that promote the sex, race, or religion of the member as superior or inferior to another sex, race, or religion.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
