<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="344" updated="2022-02-03T04:58:36Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2861" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-07-25T16:02:22-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-07-25"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following: \   SEC. __. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used for voluntary separation incentive payments as provided for in subchapter II of chapter 35 of title 5, United States Code, unless the Administrator has first certified to Congress that such payments would not result in the loss of skills related to the safety of the Space Shuttle or the International Space Station or to the conduct of independent safety oversight in the National Aeronautics and Space Administration.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to provide that none of the funds in the bill may be used for voluntary separation incentive payments unless the Administrator certifies to Congress that such payments would not result in the loss of skills related to the safety of the Space Shuttle or the International Space Station or to the conduct of independent safety oversight in NASA.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2003-07-25T16:02:22-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A019) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T15:58:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A019) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7699-7700" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7699" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T15:58:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A019) offered by Ms. Jackson-Lee (TX).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7699-7700" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7699" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T16:02:22-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Jackson-Lee (TX) amendment (A019) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25T16:02:22-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
