<bill session="109" type="h" number="233" updated="2023-01-31T21:43:00Z">
  <state datetime="2006-10-17">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Northern California Coastal Wild Heritage Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Northern California Coastal Wild Heritage Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Northern California Coastal Wild Heritage Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Northern California Coastal Wild Heritage Wilderness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate certain National Forest System lands in the Mendocino and Six Rivers National Forests and certain Bureau of Land Management lands in Humboldt, Lake, Mendocino, and Napa Counties in the State of California as wilderness, to designate the Elkhorn Ridge Potential Wilderness Area, to designate certain segments of the Black Butte River in Mendocino County, California as a wild or scenic river, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:43:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden (OR) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:44:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5630-5633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:44:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 233.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-24T15:54:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5630-5632" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:54:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-24T15:54:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5630-5632" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="533">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 533.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2006-09-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10537" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-10-05">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-10-17" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="109-362" type="public" datetime="2006-10-17">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-362.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="128" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Beaches"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural property"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-08T22:07:36Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The expanded summary of the House passed version is repeated here.) 

Northern California Coastal Wild Heritage Wilderness Act - Designates specified areas in Mendocino and Six Rivers National Forests and in Humboldt, Lake, Mendocino, and Napa Counties in the State of California as wilderness areas and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Requires that such lands be administered by the Secretary of the Interior or the Secretary of Agriculture, whoever has current administrative jurisdiction. Withdraws such federal lands designated as wilderness by this Act from all forms of: (1) entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, and (3) disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials.

Releases from further wilderness study those portions of: (1) the King Range Wilderness Study Area, Chemise Mountain Instant Study Area, Red Mountain Wilderness Study Area, and Cedar Roughs Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness; and (2) the Rocky Creek/Cache Creek Wilderness Study Area in Lake County, California, not designated as wilderness.

Designates certain public land in the State administered by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) generally known as the South Fork Eel River Wilderness Area and Elkhorn Ridge Potential Wilderness as a potential wilderness area. Requires that the Secretary of the Interior manage such lands as wilderness and carry out ecological restoration activities.

Designates specified segments of the Black Butte River in the State as a wild and scenic river. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to submit a fire management plan and a report on the cultural and historic resources of Black Butte River.

Includes land identified as the King Range National Conservation Area Additions in the King Range Wilderness Area.

Establishes the Cow Mountain Recreation Area in Lake and Mendocino Counties, California. Allows the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands or interests in lands in the Recreation Area from willing persons only. Requires lands or interests in lands within or adjacent to the boundaries of the Recreation Area that are acquired by BLM, and title or possession of which is vested in the United States, to be managed by such Secretary as part of the Recreation Area.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior, in order to continue traditional commercial surf fishing, to permit the right of entry for authorized vehicle access onto the wave slope area at that area known as Gold Bluffs Beach, Prairie Creek Redwoods State Park, and that part of the beach north and south Redwood Creek in Redwood National and State Parks.</summary>
</bill>
