<bill session="111" type="h" number="4026" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:19Z">
  <state datetime="2009-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preventing All Your Bucks from Aiding non-Citizens is Key Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the withholding of United States assistance to a foreign country in an amount equal to 110 percent of the total amount of costs incurred by United States hospitals and other medical facilities for the long-term care of aliens unlawfully present in the United States from that country during the preceding fiscal year, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PAYBACK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preventing All Your Bucks from Aiding non-Citizens is Key Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Foreign Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-04">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-19T16:49:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Preventing All Your Bucks from Aiding non-Citizens is Key Act or PAYBACK Act - Withholds from assistance to a foreign country 110% of the costs incurred by U.S. hospitals and other medical facilities for the long-term care of aliens unlawfully present in the United States from such country until the President certifies to Congress that such costs are fully paid.

Authorizes: (1) a national security waiver of such requirement; and (2) withheld funds to be used for border protection and prevention of illegal immigration.</summary>
</bill>
