<bill session="119" type="h" number="726" updated="2025-11-19T23:02:22Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Amendments Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2010 to make improvements to that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000634"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000018" joined="2025-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="240" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T16:34:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Amendments Act of 2025

This bill revises the water rights settlement agreement entered into by the Crow Tribe of Montana and Montana.

The Crow Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2010 ratified, authorized, and confirmed the water rights compact between the tribe and Montana. Among other provisions, this settlement act authorized the Bureau of Reclamation to plan, design and construct the following two major projects on the Crow Reservation: (1) the rehabilitation and improvement of the Crow Irrigation Project (CIP); and (2) the planning, design, and construction of the MR&amp;I System (the municipal, rural, and industrial water system of the Crow Reservation).

Among other provisions, the bill revises the settlement act to

replace references to the MR&amp;I System with MR&amp;I Projects;&#160;establish a nontrust, interest-bearing account&#160;(to be known as the Crow&#160;CIP Implementation Account) to allow Reclamation to continue to work on the rehabilitation of the CIP;&#160;create a new MR&amp;I Projects Account, through which the tribe must use funds for activities related to water production, treatment, or delivery infrastructure; andextend by five years (to 2030) the period during which the tribe has the exclusive right to construct hydropower facilities on the Yellowtail&#160;Afterbay Dam in Montana.</summary>
</bill>
