<bill session="109" type="hr" number="1001" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:11Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for earmarking reform in the House of Representatives.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for earmarking reform in the House of Representatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000274"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2006-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="1000" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="6201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="House Rules"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative amendments"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax expenditures"/>
    <term name="Tax preferences"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-03T22:24:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives to consider a bill, amendment, or conference report unless: (1) the committee report on the bill includes a list of earmarks in it or in the report (and the names of the requesting Members); (2) the sponsor of the amendment submits for publication in the Congressional Record a list of earmarks in such amendment (and the names of the requesting Members) two legislative days before its consideration; or (3) the accompanying joint explanatory statement on the conference report includes a list of earmarks in it or in such report (and the names of the requesting Members) that were not committed to the conference committee by either chamber, not in the committee report, not published pursuant to this Act, and not in a Senate committee report on a companion measure.

Makes it out of order in the House to consider a rule or order that waives the requirements of this Act with respect to consideration of conference reports.

Provides that, if the Committee on Rules reports a resolution making in order a bill for initial House consideration and providing for consideration, adoption, or passage of text not otherwise subject to this Act, the Committee shall include a list of earmarks in the measure (and the names of the requesting Members).

Defines earmark to include tariff relief and targeted tax benefits.</summary>
</bill>
