<bill session="108" type="s" number="212" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:15Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-07">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">High Plains Aquifer Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, and Modeling Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to cooperate with the High Plains Aquifer States in conducting a Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, and Modeling Program for the High Plains Aquifer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to cooperate with the High Plains States in conducting a hydrogeologic characterization, mapping, modeling and monitoring program for the High Plains Aquifer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">High Plains Aquifer Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, and Modeling Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">High Plains Aquifer Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, Modeling and Monitoring Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High Plains Aquifer Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, Modeling and Monitoring Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2003-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2003-01-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1487-1488"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1488-1489" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 108-21. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="36">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 36.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-04-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4911-4913" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4911-4913" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08T10:33:02-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Aquifers"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Plains"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on March 19, 2003. The summary of that version is repeated here.)High Plains Aquifer Hydrogeologic Characterization, Mapping, and Modeling Act - (Sec. 3) Directs the Secretary of the Interior, through the United States Geological Survey and in cooperation with the High Plains Aquifer States (Colorado, Kansas, Nebraska, New Mexico, Oklahoma, South Dakota, Texas, and Wyoming), to establish and carry out the High Plains Aquifer Comprehensive Hydrogeologic Program to characterize, map, and model the High Plains Aquifer.Lists as Program objectives to: (1) provide for the hydrogeologic characterization, mapping, and modeling of the Aquifer through a cooperative partnership effort between the U.S. Geological Survey and the High Plains Aquifer States; (2) coordinate Federal, State, and local data, maps, and models into an integrated physical characterization of the Aquifer; (3) support State and local activities with scientific and technical specialists; and (4) undertake activities and provide technical capabilities not available at State and local levels, as may be requested by a participating State's Governor.Directs the Secretary to establish a Review Panel to: (1) evaluate the proposals submitted for funding under this Act; and (2) review and coordinate Program priorities. Requires the Panel to consult with the Association of American State Geologists and the Western States Water Council.Requires that 50 percent of the funds appropriated to carry out the Program be allocated equally by the Secretary for the participation of State and local agencies and institutions of higher education within each of the participating States. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants from such funds based on proposals that have been recommended by a Governor and reviewed by the Panel. Requires proposals for multistate activities to be recommended by the Governors of all the affected States.(Sec. 4) Requires the Secretary to: (1) include reports on the Program in the annual budget documents for the Interior Department (the initial report to contain a Program plan developed with the concurrence of the Review Panel); and (2) submit an interim and final status report to the Governors of the High Plains Aquifer States.(Sec. 5) Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-21</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
