<bill session="117" type="s" number="3310" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BEACON Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEACON Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Equitable Access to Contribute to Our National Security Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a plan to establish the Minority Institute for Defense Research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2021-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4350" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5107" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-07T14:58:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building Equitable Access to Contribute to Our National Security Act of 2021 or the BEACON Act of 2021

This bill implements plans and requirements related to minority institutions of higher education and their contributions to national security efforts.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to submit a plan for the establishment of the Minority Institute for Defense Research. The plan must be made available on a publicly accessible DOD website.

DOD is authorized to establish a program to award grants to leading minority institutions to, among other purposes, advance research capabilities relating to national security.

Under the bill, certain contracts awarded to educational institutions must include a requirement to subcontract with one or more minority institutions for a total amount of at least 5% of the amount awarded in the contract.</summary>
</bill>
