<bill session="110" type="h" number="6790" updated="2019-11-15T20:55:43Z">
  <state datetime="2008-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access to Foreclosure Counseling Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access to Foreclosure Counseling Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that amounts made available for mortgage loss mitigation counseling in areas having the highest foreclosure rates are used in such areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001050"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-25T22:31:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Access to Foreclosure Counseling Act of 2008 - Amends the Foreclosure Prevention Act of 2008, Division B of the Housing and Economic Recovery Act of 2008, with regard to priority consideration the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation (NRC) is required to give when making grants to Department of Housing and Urban Development-approved counseling intermediaries which target loss mitigation counseling services to minority and low-income homeowners or provide such services in neighborhoods with high concentrations of minority and low-income homeowners.

Revises the requirement that the NRC give priority consideration to counseling intermediaries and legal organizations that provide legal assistance in the 100 metropolitan statistical areas (MSAs) with the highest home foreclosure rates.

Requires the NRC, in the case of any of such MSAs which do not have adequate counseling intermediaries and legal organizations providing such legal assistance, to give priority consideration to counseling intermediaries and legal organizations that: (1) do provide such legal assistance in areas near such MSA; and (2) have the capacity to provide it also in such MSA.</summary>
</bill>
