<bill session="119" type="s" number="1406" updated="2025-11-19T04:29:38Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SOAR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SOAR Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supplemental Oxygen Access Reform Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to improve the payment method for oxygen and oxygen related equipment, supplies, and services, to increase beneficiary access to oxygen and oxygen related equipment, supplies, and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2025-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="2902" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-21T20:46:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Supplemental Oxygen Access Reform Act of 2025&#160;or the SOAR Act of 2025

This bill establishes certain requirements with respect to the payment and provision of supplemental oxygen and related services under Medicare.

For example, the bill provides for separate payments, indexed to inflation, of oxygen and related equipment, supplies, and services under Medicare (rather than under the competitive acquisition program). It also specifically covers services that are provided by respiratory therapists under Medicare and provides for an additional payment adjustment for these services.

Additionally, the bill (1) requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to develop an electronic template for providers to use when prescribing oxygen and related equipment, supplies, and services; and (2) establishes certain rights for beneficiaries receiving these items and services, such as the right to choose their suppliers and to receive clear communications and be informed about the services provided.</summary>
</bill>
