<bill session="118" type="h" number="4611" updated="2024-07-11T08:05:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Candidate Voice Fraud Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Candidate Voice Fraud Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the distribution, with actual malice, of certain political communications that contain materially deceptive audio generated by artificial intelligence which impersonate a candidate's voice and are intended to injure the candidate's reputation or to deceive a voter into voting against the candidate, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000530" joined="2024-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2023-08-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2024-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2023-08-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2024-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2024-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2024-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-02T13:07:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Candidate Voice Fraud Prohibition Act

This bill prohibits the distribution of certain paid-for political communications that contain materially deceptive audio that is generated by artificial intelligence which impersonates a candidate's voice. It also establishes criminal penalties for related violations.&#160;

The bill generally prohibits individuals, political committees, and other entities from distributing such a communication if the communication&#160;(1) contains materially deceptive audio that is generated by artificial intelligence which impersonates a candidate&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s voice, (2) is distributed with actual malice, (3) is intended to injure the candidate&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s reputation or to deceive a voter into voting against the candidate, and (4) is distributed within 60 or 90 days of an election (depending on the type of election). This prohibition does not apply to certain entities, such as radio or television broadcasting stations that broadcast the deceptive audio as part of a bona fide newscast.

Additionally, the bill establishes a new criminal offense related to the distribution of materially deceptive audio that is generated by artificial intelligence which impersonates a candidate's voice. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#226;&#8364;&#8221;a fine, up to two years in prison, or both.

The bill requires the Federal Election Commission to (1) promulgate regulations related to this bill, and (2) report to Congress on matters relating to compliance with and enforcement of this bill and recommendations to ensure compliance with this bill.</summary>
</bill>
