<bill session="109" type="h" number="3327" updated="2019-11-15T20:49:40Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 10, United States Code, to allow certain beneficiaries covered by TRICARE for Life to be reimbursed for travel expenses for certain medical care.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to allow certain beneficiaries covered by TRICARE for Life to be reimbursed for travel expenses for certain medical care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000749"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-30T19:56:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Civilian Health and Medical Program of the Uniformed Services (CHAMPUS) to provide an eligible TRICARE for Life (a Department of Defense (DOD) managed health care program) beneficiary reimbursement for travel expenses to a military medical facility if: (1) the travel purpose is a follow-up appointment for medical treatment of a condition of such beneficiary; and (2) the initial appointment for treatment of the condition was at the same facility. Allows such reimbursement only: (1) for up to three follow-up appointments; and (2) if adequate treatment cannot be obtained within 100 miles of the residence of the beneficiary.

Defines a TRICARE for Life beneficiary as a person who: (1) is eligible for medical care through DOD as a military spouse or dependent; (2) attained age 65 after an initial appointment for treatment at a military medical facility; and (3) resides more than 100 miles from the facility and was referred there by a specialty care provider.</summary>
</bill>
