<bill session="117" type="h" number="6082" updated="2022-12-30T08:18:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRICE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRICE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote innovative acquisition techniques and procurement strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2022-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Small Business, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="583" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-16T16:59:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2021 or the PRICE Act of 2021

This bill directs the Management Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to publish an annual report on a DHS website on projects that have used innovative procurement techniques within DHS to accomplish specified goals.

Such goals are

 improving or encouraging better competition, reducing time to award, achieving cost savings, achieving better mission outcomes, or meeting the goals for contracts awarded to small business concerns. The Management Directorate shall (1) develop and disseminate guidance and offer training for specified personnel concerning when and how to use such techniques, and (2) share best practices across DHS and make available to other federal agencies information to improve procurement methods and training.

The Office for Federal Procurement Policy shall convene a Chief Acquisition Officers Council to examine best practices for acquisition innovation in contracting in the federal government.</summary>
</bill>
