<bill session="117" type="h" number="4456" updated="2022-12-31T05:07:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for agricultural economic injury disaster loans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Helping America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Farmers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Farmers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001081"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2021-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-23T11:07:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping America's Farmers Act

This bill provides financial assistance to certain agricultural entities.

Specifically, the bill directs the Farm Service Agency (FSA) of the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to carry out a program to provide economic disaster loans to certain agricultural entities with an adjusted gross income of less than or equal to $500,000. Under the program, such entities are eligible for zero-interest loans of up to $2 million and may seek loan forgiveness based on demonstrated economic hardship.In making loans, priority must be given to (1) entities located in states most impacted by an economic disaster; and (2) minority, veteran, and women farmers and ranchers.

The FSA may also guarantee a loan to certain agricultural entities with an adjusted gross income of greater than $500,000 if such loan meets certain requirements.

Entities that apply for a loan or loan guarantee may request that the FSA provide an emergency grant of at least $20,000 upon application.

The bill also provides funding for USDA to carry out a program to provide FSA staff with appropriate training relating to economic injury loan processing and servicing.</summary>
</bill>
