<bill session="108" type="s" number="424" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Energy Self-Sufficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish, reauthorize, and improve energy programs relating to Indian tribes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Energy Self-Sufficiency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2003-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2003-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2003-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2540"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2540-2544" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-61.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Civil engineering"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy assistance for the poor"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water power"/>
    <term name="West (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Energy Self-Sufficiency Act - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to require the Director of the Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs of the Department of Energy to establish programs within the Office to assist Indian tribes in meeting energy education, research and development, planning, and management needs. Authorizes the Director to provide grants and loan guarantees to Indian tribes for such programs.Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to establish an Office of Indian Energy Policy and Programs within the Department of Energy.Authorizes Indian tribes to: (1) grant leases of tribal lands for electrical generation, transmission, or distribution facilities and facilities to refine or otherwise process energy resources developed on tribal lands; and (2) grant rights-of-way over tribal lands, without separate approval by the Secretary of the Interior, for pipelines and electrical transmission or distribution lines.Requires Indian tribes to establish environmental review processes that identify and evaluate the significant environmental impacts of proposed Indian Energy Policy and Programs.Requires the Secretary of the Interior to review the activities that have been carried out by the government of Indian tribes under the Indian Mineral Development Act of 1982 and to recommend to specified committees ways to ensure that Indian tribes have the opportunity to develop nonrenewable energy resources and the barriers they face to do so.Requires the Administrators of the Bonneville Power Administration, the Western Area Power Administration, and other pertinent power administrations to take specified actions to encourage Indian tribal energy developments.Requires the Secretary of Energy to study and report to Congress on the cost and feasibility of developing a demonstration project that would use wind energy generated by Indian tribes and hydropower generated by the Army Corps of Engineers on the Missouri River to supply firming power to the Western Area Power Administration.Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to revise and extend renewable energy production incentives.Authorizes the Secretary of Energy to provide grants to units of local government, private, nonprofit community development organizations, and tribal economic development entities for use in improving energy efficiency, identifying and developing alternative renewable and distributed energy supplies, and increasing energy conservation in low-income rural and urban communities.Amends the Rural Electrification Act of 1936 to authorize the Secretary of Agriculture to provide rural and remote communities electrification grants to State, local, or tribal governments, or tribal colleges or universities to increase energy efficiency, siting or upgrading transmission and distribution lines, or for providing or modernizing electric facilities.</summary>
</bill>
