<bill session="108" type="s" number="1051" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Salt Cedar Council Demonstration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to carry out a demonstration program to assess potential water savings through control of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Salt Cedar Council Demonstration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2003-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2003-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6141"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6142" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Aquatic pests"/>
    <term name="Aquatic plants"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Salt Cedar Council Demonstration Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) assess the extent of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive invasion in the western United States, the research on tested and innovative methods to control these phreatophytes, the feasibility of reducing water consumption, methods and challenges in land restoration, and the estimated costs of destruction, biomass removal, and restoration and maintenance; (2) identify long-term management and funding strategies that could be implemented by Federal, State, and private land managers; and (3) initiate a program of at least three projects to demonstrate and evaluate the most effective control methods, including at least one primarily using air-born application of herbicides, one using mechanical removal, and one using biocontrol, such as goats or insects. Requires each project to: (1) monitor and document the water saved due to control of Salt Cedar and Russian Olive infestation and what portions return to surface water supplies and at what rates; (2) assess the optimum application approach and tools for an array of control methods; (3) assess all costs and benefits associated with the control methods, land restoration, and maintenance; (4) determine what conditions indicate the need to remove biomass and the optimal methods for its disposal or use; (5) define appropriate final vegetative states, optimal re-vegetation methods, and methods to prevent regrowth and reintroduction.</summary>
</bill>
