<bill session="108" type="s" number="1002" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:22Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amateur Sports Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish a program to support research and training in methods of detecting the use of performance-enhancing drugs by athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amateur Sports Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Athletic Performance-Enhancing Drugs Research and Detection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000286" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5784-5785"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5785-5786" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Basketball"/>
    <term name="College sports"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Football"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hormones"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Steroids"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amateur Sports Integrity Act - Athletic Performance-Enhancing Drugs Research and Detection Act - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to: (1) establish a program to support research into the use of performance-enhancing substances by athletes and methods of detecting their use; (2) consider research proposals involving performance-enhancing substances banned from use by competitors in events sanctioned by professional and collegiate sports organizations; (3) fund research on the detection of naturally-occurring steroids, other testosterone precursors, and other substances for which no tests are available but for which there is evidence of abuse or abuse potential; (4) fund research that focuses on population studies to ensure that tests are accurate for men, women, all relevant ages, and major ethnic groups; (5) not fund research on drugs of abuse; and (6) develop a grant program to fund educational substance abuse prevention and intervention programs related to the use of such banned performance-enhancing substances by high school and college student athletes.Amends the Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act to make it unlawful to sponsor, operate, advertise, promote, license, or authorize a betting, gambling, or wagering scheme based on a competitive game at the Summer or Winter Olympics or in which high school or college athletes participate.</summary>
</bill>
