<bill session="108" type="s" number="2281" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VOIP Regulatory Freedom Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a clear and unambiguous structure for the jurisdictional and regulatory treatment for the offering or provision of voice-over-Internet-protocol applications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">VOIP Regulatory Freedom Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VOIP Regulatory Freedom Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001078"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-19">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="812">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 812.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>By Senator McCain from Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation filed written report. Report No. 108-425.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Broadband"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication industry"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Voice mail systems"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-02-04T20:37:29Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">VOIP Regulatory Freedom Act of 2004 - Reserves solely to the Federal Government the authority to regulate the offering or provision of a voice-over-Internet-protocol (VOIP) application (an application that uses the Internet or any successor protocol to offer two-way or multidirectional voice communications). Prohibits State regulation of such authority.

States that nothing in this Act: (1) limits State jurisdiction over 911 and enhanced-911 telephone services; (2) exempts providers of a VOIP application from State universal service preservation and interprovider compensation requirements; or (3) affects the authority of the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) or any State to regulate the facilities used to transmit a voice communication of a VOIP application.

Requires the FCC to: (1) conclude a proceeding establishing a transition period in which providers of a VOIP application are required to provide 911 and enhanced-911 services comparable to those provided by other telecommunications carriers; and (2) report to specified congressional committees on the progress of enhanced-911 implementation for connected VOIP applications.

Preserves the obligation of a VOIP application provider to furnish authorized law enforcement authorities all information, facilities, and technical assistance necessary to accomplish an interception (of a phone call) or the installation of a pen register or trap and trace device. Requires a report from the: (1) Comptroller General to specified congressional committees addressing technical problems encountered by law enforcement authorities when intercepting and analyzing communications over the Internet or using the Internet protocol; and (2) FCC to such committees assessing the first ten years of implementation of the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act.

Terminates this Act three years after its enactment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-425</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
