<bill session="116" type="s" number="3243" updated="2022-08-10T23:29:20Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase students' and borrowers' access to student loan information within the National Student Loan Data System.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T19:04:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Simplifying Access to Student Loan Information Act of 2020

This bill expands the National Student Loan Data System (NSLDS) to include information about private education loans.

Specifically, the bill requires private educational lenders to submit to the NSLDS information regarding private education loans made to borrowers, including the outstanding balances and interest rates of such loans. Currently, only federal student loan information is available in the NSLDS.

The bill requires the Department of Education to

 ensure that a cosigner of a private education loan for which information is included in the NSLDS has access only to that information in a separate account, ensure that a private educational lender has access to the NSLDS only to submit information regarding the lender's loans, and establish a functionality within the NSLDS that enables a student borrower of federal student loans to input the information necessary to compare repayment plans.</summary>
</bill>
