<bill session="116" type="s" number="4603" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:45Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Forest Health and Biomass Energy Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Health and Biomass Energy Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the use of forest restoration residue harvested on National Forest System land for renewable energy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 116-382.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insects"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-02T22:05:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Forest Health and Biomass Energy Act of 2020

This bill addresses biomass energy, particularly with respect to materials removed from high-hazard areas (e.g., areas that pose wildfire risks).

The bill directs the Department of Energy, in coordination with the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture (USDA), to assess the potential to produce biomass energy from certain land under the administrative jurisdiction of Interior and USDA.

With respect to the removal of timber located within certain high-hazard areas, USDA shall not charge a stumpage rate or assign any value to (1) certain trees, (2) forest processing residues or byproducts of forest restoration, or (3) a large dead tree that is not suitable for higher-valued wood products because of decay.

The bill establishes the High Hazard Area Wood Biomass Fund, into which USDA may deposit a percentage of the revenue generated from base stumpage rates of timber sales that occur on National Forest System land to assist timber operators and biomass energy producers with the collection, harvest, storage, and transportation of biomass material removed from high-hazard areas.

The President shall include in the annual budget submission an annual performance metric, which shall be established by USDA, for the harvest of wood biomass material in green tons made available for bioenergy markets.</summary>
</bill>
