<bill session="109" type="h" number="4024" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:55Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make funds available for community disaster loans to assist local governments in providing essential services following Hurricane Katrina, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000070" joined="2005-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Disaster loans"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-21T16:32:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Disaster Loan Act of 2005 - Authorizes the transfer of up to $300 million in certain disaster relief funds to the Disaster Assistance Direct Loan Program (DADLP) for the cost of direct loans authorized by the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (the Act) to assist local governments in providing essential services. Authorizes the transfer, also, of up to $1 million of such funds to the DADLP for administrative expenses.



Amends the Act to eliminate the $5 million limit on the amount of any community disaster loans (but keep the limit of 25% of the local government annual operating budget for the fiscal year in which the major disaster occurs).

Repeals the requirement that repayment of all or part of any such loans be cancelled to the extent that the local government's revenues during the three fiscal years following the major disaster are insufficient to meet its operating budget. (Retains denial of such a government's eligibility for further assistance during any period in which it is in arrears on required repayment of such a loan.)</summary>
</bill>
