<bill session="117" type="h" number="4704" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide assistance for mature technology nodes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Mature Technology Node Resiliency and Manufacturing Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mature Technology Node Resiliency and Manufacturing Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000482" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2021-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-29T14:03:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Mature Technology Node Resiliency and Manufacturing Act of 2021

This bill provides $2 billion in FY2022 funds for the Department of Commerce to give financial assistance that incentivizes investment in semiconductor facilities and equipment at mature technology nodes. (A technology node is a specific semiconductor manufacturing process and its design rules.)

This assistance shall be provided to certain entities with a demonstrated ability to substantially finance, construct, expand, or modernize a semiconductor facility. Such entities must also (1) provide equipment or materials or operate at mature technology nodes, and (2) commit to using federal financial assistance received pursuant to the bill to increase semiconductor production at such nodes. Commerce must prioritize entities that support the resiliency of the semiconductor supply chain for critical manufacturing industries in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
