<bill session="109" type="s" number="329" updated="2019-11-15T21:55:45Z">
  <state datetime="2005-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bankruptcy Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="display">Bankruptcy Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, to increase the amount of unsecured claims for salaries and wages given priority in bankruptcy, to provide for cash payments to retirees to compensate for lost health insurance benefits resulting from the bankruptcy of their former employer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000361"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2005-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2005-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2005-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1203-1204"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1204-1205" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Executive compensation"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Retiree health benefits"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Severance pay"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-01T21:12:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bankruptcy Fairness Act - Amends Federal bankruptcy law to increase from $4,925 to $15,000 the aggregate amount of a claim to recover employee wages and benefits that has priority ranking among unsecured creditor claims.

Authorizes the bankruptcy court to avoid any transfer of compensation made to debtor's personnel or a member of its board of directors 90 days before the date of the filing of the bankruptcy petition if the court finds the transfer to be either out of the ordinary course of business, or unjust enrichment.

Revises guidelines governing payment of insurance benefits accrued by retirees to provide that: (1) a retiree whose benefits have been modified during the bankruptcy process shall have a claim for the value of the benefits lost as a result of such modification; and (2) the debtor shall pay such retiree the cost of 18 months of insurance premiums on behalf of the retiree and dependents.

Expands the prerequisites for confirmation of a bankruptcy reorganization plan to require that the holder of such a retiree insurance claim receive from the debtor, on the effective date of the plan, cash equal to the cost of 18 months of the retiree's insurance premiums.</summary>
</bill>
