<bill session="110" type="s" number="1673" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:46Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the export of United States agricultural products to Cuba as authorized by the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000, to remove impediments to the export to Cuba of medical devices and medicines, to allow travel to Cuba by United States citizens, to establish an agricultural export promotion program with respect to Cuba, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000307" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2007-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2007-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8234"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-11">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 110-937.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="2819" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-26T15:45:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting American Agricultural and Medical Exports to Cuba Act of 2007 - Prohibits the President from restricting direct transfers from a Cuban depository institution to a U.S. depository institution in payment for a product authorized for sale under the Trade Sanctions Reform and Export Enhancement Act of 2000.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to provide information and technical assistance to U.S. agricultural producers, cooperative organizations, or state agencies to promote U.S. agricultural exports products to Cuba.

Expresses the sense of Congress that temporary entry visas should be issued to Cuban nationals to facilitate purchase of U.S. agricultural products.

Amends the Department of Commerce and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 to repeal the prohibition on enforcement of rights to certain U.S. intellectual properties and such properties' transfer.

Prohibits the President from regulating or prohibiting travel to or from Cuba by U.S. citizens or legal residents, or any of the transactions ordinarily incident to such travel, and any regulation restricting or prohibiting such travel shall have no effect, relating to: (1) accompanied personal baggage; (2) payment of living expenses and the acquisition of personal-use goods or services; (3) travel arrangements; (4) nonscheduled air, sea, or land voyage transactions, (such provision does not permit the carriage of articles other than accompanied baggage into Cuba or the United States); and (5) normal banking transactions. States that such provision shall not apply in time of war or armed hostilities between the United States and Cuba, or of imminent danger to the public health or the physical safety of U.S. travelers.

Amends the Democracy Act of 1992 to repeal the requirement for onsite verification of certain medical exports to Cuba.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) increase the airport ticket tax for transportation between the United States and Cuba by $1; and (2) establish in the Treasury the Agricultural Export Promotion Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
