<bill session="116" type="h" number="6756" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:59Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Pandemic Hunger for College Students Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the eligibility standards applicable to low-income college students under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 during COVID-19 public health emergency.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Pandemic Hunger for College Students Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000455"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2020-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2020-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Oversight, and Department Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-22T16:37:10Z" status="Introduced in House">End Pandemic Hunger for College Students Act of 2020

This bill expands the eligibility of certain low-income students at institutions of higher education to participate in the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) during the COVID-19 public health emergency.

Eligibility for SNAP benefits shall not be limited for an individual who as of March 1, 2020, or anytime in the prior 30 days, was enrolled at least half-time in an institution of higher education and participating in SNAP.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) may temporarily adjust eligibility standards under SNAP through national guidance or by request of a state for individuals who are enrolled in an institution of higher education in any state affected by the outbreak of COVID-19.

Additionally, USDA must approve a state's request to adjust the eligibility standards under SNAP for such individuals who (1) are members of certain households who are otherwise eligible to participate in SNAP, or (2) had an expected family contribution equal to zero in the most recent academic year.

The temporary eligibility standards shall be in effect (1) for initial applications under SNAP until 90 days after the COVID-19 public health emergency is lifted, and (2) until the first recertification of a household beginning no earlier than 90 days after such public health emergency is lifted.

USDA must provide guidance to states on the temporary student eligibility requirements and state options within 10 days of this bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
