<bill session="111" type="h" number="4786" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:26Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-10T10:44:33-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-10T10:44:33-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide authority to compensate Federal employees for the 2-day period in which authority to make expenditures from the Highway Trust Fund lapsed, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide authority to compensate Federal employees for the 2-day period in which authority to make expenditures from the Highway Trust Fund lapsed, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000263" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000689" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000006" joined="2010-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2010-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10T10:29:15-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Oberstar moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10T10:29:16-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1226-1228" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10T10:29:17-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4786.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2010-03-10T10:44:33-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1226-1227" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10T10:44:34-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-26">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-05T18:22:46Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Declares that any federal employees furloughed as a result of the lapse in expenditure authority from the Highway Trust Fund after 11:59 p.m. on February 28, 2010, through March 2, 2010, shall be compensated for the period of that lapse at their standard rates of compensation.

Ratifies and approves all actions taken by federal employees, contractors, and grantees during that period of lapse to: (1) maintain the essential level of government operations, services, and activities to protect life and property; and (2) bring about orderly termination of government functions.

Requires that funds used by the Secretary of Transportation to compensate such employees be derived from funds previously authorized out of the Highway Trust Fund and made available or limited to the Department of Transportation by the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2010. Deems this Act to be a section of the Continuing Appropriations Resolution, 2010, as in effect on the date of the enactment of the last amendment to such Resolution.</summary>
</bill>
