<bill session="108" type="sr" number="483" updated="2021-09-29T22:08:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-07">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the detention of Tibetan political prisoners by the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding the detention of Tibetan political prisoners by the Government of the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-12-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11860-11861, S11905" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11860-11861" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11905" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-13T21:42:58Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the Government of the People's Republic of China is in violation of international human rights standards by detaining and mistreating Tibetans who engage in peaceful activities to protest China's occupation of Tibet or promote the preservation of a distinct Tibetan identity; (2) sustained international pressure on the Government of the People's Republic of China is essential to improve the human rights situation in Tibet and secure the release of Tibetan political prisoners; (3) the Government of the United States should raise the cases of Tenzin Delek and other political prisoners at every opportunity with officials from the People's Republic of China, and work with other governments concerned about human rights in China, including Tibetan areas, to encourage the release of political prisoners and promote systemic improvement of human rights in China; and (4) the Government of the People's Republic of China should release all political prisoners, including Tenzin Delek.</summary>
</bill>
