<bill session="118" type="h" number="7114" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Universal Prekindergarten and Early Childhood Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Universal Prekindergarten and Early Childhood Education Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a grant program to assist States to establish or expand universal prekindergarten in public schools and public charter schools.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2024-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2024-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E83"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T15:06:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Universal Prekindergarten and Early Childhood Education Act of 2024

This bill authorizes through FY2030 a grant program for states to establish or expand full-day prekindergarten programs that (1) permit each three- or four-year old child in the state to be voluntarily enrolled by the child's parent, regardless of income, in the program at the public school in which the child would be enrolled for kindergarten; (2) run the length of the regular school year; and (3) are taught by teachers who possess equivalent or similar qualifications to those of teachers of other grades in the school.

The federal share of such a grant shall not exceed 80% of the costs of carrying out these activities. Grant funds received under the program shall be used to supplement and not supplant other federal early childhood education funds in the state.</summary>
</bill>
