<bill session="111" type="h" number="2902" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Broadband Internet Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Federal Trade Commission, in consultation with the Federal Communications Commission, to review volume usage service plans of major broadband Internet service providers to ensure that such plans are fairly based on cost.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Broadband Internet Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001173"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2009-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2009-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000600" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2009-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-08-13T16:01:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Broadband Internet Fairness Act - Makes it unlawful for major broadband Internet service providers to offer volume usage service plans imposing rates, terms, and conditions that are unjust, unreasonable, or unreasonably discriminatory. Treats a violation as an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act.

Requires major broadband Internet service providers offering or proposing to offer volume usage plans to file a service plan analysis with the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

Requires the FTC to enforce this Act.

Defines "major broadband Internet service provider" as a broadband Internet service provider that, directly or through an affiliate, provides broadband Internet service to 2 million or more subscribers.

Defines "volume usage service plan" as any choice of service offerings to a residential consumer that includes two or more different sets of rates, terms, or conditions directly or indirectly based on the amount of data transmitted to or from the consumer within a fixed period of time.

Includes nonprofit organizations or higher education institutions in the term "residential consumer."</summary>
</bill>
