<bill session="116" type="h" number="6066" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Passenger Train Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Railroad Administration and Amtrak to implement and carry out certain National Transportation Safety Board recommendations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Passenger Train Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000369" joined="2020-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2020-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000560" joined="2020-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2020-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak)"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-01T13:54:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Passenger Train Safety Act

This bill addresses passenger safety issues aboard trains.

Specifically, the bill

 directs the Federal Railroad Administration to research safety issues relating to speed signs, seat securement mechanisms, and methods for mitigating derailment injuries; requires the National Railroad Passenger Corporation (Amtrak) to address various safety issues, including developing policies for the safe use of child safety seats and implementing enhanced crew training; directs the Department of Transportation to require each railroad carrier that provides regularly scheduled intercity rail passenger or commuter rail passenger transportation to install inward- and outward-facing audio recording devices in or on all controlling locomotive cabs and cab car operating compartments on such passenger trains; prohibits entities providing regularly scheduled intercity or commuter rail passenger transportation from beginning service on certain routes unless a positive train control system is fully implemented and operational on such routes; and requires railroad carriers to periodically review and update their speed limit action plans.</summary>
</bill>
