<bill session="119" type="s" number="264" updated="2025-11-19T04:04:40Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Experience Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Experience Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to establish the Veterans Experience Office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="423" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3578" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-18T22:04:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Experience Act of 2025

This bill establishes the Veterans Experience Office within the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out the key customer experience initiatives of the VA relating to veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; and beneficiaries&#226;&#8364;&#8482; satisfaction with and usage of VA benefits and services.

Additionally, the office must

require the heads of other organizations and offices within the VA to report regularly on customer experience metrics, action plans, and other customer experience improvement efforts;collect veteran-derived data to determine satisfaction and for use in policymaking;provide strategic guidance and strategies to VA entities for engaging with veterans and beneficiaries;assess and advise the VA on the accuracy and helpfulness of websites and customer-facing information of the VA; andassess and advise the VA on the status and opportunities for improvement of the customer service efforts of the VA.The requirements of this bill terminate on September 30, 2028.

The Government Accountability Office must analyze and report on the methodology, effectiveness, and implementation of the VA&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s approach to improving veteran and beneficiary customer experience and satisfaction.</summary>
</bill>
