<bill session="117" type="h" number="6541" updated="2023-01-25T20:00:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Local Governments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Local Governments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency to establish cybersecurity guidance for small organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2022-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000480" joined="2022-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2483" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-18T18:47:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Cybersecurity of Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Local Governments Act

This bill requires reporting and other efforts to improve the cybersecurity of small entities. These include small businesses, governments (or certain governmental bodies) that represent populations of less than 50,000, and small nonprofits.

Specifically, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must periodically report on and make recommendations about cybersecurity policies and controls for small entities. CISA, the Small Business Administration (SBA), and the Minority Business Development Agency must (1) promote the report, including by making it available through their respective websites; and (2) make voluntary training and technical assistance available to employees of small entities concerning cybersecurity recommendations identified in the report.

In addition, the Department of Commerce must report to Congress about improving the cybersecurity of small entities. Further, the SBA must collect information from small businesses concerning cybersecurity matters and report to Congress about the cybersecurity of small businesses.</summary>
</bill>
