<bill session="117" type="h" number="8766" updated="2022-12-29T12:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REFINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REFINE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reserving Energy For Independence and Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Energy to conduct studies relating to Strategic Petroleum Reserve levels, to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act with respect to such Reserve, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, Natural Resources, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6235" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-28T13:07:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Reserving Energy For Independence and Empowerment Act or the REFINE Act

This bill sets forth provisions to limit the sale and export of petroleum products from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR), increase energy production from energy producers in the United States, and make related requirements.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to issue regulations prohibiting the export of petroleum products (e.g., crude oil) sold from the SPR to (1) any country that is subject to a U.S. arms embargo as specified by the bill, (2) any country that is a state sponsor of terrorism, and (3) any entity that is owned by China.

Before DOE may sell, exchange, or loan crude oil from the SPR, DOE must first develop a plan to increase the percentage of federal land (including submerged land of the Outer Continental Shelf) leased for oil and gas production by the same percentage as the percentage of petroleum in the SPR that is to be drawn down.

In addition, the President must rescind the Executive Order titled Protecting Public Health and the Environment and Restoring Science To Tackle the Climate Crisis.

The President must also direct federal agencies to (1) identify and repeal any of their regulations that have the intent or effect of substantially reducing the energy independence of the United States, and (2) issue regulations and guidance to reduce the regulatory burden for energy producers in the United States and to increase the energy output by those producers.</summary>
</bill>
