<bill session="117" type="h" number="5191" updated="2022-12-31T09:00:07Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to establish a national service program that provides conservation opportunities on public and private lands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">REVIVE the CCC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restore Environmental Vitality and Improve Volatile Economy by the Civilian Conservation Corps Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REVIVE the CCC Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2021-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2021-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2414" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-30T20:49:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Restore Environmental Vitality and Improve Volatile Economy by the Civilian Conservation Corps Act or the REVIVE the CCC Act

This bill permits AmeriCorps to establish the Civilian Conservation Corps (CCC) to address unemployment and environmental conservation and requires the Department of Agriculture to establish an agricultural workforce development program to incentivize apprenticeships in agriculture.

 The CCC must make grants to local host entities to allow those entities to select applicants to participate in conservation-related service projects. Local entities eligible for grants include, among others, state and local offices, nonprofit organizations, sponsors of apprenticeship programs, and individual farmers. A prospective CCC member must apply for placement with an approved local host for a service position hosted by that local entity. Applicants selected are considered CCC members but are not considered employees of the local host.

 The local host must provide CCC members with an allowance of $15 per hour of service and must provide a basic healthcare plan to full-time members. A CCC member who completes a term of service with a local host may be eligible to receive an award of up to $5,000 from AmeriCorps towards the costs of an apprenticeship program. These awards and allowances are not considered income for purposes of federal income taxation.

The bill also requires the Department of Agriculture to establish an agricultural workforce development program to encourage agricultural businesses to employ apprentices by reimbursing up to 50% of apprenticeship costs.</summary>
</bill>
