<bill session="112" type="h" number="4003" updated="2021-09-28T14:25:31Z">
  <state datetime="2012-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Postmark Payment Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Postmark Payment Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 39, United States Code, to provide that the payment of a bill, invoice, or statement of account due, if made by mail, shall be considered to have been made on the date as of which the envelope which is used to transmit such  payment is postmarked.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000569" joined="2012-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2012-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2012-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-03-13T17:57:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Postmark Payment Act of 2012 - Deems any payment required to be made on or before a prescribed date that is delivered by the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) after such date to be received by the payee on the date of the U.S. postmark stamped on the envelope or other cover in which such payment is mailed. Exempts from this Act any payment: (1) other than a payment on a bill, invoice, or statement of account due; (2) which is required by law, regulation, or contract to be delivered by any method other than by mail; or (3) which is subject to any other provision of federal law specifying how a postmark date shall be used in determining the date on which such payment shall be deemed to have been delivered or made. Applies the provisions of this Act only if: (1) the postmark date falls on or before the prescribed date for making the payment; and (2) the payment was, on or before such date, deposited in the mail in the United States in an envelope or under other appropriate cover, postage prepaid, and properly addressed to the payee.</summary>
</bill>
