<bill session="108" type="h" number="216" updated="2023-01-15T21:04:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Moccasin Bend National Archeological District Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish as a unit of Chickamauga and Chattanooga National Military Park, the Moccasin Bend National Archeological District.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Moccasin Bend National Archeological District Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000119"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2003-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil War"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Military parks"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Moccasin Bend National Archeological District Act - Establishes the Moccasin Bend National Archeological District as a unit of Chickamauga and Chattanooga National Military Park in Tennessee.Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) acquire lands within the District's boundaries, and easements between noncontiguous areas of the District, from willing sellers; (2) enter into cooperative agreements with Indian tribes, governmental entities, and interested persons for the restoration, preservation, development, interpretation, and use of the District; and (3) establish and administer a visitor's center in the District.Requires the Secretary to develop a general management plan for the District which shall describe protection and preservation of resources of, visitor use of, and facility development within the District.Repeals provisions authorizing the Secretary to accept donations to the Park of specified lands situated generally within the Moccasin Bend of the Tennessee River lying west of the city of Chattanooga.</summary>
</bill>
