<bill session="110" type="s" number="3388" updated="2017-12-15T00:37:13Z">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the assignment of pre-stabilization disability ratings to certain veterans for purposes of the payment of disability compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the assignment of pre-stabilization disability ratings to certain veterans for purposes of the payment of disability compensation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-29T15:51:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, with respect to veterans who have been discharged from active-duty service for 365 days or less and for whom a permanent disability rating is not immediately assignable, to assign a pre-stabilization disability rating of: (1) 100%, for a veteran with a severe disability for whom substantially gainful employment is not feasible or advisable; and (2) 50%, for a veteran with a wound or injury for whom material impairment of employability is likely.

Terminates the pre-stabilization rating: (1) when a veteran receives a permanent disability rating based on the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) schedule for rating disabilities; or (2) 365 days after the veteran's last separation or release from active duty. Allows the Secretary, when appropriate, to extend the pre-stabilization rating beyond such date.</summary>
</bill>
