<bill session="112" type="s" number="742" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:23Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Retirement Age Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Congressional Retirement Age Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapters 83 and 84 of title 5, United States Code, to set the age at which Members of Congress are eligible for an annuity to the same age as the retirement age under the Social Security Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2011-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2011-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2011-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs referred to Subcommittee on Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSGA03" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight of Government Management, the Federal Workforce, and the District of Columbia" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2397" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-08T22:16:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Congressional Retirement Age Act of 2011 - Prohibits a Member of Congress serving on or after the enactment of this Act from being eligible for an annuity under the Civil Service Retirement System (CSRS) or the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS), unless he or she is separated from the service after attaining retirement age under the Social Security Act and completing five years of service.

Makes a Member serving on or after the enactment of this Act ineligible for a CSRS or FERS deferred retirement annuity, unless the Member is separated from the service, or transferred to a position in which the individual does not continue subject to CSRS or FERS annuity requirements, after completing five years of service.

Denies an early retirement annuity under FERS to any Member serving on or after enactment of this Act who otherwise meets FERS early retirement requirements. Delays entitlement to a FERS annuity until after attaining retirement age under the Social Security Act.</summary>
</bill>
