<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="588" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:46Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3644" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:53-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <offered datetime="2010-03-19"/>
  <description>Amendment in the nature of a substitute, as amended, makes several changes to reflect the significant economic importance of coastal areas and resources to the overall economy of the United States and also authorizes specific increases in authorized appropriation levels.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute printed in Part A of House Report 111-445 to reflect changes to the bill that address concerns raised by the minorit y during Committee consideration of the bill. In particular the ANS makes several changes to reflect the significant economic importance of coastal areas and resources to the overall economy of the United States and also authorizes specific increases in authorized appropriation levels.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:53-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="140">
      <text>On agreeing to the Capps amendment (A001) as amended Agreed to by recorded vote: 233 - 178 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T11:59:26-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mrs. Capps.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1677-1681, H1684" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1677-1679" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Capps amendment (A001) as amended Agreed to by recorded vote: 233 - 178 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:53-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Capps amendment (A001) as amended Agreed to by recorded vote: 233 - 178 (Roll no. 140).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T11:59:26-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Mrs. Capps.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1677-1681, H1684" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1677-1679" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
