<bill session="117" type="h" number="6705" updated="2023-08-21T21:30:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Shoreline Health Oversight, Restoration, Resilience, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shoreline Health Oversight, Restoration, Resilience, and Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for improvements to the rivers and harbors of the United States, to provide for the conservation and development of water and related resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001303"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001103" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2022-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7198" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3624" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3610" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-13T15:46:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Shoreline Health Oversight, Restoration, Resilience, and Enhancement Act

This bill provides for the development of water and water-related resources projects and activities with a particular emphasis on those carried out by the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers.

Among other things, the bill

 revises and modifies the flood mitigation and riverine restoration program to include coverage of coastal storm damage; authorizes the Corps to carry out specified water resources development and conservation projects in accordance with plans laid out in designated reports or decision documents; authorizes the Department of the Army to continue periodic nourishment for specified projects for coastal storm risk management for an additional period of 50 years; authorizes the Army to use funds for water resources development purposes to carry out, at full federal expense, a measure located on, or benefitting, federal land under the administrative jurisdiction of another federal agency under specified conditions; authorizes the Army to provide in advance the federal share of funds required for the acquisition of land, easements, and rights-of-way for, and the relocation of, certain projects; directs the Army to establish a program to provide environmental assistance to nonfederal interests in the Chattahoochee River Basin; and requires the Army to expedite the replacement of the Mississippi River mat sinking unit.</summary>
</bill>
