<bill session="116" type="s" number="2607" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:38Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drone Integration and Zoning Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Integration and Zoning Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prescribe zoning authority with respect to commercial unmanned aircraft systems and to preserve State, local, and Tribal authorities and private property with respect to unmanned aircraft systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-23T20:53:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drone Integration and Zoning Act of 2019

This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prescribe regulations or standards related to unmanned aircraft systems.

Among other requirements, the FAA must

 designate the area between 200 feet and 400 feet above ground level for use of civil unmanned aircraft systems; authorize, only with a property owner's permission, the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft in the immediate reaches of airspace above private property; preserve state, local, and tribal authority to issue certain reasonable restrictions on the operation of a civil unmanned aircraft system within 200 feet of the ground or a structure; and establish a process for the designation of routes above 200 feet of the ground as authorized commercial routes.</summary>
</bill>
