<bill session="111" type="s" number="2863" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:50Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Response Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that an outbreak of infectious disease or act of terrorism may be a major disaster under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5122 et seq.), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Response Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12911-12912"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-16T19:09:31Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Emergency Response Act of 2009 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to redefine "major disaster" as any natural disaster (including pandemics), act of terrorism, or other manmade disaster (under current law, any natural catastrophe) in any part of the United States that, in the determination of the President, causes damage of sufficient severity and magnitude to warrant major disaster assistance to supplement the efforts and resources of states, local governments, and disaster relief organizations.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to designate a representative to lead a working group with national organizations that represent state, local, and tribal government interests to prepare best practice recommendations for facilitating the flow of public health information to state fusion centers and the greater homeland security community.</summary>
</bill>
