<bill session="112" type="s" number="1903" updated="2022-02-03T05:53:35Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act</title>
    <title type="popular">STOCK bill ("STOCK Act")</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit commodities and securities trading based on nonpublic information relating to Congress, to require additional reporting by Members and employees of Congress of securities transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000555"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2011-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2011-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000291" joined="2011-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2011-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2011-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2012-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2012-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2012-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2011-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2012-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2011-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2011-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2011-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2011-12-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 112-344.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="1148" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1871" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Commodity Futures Trading Commission"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-12T22:16:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Trading on Congressional Knowledge Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 and the Commodity Exchange Act to direct both the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC) to prohibit purchase or sale of either securities, security-based swaps, or commodities for future delivery or swap by a person in possession of material nonpublic information regarding pending or prospective legislative action if the information was obtained: (1) knowingly from a Member or employee of Congress, (2) by reason of being a Member or employee of Congress, or (3) from other federal employees and derived from their federal employment. Makes it an element of the prohibited activity, also, that the Member or employee of Congress or the federal employee acted with the intent to assist another person, directly or indirectly, to use the information to buy or sell the securities of such publicly traded company based on such information.

Amends the Standing Rules of the Senate to prohibit a Member, officer, or employee of the Senate from disclosing material nonpublic information relating to any pending or prospective legislative action relating to any publicly-traded company or to any commodity if such person acts with intent to assist another person, directly or indirectly, to use the information to buy or sell the securities of that publicly traded company based on such information.

Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require formal disclosure of certain securities and commodities futures transactions to either the Clerk of the House of Representatives or the Secretary of the Senate.

Amends the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to subject to its registration, reporting, and disclosure requirements, as well as requirements for identification of clients and covered legislative and executive officials, all political intelligence activities, contacts, firms, and consultants. Requires the Comptroller General to include political intelligence activities, contacts, firms, and consultants in its annual compliance audits and reports.</summary>
</bill>
