<bill session="117" type="hr" number="1172" updated="2022-12-29T17:33:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing that fentanyl is a weapon of mass destruction.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing that fentanyl is a weapon of mass destruction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2022-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-22T11:01:17Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that it is U.S. policy to recognize that

 a weapon of mass destruction designation of illicit fentanyl by the federal government would empower the government to go after international trafficking syndicates and root out illicit manufacturers and traffickers to take action to stop fentanyl from reaching the border; and such a designation of illicit fentanyl would not hinder the use of legal fentanyl or stop ongoing recovery, treatment, and harm-reduction efforts to assist those residents of the United States currently suffering from substance use disorder. Finally, the resolution urges President Biden and the Department of Homeland Security to officially designate illicit fentanyl and analogues, including carfentanil, as a weapon of mass destruction.</summary>
</bill>
