<bill session="111" type="h" number="5197" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:14Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense Sexual Trauma Response Oversight and Good Governance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To implement recommendations of the Defense Task Force on Sexual Assault in the Military Services.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Sexual Trauma Response Oversight and Good Governance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense STRONG Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000465"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2010-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2010-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000794" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2010-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-21T15:44:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Defense Sexual Trauma Response Oversight and Good Governance Act (Defense STRONG Act) - Establishes within the Department of Defense (DOD) a Director of the Sexual Assault Prevention and Response Office to serve as the single point of authority, accountability, and oversight for DOD policy regarding prevention of and response to sexual assault, and to provide oversight to ensure that the sexual assault programs of the military departments comply with DOD policy.

Requires the assignment within each military department of at least one full-time Sexual Assault Response Coordinator and one full-time Sexual Assault Victim Advocate, allowing the Secretary of the military department concerned to assign additional coordinators and/or advocates based on the demographics or needs of the unit. Allows only members of the Armed Forces (members) or DOD civilian personnel to be assigned as coordinators or advocates. Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a professional training and certification program for such coordinators and advocates, and requires performance evaluations of all coordinators and advocates.

Entitles any member, or dependent of a member, who is the victim of a sexual assault to legal assistance provided by a military legal assistance counsel and Victim Advocate service, regardless of whether the member or dependent elects unrestricted or restricted (confidential) reporting of the assault. Makes privileged any communications between a member or dependent and a Victim Advocate.

Directs the Secretary to provide for the inclusion of a sexual assault prevention and response training module at each level of professional military education.</summary>
</bill>
