<bill session="116" type="s" number="4250" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Burial Equity for Guards and Reserves Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Burial Equity for Guards and Reserves Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to ensure that grants provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs for State veterans' cemeteries do not restrict States from authorizing the interment of certain deceased members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces in such cemeteries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2020-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7727" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-25T12:03:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Burial Equity for Guards and Reserves Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) from establishing a condition for a cemetery grant that restricts the ability of a state to inter certain reservists (or spouses) at a state-owned veterans' cemetery solely because such individuals are ineligible for burial in an open national cemetery.

Specifically, as a condition for grants, the VA cannot restrict the ability of a state to inter a

 member of a reserve component whose service was terminated under honorable conditions; member of the Army National Guard or Air National Guard whose service was terminated under honorable conditions; member of the Reserve Officers' Training Corps of the Army, Navy, or Air Force who died under honorable conditions while a member; and spouse of any member described above. The VA is prohibited from (1) denying an application for a grant solely on the basis that the recipient state may use funds to expand, improve, operate, or maintain a veterans' cemetery to allow for the internment of the specified reservists; and (2) enforcing certain conditions on grants for state veterans' cemeteries that were established before the date of enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
