<bill session="119" type="h" number="2322" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FRIDGE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fortifying Refrigeration Infrastructure and Developing Global Exports Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FRIDGE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide technical assistance to improve infrastructure in foreign markets for United States agricultural commodities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2025-08-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2025-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="1119" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-12T18:42:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Fortifying Refrigeration Infrastructure and Developing Global Exports Act of 2025 or the FRIDGE Act of 2025 

This bill expands the Foreign Market Development Cooperator Program to include funding for technical assistance for infrastructure-related projects to ensure U.S. agricultural commodities are not damaged or lost due to infrastructure deficiencies in new and developing markets. This Foreign Agricultural Service (FAS) program funds projects that address long-term opportunities to reduce foreign import constraints or expand export growth opportunities.

Specifically, the bill directs FAS to enter into contracts or other agreements with trade organizations to enhance the infrastructure capabilities (including cold chain capacity and port improvements) in new and developing foreign markets through needs assessments, training, and other technical assistance.</summary>
</bill>
