<bill session="117" type="h" number="3401" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Hiring Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the non-applicability of non-Department of Veterans Affairs covenants not to compete to the appointment of certain Veterans Health Administration personnel, to permit the Veterans Health Administration to make contingent appointments, and to require certain Veterans Health Administration physicians to complete residency training.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Hiring Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2022-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2021-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3967" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-28T11:48:02Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Hiring Enhancement Act

This bill modifies requirements and procedures related to the hiring of physicians at the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Specifically, the bill negates enforcement of a noncompete agreement that an applicant for a specified appointee position (e.g., physician) in the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) has entered into with a non-VA facility or party. As a condition of terminating the noncompete agreement, the physician must agree to serve at the VHA for one year or until the expiration of the noncompete agreement, whichever is later.

The bill also authorizes the VA to offer a contingent physician's appointment to a person if the VA anticipates that the person will have completed a residency program leading to board eligibility in a specialty and met other requirements for the appointment within two years after the VA offer.

Eligibility requirements for a VA physician's appointment are revised to require completion of a residency program rather than an internship.</summary>
</bill>
