<bill session="117" type="s" number="4688" updated="2023-06-08T19:45:25Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reproductive Freedom for All Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reproductive Freedom for All Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to guarantee that Americans have the freedom to make certain reproductive decisions without undue government interference.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2022-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2022-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2022-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3806-3808" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-23T15:04:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reproductive Freedom for All Act

This bill establishes a general right of all persons to make certain reproductive decisions without undue government interference.

It specifically provides statutory authority for the Supreme Court's prior holdings in Roe v. Wade and Planned Parenthood of Southeastern Pennsylvania v. Casey. In Roe, the Court held that the Constitution protects a woman's decision to terminate her pregnancy. In Casey, the Court reaffirmed this holding and additionally held that state abortion regulations may not place a substantial obstacle in the path of a woman seeking an abortion before fetal viability (i.e., an undue burden). However, a state may (1) restrict abortions after viability, except when a pregnancy endangers the life or health of the woman; and (2) enact regulations to further the health or safety of a woman seeking an abortion, except for unnecessary health regulations that present a substantial obstacle to a woman seeking an abortion.

Additionally, the bill provides statutory authority for the Court's holdings in Griswold v. Connecticut (the right of married couples to obtain contraception), Eisenstadt v. Baird (the right of single persons to obtain contraception), Carey v. Population Services International (the right of minors to obtain contraception), and Whole Woman's Health v. Hellerstedt (that certain state restrictions on abortion facilities and providers created an undue burden).

The bill allows the Department of Justice or any person adversely affected by a state law that violates this bill to seek injunctive relief. It also specifies that the bill does not affect laws regarding conscience protection.</summary>
</bill>
