<bill session="116" type="s" number="4520" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA&#226;&#8364;&#8220;SBA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA&#226;&#8364;&#8220;SBA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verification Alignment and Service-disabled Business Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer the responsibility of verifying small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans or service-disabled veterans to the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2020-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2020-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2020-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2020-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1615" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-09T13:04:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Verification Alignment and Service-disabled Business Adjustment Act or the VA-SBA Act

This bill transfers responsibility&#160;for verifying that a small business concern is owned and controlled by a veteran or service-disabled veteran, for the purposes of eligibility for certain procurement programs, from the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to the Small Business Administration (SBA).

Specifically, the bill transfers maintenance of the database of veteran-owned and service-disabled veteran-owned businesses to the SBA. For the purposes of procurement programs for small businesses owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, the SBA must certify the status of such businesses, require their periodic recertification, and penalize any small business that misrepresents its status. Accordingly, the bill also abolishes the Center for Verification and Evaluation of the VA and transfers all of its functions to the SBA.</summary>
</bill>
