<bill session="118" type="h" number="5228" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Air Reserve Component Fighter Recapitalization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Reserve Component Fighter Recapitalization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Air Force to develop a plan for the recapitalization of fighter squadrons of the Air National Guard and the Air Force Reserve and to limit modifications to the flying missions of such squadrons until such plan is complete.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-26T16:54:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Air Reserve Component Fighter Recapitalization Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of the Air Force to develop a notional plan for the recapitalization of all fighter squadrons of the Air National Guard and the Air Force Reserve. The Department of the Air Force may not terminate the fighter flying mission of any fighter squadron of the Air National Guard or the Air Force Reserve until 180 days have elapsed following the date on which the required notional plan is submitted.

The plan must be submitted with an explanation of (1) any programmatic funding required to implement the plan, (2) how the plan differs from other Air Force plans with respect to fighter aircraft squadrons of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve, and (3) any effects of the plan on operations and efforts to recapitalize or transition existing fighter aircraft squadrons of the Air National Guard and Air Force Reserve as proposed in the future-years defense program for FY2024.</summary>
</bill>
