<bill session="117" type="h" number="4754" updated="2022-12-31T05:04:51Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a 30-day deadline for the Joint Committee on the Library to approve or disapprove requests and other actions relating to the procedures for the replacement of statues donated by States for display in National Statuary Hall.</title>
    <title type="display">National Statuary Hall Collection Progress Assurance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Statuary Hall Collection Progress Assurance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000619"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2021-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001213" joined="2021-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-02T18:23:04Z" status="Introduced in House">National Statuary Hall Collection Progress Assurance Act

This bill establishes a timeline for the Joint Committee on the Library to approve or disapprove requests for replacing statutes (or any related actions that are subject to Joint Committee approval) in the National Statutory Hall of the U.S. Capitol. The Joint Committee oversees operations of the Library of Congress, as well as management of the National Statuary Hall, the U.S. Botanic Garden, and works of fine art in the Capitol.

 Generally, the bill requires the Joint Committee to approve or disapprove a request to replace a statue not later than 30 days after the Architect of the Capitol forwards the request to the Joint Committee. If the Architect forwards the request before the Joint Committee's first organizational meeting of a Congress, the Joint Committee must approve or disapprove the request not later than 30 days after the Architect forwards the request to the Joint Committee or the date of the meeting, whichever is later.</summary>
</bill>
