<bill session="115" type="s" number="1660" updated="2023-01-11T13:37:01Z">
  <state datetime="2017-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit the acceptance by political committees of online contributions from certain unverified sources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2017-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2017-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1341" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-20T21:36:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Foreign Donations Affecting Our Elections Act

This bill amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit political committees from accepting any Internet credit card contribution unless:

 the individual or entity making the contribution is required, at the time of the contribution, to disclose the credit card's verification value; and the billing address associated with the card is located in the United States or, if the contribution comes from an individual U.S. citizen living outside of the United States, the individual gives the committee the U.S. mailing address he or she uses for voter registration. The person receiving an Internet credit card contribution shall forward it to the treasurer of the political committee within 10 days, together with the name and address of the contributor and the date of receipt. The treasurer shall keep an account of the contributor's name and address, together with the date and amount of the contribution.</summary>
</bill>
