<bill session="110" type="s" number="2871" updated="2017-12-15T00:03:07Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reserve Education Assistance Program (REAP) Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Reserve Education Assistance Program (REAP) Enhancement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to recodify as part of that title chapter 1607 of title 10, United States Code, to enhance the program of educational assistance under that chapter, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2008-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001163" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2008-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military operations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-07-15T19:23:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reserve Education Assistance Program (REAP) Enhancement Act of 2008 - Recodifies and revises under federal veterans' benefits law a current chapter under federal armed forces law concerning educational assistance for reserve personnel supporting contingency operations and certain other operations.

Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs (Secretary) to carry out such assistance program. Directs the Secretary of each military department, and the Secretary of Homeland Security when it is not operating as a service in the Navy, to provide notice to individuals who meet program eligibility requirements.

Revises educational assistance allowance rates based on periods of active duty service.

Provides a ten-year limit after separation for the use of such assistance for a member of the Selected Reserve who completes a required period of service under other than dishonorable conditions.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to transfer to the Secretary, by the beginning of FY2010, amounts provided or remaining in the Department of Defense Education Benefits Fund that are attributable to the reserve educational assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
