<bill session="119" type="s" number="892" updated="2025-05-21T19:38:52Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the repayment by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of benefits misused by a fiduciary, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2025-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1912" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-21T19:38:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veteran Fraud Reimbursement Act of 2025

This bill modifies the procedures by which the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) reissues misused benefits to a beneficiary, including by requiring the VA to establish methods and timing with respect to determining whether an instance of misuse by a fiduciary is the result of negligence by the VA. The bill also provides that if a beneficiary predeceases a&#160;reissuance, the VA must pay the amount to a surviving beneficiary in the same method as certain other VA benefits are paid upon the death of a beneficiary.

Under the bill, the VA may not withhold the reissuing of a benefit payment by reason of a pending determination regarding the VA's negligence in relation to the instance of misuse by a fiduciary. Additionally, the VA is not required to make a determination regarding its negligence for each instance of misuse by a fiduciary of all or part of an individual's benefit paid to such fiduciary.</summary>
</bill>
