<bill session="117" type="s" number="1197" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">QUANTUM for National Security Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to apply public-private talent exchange programs in the Department of Defense to quantum information sciences and technology research, to increase coordination across agencies and emphasize opportunities in the Department for quantum information sciences and technology research, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">QUANTUM for National Security Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Quantum for Universal Advancement in Nationwide Technology Use and Modernization for National Security Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-24T18:30:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Quantum for Universal Advancement in Nationwide Technology Use and Modernization for National Security Act of 2021 or the QUANTUM for National Security Act of 2021

This bill addresses quantum science research and its role in national security through the Department of Defense (DOD).

For purposes of the public-private talent exchange program, DOD must ensure there are exchanges of personnel that are working on the modernization priorities of DOD, including quantum science and technology research.

Among other requirements, DOD must

 seek to establish public-private exchange programs in the Army, Navy, and Marine Corps focused on private sector entities working on quantum information sciences and technology research applications; implement the National Security Pipeline Pilot Program to seek to enter into partnerships with minority-serving institutions to diversify participants in the Science, Mathematics, and Research Transformation (SMART) Defense Education Program; and implement a fellowship program in quantum information science and technology research and development for individuals who have graduate or post-graduate degrees. The Government Accountability Office (GAO) must assess the National Quantum Initiative Program and report on its findings. Additionally, the GAO must brief Congress on its assessment of the quantum information fellowship program established by this bill.

The President must establish, through the National Science and Technology Council, a temporary Subcommittee on the Economic and Security Implications of Quantum Science.

The National Quantum Initiative Advisory Committee must include defense researchers and ensure the integration of DOD in committee actions and programs.</summary>
</bill>
