<bill session="115" type="h" number="4697" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:13Z">
  <state datetime="2017-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Wyoming Wilderness Act of 1984 to clarify authorized recreational uses in the Palisades, High Lakes, and Shoal Creek Wilderness Study Areas.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Wyoming Wilderness Act of 1984 to clarify authorized recreational uses in the Palisades, High Lakes, and Shoal Creek Wilderness Study Areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-04T16:27:53Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill amends the Wyoming Wilderness Act of 1984 to direct the Department of Agriculture, with respect to helicopter skiing in the Palisades Wilderness Study Area in the Bridger-Teton and Targhee National Forests in Wyoming, to authorize the number of permitted days of helicopter skiing to be at least the number of days specified in the High Mountain Heli-Skiing Final Environmental Impact Statement for certain national forest districts in Wyoming and Idaho, issued by the Forest Service on June 30, 2005.

Subject to such requirement, all recreational uses occurring before the enactment of this bill within the Palisades, High Lakes, and Shoal Creek Wilderness Study Areas, including horseback riding, snowmobiling, dirt bike riding, mountain biking, and helicopter skiing shall continue to be permitted in those areas.

The bill bars the construction of any recreational access points in such wilderness study areas, except by an express authorization of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
