<bill session="109" type="h" number="4844" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:00Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20T15:59:55-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-20T15:59:55-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require each individual who desires to vote in an election for Federal office to provide the appropriate election official with a government-issued photo identification, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to require any individual who desires to register or re-register to vote in an election for Federal office to provide the appropriate State election official with proof that the individual is a citizen of the United States to prevent fraud in Federal elections, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001022"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000429" joined="2006-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2006-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000447" joined="2006-04-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001144" joined="2006-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2006-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2006-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001143" joined="2006-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000796" joined="2006-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2006-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 4 - 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on House Administration. H. Rept. 109-666.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-19" calendar="Union" number="397">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 397.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-19T19:43:09-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1015 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4844 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Administration now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T13:11:21-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1015 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T13:45:49-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1015.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6765-6785" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T13:45:54-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4844 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit with or without instructions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on House Administration now printed in the bill shall be considered as adopted.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T13:46:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 4844.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:15:36-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6782" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:15:58-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Millender-McDonald moved to recommit with instructions to House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:16:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Millender-McDonald motion to recommit with instuctions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with an amendment in the nature of a substitute entitled "Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006" which inserts a complete new text.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:24:54-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6784-6785" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6782-6783" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:50:04-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 196 - 225 (Roll no. 458).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="459" datetime="2006-09-20T15:59:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 228 - 196 (Roll no. 459).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6765" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:59:56-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20T15:59:57-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="hr" number="1015" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Absentee voting"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Ballots"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Soldier voting"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1210"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-09-22T19:53:33Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on September 19, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Federal Election Integrity Act of 2006 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the appropriate state or local election official from providing a federal election ballot to an individual who desires to vote in person unless the individual presents to the official: (1) a government-issued, current, and valid photo identification (ID); or (2) for regularly scheduled federal general elections held in November 2010 and subsequent years, a government-issued, current, and valid photo ID for which the individual was required to provide proof of U.S. citizenship as a condition for issuance of the ID.

Requires an individual who does not present such an ID to be permitted to cast a provisional ballot in such an election. Requires such individual, however, to present the required ID within 48 hours after casting the provisional ballot, or the appropriate state or local election official may not determine the individual's eligibility to vote.

Requires individuals who vote other than in person in a federal election (for example, by mail) to submit a copy of such a photo ID with a ballot, or the appropriate official may not accept the ballot. Exempts from this requirement the absentee ballot of any eligible overseas military voter absent from the United States by reason of active duty or service.

(Sec. 3) Requires states to establish a program to provide photo IDs in accordance with this Act to individuals who desire to vote but do not otherwise possess a government-issued photo ID.

Provides that, if a state charges a fee for providing such a photo ID, the fee: (1) may not exceed the reasonable cost to the state of providing the ID; and (2) may not be charged to any individual who provides an attestation that the individual is unable to afford the fee.

Prohibits the use of any such photo IDs for any state or local government program or function other than election administration.

Requires the Election Assistance Commission to make payments to states to cover the costs incurred in providing photo IDs to individuals unable to afford the fee that would otherwise be charged.

Authorizes appropriations for FY2008 and following fiscal years.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-666</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
