<bill session="116" type="s" number="2971" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CAPTA Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">CAPTA Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CAPTA Reauthorization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend and reauthorize the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000055"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000300" joined="2019-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-15">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Alexander with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-01-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="408">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 408.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="85" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2969" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1160" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-28T20:42:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CAPTA Reauthorization Act of 2019 The bill revises and reauthorizes through FY2026 state and community-based child abuse and prevention grants programs. Specifically, the bill directs the Children&#8217;s Bureau of the Office of the Administration of Children and Families and state-level child protective service systems to use state grants to support (1) interagency coordination; (2) evidence-informed best practices; (3) services for underserved or overrepresented populations, including abandoned youth, victims of sexual abuse and exploitation, and unaccompanied homeless youth; and (4) addressing the link between child abuse and domestic violence, among other purposes.

The bill also revises various reporting requirements, including requiring states to provide more detailed information about the number and circumstances of child deaths that result from abuse and neglect. The bill further modifies the community-based grants program, through which a designated lead agency coordinates resources and develops continuity of care. Specifically, the lead agency must select local programs to support based on such program&#8217;s ability to (1) provide broad and comprehensive services, (2) involve parents, and (3) increase access to community-based and prevention-based services to underserved and overrepresented populations.

Such community-based grants also are revised to permit using funds for (1) assessments of community needs, (2) connecting individuals and families to nutrition programs; (3) referrals to workforce development programs; and (4) developing and maintaining kinship caregiver relationships, among other uses.</summary>
</bill>
