<bill session="108" type="s" number="1799" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Standards Development Organization Advancement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage the development and promulgation of voluntary consensus standards by providing relief under the anti-trust laws to standards development organizations with respect to conduct engaged in for the purpose of developing voluntary consensus standards, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standards Development Organization Advancement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2003-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1086" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Associations, institutions, etc."/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-09T19:42:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Standards Development Organization Advancement Act of 2003 - Amends the National Cooperative Research and Production Act of 1993 to provide that, in any action under the antitrust laws, the conduct of a standards development organization (SDO) while engaged in a standards development activity shall be subject to a rule of reason standard.Limits the amount recoverable and attorney's fees with respect to standards development activity engaged in by an SDO.States that an SDO may, not later than 90 days after commencing activity for the purpose of developing or promulgating voluntary consensus standards or 90 days after enactment of this Act, whichever is later, file simultaneously with the Attorney General and the Commission a written notification disclosing: (1) the name and principal place of business of the SDO; and (2) documents showing the nature and scope of such activity. Allows an SDO to file additional disclosure notifications as appropriate to extend protections under this Act to standards development activities that are not covered by, or that have changed significantly since, the initial filing.Includes standards development activity within notice, disclosure, and withdrawal from notification requirements of the Act.</summary>
</bill>
