<bill session="117" type="h" number="7452" updated="2023-06-22T03:45:54Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Updated Standards for Asylum (USA) Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to tighten asylum laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Updated Standards for Asylum (USA) Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="759" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1901" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6637" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="884" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-27T17:53:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Updated Standards for Asylum (USA) Act of 2022 

This bill modifies standards and requirements related to individuals seeking asylum.

 The bill amends the definition of credible fear of persecution to require that such fear can be established by statements that are more probable than not. The bill also imposes certain rules relating to credible fear interviews, including requirements for recordings and interpreters.

If an alien is granted asylum because of fear of persecution in a country, the alien shall be deemed to have renounced asylum status by returning to that country, if there has been no change in the country's conditions.

 Any individual who knowingly and willfully makes materially false statements or uses fraudulent documents in asylum-related proceedings shall be fined or imprisoned up to 10 years, or both.</summary>
</bill>
