<bill session="110" type="h" number="4189" updated="2023-01-11T20:11:42Z">
  <state datetime="2007-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Energy to provide for the re-enrichment of certain uranium tailings, and the sale of the product of such re-enrichment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Energy to provide for the re-enrichment of certain uranium tailings, and the sale of the product of such re-enrichment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000413"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2008-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001164" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2008-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-02-29T18:13:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Energy to contract with the operator of the Paducah Gaseous Diffusion Facility for the transfer from the Department of Energy's enrichment facility at Piketon, Ohio, to the Paducah facility of cylinders of uranium tailings with an assay of such value as the Secretary finds economically suitable for re-enrichment.

Requires such contract to provide for re-enrichment at the Paducah facility of the materials in the cylinders and in similar cylinders of comparable value.

Requires the Secretary to sell or contract for the sale of the product of such re-enrichment, whose net proceeds shall be deposited into the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund (UEDD Fund) and disbursed by appropriation for environmental remediation at the Paducah, Kentucky, and Portsmouth, Ohio, uranium enrichment facilities.

Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to reauthorize the UEDD Fund for an additional three years.</summary>
</bill>
