<bill session="111" type="h" number="5153" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:04Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1999 to modify the boundary of the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site in South Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-27">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="2726" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-01T16:40:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification Act - Amends the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Establishment Act of 1999 to modify the boundary of the Minuteman Missile National Historic Site in South Dakota by including in the Historic Site the following lands and interests in Jackson County, South Dakota, identified on the map entitled "Minuteman Missile National Historic Site Boundary Modification," and dated July 17, 2009: (1) approximately 25 acres of land north of exit 131 on Interstate 90 in Jackson County for the construction and use of a visitor facility and administrative site; and (2) approximately 3.65 acres of land at the Delta 1 Launch Control Facility for the construction and use of a parking lot and for other administrative purposes.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture (USDA) to transfer the administrative jurisdiction over such lands to the Secretary of the Interior and modify the boundaries of the Buffalo Gap National Boundary Grassland to exclude such land.</summary>
</bill>
