<bill session="111" type="h" number="6068" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paperwork Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 44, United States Code, to require each agency to include contact information for the agency in its collection of information.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paperwork Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2010-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-04T22:27:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Paperwork Assistance Act - Requires a federal agency to inform any person receiving a collection of information from the agency of the agency's contact information, including a website and a telephone number, by which a person may obtain a specific contact person responsible for answering questions about the information collection and other information to assist in responding to the information collection.

Requires the Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to include in the Director's annual report on information policy activities: (1) the status of implementation by agencies of the requirements of this Act; and (2) a description of how each agency has responded to complaints related to the agency's compliance with such requirements.

Makes this Act's contact information requirements applicable to new or revised collections of information approved by the Director beginning one year after enactment.</summary>
</bill>
