<bill session="116" type="h" number="8975" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DETOUR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deceptive Experiences To Online Users Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DETOUR Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the usage of exploitative and deceptive practices by large online operators and to promote consumer welfare in the use of behavioral research by such providers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001303"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Behavioral sciences"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T20:04:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Deceptive Experiences To Online Users Reduction Act or the DETOUR Act This bill prohibits large online operators from manipulating their products to mislead consumers into providing personal information or giving consent. The bill further prohibits these operators from (1) studying the behavioral patterns of subsets of users without first obtaining informed consent, (2) designing online products that lead to compulsive usage, or (3) designing products directed to children that lead to an increase in the use of products through which users interact with other users without parental consent. The bill also requires large online operators conducting psychological or behavioral research to disclose certain information, discontinue such research if consent was improperly acquired, and establish an independent review board.</summary>
</bill>
