<bill session="116" type="s" number="4986" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Security COVID Correction and Equity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security COVID Correction and Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent an unintended drop in Social Security benefits due to COVID-19 and the application of the National Average Wage Index, and improve Social Security and Supplemental Security Income benefits on an emergency basis.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-12-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7328" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6356" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7499" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-09T23:25:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Security COVID Correction and Equity Act This bill expands the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) benefits program, temporarily expands the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) program, and otherwise modifies these programs. Specifically, the bill revises OASDI benefits by (1) modifying funding formulas, (2) extending eligibility for certain benefits, and (3) increasing income thresholds used to determine the percentage of benefits subject to federal income tax. Changes to OASDI funding formulas include (1) increasing the primary insurance amount, (2) establishing new methods to calculate benefits for individuals with lifetime low earnings and for widows and widowers, and (3) modifiying application of the national average wage index to prevent certain reductions to benefits. In addition, children of a deceased, disabled, or retired worker remain eligible for OASDI benefits through age 22 if they are full-time students. Under current law, they receive benefits through age 18. The bill also extends dependent child benefits under the OASDI program to specified family members other than grandparents or step-grandparents, including in cases where a court grants custody of the dependent child to an eligible family member. To receive benefits under current law, either both parents must be disabled or deceased or a grandparent or step-grandparent must legally adopt the dependent child. The bill also temporarily increases income and resource limits for the SSI program, thereby temporarily expanding eligibility. This program helps aged, blind, and disabled individuals with limited income and resources meet their basic needs.</summary>
</bill>
