<bill session="116" type="h" number="1491" updated="2022-11-01T17:03:28Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Facilitating Innovation and New Technology so Entrepreneurs Create and Hire Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a FinTech Council to designate a single primary regulator of eligible FinTech startups, to create the Offices of Financial Innovation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Facilitating Innovation and New Technology so Entrepreneurs Create and Hire Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2019-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committees on Agriculture, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commodity Exchanges, Energy, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-07T17:33:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Facilitating Innovation and New Technology so Entrepreneurs Create and Hire Act of 2019 or the FINTECH Act of 2019 

This bill addresses the regulation of financial technology (fintech) start-ups. The FinTech Council is established within the Department of the Treasury. The council must designate, upon request by a fintech start-up, which federal financial regulators have exclusive oversight authority over that start-up. This designation lasts for two years and in general provides a safe harbor from enforcement actions by other regulators. To be eligible, a fintech start-up must meet certain requirements, including by demonstrating that they offer a financial innovation that serves the public interest.

In each federal financial regulatory agency there is established an Office of Financial Innovation. Duties of the office include coordinating agency efforts to reduce regulatory burdens on eligible start-ups and conducting outreach to a start-up in the event of a regulatory action.

The Advisory Council of FinTech Directors is established to provide advice to each federal financial regulator regarding the supervision of eligible fintech start-ups.</summary>
</bill>
