<bill session="118" type="h" number="1700" updated="2025-11-19T04:18:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ATF Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATF Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms, and Explosives to establish an administrative relief process for individuals whose applications for transfer and registration of a firearm were denied, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000469"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000235" joined="2024-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000589" joined="2024-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2023-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2023-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="632" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T19:32:18Z" status="Introduced in House">ATF Transparency Act

This bill modifies procedural requirements related to the transfer or making of firearms that are subject to regulation under the National Firearms Act (e.g., machine guns, short-barreled shotguns, and silencers).

The bill permits the transfer of a firearm if 90 days have elapsed since the application to transfer the firearm was filed, and the application has not been denied. Additionally, the bill establishes an administrative relief process with respect to an application to transfer that is denied.

The bill permits the making of a firearm if 90 days have elapsed since the application to make the firearm was filed,&#160;and the application has not been denied.

Finally, the bill requires reports on firearms-related background check inquiries that remain unresolved after 90 days and the percentage of firearms-related background check inquiries related to the transfer of a firearm that were administered by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</summary>
</bill>
