<bill session="118" type="h" number="5087" updated="2024-09-04T18:30:00Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SEAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Equity for Aquaculture and Seafood Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to submit a report to Congress on Department of Agriculture spending related to seafood purchases and grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2023-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001039" joined="2023-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001135" joined="2023-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001217" joined="2023-12-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2023-08-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-08-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-04T18:22:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Equity for Aquaculture and Seafood Act or the SEAS Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to increase support for aquaculture grants and assistance. (Aquaculture is the controlled breeding, rearing, and harvesting of fish, shellfish, and sea vegetables.)

Specifically, the bill directs USDA to give aquaculture producers the same consideration as animal agriculture producers in awarding grants or other assistance. Further, USDA must ensure adequate and fair funding levels for aquaculture producers under USDA programs. USDA must also provide its staff with specific education and trainings on aquaculture.&#160;

USDA must submit to Congress (1) an annual report that includes information on USDA seafood and aquaculture purchases and grants, and (2) a report on USDA's role in supporting aquaculture and the seafood industry.

USDA must make competitive grants (e.g., to regional aquaculture centers or nonprofit organizations) to develop next generation technology to reduce pollution and fuel usage in the seafood and aquaculture industries. Further, Agriculture and Food Research Initiative program grants must address methods of increasing the survival rate and adaptability of shellfish, including resistance to heat, disease, salinity, and acidification.

In addition, the federal crop insurance program (FCIP) must research and develop a policy to insure aquaculture products and the&#160;Federal Crop Insurance Corporation (the agency that finances FCIP operations) must establish a policy to insure aquaculture products.&#160;&#160;&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
