<bill session="117" type="s" number="615" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:47Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trans-Sahara Counterterrorism Partnership Program Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an interagency program to assist countries in North Africa and West Africa to improve immediate and long-term capabilities to counter terrorist threats, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trans-Sahara Counterterrorism Partnership Program Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2021-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="567" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-12T22:34:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Trans-Sahara Counterterrorism Partnership Program Act of 2021

This bill provides statutory authority for the Trans-Sahara Counterterrorism Partnership Program, an interagency program launched in 2005 to partner with countries in the Sahel and Maghreb regions of Africa to counter terrorism and violent extremism.

The Department of State, in consultation with the Department of Defense and the U.S. Agency for International Development,&#160;shall establish the partnership program, which must coordinate all U.S. programs in North and West Africa related to various counterterrorism activities, such as building&#160;foreign-military capacity, enhancing border security, promoting youth employment, and supporting independent media to counter terrorist propaganda.

The State Department must submit comprehensive, five-year strategies that include specified activities for the Sahel and Maghreb regions and for program counterterrorism efforts. Further, program activities must, among other things (1) be carried out in countries where there is an adequate level of partner country committment, and (2) have clearly defined outcomes and specific plans with indicators to regularly monitor and evaluate outcomes and impact. Such activities must also take into account the counterterrorism and development strategies of partner countries and align with such strategies to the extent possible.

The State Department shall notify Congress before obligating funds&#160;for such programs, and must submit annual reports about program activities.</summary>
</bill>
