<bill session="116" type="h" number="8987" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enhancing the Security of the U.S. Pharmaceutical Supply Chain Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing the Security of the U.S. Pharmaceutical Supply Chain Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to incentivize the manufacture of certain medicines in the United States and to enhance the security of the United States pharmaceutical supply chain, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-11T21:24:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing the Security of the U.S. Pharmaceutical Supply Chain Act of 2020

This bill provides tax credits for manufacturing certain priority medicines and establishes an expedited review procedure for drug manufacturers seeking to transition from foreign manufacturing to domestic manufacturing.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must publish annually a list of priority drugs and active pharmaceutical ingredients that (1) are necessary for use in a public health emergency, (2) are at high risk of becoming in short supply, and (3) have a vulnerable global supply chain. The bill provides a tax credit for 50% of a manufacturer's direct and indirect costs incurred in a taxable year for the production of a drug or active ingredient that was on this list in any of the five preceding years.

Furthermore, the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) must expedite the review and approval of a supplemental application that seeks to transfer manufacturing of an already-approved drug or active pharmaceutical ingredient to a domestic establishment. (A supplemental application generally involves a change, such as a manufacturing change, to an existing application for FDA market approval.) The bill imposes various requirements for this expedited review, including a deadline for the FDA to take action on such a supplemental application within six months of submission.

HHS shall also establish the Facility Transfer Working Group to assist with evaluating such applications and provide advice and feedback to applicants upon request.</summary>
</bill>
