<bill session="118" type="s" number="422" updated="2025-11-19T03:50:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Build the Wall Now Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Build the Wall Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remove legal impediments preventing construction of a border barrier along the international border between the United States and Mexico, improve the construction requirements for such barrier, make previously appropriated funds available for constructing such barrier until expanded, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1531" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="989" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-19T16:55:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Build the Wall Now Act

This bill resumes the construction of, and modifies the requirements for, a physical barrier along the U.S.-Mexico border.

 Specifically, the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must, within one day of the bill's enactment, resume any project related to the construction of such barriers (and any related infrastructure), and DHS may not cancel any contracts related to such construction that were entered into on or before January 20, 2021. Additionally, funds already appropriated for such construction must remain available until expended.

The bill also modifies the requirements for the physical barriers along the southern border and requires DHS to consult with the labor organization representing border patrol agents about the safety and effectiveness of the agents deployed in the vicinity of the barriers.

Finally, the bill exempts these construction projects from certain legal requirements, including requirements stemming from the Administrative Procedure Act, the Clean Air Act, the Clean Water Act, and the federal laws regarding public contracts.</summary>
</bill>
