<bill session="108" type="s" number="509" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:21Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy Market Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the authority of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to conduct investigations, to increase the penalties for violations of the Federal Power Act and Natural Gas Act, to authorize the Chairman of the Federal Energy Regulatory  Commission to contract for consultant services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Market Oversight Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000442" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2003-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2003-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3094-3101"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commodity exchanges"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Derivative securities"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Market manipulation"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy Market Oversight Act - Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to require that: (1) the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) refer to the appropriate Federal agency any contract for a derivative transaction or other financial transaction that FERC determines is not under its jurisdiction; (2) a FERC designee meet quarterly with specified agencies to discuss conditions in energy trading markets and legislative changes that may be appropriate to regulate such markets; and (3) maintain a liaison between the Commission and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission (CFTC).Amends the Natural Gas Act and the Federal Power Act to: (1) repeal subjection of the investigations authority of FERC to the consent of the Office of Management and Budget and any other Federal agency; and (2) increase criminal penalties for violations.Amends the Commodity Exchange Act to revise requirements for regulation of excluded swap transactions, transactions not on trading facilities, and other off-exchange transactions exempt from such Act but subject to regulations applicable to transactions on derivatives transaction execution facilities. Replaces the designation "electronic trading facilities" with "covered entities." Prescribes requirements for and limitations on CFTC regulation of covered entities. Authorizes the CFTC to establish core principles requiring a covered entity to monitor trading to prevent fraud and price distortion while ensuring adequate resources to discharge its responsibilities and comply with all reporting, notice, and registration requirements.Revises the prohibition against fraudulent transactions to state that such prohibitions do not impose on parties to transactions subject to the rules of designated contract markets or registered derivative transaction execution facilities any legal duty to provide counterparties or other market participants with any material market information.Sets a maximum civil penalty for commodity price manipulation of $1 million or triple the monetary gain for each violation, and a maximum ten-year prison term.</summary>
</bill>
