<bill session="108" type="hr" number="616" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:33Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Condemning the recent increase in acts of anti-Semitism in members countries of the European Union, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning the recent increase in acts of anti-Semitism in members countries of the European Union, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000575" joined="2004-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001058" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000597" joined="2004-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000179" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2004-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000590" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000587" joined="2004-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2004-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2004-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antisemitism"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Multicultural education"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-05T21:53:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that: (1) all countries should recognize the seriousness of anti-Semitic acts and should take action against those individuals and entities that incite hatred and perpetrate criminal acts against Jewish populations; (2) member countries of the European Union (EU) should continue to officially and publicly repudiate those individuals and entities that carry out such acts and should undertake tougher and more unified measures to combat the growth of anti-Semitic violence and intimidation throughout the European continent; (3) the EU should protect the safety of their Jewish communities through the establishment of the position of a director to monitor and combat anti-Semitism within the EU through education, media analysis, and coordination with responsible partners in each EU member country; (4) the delegates from the Organization for Security and Cooperation in Europe (OSCE) Conference on Anti-Semitism should call on their governments to make anti-Semitism a criminal offense and should establish within the OSCE a framework to monitor anti-Semitic activities, to monitor legislation to combat anti-Semitism, to coordinate between law enforcement organizations in such countries, and to implement relevant educational programs for the next generation of Europeans; (5) the President should direct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to work with EU member countries to secure passage of a resolution condemning anti-Semitism at the upcoming session of the United Nations General Assembly; and (6) combating acts of anti-Semitism worldwide through diplomatic efforts should be a U.S. foreign policy priority.</summary>
</bill>
