<bill session="108" type="s" number="2300" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:32Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense of Medicare Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003 to eliminate privatization of the medicare program and to reduce excessive payments to health maintenance organizations and other private sector insurance plans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense of Medicare Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000286" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000725" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2004-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2004-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3937"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Capitation (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Managed care"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical fees"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Prescription pricing"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-15T15:14:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Defense of Medicare Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in applying risk adjustment factors to payments to Medicare+Choice organizations under part C (Medicare+Choice) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), to ensure that payments to such organizations are adjusted based on factors that ensure that the health status of the enrollee is reflected in such adjusted payments, including adjusting for the difference between the health status of the enrollee and individuals enrolled under the original Medicare fee-for-service program under Medicare parts A (Hospital Insurance) and part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance). Requires payments to such organizations, in the aggregate, to reflect such differences.

Amends SSA title XVIII part C, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to: (1) revise the formula for determination of the minimum annual Medicare+Choice (Medicare Advantage) capitation rate for 2005 and subsequent years (making it the same as the minimum rate for 2004); and (2) eliminate the Medicare Advantage (MA) Regional Plan Stabilization Fund.

Repeals the Comparative Cost Adjustment Program.

Amends SSA title XVIII, as amended by the Medicare Prescription Drug, Improvement, and Modernization Act of 2003, to require the Secretary to ensure that each individual eligible for such program has available a choice of enrollment in at least two prescription drug plans (currently, at least two qualifying plans, which may be a prescription drug plan or a specified Medicare Advantage-Prescription Drug (MA-PD) plan).</summary>
</bill>
