<bill session="118" type="h" number="675" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-24">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Secure Space Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Secure Space Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure Space Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 to prohibit the Federal Communications Commission from granting a license or United States market access for a non-geostationary orbit satellite system if the license or grant of market access would be held or controlled by an entity that produces or provides any covered communications equipment or service or an affiliate of such an entity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001159" joined="2023-01-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 0 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 46 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-41.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-04-25" calendar="Union" number="27">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 27.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-01T18:23:00Z" status="Reported to House">Secure Space Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) from granting licenses or access to U.S. markets for geostationary or non-geostationary orbit satellite systems or authorizations for related earth-based stations that communicate with those systems to certain producers or providers of communications equipment or services. Specifically, the FCC may not grant a license, market access, or authorization to an entity that produces or provides equipment or a service that the FCC determines poses an unacceptable risk to national security or the security and safety of U.S. persons (e.g., Huawei Technologies Company and China Mobile International USA Inc.).

Geostationary satellite systems include satellites that stay in the same position relative to points on the Earth's surface. Non-geostationary satellite systems are comprised of satellites that do not maintain a stationary position but rather move in relation to the Earth's surface. Both types of systems may be used to provide broadband and other telecommunications services.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-41</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
