<bill session="116" type="h" number="2159" updated="2022-11-01T19:17:10Z">
  <state datetime="2019-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Diplomacy Modernization Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modernize and streamline the public diplomacy capabilities of the Department of State, increase evaluation of public diplomacy programming, enhance strategic planning for the Department's public diplomacy physical presence abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Diplomacy Modernization Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000824"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001157" joined="2019-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3352" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="482" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-29T19:31:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Public Diplomacy Modernization Act of 2019

This bill directs the Department of State to appoint a Director of Research and Evaluation in the State Department's Office of Policy, Planning, and Resources for Public Diplomacy and Public Affairs. The director's responsibilities shall include (1) overseeing research to improve State Department public diplomacy strategy and tactics, and (2) developing guidance and training for public diplomacy officers on interpreting and implementing public diplomacy-related research.

The bill permanently reauthorizes the U.S. Advisory Commission on Public Diplomacy and directs the commission to establish the Subcommittee for Research and Evaluation. The subcommittee shall provide advice regarding audience research, digital analytics, and impact evaluation for State Department activities.

The bill directs the State Department's Under Secretary for Public Diplomacy to consolidate various executive support functions for all the bureaus reporting to the under secretary. The under secretary shall also identify opportunities to improve operations efficiency and to maximize the shared use of resources.

The State Department shall adopt certain guidelines related to collecting and utilizing information in the event of a closure or consolidation of a public diplomacy facility.</summary>
</bill>
