<bill session="117" type="h" number="8216" updated="2022-12-29T17:33:56Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Citizenship and Media Literacy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Citizenship and Media Literacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote digital citizenship and media literacy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001208"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4490" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-12T16:00:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Citizenship and Media Literacy Act

This bill directs the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to award grants to state and local educational agencies, public libraries, and qualified nonprofit organizations to develop and promote media literacy and digital citizenship education for elementary and secondary school students.

Media literacy includes the ability to access relevant information, analyze media content, evaluate the accuracy of information, and make educated decisions based on information obtained from media and digital sources.

Digital citizenship includes the ability to safely, responsibly, and ethically use communication technologies and to participate in the political, economic, social, and cultural aspects of life related to technology and the digital world.</summary>
</bill>
