<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="189" updated="2022-04-02T07:16:19Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3617" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-04-01T11:51:54-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-04-01"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part B of House Report 117-285 to direct the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) to conduct a study on the impact of legalization to the workplace, using states that have legalized recreational use of cannabis as a guide, and to require NIOSH to develop best practices for employers as companies transition their policies related to cannabis, prioritizing employers engaged in federal infrastructure projects, transportation, public safety and national security. To direct the Department of Education to conduct a study on the impact of legalization to schools and school aged children, using states that have legalized recreational use of cannabis as a guide, and to require the Department of Education to develop best practices for educators and administrators to protect children from any negative impacts.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment directs the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (NIOSH) to conduct a study on the impact of legalization to the workplace, using states that have legalized recreational use of cannabis as a guide, and to require NIOSH to develop best practices for employers as companies transition their policies related to cannabis, prioritizing employers engaged in federal infrastructure projects, transportation, public safety and national security.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-04-01T11:51:54-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="104">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lamb amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 189 (Roll no. 104).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T10:51:20-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A003) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T10:41:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Lamb.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4107-4108" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4107" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T10:41:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Lamb.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T11:51:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Lamb amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 189 (Roll no. 104).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T11:51:54-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01T11:51:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lamb amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 234 - 189 (Roll no. 104).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
