<amendment session="116" chamber="h" number="668" updated="2022-02-08T23:01:03Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4863" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2019-11-15T11:23:02-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001209"/>
  <offered datetime="2019-11-14"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 4 printed in House Report 116-289 to expand the prohibition of the Board of Directors from approving a transaction unless the person receiving the Agencys support certifies that the person does not engage in any activity in contravention of any U.S. law, regulation, or order concerning sanctions relating to the illegal trafficking of synthetic opioids, including any sanctions imposed pursuant to the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment expands the prohibition on the Board of Directors of the Export-Import Bank from approving a transaction unless the person receiving the Agency's support certifies that the individual does not engage in any activity in contravention of any U.S. law, regulation, or order concerning sanctions relating to the illegal trafficking of synthetic opioids, including any sanctions imposed pursuant to the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2019-11-15T11:23:02-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="619">
      <text>On agreeing to the McAdams amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 414 - 1 (Roll no. 619).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8896-8897" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14T15:56:01-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. McAdams.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8862-8863" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8862" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:23:02-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14T15:56:01-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A004) offered by Mr. McAdams.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8862-8863" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8862" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:23:02-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the McAdams amendment (A004) Agreed to by recorded vote: 414 - 1 (Roll no. 619).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-15T11:23:02-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
