<bill session="108" type="s" number="2127" updated="2023-01-15T10:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stabilization and Reconstruction Civilian Management Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to build operational readiness in civilian agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Stabilization and Reconstruction Civilian Management Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stabilization and Reconstruction Civilian Management Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2004-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2004-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1593-1594"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1594-1596" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-03">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-481.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-18">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Lugar under authority of the order of the Senate of 03/12/04 without amendment. With written report No. 108-247.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-03-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="460">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 460.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3996" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Civil War"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Haiti compilation"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Military civic action"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Promotions"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Volunteer forces"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-04-21T20:16:52Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Stabilization and Reconstruction Civilian Management Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) States that the purpose of this Act is to provide for the development, as a core mission of the Department of State and the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), of an expert civilian response capability to carry out stabilization and reconstruction activities in a country or region that is in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife.

(Sec. 4) Expresses the sense of Congress respecting specified steps to improve stabilization and reconstruction activities.

(Sec. 5) Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the President to furnish assistance and permit the export of goods and services to assist in stabilizing and reconstructing a country or region that is in, or is in transition from, conflict or civil strife. Authorizes: (1) $100 million for such assistance; and (2) appropriations as necessary to replenish such initial authorization.

(Sec. 6) Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to direct the Secretary of State to establish within the Department of State an Office of International Stabilization and Reconstruction, to be headed by a Coordinator. Sets forth Office functions, including: (1) monitoring political and economic instability, and planning for stabilization and reconstruction responses: (2) developing interagency coordination; (3) identifying appropriate State, local, and private sector personnel; and (4) coordinating joint military-civilian planning.

(Sec. 7) Authorizes: (1) the Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of USAID, to establish a Response Readiness Corps (up to 250 personnel to serve in the Corps, and such other personnel as the Secretary may designate from the Department of State and USAID) to provide stabilization and reconstruction activities in foreign countries or regions that are in, or are in transition from, conflict or civil strife; and (2) the Secretary to establish a Response Readiness Reserve of Federal and non-Federal personnel to augment the Corps.

Directs the Secretary to report on efforts to establish the Response Readiness Corps and the Response Readiness Reserve.

(Sec. 8) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize the Secretary, in cooperation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of the Army, to establish a stabilization and reconstruction curriculum for use in programs of the Foreign Service Institute, the National Defense University, and the United States Army War College.

(Sec. 9) States that service in stabilization and reconstruction operations overseas, membership in the Response Readiness Corps, and education and training in the stabilization and reconstruction curriculum should be considered among the favorable factors for promotion of employees of executive agencies. Authorizes the creation of incentives and benefits to recognize and reward participants.

(Sec. 10) Sets forth personnel provisions.

(Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations for personnel, education and training, equipment, and travel costs. Obligates amounts for the Office of International Stabilization and Reconstruction.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-247</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
