<bill session="116" type="h" number="7815" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Desert Tortoise Habitat Conservation Plan Expansion Act, Washington County, Utah</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Desert Tortoise Habitat Conservation Plan Expansion Act, Washington County, Utah</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the expansion of the Desert Tortoise Habitat Conservation Plan, Washington County, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001192"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Reptiles"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-09T18:06:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Desert Tortoise Habitat Conservation Plan Expansion Act, Washington County, Utah

This bill directs the Department of the Interior to amend and renew the Desert Tortoise Habitat Conservation Plan, Washington County, Utah, and approve such amendment and renew such plan and the permit that was issued for such plan under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (ESA), for a 25-year period.

Interior must amend the resource management plans for the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area, the Red Cliffs National Conservation Area, and the Red Cliffs Desert Reserve, Zone 6, and shall seek to acquire those lands through exchange or by purchase or donation.

Interior shall manage the Red Cliffs Desert Reserve, Zone 6, as a land bank to provide mitigation credits for future disturbances of the reserve, including utility disturbances and the construction of the Northern Transportation Corridor.

In the permit extended by the ESA, Interior shall credit Washington County a mitigation credit (1) for the tortoises protected on nonfederal lands in Zone 6; and (2) for those tortoises successfully translocated and surviving, based on survivorship and juvenile recruitment estimates.

The Red Cliffs National Conservation Area shall consist of approximately 45,000 acres of public and nonfederal land in Washington County, Utah.

Interior shall recognize on federally managed lands a 150 foot-wide transportation and utility corridor through the Beaver Dam Wash National Conservation Area.</summary>
</bill>
