<bill session="118" type="s" number="2134" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Smoke Exposure Crop Insurance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smoke Exposure Crop Insurance Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Crop Insurance Act to require research and development regarding a policy to insure wine grapes against losses due to smoke exposure, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2227-2228" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4308" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural insurance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Alcoholic beverages"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-17T17:54:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Smoke Exposure Crop Insurance Act of 2023

This bill requires the federal crop insurance program (FCIP) to provide for the research and development of a policy to insure wine grapes (including wine grapes produced in California, Oregon, and Washington) against losses due to wildfire smoke exposure. (The term policy means an insurance policy, plan of insurance, provision of a policy or plan of insurance, and related materials.) The Federal Crop Insurance Corporation, the agency that finances FCIP operations, must make any resulting policy available that meets specified FCIP requirements.

The FCIP must also submit a report to Congress on the research and any resulting policy. The report must include an evaluation of the feasibility of a policy that allows producers to claim an indemnity through post-harvest, post-vinification testing if such testing demonstrates smoke damage that was not detectable prior to harvest.</summary>
</bill>
