<bill session="118" type="h" number="878" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to appoint an Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety Technology, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to appoint an Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety Technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-28T15:07:53Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to appoint an Associate Administrator for Aviation Safety Technology and establish a rulemaking committee on aviation safety technologies. Under the bill, aviation safety technology is airborne or ground-based equipment that is meant to reduce the occurrence of aviation accidents (e.g., auto take-off, navigation, and taxi technology; navigation technology; and remote piloting technology).

Specifically, the new associate administrator's responsibilities include coordinating, developing, and implementing a variety of processes and measures for FAA certification and operational approval of aviation safety technologies.

Further, the aviation rulemaking committee must make recommendations for the development of&#160;a detailed roadmap for the certification and operational approval of aviation safety technologies by the FAA, with a focus on technologies, software, and automation to enhance operational safety. The committee must also issue a notice of proposed rulemaking based on any consensus recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
