<bill session="116" type="s" number="2711" updated="2022-11-01T04:17:42Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">END ALL Hazing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Notification and Disclosure of Actions risking Loss of Life by Hazing Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">END ALL Hazing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require institutions of higher education to disclose hazing-related misconduct, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2019-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2019-11-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2020-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-11-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3267" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-26T16:36:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Educational Notification and Disclosure of Actions risking Loss of Life by Hazing Act or the END ALL Hazing Act

This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) that participate in federal student-aid programs to collect information and publicly report on hazing-related misconduct.

Specifically, IHEs must prepare biannual reports and post such reports on their websites. The reports must include information on hazing-related misconduct committed by a student organization, including the name of the student organization that committed the violation, a description of the violation, and sanctions placed on the organization.

IHEs must report to campus police and law enforcement authorities within 72 hours of becoming aware of any allegation of hazing that involved serious bodily injury or a significant risk of serious bodily injury.

The bill does not apply to foreign IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
