<bill session="118" type="s" number="1476" updated="2025-11-19T03:21:35Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pharmaceutical Research Transparency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pharmaceutical Research Transparency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to increase the transparency of pharmaceutical research costs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3160" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-06T12:57:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pharmaceutical Research Transparency Act of 2023

This bill requires the disclosure of costs associated with clinical trials and pharmaceutical research and development.

Specifically, the National Institutes of Health must create a publicly available repository of cost data from certain clinical trials that test the efficacy of drugs, biological products, and devices in human subjects. For each applicable trial, the registry must, among other information, include the total and per patient cost of the trial, as well as costs for personnel, health care services, and other categories of expenditures. Information must be added to the registry within one year of the trial's completion.

The bill also requires drug manufacturers to include their research and development expenditures for drugs and biological products in annual disclosures made to the Securities and Exchange Commission.</summary>
</bill>
