<bill session="116" type="s" number="1427" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Leadership in Advanced Manufacturing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Global Leadership in Advanced Manufacturing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Leadership in Advanced Manufacturing Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Institute of Standards and Technology Act to improve the Network for Manufacturing Innovation Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000562" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2019-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-16">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Wicker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-291.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-11-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="584">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 584.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Materials"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T15:01:03Z" status="Reported to Senate">Global Leadership in Advanced Manufacturing Act of 2019

This bill expands the scope of the Network for Manufacturing Innovation program, makes changes to the funding design for the centers for manufacturing innovation, and directs interagency collaboration to develop national certifications for advanced manufacturing workforce skills.

The Network for Manufacturing Innovation program established a nationwide network of centers for manufacturing innovation, each of which has a unique technological concentration. The bill expands the definition of a center for manufacturing innovation to make eligible for inclusion in the program a center that has a predominant focus on innovative sectors (e.g., food manufacturing, superconductors, and quantum information science).

Further, the Department of Commerce must establish a regional innovation program to encourage and support the development of regional innovation strategies designed to increase innovation-driven economic opportunity within their respective regions.

The bill also strikes provisions that progressively decrease the amount of financial assistance provided to a center over a term of years and subsequently cut the center's funding entirely after seven years, replacing them with a continuing five-year, metrics-based review of a center.

Additionally, the bill (1) directs Commerce to collaborate with relevant federal departments and agencies when awarding financial assistance, and (2) authorizes Commerce to collaborate with stakeholders for the development of national certifications for advanced manufacturing workforce skills in the respective technology area of each center.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-291</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
