<bill session="109" type="s" number="2108" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:18Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Backcountry Landing Strip Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure general aviation aircraft access to Federal land and to the airspace over Federal land.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Backcountry Landing Strip Access Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2005-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2006-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="4970" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air routes"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Airspace (Law)"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Private aviation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-02-02T17:39:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Backcountry Landing Strip Access Act - Prohibits the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture from taking any action that would permanently close, restrict, render or declare as unserviceable any aircraft landing strip located on federal land under their respective jurisdiction, unless: (1) the head of the aviation department of each state in which the aircraft landing strip is located approves the action; (2) notice of the proposed action has been published in the Federal Register; (3) a public comment period on the action has been provided; and (4) the relevant Secretary and the head of the aviation department of each state in which the affected aircraft landing strip is located have taken into consideration any comments received during the comment period.

Directs the Secretaries to: (1) adopt a nationwide policy for governing backcountry aviation issues related to the management of federal land under their jurisdiction; and (2) require regional managers to adhere to it. Declares that a policy affecting air access to an aircraft landing strip located on federal land will not take effect unless certain conditions are met.</summary>
</bill>
