<bill session="117" type="h" number="2555" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CARE for Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to establish a grant program to provide grants to local agencies and clinics to improve the health of mothers and infants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE for Families Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Access, Resources, and Education for Families Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2021-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-16T11:25:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Community Access, Resources, and Education for Families Act or the CARE for Families Act

This bill sets out a grant program and other requirements to facilitate collaboration between the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) and various social services.

Specifically, the bill establishes a grant program to promote and support linkages between WIC agencies and health care providers, early childhood care providers, and other social services providers.

Additionally, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must undertake an initiative to improve communication between state and local WIC agencies and medical providers regarding WIC participants' health information. As part of the initiative, USDA must support the development of software or systems to facilitate such communication and promote bidirectional interoperability between WIC information systems and electronic health records. USDA must also ensure that any disclosure of health information is consistent with federal privacy standards for personal health information.</summary>
</bill>
