<bill session="117" type="s" number="4295" updated="2022-12-29T16:48:34Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Data Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Data Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend securities and banking laws to make the information reported to financial regulatory agencies electronically searchable, to further enable the development of regulatory technologies and artificial intelligence applications, to put the United States on a path towards building a comprehensive Standard Business Reporting program to ultimately harmonize and reduce the private sector's regulatory compliance burden, while enhancing transparency and accountability, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2022-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2022-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2022-09-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-02T16:04:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Financial Data Transparency Act of 2022

This bill requires federal financial regulatory agencies to adopt specified data standards with respect to format, searchability, and transparency.

The bill also decreases, beginning September 30, 2031, the cap on the surplus funds of the Federal Reserve banks. (Amounts exceeding this cap are deposited in the general fund of the Treasury.)

The Government Accountability Office must report on the feasibility of applying the taxonomy established by this bill to the wider federal government.</summary>
</bill>
