<bill session="109" type="h" number="6007" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:32Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To address critical needs for additional resources, coordination between Federal, State, and local law enforcement, and supplemental funding, to support border security activities of State and local law enforcement agencies, including sheriffs, in regions near an international land border of the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address critical needs for additional resources, coordination between Federal, State, and local law enforcement, and supplemental funding, to support border security activities of State and local law enforcement agencies, including sheriffs, in regions near an international land border of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Cameras"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal aliens"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-09-21T20:16:03Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate a high-threat area (five-year designation period) adjacent to a U.S. international land border for a border area security initiative in order to provide state and local agencies, including sheriffs, with resources and capabilities to: (1) assist the Secretary in gaining operational border control in the area; (2) address increased cross-border criminal activity in the area; and (3) reduce national security threats posed by terrorists entering the United States at an international land border.

Sets forth high-threat area designation criteria.

States that upon designation the Secretary shall: (1) establish a border area security initiative executive committee comprised of senior executives from local, state, and federal domestic security and law enforcement agencies, including sheriffs, to develop multi-agency enforcement strategies and activities to support federal border security missions; (2) provide for additional federal resources to be sent to the area, including personnel, equipment, and technology; (3) provide for the construction or acquisition of temporary detention facilities; and (4) provide funds to state and local law enforcement entities, including sheriffs, for personnel, operational, and equipment expenses.</summary>
</bill>
