<bill session="116" type="s" number="4340" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:34Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SACRED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SACRED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Americans from Coronavirus and Religious Exercise Discrimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that a State or local jurisdiction is ineligible to receive or use funds allocated, appropriated, or authorized to address COVID-19 if that State or jurisdiction discriminates against religious individuals or religious institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2020-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4537" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-18T20:03:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding Americans from Coronavirus and Religious Exercise Discrimination Act or the SACRED Act

This bill makes a state or local jurisdiction that discriminates against religious individuals or religious institutions ineligible to receive or use funds allocated, appropriated, or authorized to address COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, a state or local jurisdiction violates this bill's prohibition if it (1) enforces, or announces the intent to enforce, any law, regulation, policy, order, proclamation, or decree related to COVID-19 that discriminates against religious individuals or religious institutions; or (2) provides, or shows an intention to provide, funds to a separate jurisdiction that is ineligible to receive or use those funds because the jurisdiction has committed a violation.

The Department of Justice shall determine whether a state or local jurisdiction is ineligible to receive or use such funds.</summary>
</bill>
