<bill session="117" type="s" number="1278" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Military Installations and Ranges Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States to review any purchase or lease of real estate near a military installation or military airspace in the United States by a foreign person connected to or subsidized by the Russian Federation, the People's Republic of China, the Islamic Republic of Iran, or the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Military Installations and Ranges Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2021-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2728" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-17T18:41:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Military Installations and Ranges Act of 2021

This bill places restrictions on the purchase of certain property by a foreign person who is owned or controlled by, is acting for or on behalf of, or receives subsidies from Russia, China, Iran, or North Korea.

Specifically, the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States must review a purchase or lease by, or a concession to, any such foreign person of private or public real estate in the United States that is within (1) 100 miles of a military installation; or (2) 50 miles of a military training route, special use airspace, a controlled firing area, or a military operations area.

Further, the Department of Defense and the Department of Transportation may not issue final determinations regarding specified projects (e.g., energy projects) that involve a transaction under review by the committee until the committee concludes its action.</summary>
</bill>
