<bill session="111" type="h" number="834" updated="2022-02-03T06:07:16Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ramos and Compean Justice Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Ramos and Compean Justice Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 44 of title 18, United States Code, to exempt certain peace officers from certain minimum sentencing requirements for using a firearm to commit a crime of violence during or in relation to their employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2009-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-01T18:48:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Ramos and Compean Justice Act of 2009 - Amends the federal criminal code to provide that provisions imposing additional terms of imprisonment for using or carrying a firearm during and in relation to any crime of violence or drug trafficking crime shall not apply to a person if: (1) the offense occurred during or in relation to the performance of peron's duties as a peace officer; (2) the firearm is of the same type as the firearm authorized to be carried by the person in the performance of those duties; and (3) the crime during and in relation to which the offense occurred is a crime of violence.

Defines "peace officer" to mean an officer or employee of the federal government, or of a state or local government, who is authorized by law to carry a firearm in the lawful performance of his or her duties.</summary>
</bill>
