<bill session="118" type="s" number="1123" updated="2025-01-14T17:07:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MARTTE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Managing Active and Reserve Tech Talent Effectively Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MARTTE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure computer programming, coding, and artificial intelligence capabilities in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-07T00:31:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Managing Active and Reserve Tech Talent Effectively Act of 2023 or the MARTTE Act of 2023

This bill requires the military departments to establish and implement policies related to human capital infrastructure for the purposes of leveraging computer programming capabilities of personnel. Human capital infrastructure means the policies and processes that support development, training, evaluating, and tracking of personnel with specific occupational skills, experiences, and positions (e.g., personnel software).

First, the bill sets forth a policy of the Armed Forces to establish human capital infrastructure that allows the military departments to provide the combatant commands a qualified and known occupational standard (i.e., a defined, reviewed, and published standard) with respect to computer programming skills.

Second, the bill sets forth a policy of the Armed Forces to utilize human capital infrastructure to bolster the capacity of the reserve components to evaluate, track, and provide the military departments with a qualified and known occupational standard with respect to computer programming occupational areas.

With regard to each of the policies established under the bill, each military department must

 develop, discharge, and implement the policies; establish human capital infrastructure to provide the combatant commands with force capability associated with computer programming, coding, and artificial intelligence skills; and submit to Congress an implementation plan for the policies established in this bill, including an update on the implementation of the policy in budget justification materials from FY2025 and onward until all plan milestones have been met.</summary>
</bill>
