<bill session="115" type="h" number="6532" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:57Z">
  <state datetime="2018-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to update and improve eligibility criteria for the Social Security Disability Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000592"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2018-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="2031" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="3385" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-09-07T15:57:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Making DI Work For All Americans Act of 2018



 This bill revises requirements&#160;related to&#160;the Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance (OASDI) benefits program, the Supplemental Security Income (SSI) benefits program, and disability&#160;determinations made by&#160;the Social Security Administration (SSA).

Specifically, the bill:

 applies the judicial code of conduct applicable to U.S. judges to administrative law judges (ALJs) for the SSA, prohibits the SSA from prescribing certain fees regarding the representation of claimants for OASDI and SSI benefits, permits the SSA to withhold less than the amount required to correctly adjust a recipient's OASDI benefits amount under certain conditions, disqualifies an individual from receiving OASDI benefits&#160;for any month for which the individual receives unemployment-insurance benefits, eliminates the application stages for reconsideration reviews of disability determinations, increases the frequency of benefits-eligibility reviews, and decreases the amount of time provided to an individual to apply for OASDI benefits and receive funds retroactively from the first month of eligibility.Additionally, the SSA must: review a sample of decisions in favor of claimants for OASDI benefits from outlier ALJs, update the medical-vocational guidelines used in disability determinations, consider any relevant evidence from a claimant's social media prior to issuing a disability determination, update the data used to determine the full range of work available to individuals in the national economy, ensure that communications between the SSA and an individual eligible for OASDI benefits include a description of the individual's responsibility to report to the SSA on any change of circumstance that may affect such individual's eligibility, and include unearned income in the determination of an individual's substantial gainful activity.</summary>
</bill>
