<bill session="117" type="h" number="9356" updated="2023-08-02T15:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESILIENCE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESILIENCE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Resources for Emergency and Security Infrastructure Logistics In Every Neighborhood to Curb Extremism Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program for State, local, Tribal, and territorial government officials to be trained by the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency regarding carrying out security vulnerability or terrorism risk assessments of critical infrastructure facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000040"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-02T15:35:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Resources for Emergency and Security Infrastructure Logistics In Every Neighborhood to Curb Extremism Act of 2022 or the RESILIENCE Act of 2022

This bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) to establish a pilot program to train state, local, tribal, and territorial government officials&#160;to carry out security vulnerability or terrorism risk assessments of critical infrastructure. CISA must also maintain one or more clearinghouses for critical infrastructure owners and operators to access security guidance and other relevant information.</summary>
</bill>
