<bill session="110" type="h" number="3194" updated="2023-01-11T21:18:07Z">
  <state datetime="2007-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the H-1B nonimmigrant program by increasing the exchange of information between the Departments of Labor and Homeland Security.</title>
    <title type="display">H1B Strengthening Anti-Fraud Effectiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">H1B SAFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">H1B Strengthening Anti-Fraud Effectiveness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000447"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Employers' liability"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Skilled labor"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-10-24T20:38:15Z" status="Introduced in House">H1B Strengthening Anti-Fraud Effectiveness Act or H1B SAFE Act - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security, if the Secretary has specific information concerning an employer's improper hiring of a nonimmigrant H-1B alien (temporary employment in a specialty occupation or as a fashion model), to provide the Secretary of Labor with such information which may be used to initiate a Department of Labor compliance investigation.

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to require an employer filing an H-1B labor condition application with the Department of Labor to include the application number on the subsequent H-1B petition filed with the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).</summary>
</bill>
