<bill session="116" type="s" number="4329" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Continuous Health Coverage for Workers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuous Health Coverage for Workers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide premium assistance for COBRA continuation coverage, church plan continuation coverage, and furloughed continuation coverage for individuals and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001197"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2020-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4714" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Employment taxes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-25T16:35:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continuous Health Coverage for Workers Act

This bill provides health insurance premium assistance through 2020 for individuals who become unemployed, are furloughed, or receive a reduction in hours. Specifically, the bill treats premiums as paid for individuals who pay a specified minimum amount toward the premium and (1) are terminated from employment and elect to continue insurance coverage through the COBRA (Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act) program, (2) receive a greater than 30% reduction in paid hours but remain eligible for coverage under a group health plan, or (3) have been terminated or receive reduced hours for the duration of time that their employers voluntarily offer coverage under a church health plan.

The bill also specifies requirements for individuals changing, or enrolling in, health plans under the program. Additionally, the bill requires employers to provide eligible individuals specified written notice about the premium assistance program, including, among other information, available health plan enrollment options and the date that such assistance expires.

The Department of the Treasury must reimburse employers, group health plans, and insurance issuers through a payroll tax credit or refund for unpaid premiums that were treated as paid under the program.

Premium assistance is not considered income for federal income tax purposes.</summary>
</bill>
