<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="322" updated="2022-02-25T17:31:04Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1540" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-05-26T12:59:45-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to limit use of funds to transfer individuals who are not United States citizens or members of the Armed Forces to the United States until 45 days after the President has submitted to the Congressional defense committees a plan for the disposition of each individual who is proposed to be transferred to the United States. The amendment also sought to hold open the use of Article 3 courts as a means of trying individuals (detainees) when such individuals or detainees are transferred to the United States.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 42 printed in House Report 112-88 to amend Section 1039 to allow transfer of detainees to the US to testify in federal court. The amendment strikes language barring transfer of detainees held abroad to the US. The amendment requires certification by the Attorney General prior to transfer.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-05-26T12:59:45-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="356">
      <text>On agreeing to the Smith (WA) amendment (A022) Failed by recorded vote: 165 - 253 (Roll no. 356).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3723-3724" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:43:39-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A022) offered by Mr. Smith (WA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3641-3643" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3641" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T12:59:45-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T12:59:45-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-26T12:59:45-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Smith (WA) amendment (A022) Failed by recorded vote: 165 - 253 (Roll no. 356).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3723-3724" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:43:39-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A022) offered by Mr. Smith (WA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3641-3643" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3641" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
