<bill session="117" type="h" number="5298" updated="2022-12-31T08:59:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to provide assistance for common interest communities, condominiums, and housing cooperatives damaged by a major disaster, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000002"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2022-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2021-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2021-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-04T13:05:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Disaster Assistance Equity Act of 2021

This bill makes common interest communities, such as housing cooperatives (co-ops) and condominiums, eligible for the same assistance from the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) as other homeowners.

Specifically, the bill

 adds definitions of residential common interest community, condominium, and housing cooperative to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; requires FEMA to issue rules for the removal of debris or wreckage from real estate owned by a residential common interest community resulting from a major disaster and deems such removal to be in the public interest when a state or local government determines in writing that such debris or wreckage constitutes a threat to life, public health or safety, or the economic recovery of such community; and provides for the repair of essential common elements of a condominium or co-op damaged by a disaster under FEMA's Federal Assistance to Individuals and Households Program.</summary>
</bill>
