<bill session="117" type="h" number="6605" updated="2022-12-30T04:18:58Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate Security Intelligence Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Security Intelligence Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to make permanent the Climate Security Advisory Council of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001121"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2022-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2022-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2022-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-29T16:45:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Climate Security Intelligence Act of 2022

This bill permanently authorizes the Climate Security Advisory Council (currently authorized until December 31, 2025). The bill also requires the advisory council to report to Congress a plan to permanently establish a Climate Security Intelligence Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence.

The plan must contain recommendations relating to the proposed center's duties, which shall include (1) serving as the primary intelligence community organization addressing the climate security intelligence needs and priorities of policymakers, (2) analyzing U.S. climate security risks and U.S. influence on climate policies around the world, and (3) conducting strategic forecasting for future climate security risks and opportunities.

The plan shall also include a proposed process for transferring recommended functions and duties from the advisory council to the center.</summary>
</bill>
