<bill session="118" type="s" number="1902" updated="2025-11-19T04:31:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hydrogen Aviation Strategy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydrogen Aviation Strategy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretary of Energy to exercise leadership in the creation of Federal and international policies relating to the safe and efficient use of hydrogen to increase aviation decarbonization and reduce air and noise pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4032" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Spacecraft and satellites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-16T17:33:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hydrogen Aviation Strategy Act

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) and the Department of Energy (DOE) to exercise leadership in the creation of federal and international policies relating to the safe and efficient use of hydrogen to increase aviation decarbonization and reduce air and noise pollution.

For example, the FAA and DOE must

 establish positions and goals for the use of hydrogen to increase aviation decarbonization; study (through grants, contracts, or interagency agreements) how the use of hydrogen would contribute to aviation decarbonization and air and noise pollution; study ways of accelerating the introduction of hydrogen-powered aircraft; and establish an advisory committee composed of representatives of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, the aerospace industry, aviation suppliers, hydrogen producers, airlines, airport sponsors, fixed base operators, and other stakeholders to advise the Department of Transportation, the FAA, and DOE on related activities. The FAA must also exercise leadership in the creation of federal regulations, standards, and guidance relating to the safe and efficient use of hydrogen to increase aviation decarbonization and reduce air and noise pollution.</summary>
</bill>
