<bill session="117" type="h" number="7575" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Green Jobs and Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Green Jobs and Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and Secretary of Education, to submit a report on current and future trends and shortages in the clean energy technology industry to achieve a clean energy economy, and to provide grants to establish and enhance training programs for any occupation or field of work for which a shortage is identified, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000630"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-29T12:37:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Green Jobs and Opportunity Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to address current and future workforce shortages within the clean energy technology sector.

Labor must monitor trends and shortages within the sector, recommend ways to prepare the workforce to meet the demands of a clean energy economy, and provide grants to establish training programs for occupations or fields of work with such shortages.

Labor must also establish a National Advisory Committee on the Clean Energy Technology Workforce to provide advice on preparing the workforce to transition to a clean energy economy.</summary>
</bill>
