<bill session="117" type="h" number="2477" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Urban Forests Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide support for urban forests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Forests Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000317"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2022-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2021-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2022-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2022-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2021-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2639" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-30T15:52:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Urban Forests Act of 2021

This bill provides for support to maintain urban forests.

The Department of Agriculture (USDA) shall establish a grant program to be known as the Tree City USA Grant Program to provide competitive grants to qualifying local governments to enhance and maintain urban forests.

USDA and the Department of Labor shall jointly establish Civilian Conservation Centers in urban and community areas.

A specified five-year report on state forests and their resources shall contain an analysis of forest carbon over the previous two decades. Such report shall demonstrate the efforts taken by the Forest Service to

 conduct a strategic national forest inventory by measuring field plots in combination with advanced technology to improve data, information, and estimates of precision; and use advanced geospatial technologies to improve the area and volume estimates of those field plots, especially for sub-state regions and smaller areas. USDA shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Departments of Health and Human Services, Housing and Urban Development, the Interior, Labor, and Transportation and the Environmental Protection Agency to

 identify strategies to increase equitable access to urban forests through existing programs and authorities; and conduct research on the benefits of urban forests for air quality, heat island mitigation, energy burden reduction, and enhanced shading for heat-resilient housing and active transit.</summary>
</bill>
