<bill session="117" type="h" number="6752" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DELETE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Data Elimination and Limiting Extensive Tracking and Exchange Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DELETE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a centralized system to allow individuals to request the simultaneous deletion of their personal identifiers across certain data brokers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000482"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3627" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-07T18:42:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Data Elimination and Limiting Extensive Tracking and Exchange Act or the DELETE Act This bill establishes a process for the deletion of personal information held by data brokers (i.e., entities that collect or obtain personal information for commercial purposes from individuals with whom they do not have a direct relationship). First, it requires the Federal Trade Commission to issue rules requiring data brokers to (1) register with the commission, (2) provide specified contact information, and (3) disclose certain data collection practices. Second, the commission must establish a centralized system to allow individuals to make a single request for the deletion of any of their personal information held by a data broker (or an affiliated legal entity). Each data broker must delete the personal information not later than 31 days after a request is made. An individual who submits a deletion request also must be added to a do-not-track list and registered data brokers are prohibited from collecting personal information about that individual. The bill provides for enforcement of these requirements by the commission.</summary>
</bill>
