<bill session="110" type="s" number="2924" updated="2017-12-15T00:04:24Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Original Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Bullion Coin Act</title>
    <title type="display">Original Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Bullion Coin Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the production of Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle ultra-high relief bullion coins in palladium to provide affordable opportunities for investments in precious metals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2008-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="5614" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Sculpture"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-30T15:57:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Original Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle Ultra-High Relief Bullion Coin Act - Permits the Secretary of the Treasury to mint and issue a $20 coin that bears, on the obverse and reverse, the designs of the famous 27-millimeter version of the 1907 Augustus Saint-Gaudens Double Eagle ultra-high relief gold piece.

Authorizes the Secretary to commence minting and issuing such coins for sale, beginning January 1, 2009.

Prohibits the coins, regardless of the composition, from being made available as so-called "fractional" coins.

States that no more than 25,000 shall be available for sale in a special "Golden Age of American Coinage" set.

Requires the Secretary to take specified protective and anti-counterfeiting measures.

Instructs the Treasury Inspector General to report to certain congressional committees on the extent of counterfeiting of rare, collectible, or numismatic coins for sale in the United States, regardless of the country where the original of such coin was produced or of the country in which the counterfeiting takes place, or sales overseas if such counterfeit coins are unauthorized copies of coins originally produced by the United States Mint.</summary>
</bill>
