<bill session="116" type="s" number="3526" updated="2022-02-08T23:15:15Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Taxpayer's Return on Investment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Taxpayer's Return on Investment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restrict the authority of the Secretary of the Treasury to purchase or guarantee assets in response to the coronavirus disease (COVID-19) outbreak.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6379" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Income tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-11T18:47:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting Taxpayer's Return on Investment Act of 2020

This bill sets forth requirements for the purchase or guarantee of a company's assets by the Department of the Treasury in response to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic. Specifically, as a condition of such a transaction, companies must provide a warrant (i.e., the right to purchase company stock in the future at a specified exercise price) or a senior debt instrument to Treasury. The exercise price for a warrant must be set by Treasury for the primary benefit of taxpayers.

Treasury is generally prohibited from purchasing or guaranteeing assets from an inverted domestic corporation (i.e., a domestic corporation that has been restructured to incorporate in a foreign jurisdiction for tax purposes) in response to COVID-19.

An entity receiving specified assistance in response to COVID-19 may not claim the trade or business expenses tax deduction for the amount an individual employee is compensated above $500,000.</summary>
</bill>
