<bill session="117" type="h" number="5046" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Chemical and Biological Weapons Control and Warfare Elimination Act of 1991 to impose sanctions against governments of foreign states that engage in an act or acts of gross negligence with respect to state owned, operated, or directed chemical or biological programs.</title>
    <title type="display">Holding Countries Accountable for Negligent Chemical and Biological Programs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Holding Countries Accountable for Negligent Chemical and Biological Programs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000446"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, and Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4792" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-23T14:08:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Holding Countries Accountable for Negligent Chemical and Biological Programs Act

This bill authorizes initial, intermediate, and final sanctions against countries that act grossly negligent (i.e., knew or should have known that an act or acts would harm another foreign state) with respect to a chemical or biological weapons program.

Before imposing initial sanctions, the President must determine that a country acted with gross negligence. Following such a determination, the President must impose the initial sanctions (e.g., suspending scientific cooperative programs and restricting U.S. government contracting with entities operating in chemical or biological sectors of a sanctioned country).

Within 120 days of imposing initial sanctions, the President must determine whether the country has taken adequate steps to redress its sanctionable conduct. If the country has not taken adequate steps, the President must impose intermediate sanctions (e.g., terminating financial assistance and prohibiting arms transactions).

Within 210 days of imposing intermediate sanctions, the President must again determine whether the country has taken adequate steps to redress its sanctionable conduct. If the country has not taken adequate steps, the President must impose final sanctions (e.g., prohibiting certain transactions in foreign exchange or transfers of credit or payment).

The sanctions may be removed after 12 months if the President certifies a country adequately redressed the sanctionable conduct. The bill also authorizes waivers of the sanctions, subject to certain restrictions.

Furthermore, the President must determine and report to Congress about whether China meets the criteria for gross negligence with respect to its chemical or biological weapons program.</summary>
</bill>
