<bill session="112" type="h" number="3349" updated="2019-11-15T20:51:48Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reserve Equality in Education Act</title>
    <title type="display">National Guard and Reserve Equality in Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to recognize the distance education program developed by the Department of Defense to provide advanced joint professional military education through a combination of non-resident and resident instruction as equivalent to the joint professional military education phase II program consisting of exclusively of resident instruction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000577" joined="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-15T20:16:54Z" status="Introduced in House">National Guard and Reserve Equality in Education Act - Authorizes the use of a combination of Department of Defense (DOD) distance learning for advanced professional military education and resident instruction (under current law, only resident instruction) for the joint professional military education phase II program.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to retroactively award credit for phase II completion for each officer who, before the enactment of this Act, completed the DOD distance education program through a combination of distance learning and resident instruction, but was awarded credit for only phase I joint professional military education.</summary>
</bill>
