<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="516" updated="2022-02-03T04:57:41Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2844" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-04-22T15:38:30-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000557"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-04-22"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to delete provisions establishing a 10-day deadline for parties to nominate candidates in a special election and substitutes language that provides that candidates would be eligible to run in a special election if that candidate meets the requirements to get on the ballot as set by state law; and allow states to extend the deadline for a special election.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part B of House Report 108-466 which s eeks to permit the state to extend the overall 45-day deadline to the extent necessary to ensure that the ballots containing the names of all eligible candidates are prepared and distributed to absentee voters and to ensure all candidates are given sufficient time to prepare for the election.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-04-22T15:38:30-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="129">
      <text>On agreeing to the Larson (CT) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 217 (Roll no. 129).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22T14:23:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Larson (CT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2326-2328, H2331, H2332" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2326" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22T14:23:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Larson (CT).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2326-2328, H2331, H2332" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2326" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22T15:38:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22T15:38:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Larson (CT) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 188 - 217 (Roll no. 129).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22T15:38:30-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
