<bill session="110" type="s" number="1929" updated="2023-01-11T20:36:30Z">
  <state datetime="2008-05-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to conduct a feasibility study of water augmentation alternatives in the Sierra Vista Subwatershed.</title>
    <title type="display">Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000303" joined="2007-08-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10621"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-02-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-376.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman without amendment. With written report No. 110-360.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="792">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 792.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3328" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-08-27T22:13:39Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Sierra Vista Subwatershed Feasibility Study Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, through the Commissioner of Reclamation, to complete a feasibility study of alternatives to augment water supplies in the Sierra Vista Subwatershed, Arizona, that are identified as appropriate for further study in a Bureau of Reclamation appraisal report dated June 2007.

Directs the Secretary, in evaluating the feasibility of alternatives, to: (1) include any required environmental reviews, the construction, operations, maintenance, and replacement costs for each alternative, and the economic feasibility of each alternative; (2) take into consideration the ability of government and private sources to fund such costs; (3) establish the basis for any cost-sharing allocations and any anticipated repayment of federal contributions; and (4) perform a cost-benefit analysis.

Limits the federal share of total costs of the study to 45%. Permits the nonfederal share to be in the form of in-kind services that the Secretary determines would contribute substantially toward the conduct and completion of the study. Expresses the intent of Congress that the Secretary complete the study within 30 months of enactment. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 110-360</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
