<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="827" updated="2022-02-03T06:01:59Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2250" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-10-11T19:27:08-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000133"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-10-11"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill, add the following section:    SEC. 6. PROTECTION FROM AVOIDABLE CASES OF CANCER.    Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the Administrator shall not delay actions pursuant to the rules identified in section 2(b) of this Act to reduce emissions from waste incinerators or industrial boilers at chemical facilities, oil refineries, or large manufacturing facilities if such emissions are increasing the risk of cancer.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 7 printed in the Congressional Record to insert a section stating that the Administrator shall not delay actions to reduce emissions from waste incinerators or industrial boilers at chemical facilities, oil refineries, or large manufacturing facilities if such emissions are increasing the risk of cancer.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-10-11T19:27:08-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="774">
      <text>On agreeing to the Markey amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 166 - 252 (Roll no. 774).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:59:55-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Markey.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6700-6702, H6723-6724" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6700" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:27:08-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:27:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Markey amendment (A008) Failed by recorded vote: 166 - 252 (Roll no. 774).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T19:27:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11T15:59:55-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A008) offered by Mr. Markey.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6700-6702, H6723-6724" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6700" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-11">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
