<bill session="111" type="h" number="4228" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:59Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require the Forest Service to accommodate, to the extent consistent with the management objectives and limitations applicable to the National Forest System lands at issue, individuals with mobility disabilities who need to use a power-driven mobility device for reasonable access to such lands.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Forest Service to accommodate, to the extent consistent with the management objectives and limitations applicable to the National Forest System lands at issue, individuals with mobility disabilities who need to use a power-driven mobility device for reasonable access to such lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000361"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Agriculture</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-08">
      <text>Referred to House Natural Resources</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-17T20:45:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, through the Chief of the Forest Service, to require Forest Service personnel, in the implementation of off-road vehicle management under the Forest Service Travel Management Rule, to endeavor to accommodate individuals with mobility disabilities who would need to use a power-driven mobility device for access to such lands.

Requires Forest Service personnel to provide an individual with mobility disabilities who uses a power-driven mobility device to access specific National Forest System lands, who seeks permission to access such lands, and who is denied such access, with an explanation for the denial of access to such lands.</summary>
</bill>
