<bill session="117" type="h" number="1728" updated="2023-04-26T20:00:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strategy and Investment in Rural Housing Preservation Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide rental assistance to low-income tenants in certain multifamily rural housing projects financed by the Rural Housing Service of the Department of Agriculture, and to develop and implement a plan for preserving the affordability of rural rental housing, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategy and Investment in Rural Housing Preservation Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000378"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000586" joined="2021-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1537" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1603" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2820" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4872" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-20T19:20:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Strategy and Investment in Rural Housing Preservation Act of 2021

This bill provides assistance to rural, multifamily rental-housing projects and tenants.

Specifically, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must implement a program for the preservation and revitalization of such housing projects that are financed with USDA loans. As part of this program, USDA may restructure existing housing loans by reducing or eliminating interest and deferring loan payments.

When offering to restructure such a loan, USDA must also offer to renew a property owner's contract for rental assistance payments for a term of 20 years, provided that the property owner agrees to maintain the property as decent, safe, and sanitary housing for the full term of the contract.

USDA must annually provide written notice explaining the options to restructure such loans to certain property owners.

Additionally, USDA may provide technical assistance grants to qualified nonprofit organizations and public housing agencies to help borrowers acquire multifamily rental-housing properties in areas where there is a risk of loss of affordable housing.

Further, USDA may provide rural housing vouchers for low-income households (including those not receiving rental assistance) residing in certain properties financed with or insured by USDA loans.

The bill also extends existing housing protections for victims of domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, and stalking to victims who receive rural housing voucher assistance. These protections include protections against denial or termination of assistance or eviction.</summary>
</bill>
