<bill session="117" type="s" number="3196" updated="2023-03-06T00:51:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the policies, procedures, and training for midshipmen at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2021-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="597">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 597.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5964" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-28T18:14:48Z" status="Reported to Senate">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act

This bill addresses sexual harassment, sexual assault, and other policies, procedures, and training for midshipmen at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy.

For example, the Department of Transportation (DOT) shall establish a Sexual Assault Advisory Council to review the academy's policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking and other relevant matters related to sexual assault and sexual harassment.

The DOT's Maritime Administration shall (1) establish an information management system to track and maintain information regarding claims and incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking involving cadets at the academy; (2) implement comprehensive in-person sexual assault risk-reduction and response training for all midshipmen at the academy; and (3) require a biannual survey of midshipmen, faculty, and staff of the academy assessing the inclusiveness of the environment at the academy and an annual survey assessing the inclusiveness of the environment of the Sea Year program.

Additionally, the bill designates a Special Victims' Advisor to provide legal assistance to any cadet of the academy who is the victim of a sex-related offense.

Further, the Coast Guard shall assess the feasibility of implementing a program modeled on the Catch a Serial Offender program of the Department of Defense. The bill also expands the authority of the Coast Guard to suspend or revoke a mariner's license on grounds related to sexual harassment or assault.</summary>
</bill>
