<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>4119</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:17:17Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:17Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-11-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2009-11-23T18:41:26Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-11-19T15:04:45Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>637</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-07-23</actionDate>
          <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-91.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-19</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000571</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Rehberg, Denny [R-MT-At Large]</fullName>
        <firstName>DENNY</firstName>
        <lastName>REHBERG</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Electric power generation and transmission</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Missouri River</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Montana</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>North Dakota</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water resources funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water use and supply</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Water Resources Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-11-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-03-07T15:50:30Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to enter into a cooperative agreement to provide federal assistance for the planning, design, and construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System for specified counties in Montana and North Dakota.</p> <p>Lists agreement requirements. Limits the federal share of planning, design, and construction of the System to 75% of the total cost. Delineates the components of System facilities for which federal funds may be expended and the System's service area. Limits the obligation of funds for construction. Provides that any cost relating to the System's operation, maintenance, or replacement shall not be a federal responsibility and shall be paid by the System.</p> <p>Directs the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration to make available to the System a quantity of power required, up to one and a half megawatt capacity, to meet the System's pumping and incidental operation requirements between May 1 and October 31 of each year from the water intake facilities and through all pumping stations, water treatment facilities, reservoirs, storage tanks, and pipelines up to the point of delivery of water by the water supply system to all storage reservoirs and tanks and each entity that distributes water at retail to individual users. Makes the System eligible to receive power only if it operates on a nonprofit basis and is constructed pursuant to the agreement. Sets forth provisions regarding the purchase of additional power and the Authority's responsibility for power charges, non-federal delivery costs, and non-federal transmission and distribution system delivery and service arrangements.</p> <p>Directs the Authority to develop a water conservation plan containing a description of water conservation objectives and measures and a schedule for carrying out such measures. Requires the plan to be designed to ensure that users of water provided by the System use the best practical technology and management techniques to conserve water.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To authorize the construction of the Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System in the State of Montana and a portion of McKenzie County, North Dakota, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in House</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IH</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Dry-Redwater Regional Water Authority System Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2009-11-19T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111hr4119ih/xml/BILLS-111hr4119ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-11-23</actionDate>
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
