<bill session="117" type="h" number="383" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include certain eligibility requirements in the surface transportation system funding alternatives program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2021-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E59-60"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-22T15:04:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Road User Charge Advancement Act of 2021

This bill revises the Surface Transportation Systems Funding Alternatives program. The program provides grants to states to demonstrate user-based alternative revenue mechanisms that utilize a user fee structure to maintain the long-term solvency of the Highway Trust Fund.

Specifically, the bill revises the program to

 set forth certain eligibility requirements, ensure that activities carried out using grant funds include test solutions to ensure the privacy and security of data collected for the purpose of implementing a user-based alternative revenue mechanism, increase the maximum amount of federal share that may payable for the costs of an activity from 50% to 80% of the total costs, and modify reporting requirements for the Department of Transportation to include annually publishing a report that contains a determination of the characteristics of the most successful mechanisms with the highest potential for future widespread deployment. The bill also provides funding for FY2022-FY2025 to carry out the program.</summary>
</bill>
