<bill session="116" type="s" number="4144" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:42Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act with respect to sport fish restoration and recreational boating safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2020-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4828" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T17:04:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sport Fish Restoration and Recreational Boating Safety Act of 2020

This bill reauthorizes through FY2025 and modifies use of the Sport Fish Restoration and Boating Trust Fund, which provides funding for several things, including fisheries conservation and management, water and boating infrastructure, and recreational boating safety. The bill modifies use of the Federal Aid to Wildlife Restoration Fund, which supports wildlife restoration, conservation, and hunter education and safety programs.

The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to report on (1) the increasing use of nonmotorized vessels and their impacts on motorized and nonmotorized vessel access, (2) user conflicts at waterway access points, (3) the use of Sport Fish Restoration Program funds to improve nonmotorized vessel access and the reasons for providing such access, and (4) the use of Recreational Boating Safety Program funds for nonmotorized boating safety programs.

The GAO shall consult with the Sport Fishing and Boating Partnership Council and the National Boating Safety Advisory Council on study design, scope, and priorities for the report.</summary>
</bill>
