<bill session="117" type="h" number="6208" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:04Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VET CARE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET CARE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Early Treatment for Chronic Ailment Resurgence through Examinations Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide administrative support to providers of dental care who provide such care to veterans that is not furnished under such title, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program for the provision of dental care to certain veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001257"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000465" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000462" joined="2022-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2021-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-04T10:27:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Early Treatment for Chronic Ailment Resurgence through Examinations Act of 2021 or the VET CARE Act of 2021

This bill addresses dental care programs for veterans. Specifically, the bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to furnish administrative support to a dental care provider that provides services to a veteran that would not be covered by VA benefits.

The bill also requires the VA to implement a pilot program to provide free outpatient dental services and treatment, and related dental appliances, to eligible veterans. Eligible veterans are those who are (1) enrolled in the VA health care system but are not eligible for VA dental care, (2) not receiving regular periodontal care, (3) between 40 and 70 years old, and (4) diagnosed with type 2 diabetes.</summary>
</bill>
