<bill session="109" type="s" number="1105" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:06Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">International and Foreign Language Studies Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VI of the Higher Education Act of 1965 regarding international and foreign language studies.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International and Foreign Language Studies Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5788-5789"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-24T19:25:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">International and Foreign Language Studies Act of 2005 - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 (HEA) to extend the authorization of appropriations for international education programs under title VI: (1) part A, international and foreign language studies; (2) part B, business and international education; and (3) part C, Institute for International Public Policy (IIPP). Authorizes the Secretary of Education to use up to 1% of title VI funds for program evaluation, outreach, and information dissemination.

Revises VI-A to: (1) include support for instructors of less commonly taught languages among activities of national language and area centers and programs; (2) make undergraduate students eligible for fellowships for foreign language and area or international studies (in addition to graduate students under current law); (3) allow a portion of funds for undergraduate international studies and foreign language programs to be used for subgrants to undergraduate students for educational programs abroad that promote foreign language literacy and cultural knowledge, and are closely linked to grant program goals; (4) authorize the Secretary of Education to support data collection, analysis, and dissemination that helps achieve VI-A purposes; and (5) add to authorized uses of funds for technological innovation and cooperation for foreign information access.

Revises VI-C to authorize the IIPP to provide summer stipends and Ralph Bunche scholarships for needy students to participate in IIPP programs. Authorizes: (1) waiver of an eligible recipient's match requirement for a professional development program; (2) broader institutional development; (3) advanced degrees in international relations; and (4) biennial reports.</summary>
</bill>
