<bill session="109" type="h" number="3515" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:32Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Truth in Automobile Insurance Rates Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to require persons who are plan administrators of employee pension benefit plans or provide administrative services to such plans, and who also provide automobile insurance coverage or provide persons offering such coverage identifying information relating to plan participants or beneficiaries, to submit to the Federal Trade Commission certain information relating to such automobile insurance coverage.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Truth in Automobile Insurance Rates Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Employer-Employee Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-29T22:56:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Truth in Automobile Insurance Rates Act of 2005 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to require that certain information relating to automobile insurance coverage be submitted to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) by persons: (1) who are plan administrators of employee pension benefit plans or provide administrative services to such plans; and (2) who also provide automobile insurance coverage or provide persons offering such coverage identifying information relating to plan participants or beneficiaries.</summary>
</bill>
