<bill session="108" type="h" number="4228" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Acquisition System Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for an improved acquisition system.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acquisition System Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000981" joined="2004-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-05">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competitive bidding"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government ethics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication systems"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="United States Postal Service"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-09T20:03:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Acquisition System Improvement Act - Authorizes the assignment from a Federal agency to a private sector organization, or from a private sector to a Federal agency, of employees who work in Federal acquisition or acquisition management, who are considered exceptional performers, and who are expected to assume increased acquisition management responsibilities.

Modifies share-in-savings contract authority with respect to defense contracts and under the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to remove provisions limiting the use of such contracts to information technology.

Requires inflation adjustments to acquisition-related dollar thresholds.

Extends through FY 2009 the use of special simplified procedures for purchases of commercial items in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold.

Mandates that the Federal Acquisition Regulation be revised to require, in the procurement of telecommunications services, that such services include redundant and separate points of entry and diverse local network facilities.

Establishes in: (1) the Department of Defense the Department of Defense Board of Contract Appeals; and (2) the General Services Administration the Civilian Board of Contract Appeals to resolve Federal contract disputes.

Requires procedures for expediting the disposition of appeals in cases of small business concerns where the disputed amount is $150,000 or less.

Makes the authority of the Defense and Civilian Boards applicable to: (1) contracts at or below the simplified acquisition threshold; and (2) contracts for the procurement of commercial items.

Transfers personnel, funds, and property of the: (1) Armed Services Board of Contract Appeals to the Defense Board of Contract Appeals; and (2) other Boards of Contract Appeals (with exceptions) to the Civilian Board of Contract Appeals.

Specifies the jurisdiction of the Defense and Civilian Boards.

Establishes the Postal Service Board of Contract Appeals (having jurisdiction respecting the U.S. Postal Service and the Postal Rate Commission).</summary>
</bill>
