<bill session="111" type="h" number="5165" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:04Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Education in the Classroom Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title V of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to State educational agencies in order to provide subgrants to eligible local entities to promote financial education to students in the classroom.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Education in the Classroom Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000243"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Financial literacy"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-06T15:17:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Education in the Classroom Act of 2010 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award competitive grants to states and, through them, competitive subgrants to local educational agencies (LEAs) that partner with certain nonprofit, educational, community-based, or business entities to develop and carry out financial education programs to assist students in kindergarten through grade 12 achieve financial literacy.

Authorizes the Secretary to award a competitive grant to a national nonprofit educational organization to improve the quality of financial education programs directly and through subgrants to states, LEAs, and state or local economic, personal finance, or entrepreneurial education organizations. Requires such grant or subgrant funds to be used for: (1) teacher training regarding economics, personal finance, and entrepreneurship; (2) evaluations of the impact economic and financial literacy education has on students; (3) incorporating economics and personal finance into school curricula; (4) economic and financial literacy education research; and (5) the development and dissemination of appropriate materials and best practices to promote economic and financial literacy.</summary>
</bill>
