<bill session="111" type="h" number="4416" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:47Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reauthorize the Great Ape Conservation Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2010-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001140" joined="2010-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2010-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-650.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-09-29" calendar="Union" number="388">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 388.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-14T16:30:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Ape Conservation Reauthorization Amendments Act of 2010 - Amends the Great Ape Conservation Act of 2000 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to award a multiyear grant to an eligible person to implement a great ape conservation project that the person demonstrates is an effective, long-term conservation strategy for great apes and their habitats.

Requires the Secretary to convene a panel of experts to identify the greatest needs and priorities for the conservation of great apes within a year of this Act's enactment and every five years thereafter (current law authorizes the Secretary to convene a panel to consider the greatest conservation needs every two years). Requires the panel to consider relevant great ape conservation plans or strategies, including: (1) applicable strategies or plans developed or initiated by the Secretary; (2) the Global Strategy for the Survival of Great Apes and their Habitat, or subsequent reports, developed by the United Nations Environment Programme Great Apes Survival Partnership; (3) regional or species-specific action plans developed by the International Union for the Conservation of Nature Primate Specialist Group; (4) relevant conservation strategies, plans, or initiatives developed by the Species Survival Network Primate Working Group; and (5) other applicable strategies, plans, or scientific research and findings related to the conservation needs and priorities of great apes. Authorizes the Secretary to pay expenses of convening and facilitating meetings of the panel.

Authorizes appropriations for the Great Ape Conservation Fund for FY2011-FY2015.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-650</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
