<bill session="109" type="h" number="3511" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:32Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicaid State Long-Term Care Partnership Program Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to expand State long-term care partnership programs under the Medicaid Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid State Long-Term Care Partnership Program Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2005-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001037" joined="2006-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000287" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000163" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001134" joined="2005-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2005-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000263" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000422" joined="2005-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2006-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000459" joined="2005-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Insurance agents"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care insurance"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Welfare eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-12T18:40:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicaid State Long-Term Care Partnership Program Act of 2005 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) with respect to the requirement that a state seek adjustment or recovery of any medical assistance correctly paid on behalf of an individual under the state plan in the case of an individual who has received (or is entitled to receive) benefits under a long-term care insurance policy in connection with which assets or resources are disregarded in specified manner.

Converts to a discretionary option the current requirement that the state seek adjustment or recovery from an individual's estate on account of medical assistance paid on the individual's behalf for nursing facility and other long-term care services. Exempts from application of such authority the case of an individual who received medical assistance under a state plan of a state which has a state plan amendment that provides for a qualified state long-term care insurance partnership.

Defines "qualified state long-term care insurance partnership" to mean a state plan amendment under title XIX that provides for the disregard of any assets or resources in an amount equal to the insurance benefit payments that are made under a long-term care insurance policy, regardless of whether the policy was issued before the effective date of such plan amendment, if specified requirements are met.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promote the education of consumers regarding qualified state long-term care insurance partnerships.</summary>
</bill>
