<bill session="111" type="h" number="4328" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:56Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to award credit toward the service of a sentence to prisoners who participate in designated educational, vocational, treatment, assigned work, or other developmental programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000185"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-21T20:13:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Literacy, Education, and Rehabilitation Act - Amends the federal criminal code to allow a prisoner serving a term of imprisonment of more than one year to receive credit beyond time already served for up to 60 days each year, in addition to any credit received for satisfactory behavior, for earning a certificate of completion in, or for participating in or teaching, a designated program that benefits prisoners or the Bureau of Prisons, including specified educational and vocational, treatment, and work and developmental programs.

Requires the Director of the Bureau to establish the number of days of credit a prisoner may be awarded considering the difficulty, time required, responsibility expected, and rehabilitative benefits of the program.

 Makes any person sentenced to a term of imprisonment under the Attorney General's custody eligible for the credits, including prisoners transferred from foreign countries.

Allows: (1) federal prisoners to earn up to 54 days of credit toward the service of a sentence for each year of the prisoner's sentence imposed by the court if the Bureau determines the prisoner has displayed exemplary compliance with institutional disciplinary regulations; and (2) the Bureau to restore credit previously denied to a prisoner, based on such prisoner maintaining good behavior.</summary>
</bill>
