<bill session="118" type="h" number="519" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Act of December 19, 1913 (38 Stat. 242), to expand access to the Hetch Hetchy Reservoir and Lake Eleanor Basin areas for recreational purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001177"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-13T17:57:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Yosemite National Park Equal Access and Fairness Act

This bill makes changes with respect to the Hetch Hetchy Reservoir and Lake Eleanor Basin areas of Yosemite National Park.

Specifically, the bill increases rent paid by the San Francisco Public Utilities Commission for the use of the park from $30,000 to $2 million per year. That amount shall be adjusted annually to reflect increases in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers. The commission may not recoup such sums from wholesale water or power customers. The bill allows collected rent to be used by the Department of the Interior for wildfire mitigation activities in the park and other national parks in California.

The bill requires the National Park Service to administer the Hetch Hetchy Reservoir and Lake Eleanor Basin areas for public recreation, benefit, and use in a manner that will preserve scenic, historic, scientific, or otherwise important features.</summary>
</bill>
