<bill session="118" type="h" number="4488" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Voter Identification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Voter Identification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to establish certain photo identification requirements for voting in District of Columbia elections and to require proof of citizenship to register to vote in District of Columbia elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2023-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2023-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4487" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4396" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4494" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-23T14:26:09Z" status="Introduced in House">American Confidence in Elections: District of Columbia Voter Identification Act

This bill establishes citizenship and identification requirements to vote in the District of Columbia (DC).

The bill requires an individual to provide documentary proof that they are a U.S. citizen to register to vote in DC.

Additionally, the bill requires an individual to present&#160;current and valid identification to vote or to receive a ballot&#160;(i.e., when not voting in person). Acceptable identification includes a DC driver's license, U.S. passport, military identification, or student identification. The bill also requires an election official to obtain proof of residency for any voter whose identification does not include the voter's current address.

Further, DC must provide certain identification (e.g., a driver's license)&#160;at no cost to an individual&#160;who&#160;is unable to afford the fee.&#160;

Finally, the bill requires election officials to compile photographs of all eligible DC voters in the poll book used to administer elections. The bill authorizes and directs the DC government to obtain such photo records from DC government records, by photographing voters, or by making a copy of a voter's photo identification. The bill prohibits the photo records included in the poll book from being used for purposes other than for the administration of DC elections.</summary>
</bill>
