<bill session="117" type="h" number="7714" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">OUR Public Buildings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">OUR Public Buildings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Outlease Reform in Public Buildings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 40, United States Code, to establish requirements for outleasing certain Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2022-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4901"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-04T15:45:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Outlease Reform in Public Buildings Act or the OUR Public Buildings Act

This bill establishes requirements for outleasing certain federal buildings.

Specifically, the General Services Administration (GSA) must develop and require the use of standard clauses to use in any outlease agreement that

 is for a public building that is at least 150,000 gross square feet; is entered into by the GSA and a private entity; for which the leased space totals at least 51% of the usable square feet of the building; and for which the term of the lease, including options, is in excess of five years. Any such agreement must require the lessee to submit a form disclosing any foreign ownership interest in the outlease.

The GSA may not enter into such an outlease with the President, the Vice President, the head of an executive agency, or a Member of Congress.

The outlease shall not take effect if Congress enacts a joint resolution of disapproval of the outlease and such joint resolution is signed by the President.</summary>
</bill>
