<bill session="118" type="h" number="4446" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:24Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Store On-Board Wheelchairs in Cabin Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Store On-Board Wheelchairs in Cabin Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require air carriers and foreign air carriers to provide on a publicly available website of the carrier information on requirements for on-board wheelchairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2023-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-09T15:10:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Store On-Board Wheelchairs in Cabin Act of 2023

This bill requires an air carrier (including a foreign air carrier) to provide information and training on requirements for onboard wheelchairs.

Specifically, in the case of an aircraft that is required to be equipped with an onboard wheelchair, an air carrier must provide information on its website (and in any place where a passenger can make a reservation) on the rights and responsibilities of both passengers and air carriers. This information must include the requirement that aircraft with more than 60 passenger seats and an accessible lavatory must be equipped with an onboard wheelchair.

An air carrier must also require that all personnel who regularly interact with the traveling public, including contractors, complete annual training regarding assisting a qualified individual with a disability. The training must include information on the availability of accessible lavatories and onboard wheelchairs and the right to request an onboard wheelchair.

The Department of Transportation must conduct a public awareness campaign on the rights of qualified individuals with a disability.

The bill provides for increased civil penalties against an air carrier for failure to equip an aircraft with an onboard wheelchair.</summary>
</bill>
