<bill session="108" type="hr" number="666" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congratulating the people and Government of the Republic of Indonesia on successfully completing elections for national, provincial, and regional parliamentary representatives, and praising the growing friendship between the United States and Indonesia.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Congratulating the people and Government of the Republic of Indonesia on successfully completing elections for national, provincial, and regional parliamentary representatives, and praising the growing friendship between the United States and Indonesia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000403" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000549" joined="2004-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2004-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2004-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2004-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Indonesia"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Parliamentary government"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-07-08T18:14:56Z" status="Introduced in House">States that the House of Representatives: (1) congratulates the people and Government of the Republic of Indonesia on successfully completing elections on April 5, 2004, for national, provincial, and regional parliamentary representatives; (2) supports political and economic transformations achieved by Indonesia as it continues toward complete democratization; (3) expresses gratitude for the leadership of the Government of Indonesia, which has arrested 109 suspected Jemaah Islamiya members, including key suspects in the Bali attacks, the Marriott Hotel attack, and other criminal acts linked to terrorism; (4) supports Indonesia's legal framework in adopting amendments to its anti-money laundering law, which strengthened the legal authority of the Government of Indonesia to combat terrorist financing; (5) commends Indonesia on discovering new ways of working with regional law enforcement and intelligence communities to root out domestic radicalism; (6) expresses gratitude to the international observers who viewed the April elections as largely free, fair, and peaceful; and (7) urges further strengthening of strategic political, economic, and security initiatives and more effective public diplomacy between Indonesia and the United States.</summary>
</bill>
