<bill session="109" type="h" number="3729" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:12Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-17T19:22:39-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-17T19:22:39-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Judiciary Emergency Tolling Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide emergency authority to delay or toll judicial proceedings in United States district and circuit courts.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Judiciary Emergency Tolling Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Judiciary Emergency Tolling Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-371.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-02-08" calendar="Union" number="202">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 202.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T15:09:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T15:09:59-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5240-5242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T15:10:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3729.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T15:16:29-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T19:06:48-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5246-5247" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="377" datetime="2006-07-17T19:22:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 363 - 0 (Roll no. 377).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5240-5241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-17T19:22:39-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="377" datetime="2006-07-17T19:22:39-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 363 - 0 (Roll no. 377).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5240-5241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appellate procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil disobedience"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Hurricane aftermath legislation"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-21T18:07:38Z" status="Passed House amended">Federal Judiciary Emergency Tolling Act of 2006 - Authorizes the chief judge of a federal judicial district or circuit to delay, toll, or otherwise grant relief from time deadlines (including the time for filing or perfecting an appeal) for any class of cases pending or thereafter filed in the district court or bankruptcy court of the district, or for any class of cases pending in the court of appeals, in the event of a natural disaster or other emergency situation requiring the closure of courts or rendering it impracticable for the U.S. Government or a class of litigants to comply with deadlines imposed by any federal or state law or rule that applies in federal court.

Extends such tolling authority to all laws and rules affecting criminal and juvenile proceedings (including, prearrest, post-arrest, pretrial, trial, and post-trial procedures), civil actions, bankruptcy proceedings, and the time for filing and perfecting an appeal.

Excludes from such authority, however, any statute of limitation for: (1) a criminal action; or (2) a civil action, if the claim arises under state law and extending the limitations period would be inconsistent with such law.

Allows the exercise of such authority, in the absence of the chief judge, by: (1) the senior district judge in regular active service, or, if no such judge is available, by the chief judge of the circuit that includes the district; or (2) by the senior circuit judge of appeals in regular active service.

Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to authorize suspension of the writ of habeas corpus.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-371</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
