<bill session="112" type="h" number="4191" updated="2019-11-15T20:54:49Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Union Small Business Lending Act</title>
    <title type="display">Credit Union Small Business Lending Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Credit Union Act and the Small Business Act to improve small business lending, improve cooperation between the National Credit Union Administration and the Small Business Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2012-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Financial Institutions and Consumer Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA15" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Consumer Protection and Financial Institutions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-04-23T20:31:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Credit Union Small Business Lending Act - Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to establish a dedicated process by which credit unions participating in a certain small business loan program may receive approvals and repurchases concerning program loan guarantees.

Requires such process to: (1) be distinct from that used by participating non-credit unions, and (2) make use of existing agency resources. Amends the Small Business Act to direct the SBA Administrator to implement a program to: (1) provide outreach and assistance to credit unions to increase their participation in the SBA small business loan program, (2) simplify the application process for such participation, and (3) provide a guaranty of up to 85% for loans made by credit unions to their members in underserved areas.</summary>
</bill>
