<bill session="108" type="h" number="3491" updated="2023-01-15T08:33:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Museum of African American History and Culture Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish within the Smithsonian Institution the National Museum of African American History and Culture, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">National Museum of African American History and Culture Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Museum of African American History and Culture Act</title>
    <title type="popular">African American History Museum bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000220" joined="2003-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Transportation and Infrastructure, and Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T21:13:39-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Ney moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T21:14:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/19/2003 H11487-11493" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T21:14:03-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3491.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18T21:43:53-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T13:42:47-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11552" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="636" datetime="2003-11-19T13:49:35-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 409 - 9 (Roll no. 636).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H11487-11489" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-19T13:49:36-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2003-11-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15303-15306" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-21">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2003-12-05">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2003-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-184" type="public" datetime="2003-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-184.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2205" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1157" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights movements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-07T20:57:22Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

National Museum of African American History and Culture Act - (Sec. 4) Establishes within the Smithsonian Institution (SI) the National Museum of African American History and Culture, to be operated as a center for scholarship and a location for museum training, public education, exhibits, and collection and study of items and materials relating to the life, art, history, and culture of African Americans that encompass the period of slavery, the era of reconstruction, the Harlem renaissance, the civil rights movement, and other periods of the African American diaspora.

(Sec. 5) Establishes the National Museum of African American History and Culture Council to: (1) advise and assist the SI Board of Regents on Museum planning, design, construction, operation, and budgets; and (2) have responsibility and authority with respect to the Museum's collections and work, subject to the Board of Regents' general policies.(Sec. 6) Requires the Secretary of SI to appoint a Director to manage the Museum. (Sec. 7) Authorizes the Director of the Museum to carry out educational and liaison programs in support of Museum goals. Requires the Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Services (IMLS), in consultation with the Council and the Director of the Museum, to establish specified grant, scholarship, internship, and fellowship programs relating to African American museums. Authorizes appropriations to the IMLS Director for such programs. (Sec. 8) Directs the Board of Regents, in consultation with specified Commissions and congressional committee officials, to select the Museum's site from one of four specified sites on, adjacent to, or near the national mall. Requires the Board of Regents to pay costs of planning, design, and construction of the Museum on the chosen site as follows: 50 percent from Federal funds and 50 percent from non-Federal sources. Authorizes appropriations. (Sec. 9) Provides for Congressional Budget Act compliance by declaring that authority under this Act to enter into contracts or to make payments shall be effective in any fiscal year only to the extent provided in advance in an appropriations Act, except that amounts made available under section 11 of this Act shall remain available until expended. (Sec. 10) Directs the Council and the Board of Regents, in carrying out their duties under this Act, to consider the reports and plans submitted by the National Museum of African American History and Culture Plan for Action Presidential Commission under the National Museum of African American History and Culture Plan for Action Presidential Commission Act of 2001 (Public Law 107-106). (Sec. 11) Authorizes appropriations to SI to carry out this Act (except as already provided) in a specified amount for FY 2004, and in necessary amounts for subsequent fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
