<bill session="118" type="s" number="2042" updated="2025-11-19T04:39:25Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area Act to adjust the boundary of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sloan Canyon Conservation and Horizon Lateral Water Pipeline Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Senate Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-147.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="299">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 299.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7166" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7166" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T17:26:26-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T18:05:08-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4457" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6209" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-27T16:02:01Z" status="Passed Senate">Sloan Canyon Conservation and Lateral Pipeline Act

This bill expands the boundaries of the Sloan Canyon National Conservation Area in Clark County, Nevada, and grants rights-of-way through the conservation area for the construction of a water transmission pipeline and related facilities.&#160;

Specifically, the bill requires the Bureau of Land Management (BLM), which administers the conservation area, to grant certain rights-of-way to the Southern Nevada Water Authority (SNWA) for the purposes of (1) performing geotechnical investigations within the rights-of-way, and (2) constructing and operating a water pipeline and related facilities.&#160;

Rights-of-way may not be located through or under areas designated as wilderness, and construction of the pipeline may not permanently adversely affect surface resources within the conservation area. The BLM may place other reasonable terms and conditions on the issuance of rights-of-way as necessary to protect the conservation area&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s resources.&#160;&#160;In tunneling the water pipeline, SNWA may excavate and dispose of sand, gravel, minerals, and other materials as needed. The BLM must enter into a memorandum of understanding with SNWA to identify federal land on which SNWA may dispose of such materials.&#160;

The bill also adds approximately 9,000 acres of land&#160;to the conservation area. This expansion of the conservation area is subject to valid existing rights (e.g., utility transmission rights), must not preclude authorized activities within existing rights-of-way or corridors, and must not preclude the BLM from authorizing new utility rights-of-way.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-147</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
