<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1416" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:01Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives regarding the public disclosure by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of written reports and findings of the board of the Office of Congressional Ethics, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives regarding the public disclosure by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of written reports and findings of the board of the Office of Congressional Ethics, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000455"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000490" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000187" joined="2010-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000207" joined="2010-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-28">
      <text>Referred to House Administration</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-21T16:06:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends Rule XI (Procedures of Committees and Unfinished Business) of the Rules of the House of Representatives regarding public disclosure by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of written reports and findings of the board of the Office of Congressional Ethics.

 Prohibits the Committee from making a public statement if the board transmits a report on a matter recommending its dismissal or that it is unresolved due to a tie vote.

 States that if the Committee establishes an investigative subcommittee respecting such matter, the board's report and findings shall not be made public until the Committee has taken its final vote on the subcommittee's conclusions.

Requires: (1) the subcommittee to conclude its review within one year after the board transmits a report respecting any matter; and (2) the Committee to make public the report and findings upon conclusion of review of the matter if misconduct is found. Prohibits release of any report, however, if dismissal is recommended or if the matter is unresolved due to a tie vote.

States that if, after receipt of a written report and any findings and supporting documentation regarding a referral from the board, or of a referral of the matter from the board to the Committee at the Committee's request, the Committee agrees to a request from an appropriate law enforcement or regulatory authority to defer taking action on the matter, then the Committee shall make no public disclosure unless and until it has acted on the matter.

Provides that if a report regarding a board's referral is deemed frivolous by an affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Committee, it may take such action as it, by such vote, considers appropriate in the circumstances.

Revises procedures by which all board members, upon the request of two members, shall undertake a preliminary review of any alleged violation by a Member, officer, or employee of the House of any law, rule, regulation, or other standard of conduct. Requires the board's receipt of a sworn complaint from a citizen asserting personal knowledge of such alleged violation before commencement of such review.

Requires the Office to seal all of its records respecting a matter immediately if the Committee: (1) votes to dismiss any matter as frivolous or unfounded that is referred from the board; and (2) orders the records sealed.

Directs the board to amend its rules to define the standard of proof required to: (1) undertake a preliminary review; (2) commence a second-phase review of any matter under consideration; and (3) refer any matter to the Committee.</summary>
</bill>
