<bill session="118" type="s" number="948" updated="2025-11-19T03:52:51Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthy Moms and Babies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthy Moms and Babies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to improve maternal health coverage under Medicaid and CHIP, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2023-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="712" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8532" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4605" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-23T21:11:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthy Moms and Babies Act

This bill establishes programs and requirements to support maternal health services under Medicaid and the Children's Health Insurance Program (CHIP).

For example, the bill allows state Medicaid programs to cover services that are provided by maternity health homes (designated providers or health teams that provide pregnancy and postpartum coordinated care services). It also establishes a demonstration program to expand telehealth services for pregnant and postpartum women under Medicaid.

The bill also establishes an advisory group on birthing practices for health care professionals, requires a study on Medicaid coverage of doula services, and establishes other requirements relating to the maternal health care workforce. It also requires the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services to develop guidance on ways to address social determinants of health for pregnant and postpartum women and to reduce maternal mortality for Medicaid and CHIP beneficiaries.</summary>
</bill>
