<bill session="117" type="s" number="4355" updated="2023-01-27T05:17:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Clean Competition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create a carbon border adjustment based on carbon intensity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2022-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-25T14:52:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Clean Competition Act 

This bill creates a carbon border adjustment mechanism to lower greenhouse gas emissions in high-polluting sectors. This mechanism imposes charges on imports from carbon-intensive (e.g., fossil fuels, refined petroleum products, petrochemicals) manufacturers, encourages decarbonization efforts, and funds future research, development, and deployment efforts to achieve a net-zero carbon future.

The bill requires annual calculations of carbon intensity, imposes a carbon intensity charge on imports into the United States beginning after 2023, and allows for rebates for overpayments of charges.

The bill also establishes a grant program in FY2025 and subsequent fiscal years for investments in new technology to reduce carbon intensity in existing facilities and ensure best-in-class carbon intensity for proposed facilities.</summary>
</bill>
