<bill session="117" type="s" number="3617" updated="2022-12-29T21:18:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Confidence to the World Anti-Doping Agency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Confidence to the World Anti-Doping Agency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 2006 to modify the authority of the Office of National Drug Control Policy and the United States Anti-Doping Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001243"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2022-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-20T11:52:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Confidence to the World Anti-Doping Agency Act of 2022

This bill modifies the authority of the Office of National Drug Control Policy (ONDCP) and the United States Anti-Doping Agency (USADA) with respect to the World Anti-Doping Agency (WADA).

Specifically, the ONDCP, in conjunction with USADA, must

 use all available tools to ensure that WADA maintains a proper conflict-of-interest policy and that independent athletes from the United States and other democratic countries, or representatives of such athletes, have voting positions on the Executive Committee and governing bodies of WADA; demonstrate leadership within the global community; have strict standards that work toward countering the state-sponsored doping system of the Russian Federation and other state-sponsored, systemic fraud through doping; and work collaboratively with democratic countries. The bill requires the United States to have at least one seat on the Executive Committee of WADA as a condition of its participation in WADA.</summary>
</bill>
