<bill session="117" type="s" number="3129" updated="2023-08-23T21:45:19Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate certain segments of the Gila River system in the State of New Mexico as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, to provide for the transfer of administrative jurisdiction over certain Federal land in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2021-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-283.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="685">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 685.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-23T21:36:26Z" status="Reported to Senate">M.H. Dutch Salmon Greater Gila Wild and Scenic River Act

This bill designates specified segments of rivers and creeks of the Gila River system in New Mexico as components of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System and transfers 440 acres of land from the Gila National Forest to the Gila Cliff Dwellings Monument.

The Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must consult with tribal governments, applicable political subdivisions of states, and interested members of the public when preparing the comprehensive management plan for such segments pursuant to the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act.

 Any nonfederal land within or adjacent to such a segment that is acquired by the United States shall be incorporated in, and be administered as part of, the applicable segment.

No land or interest in land shall be acquired without the owner's consent.

Interior or USDA may authorize the construction of a native fish habitat restoration project within such a segment if the project

 would enhance the recovery of a threatened or endangered species, a sensitive species, or a species of greatest conservation need, including the Gila Trout; and would not unreasonably diminish the free-flowing nature or outstandingly remarkable values of the segment.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-283</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
