<bill session="111" type="s" number="1760" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:45Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Family Asthma Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with regard to research on asthma, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Asthma Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000123"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2010-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3754" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-04T22:59:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Family Asthma Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to award grants for pilot projects to prevent and control asthma symptoms and to reduce asthma attacks and improve self-management for individuals and families. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of NIH, in awarding grants, to give: (1) priority to entities that serve populations disproportionately impacted by asthma; and (2) consideration to an adequate national understanding of asthma prevalence.

Authorizes additional appropriations for FY2010-FY2014 to the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute to develop a National Asthma Action Plan and to fund a report to Congress by the National Asthma Education and Prevention Program on federal asthma activities.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to: (1) collaborate with state and local health departments to conduct activities to inform and educate the public regarding asthma; (2) conduct asthma surveillance activities to collect data on the prevalence and severity of asthma, the effectiveness of public heath asthma intervention, and the quality of asthma management; and (3) compile and annually publish data on childhood and adult asthma.</summary>
</bill>
