<bill session="115" type="h" number="6920" updated="2023-01-11T13:41:28Z">
  <state datetime="2018-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">School Security is Homeland Security Grant Act of 2018</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance Department of Homeland Security school security efforts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">School Security is Homeland Security Grant Act of 2018</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2018-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-10-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Emergency Preparedness, Response and Communications.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM12" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Emergency Management and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="5257" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Preschool education"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-03-04T19:41:28Z" status="Introduced in House">School Security is Homeland Security Grant Act of 2018

This bill amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to authorize the use of homeland security grants for enhanced school security efforts.

The bill authorizes appropriations for FY2019-FY2023 for homeland security grants, of which not less than 5% in each fiscal year shall be for grants relating to securing early childhood education programs, elementary schools, high schools, and secondary schools.

Grants awarded under the Urban Areas Security Initiative or the State Homeland Security Grant Program may not be used to purchase firearms or firearm accessories, such as ammunition, including for use by teachers. Such grants relating to securing early childhood education programs, elementary schools, high schools, or secondary schools may be used for: (1) target hardening and other enhancements of the physical security of such programs and schools; and (2) security planning, exercises, and training.</summary>
</bill>
