<bill session="119" type="s" number="1704" updated="2025-06-09T17:13:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Taxpayer Advocate Enhancement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Taxpayer Advocate Enhancement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to conform to the intent of the Internal Revenue Service Restructuring and Reform Act of 1998, as set forth in the joint explanatory statement of the committee of conference accompanying Conference Report 105-599, that the National Taxpayer Advocate be able to hire and consult counsel as appropriate.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="997" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T17:12:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Taxpayer Advocate Enhancement Act of 2025 

This bill authorizes the National Taxpayer Advocate to appoint legal counsel within the Taxpayer Advocate Service (TAS) to report directly to the National Taxpayer Advocate. The bill also expands the authority of the National Taxpayer Advocate to take personnel actions with respect to local taxpayer advocates (located in each state) to include actions with respect to any employee of TAS.

Currently, pursuant to a Department of the Treasury order, all legal counsel whose duties include providing legal advice to any official in any office or bureau of Treasury are part of the Legal Division within Treasury and under the supervision of the General Counsel, with limited exceptions. TAS assists taxpayers in matters involving the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) and is part of the IRS, within Treasury.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
