<bill session="116" type="h" number="7580" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">White House Open Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the White House to maintain a publicly accessible website that includes a visitor's log and salary and financial disclosure information for White House employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White House Open Data Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="706" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-08T16:08:14Z" status="Introduced in House">White House Open Data Act

This bill requires the White House to maintain a publicly accessible website that includes a visitor's log and salary and financial disclosure information for White House employees.

 Specifically, the Executive Office of the President shall make available on such website

 visitor records for any location where the President or Vice President regularly conducts official business, including the name of each visitor, the name of each individual with whom the visitor met, and the purpose of the visit, updated every 30 days; the annual salary of each White House employee, updated quarterly; and the most recent financial disclosure statement for each White House employee filed pursuant to the Ethics in Government Act of 1978, updated annually. The bill (1) lists exceptions to these requirements, including those involving a national security threat and personal visits that do not involve official or political business; and (2) requires specified disclosure of records that are withheld.</summary>
</bill>
