<bill session="116" type="s" number="4808" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to protect the independence of journalists by preventing undue political influence at the United States Agency for Global Media.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the independence of journalists by preventing undue political influence at the United States Agency for Global Media.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for Global Media"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-04T17:36:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill modifies provisions related to journalistic independence and the United States Agency for Global Media (USAGM), which oversees public service media networks that provide news and information in countries where the press is restricted.

Specifically, the bill establishes a noninterference standard that provides U.S. international broadcasting with the expectation that other U.S. government agencies or officials shall not interfere with its journalists. It also requires the Department of State and the Broadcast Board of Governors to (1) respect the professional independence and integrity of the USAGM, its broadcasting services, and its grantees; (2) protect USAGM journalists from undue interference by U.S. government agencies or officials; and (3) ensure that USAGM employees are judged solely on the basis of their adherence to professional standards of broadcast journalism.

Further, the bill requires the Inspector General of the State Department and the Foreign Service to investigate any potential infringements to journalistic independence by senior USAGM officials or other federal officials.</summary>
</bill>
