<bill session="118" type="h" number="3287" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:07Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CABLE Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cable Access for Broadband and Local Economic Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CABLE Leadership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to preserve cable franchising authority, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Television and film"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-17T17:02:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Cable Access for Broadband and Local Economic Leadership Act or the CABLE Leadership Act

This bill requires a state or local entity that regulates certain aspects of cable operators (franchising authorities) to make decisions about whether to grant or deny a complete request for a new cable franchise within a specified time frame. The bill also outlines what constitutes a complete request.

If a franchising authority fails to respond within the time frame, the request is deemed automatically granted. Additionally, a denial of a request must be in writing, supported by substantial evidence contained in a written record, and publicly released (and provided to the party who made the request) on the same day the decision is made.</summary>
</bill>
