<bill session="116" type="s" number="4109" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CRITICAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CRITICAL Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of General Services to establish an agency electronic recycling program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2020-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2020-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-09T18:49:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">CRITICAL Act

This bill directs the General Services Administration (GSA), the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and the Department of the Interior to take specified actions with respect to electronic recycling and critical mineral extraction.

Specifically, the GSA shall establish an electronic recycling program that services each executive agency.

The EPA shall (1) establish a program to ensure that electronics collected under the agency recycling program are entered into a certified recycling stream for dismantling and refining by certified entities; (2) ensure that refined critical minerals developed through the certified recycling stream program are retained in the United States for use by industry; and (3) award prizes for the development of E-waste recycling systems, with a goal of increasing the collection of recyclable electronics.

Interior shall study and report on critical mineral extraction, evaluating, among other things, the total quantity of recoverable critical minerals from all certified recycling streams, as compared to the total quantity of critical minerals necessary for manufacturing, consumer products, and national defense in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
