<bill session="117" type="h" number="9571" updated="2023-08-28T13:00:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title II of the Public Health Services to provide clarity with respect to coverage of claims against health care practitioners providing health professional volunteer services at community health centers during declared emergencies.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Public Health Services to provide clarity with respect to coverage of claims against health care practitioners providing health professional volunteer services at community health centers during declared emergencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-28T12:54:50Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill extends certain liability protections available for health care practitioners who provide voluntary health care services in declared emergencies through a community health center other than the one that initially sponsored them.

Current law makes the liability protections available to volunteer practitioners that are sponsored by a particular community health center. This bill maintains the liability protections for a volunteer practitioner who provides services through a different community health center if the center (1) seeks the assistance of the volunteer practitioner to respond to a declared emergency, and (2) promptly notifies the Department of Health and Human Services that the volunteer practitioner will be providing services.</summary>
</bill>
