<bill session="117" type="h" number="6360" updated="2022-12-30T03:33:58Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Supply Chain Relief Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Supply Chain Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Supply Chain Czar, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000585" joined="2022-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2022-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-05T22:32:51Z" status="Introduced in House">COVID-19 Supply Chain Relief Act

This bill establishes in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Supply Chain Policy, headed by a Supply Chain Czar appointed by the President.

Such office shall

 coordinate a national response to supply chain disruptions, shortages, and increased prices; serve as a resource for states as they deploy unused COVID-19 relief funds to address supply chain bottlenecks; and appoint, oversee, and coordinate among regional supply chain leaders. Unobligated COVID-19 relief funds may be made available to states, territories, or tribal governments to help address supply chain disruptions and labor shortages by undertaking one or more of the following:

 promoting employment in the trucking and logistics industries, implementing apprenticeship programs to recruit more women and military veterans to become licensed commercial motor vehicle drivers, undertaking port and shipping infrastructure projects, and providing relief from other detrimental economic impacts of supply chain disruptions. The Department of Commerce must issue guidance, as needed, to define the scope of the allowable activities listed above.

Further, Commerce shall publish and submit to Congress a report on (1) supply chain points of congestion or blockages; (2) underlying causes of supply chain disruptions, shortages, and delays; and (3) other supply chain shortcomings which could be remedied with public or private investment.</summary>
</bill>
