<bill session="117" type="s" number="1110" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MATCH Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Credit Act of 1978 with respect to preagreement costs of emergency watershed protection measures, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Access To Cleanup Happen Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MATCH Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000615"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2507" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-17T10:13:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Making Access To Cleanup Happen Act of 2021 or the MATCH Act of 2021

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to (1) identify a list of emergency watershed protection measures the cost of which may be incurred by a state, local government, or Indian tribe prior to entering into an agreement with USDA under the Emergency Watershed Protection Program; and (2) develop procedures, including appropriate deadlines, to be implemented at the state level, through which such entities may request and incur the cost for additional emergency watershed protection measures.

USDA must consider any applicable pre-agreement costs incurred by a state, local government, or Indian tribe for undertaking emergency watershed protection measures as meeting part of its contribution towards the project costs.</summary>
</bill>
