<bill session="117" type="h" number="210" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-18T20:00:35-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-05-18T20:00:35-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural STEM Education Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Rural STEM Education Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Rural STEM Education Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural STEM Education Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To coordinate Federal research and development efforts focused on STEM education and workforce development in rural areas, including the development and application of new technologies to support and improve rural STEM education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000491"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001108" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000630" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000446" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000588" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001056" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2021-01-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000588" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000266" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001186" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000189" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000019" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001212" joined="2021-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2021-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2021-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17T16:19:41-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Bonamici moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17T16:20:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2387-2390" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2387-2389" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17T16:20:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 210.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-17T16:32:36-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18T20:00:34-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 403, proceedings on H.R. 210 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2021-05-18T20:00:35-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 5 of H. Res. 403, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 144, as amended; H.R. 204, as amended; H.R. 210, as amended; H.R. 240; H.R. 707, as amended; H.R. 711, as amended; H.R. 1157, as amended; H.R. 1447, as amended; H.R. 1510, as amended; H.R. 1711, as amended; H.R. 2027; H.R. 2167, as amended; H.R. 2441; H.R. 2494; H.R. 2533; H.R. 2655, as amended; H.R. 2695, H.R. 2704; H.R. 2788; H.R. 2878, as amended; and H.R. 3008.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2482-2520" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2487-2489" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-05-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="403" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1374" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-01T15:42:05Z" status="Passed House">Rural STEM Education Research Act

This bill specifies federal scientific research and development efforts towards STEM (science, technology, engineering, and mathematics, including computer science) workforce development and rural STEM education.

(Sec. 3) The bill amends the objectives of the Manufacturing Extension Partnership program to include

 the provision to secondary schools of information about the job skills needed in manufacturing companies, and the promotion and expansion of certification systems offered through local high schools. The activities of a manufacturing extension center are expanded to include local high schools in the facilitation of collaborations and partnerships between manufacturing companies and schools to help those entities better understand the specific needs of manufacturers and to help manufacturers better understand the skill sets that students learn in school programs.

The National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) must award prizes to stimulate research and development of creative technologies in order to deploy affordable and reliable broadband connectivity to underserved rural communities. NIST may award not more than a total of $5 million in prizes.

(Sec. 4) The Office of Science and Technology Policy must establish a broadband research and development working group to address national research challenges and opportunities for improving broadband access and adoption across the United States.

(Sec. 5) The National Science Foundation (NSF) shall enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences under which the National Academy of Sciences agrees to evaluate aspects of STEM education and workforce development in rural areas.

 (Sec. 6) The Government Accountability Office shall conduct a study on the engagement of rural populations in federal STEM programs.

(Sec. 7) Experimental Program to Stimulate Competitive Research (EPSCoR) programs shall consider modifications to award structures to increase the capacity of rural communities to provide quality STEM education and STEM workforce development programming to students and teachers.

(Sec. 8) The NSF must award grants to institutions of higher education or nonprofit organizations for (1) research and development to advance innovative approaches to support and sustain high-quality STEM teaching in rural schools, (2) research and development of programming to identify the barriers rural students face in accessing high-quality STEM education, (3) development of innovative solutions to improve the participation and advancement of rural students in grades Pre-K through 12 in STEM studies, and (4) research on online STEM education courses for rural communities.

The NSF may establish a pilot program of regional cohorts in rural areas to provide peer support, mentoring, and hands-on research experiences for rural STEM educators of students in grades Pre-K through 12 in order to build an ecosystem of cooperation among educators, researchers, academia, and local industry.</summary>
</bill>
