<bill session="112" type="h" number="3012" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:22Z">
  <state datetime="2011-11-29T18:54:26-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-11-29T18:54:26-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to eliminate the per-country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, to increase the per-country numerical limitation for family-sponsored immigrants, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000567" joined="2011-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2011-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2011-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000283" joined="2011-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2011-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2011-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2011-11-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration Policy and Enforcement.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-10-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-18">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 112-292.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-11-18" calendar="Union" number="193">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 193.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:07:03-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:07:17-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7903-7905" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:07:19-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3012.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T16:23:18-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the chair put the question on the motion to suspend the rules. Mr. Cohen objected to the vote on the grounds that a quorum was not present. Further proceedings on the motion were postponed. The point of no quorum was withdrawn.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T18:31:02-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7916-7917" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="860" datetime="2011-11-29T18:54:26-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 389 - 15 (Roll no. 860).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7903" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-29T18:54:27-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-17">
      <text>Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2012-01-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="293">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 293.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="3476" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1866" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1983" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3217" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1857" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-12-05T18:34:47Z" status="Passed House amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the House on November 18, 2011. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Fairness for High-Skilled Immigrants Act of 2011 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to: (1) eliminate the per country numerical limitation for employment-based immigrants, and (2) increase the per country numerical limitation for family based immigrants from 7% to 15% of the total number of family-sponsored visas.

Amends the Chinese Student Protection Act of 1992 to eliminate the provision requiring the reduction of annual Chinese (PRC) immigrant visas to offset status adjustments under such Act.

Sets forth the following transition period for employment-based second and third preference (EB-2 and EB-3) immigrant visas: (1) for FY2012, 15% of such visas allotted to natives of countries other than the two countries with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2010; (2) for FY2013, 10% of such visas allotted in each category to natives of countries other than the two with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2011; and (3) for FY2014, 10% of such visas allotted in each category to natives of countries other than the two with the largest aggregate numbers of natives obtaining such visas in FY2012.

Sets forth the following per country distribution rules: (1) for transition period visas, not more than 25% of the total number of EB-2 and EB-3 visas for natives of a single country; and (2) for non-transition period visas, not more than 85% of EB-2 and EB-3 visas for natives of a single country.

Provides that the amendments made by this Act will take place as if enacted on September 30, 2011, and shall apply beginning in FY2012.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-292</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
