<bill session="117" type="h" number="4349" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to make certain improvements in the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Authorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-08T02:14:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Department of Homeland Security Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Authorization Act

This bill makes changes to the Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties (CRCL) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

The bill expands the duties of the CRCL to include

 integrating civil rights and civil liberties protections into all DHS programs and activities; conducting civil rights and civil liberties impact assessments; initiating reviews, assessments, and investigations of the administration of DHS programs and activities; leading the equal employment opportunity programs of DHS; engaging with individuals and communities whose civil rights and civil liberties may be affected by DHS programs and activities; and leading the language access program for DHS to ensure that DHS can effectively communicate with all individuals impacted by its programs and activities. The bill requires each operational component of DHS to designate an Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties to report to the CRCL.

The CRCL must make certain information regarding its investigations publicly available.

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress within two years of this bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
