<bill session="109" type="h" number="3534" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:31Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-25T15:20:00-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-09-25T15:20:00-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To designate the Piedras Blancas Light Station and the surrounding public land as an Outstanding Natural Area to be administered as a part of the National Landscape Conservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-08-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-627.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06" calendar="Union" number="367">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 367.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T15:16:50-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Pearce moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T15:17:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6951-6952" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T15:17:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3534.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-09-25T15:20:00-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6951-6952" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25T15:20:07-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-13">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Landscape protection"/>
    <term name="Lighthouses and lightships"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-01T21:29:48Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area Act of 2005 - Establishes the Piedras Blancas Historic Light Station Outstanding Natural Area (Outstanding Natural Area) in San Luis Obispo County, California.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage the Outstanding Natural Area as part of the National Landscape Conservation System and to allow only those uses that further the purposes for the establishment of the Area, the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976, and other applicable laws.

Withdraws the federal lands and interests in lands included within the Outstanding Natural Area from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the public land mining laws, and (3) operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws and the mineral material laws.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) manage the Outstanding Natural Area in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the unique and nationally important historical, natural, cultural, scientific, educational, scenic, and recreational values of that area, including an emphasis on preserving and restoring the Light Station facilities; and (2) complete a comprehensive management plan to provide long-term management guidance for the public lands within the Outstanding Natural Area and fulfill the purposes for which it is established.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with federal, state, and local agencies to implement the management plan in the Outstanding Natural Area and to continue partnerships with local communities and the Hearst San Simeon State Historical Monument. Provides for the acquisition of state and privately held lands or interests adjacent to the Outstanding Natural Area as additions to the Outstanding Natural Area.

Prohibits restrictions on overflights and law enforcement activities in the Outstanding Natural Area.

Directs the Secretary to ensure access to the Outstanding Natural Area by Indians and Indian tribes for cultural and religious purposes.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-627</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
