<bill session="118" type="s" number="1481" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Exploitation Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Exploitation Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Investment Company Act of 1940 to postpone the date of payment or satisfaction upon redemption of certain securities in the case of the financial exploitation of specified adults, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000601"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2023-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-01">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-12">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="500" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="White-collar crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-20T14:43:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Financial Exploitation Prevention Act of 2023

This bill addresses the redemption of securities involving the potential financial exploitation of an adult by allowing an open-end investment company to elect to comply with certain procedures. (Open-end investment management companies offer securities in pooled investment vehicles such as mutual funds.)

Specifically, the bill allows for the delay of the redemption of a security issued by an open-end investment management company if the company reasonably believes the redemption involves the financial exploitation of an individual age 65 or older or an individual age 18 or older who is unable to protect his or her own interests.

The company may initially delay the redemption for up to 15 days and, upon making a determination of exploitation, may delay the redemption an additional 10 days. In the event of delay, the company must hold the amounts related to the redemption in a demand deposit account.

Additionally, the Securities and Exchange Commission must make legislative and regulatory recommendations to address the financial exploitation of these adults.</summary>
</bill>
