<bill session="108" type="s" number="1535" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Highway Borders and Trade Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to establish programs to facilitate international and interstate trade.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Highway Borders and Trade Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10666-10667"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10667-10668" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Containerization"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intermodal transportation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-12-16T19:58:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Highway Borders and Trade Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish and implement a coordinated border infrastructure program under which the Secretary shall make allocations to border States (i.e., States with a common boundary with Canada or Mexico) for projects within a border region (the portion of a border State located within 100 kilometers of a land border crossing with Canada or Mexico) to improve the safe movement of people and goods at or across the U.S.-Canadian and U.S.-Mexican borders.

Permits allocations to States to be used in a border region only for specified: (1) improvements to transportation and supporting infrastructure that facilitate cross-border vehicle and cargo movement; (2) construction of highways and related safety and safety enforcement facilities; (3) operational improvements; (4) international coordination of planning, programming, and border operation; (5) projects in Canada or Mexico proposed by border States that directly and predominantly facilitate cross-border vehicle and commercial cargo movements; and (6) planning and environmental studies.

Directs the Secretary to allocate among border States funds based on a formula which takes into consideration the average annual weight of cargo entering a border State by commercial vehicles across the international borders and the average trade value of all cargo imported and exported. Sets the Federal cost share of projects under this Act at 80 percent.

Directs the Secretary to carry out a program to allocate funds to States for coordinated planning, design, and construction of corridors of national significance.</summary>
</bill>
