<bill session="116" type="s" number="2336" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the management of information technology projects and investments of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2019-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Moran without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-02-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="423">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 423.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2020-07-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4648-4650" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S4648-4650" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07T10:02:59-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-07T10:52:57-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-28T15:03:58Z" status="Passed Senate">Department of Veterans Affairs Information Technology Reform Act of 2019

This bill revises several policies and procedures related to the management of information technology projects and programs of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

Among other requirements, the bill requires the VA to

 update the review process for information technology projects to ensure active risks are factored into the Information Technology Dashboard Chief Information Officer ratings; submit a plan for expenditures relating to large information technology projects and investments; include a specific accounting of funds requested for VA information technology programs in budget justification materials; comply with applicable requirements of the Data Center Optimization Initiative of the Office of Management and Budget; submit a comprehensive, prioritized list of information technology projects being funded by the VA; assess information technology investments to determine the suitability of the investments for migration to a cloud computing service; create a mechanism to track savings and cost avoidances from migration to cloud computing services and deployment of such services; ensure that information technology management policies address the role of the Chief Information Officer with respect to key responsibilities; develop a continuous monitoring strategy to address organization metrics, frequency of monitoring metrics, ongoing status monitoring of metrics, and reporting of security status; and revise Office of Information and Technology processes relating to risk management. The bill also requires the Government Accountability Office to review the VA's updated processes related to the review of information technology projects and risk management.</summary>
</bill>
