<bill session="108" type="s" number="616" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mercury Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to reduce the quantity of mercury in the environment by limiting the use of mercury fever thermometers and improving the collection and proper management of mercury, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mercury Reduction Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Mercury Reduction Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001016" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2003-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3733-3734"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported by Senator Inhofe without amendment. With written report No. 108-199.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="398">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 398.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Mercury"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Waste reduction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mercury Reduction Act of 2003 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to: (1) prohibit the sale or supply of mercury fever thermometers to consumers, except by prescription; and (2) require manufacturers to provide clear instructions on handling of thermometers to avoid breakage and on proper cleanup in the event of breakage. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide grants for a household mercury thermometer collection and exchange program. Establishes a Task Force on Mercury to make recommendations on: (1) the long-term management of surplus mercury collected from thermometers and from medical, commercial, government, and industrial and other sources; (2) programs to test technologies for sequestration of retired mercury; (3) storage of mercury in a manner that ensures no release into the environment; (4) reduction of the total threat posed by mercury to humans and the environment; and (5) reduction of mercury produced, used, and released. Directs the Administrator, in consultation with the Task Force, to: (1) take title to mercury collected under the thermometer exchange program or from another source; (2) manage the mercury in a manner that prevents its release into the environment; (3) ensure that collected mercury is not reintroduced into commerce; (4) provide to the Task Force an analysis of, and recommendations concerning, collection and management activities under this Act; and (5) identify stabilization technologies and long-term storage measures that prevent mercury release and conduct appropriate research, development, and demonstration.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-199</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
