<bill session="117" type="h" number="4896" updated="2022-12-31T05:03:58Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program to provide reimbursement to agricultural producers for losses sustained due to illegal immigration.</title>
    <title type="display">Reimbursing Agricultural Producers for Immigration Damages Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RAPID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reimbursing Agricultural Producers for Immigration Damages Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000594" joined="2021-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000581" joined="2021-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-08T14:36:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Reimbursing Agricultural Producers for Immigration Damages Act or the RAPID Act

This bill temporarily establishes a program to reimburse agricultural producers for damages to livestock, crops, and property that result from the actions of an alien present in the United States without lawful immigration status. The Department of Agriculture may not provide reimbursements on or after September 30, 2023.

The bill also rescinds specified unobligated funding available to states, Indian tribes, and territories for mitigating fiscal effects that stem from the COVID-19 pandemic and makes such funding available to carry out the reimbursement program.</summary>
</bill>
