<bill session="111" type="h" number="5864" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:53Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Innovation through Investment Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against income tax for qualified equity investments in certain small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Innovation through Investment Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001169"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-15T14:06:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Small Business Innovation through Investment Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a new business-related tax credit for 30% of the equity investment in a small business concern. Allows a maximum credit of $500,000, but reduces such amount by so much of $250,000 that is not an investment in a manufacturing or biotechnology small business concern, a minority and women-owned small business, or a qualified HUBzone (historically underutilized business zone) small business concern. Terminates such credit after 2016.

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to provide to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) any data on the implementation and use of the equity investment in small business tax credit that is requested by the Administrator for analysis purposes. Requires the Administrator to report to Congress annually on the implementation and use of such tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
