<bill session="116" type="s" number="2391" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:12Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stock Buyback Reform and Worker Dividend Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stock Buyback Reform and Worker Dividend Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to impose requirements relating to the purchase of certain equity securities by issuers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-21T18:45:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stock Buyback Reform and Worker Dividend Act of 2019

This bill revises requirements related to stock buybacks (i.e., a company repurchasing shares of common stock). Specifically, issuers of securities must provide an annual dividend to non-executive employees in certain circumstances. The calculation of this dividend is based on (1) the amount the issuer spends on stock buybacks, (2) increases in dividends, and (3) any special dividends.

Additionally, an issuer is prohibited from repurchasing shares unless details of the buyback are disclosed to the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), including the rationale for the repurchase. The buyback must also comply with certain purchasing requirements. The bill lowers the allowed daily amount of repurchased shares. Executive officers may not sell shares for seven days beginning on the date of an announced buyback, subject to certain exceptions.

The SEC may enforce these provisions. Employees are afforded a private right of action against an issuer regarding required employee dividends.</summary>
</bill>
