<bill session="116" type="h" number="5894" updated="2022-02-08T23:54:43Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transparency in Prescription Drug Advertising Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue guidance requiring the list prices of drugs to be included in advertisements for such drugs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transparency in Prescription Drug Advertising Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000467" joined="2020-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2020-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2020-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-12T21:23:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Transparency in Prescription Drug Advertising Act

This bill requires that the list prices of drugs be included, as appropriate, in advertising for such drugs and directs the Department of Health and Human Services to issue department-wide guidance to that effect that is consistent with regulations issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) regarding drug price transparency.

On May 10, 2019, the CMS issued a final rule titled Medicare and Medicaid Programs; Regulation to Require Drug Pricing Transparency. The rule requires direct-to-consumer television advertisements for drugs and biologics covered under Medicare and Medicaid to include the list price of a 30-day supply or for a typical course of treatment, if the list price is at least $35 per month. The rule was scheduled to take effect on July 9, 2019; however, a federal court blocked the rule's implementation, citing a lack of statutory authority.</summary>
</bill>
