<bill session="112" type="h" number="562" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:39Z">
  <state datetime="2011-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to improve the Alaska pipeline construction training program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to improve the Alaska pipeline construction training program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="304" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="104" relation="text similarities"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-03-28T20:32:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Alaska Natural Gas Pipeline Act to add to the purpose of any grants by the Secretary of Labor to the Alaska Workforce Investment board support of a program to train workers in the construction, operation, maintenance, and performance of all related environmental processes involving existing and future oil and gas infrastructure in Alaska.

Modifies grant requirements by replacing the current ones with a mandatory certification by the Governor of Alaska that there is a need for the funds in order to ensure an adequately skilled, safe, and competent workforce to construct, operate, and maintain: (1) an Alaska natural gas pipeline system; or (2) all related environmental processes involving existing and future oil and gas infrastructure in Alaska.

Increases from 15% to 50% the amount of federal funds that may be used for such training facility.</summary>
</bill>
