<bill session="108" type="s" number="1798" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Home Fire Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for comprehensive fire safety standards for upholstered furniture, mattresses, bedclothing, and candles.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">American Home Fire Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Home Fire Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2003-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2003-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2003-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2003-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2003-10-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/31/2003 S13661-13662"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 10/31/2003 S13662" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-964.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-10">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator McCain under authority of the order of the Senate of 10/11/04 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-11-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="798">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 798.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4233" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Furniture industry"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Textile fabrics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-09T21:51:19Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">American Home Fire Safety Act - Requires the Consumer Product Safety Commission to evaluate and report to Congress on: (1) the interaction of bedclothing with the mattress in a fire and methodologies to improve the fire resistance of these products; (2) the current risk candles create as an ignition source in the home and the effectiveness of and level of compliance with the ASTM International Standard Specification for Fire Safety for Candles.

 Requires the Commission, if it has not promulgated a rule to improve the fire retardancy of upholstered furniture by June 1, 2005, to transmit a report to Congress explaining why such rule was not issued.

 Requires the Commission, if it has not issued an advance notice of proposed rulemaking regarding fire safe mattresses by June 1, 2005, to: (1) initiate a study to evaluate methodologies to improve fire resistance of such mattresses by June 30, 2005; (2) perform a comparative cost-benefit analysis of a mattress standard that would mandate 30-, 45-, and 60-minute flashover prevention; and (3) report its findings and recommendations to Congress.

Directs the Commission to create a registry of fire-retardant chemicals by June 1, 2005. Requires the registry to include: (1) a list of manufacturers producing fire-retardant chemicals for sale or use in or on Commission-regulated products sold or used in the United States; (2) a list of such chemicals for each manufacturer; (3) a ranking of sales of such chemicals by each manufacturer measured by volume of chemicals sold; and (4) a list of studies and reports on the human impact of such chemicals performed by those manufacturers.

Requires the Commission to submit an annual report to Congress on the results of the registry.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
