<bill session="111" type="h" number="4442" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:46Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PLANES Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to conduct a study and submit a report to Congress on the use of explosives detection technologies in air transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PLANES Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect the Lives of Americans Now through Enhanced Screening Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001259"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000575" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-06T17:08:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect the Lives of Americans Now through Enhanced Screening Act of 2010 or PLANES Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS), acting through the Assistant Secretary of Homeland Security (Transportation Security Administration [TSA]), to: (1) study and report to Congress on the use and effectiveness of explosives detection technologies, including whole-body imaging technology, explosives trace detection technology, and explosives detection canine teams, for screening cargo, passenger checked and carry-on baggage, and air passengers on domestic and foreign aircraft; (2) submit to Congress an explosives detection technologies rapid deployment plan; and (3) ensure that each U.S. commercial service airport has at least one explosives detection canine team, and that a sufficient number of such teams be deployed to meet 100% of federal air cargo screening requirements for domestic and foreign passenger aircraft.</summary>
</bill>
