<bill session="111" type="s" number="3596" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:43Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Culture of Safety Hospital Accountability Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Culture of Safety Hospital Accountability Study and Demonstration Program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Culture of Safety Hospital Accountability Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001049"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5968-5969"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-03T15:16:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Culture of Safety Hospital Accountability Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of Heatlh and Human Services (HHS) to study for a report made available on the Internet website of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services: (1) existing activities and programs in hospitals for quality assurance, patient safety, and performance improvement; and (2) any best practices that should be replicated in hospitals to improve patient safety and quality of care, consistent with the quality assessment and performance improvement program, as required by the conditions of participation for hospitals under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act.

Directs the Secretary to establish the Culture of Safety Hospital Accountability demonstration program to support establishing partnerships and other cooperative approaches among hospitals, state health care agencies, and HHS to promote and implement the best practices.</summary>
</bill>
