<bill session="119" type="s" number="450" updated="2025-06-09T17:07:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Decoupling from Foreign Adversarial Battery Dependence Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decoupling from Foreign Adversarial Battery Dependence Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Secretary of Homeland Security from procuring certain foreign-made batteries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1166" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T16:56:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Decoupling from Foreign Adversarial Battery Dependence Act

This bill prohibits the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) from using appropriated funds to procure a battery produced by certain entities, particularly six specific companies owned and operated in China. This prohibition begins on October 1, 2027.

The bill allows DHS to waive the prohibition if DHS assesses in the affirmative that (1)&#160;the batteries to be procured do not pose a risk to U.S. national security, data, or infrastructure; and (2)&#160;there is no available alternative to procure batteries that are of similar or better cost and quality and that are produced by an entity not specified in this bill.

DHS may also waive the prohibition upon a determination that the batteries to be procured are for the sole purpose of research, evaluation, training, testing, or analysis.

The bill requires DHS to notify Congress within 15 days after granting a waiver under this bill.

The bill also requires DHS to report to Congress on the anticipated impacts associated with carrying out this bill, including with respect to specified agencies of DHS.</summary>
</bill>
