<bill session="117" type="h" number="1920" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROVE IT Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal agency accountability and improve the effectiveness of major rules in accomplishing their regulatory objectives by requiring retrospective review and report, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROVE IT Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Retrospective Observations Validating Economics and Increasing Transparency Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2021-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Antitrust, Commercial, and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU05" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Administrative State, Regulatory Reform, and Antitrust" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-25T19:14:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Retrospective Observations Validating Economics and Increasing Transparency Act of 2021 or the PROVE IT Act of 2021



This bill requires agencies, when publishing a final major rule and biennially thereafter, to assess the impact of the rule on regulated entities, determine how the actual benefits and costs of the rule have varied from those anticipated, and assess the effectiveness of the rule at meeting its regulatory objectives.

If an agency determines that the cost to regulated entities has exceeded the anticipated cost, then the agency must assess and report whether the rule is meeting its objectives and whether the rule is necessary. Further, in such case, the agency must reopen the public comment period for 60 days and consider modifications or alternatives to the rule. The bill defines a&#160;major rule&#160;as a rule likely to cause (1)&#160;an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; (2) a major increase in costs or prices; or (3) significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, or the ability of U.S.-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises.</summary>
</bill>
