<bill session="111" type="h" number="4885" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:23Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To protect the civil rights of victims of gender-motivated violence and to promote public safety, health, and regulate activities affecting interstate commerce by creating employer liability for negligent conduct that results in an individual's committing a gender-motivated crime of violence against another individual on premises controlled by the employer, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect the civil rights of victims of gender-motivated violence and to promote public safety, health, and regulate activities affecting interstate commerce by creating employer liability for negligent conduct that results in an individual's committing a gender-motivated crime of violence against another individual on premises controlled by the employer, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E411-412"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-26T18:09:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Makes an employer liable to a party injured in a crime of violence motivated by gender if: (1) the employer's business is in or affects interstate or foreign commerce; and (2) the employer's negligent conduct results in the perpetration of a gender-motivated crime of violence against an individual on premises under the employer's control.

Prohibits anything in this Act from being construed as: (1) entitling a person to a cause of action for random acts of violence unrelated to gender or for acts that cannot be demonstrated to be motivated by gender; or (2) requiring a prior criminal complaint, prosecution, or conviction to establish the elements of a cause of action.

Gives federal and state courts concurrent jurisdiction over actions brought pursuant to this Act.

Directs the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) to create and provide to employers materials regarding personnel policies and safety standards to assist them in avoiding liability under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
