<bill session="117" type="h" number="8072" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LOVE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lavender Offense Victim Exoneration Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LOVE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To review the termination characterization of former employees of the Department of State who were fired by reason of the sexual orientation of such employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000486" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2022-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-23T16:59:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Lavender Offense Victim Exoneration Act of 2022 or the LOVE Act of 2022

This bill offers a formal apology from Congress for encouraging policies at the Department of State, such as the Lavender Scare, which resulted in the wrongful termination of at least 1,000 people for alleged homosexuality, and addresses related issues.

The State Department must (1) review all employee terminations that occurred as a consequence of the Lavender Scare to identify those who were wrongfully terminated, and (2) issue a public report on the findings.

The State Department must establish an independent Reconciliation Board to contact any employee (or a family member of a deceased employee) wrongfully terminated during the Lavender Scare and offer to change the employee's record to reflect this finding. The board must accept and review petitions from former employees who believe they were terminated due to sexual orientation.

The State Department must establish a board of senior-level officials to address issues that lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer, and intersex (LGBTQI) Foreign Service employees and their families face. The board must report on improving State Department policies to prevent discrimination based on sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics.

The State Department must report on (1) countries that do not issue spousal visas for Foreign Service employee spouses due to sexual orientation, gender identity, or sex characteristics; and (2) recommendations for State Department responses, such as eliminating visa reciprocity for such countries.</summary>
</bill>
