<bill session="116" type="s" number="2402" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:13Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Crude Oil Advance Tracking Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the safety of Class 3 flammable liquid transportation by rail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-21T21:08:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Crude Oil Advance Tracking Act or the COAT Act 

This bill addresses safety concerns regarding railroad carriers transporting Class 3 flammable liquids (e.g., crude oil) and other high hazardous liquids or gases.

Specifically, the bill

 requires railroad carriers transporting Class 3 flammable liquids to (1) share information regarding such shipments with state emergency responders, including the number of gallons of the liquids; and (2) include in each annual report information regarding their ability to pay all costs of cleaning up a reasonable, worst-case spill; provides grants for local communities to develop, improve, and implement emergency plans that address responses to high-hazard rail shipments; and provides financial assistance for local projects, activities, and personnel that mitigate the impacts of, and public health or environmental risks associated with, the transport of flammable liquids or gases by rail.</summary>
</bill>
