<bill session="118" type="s" number="1837" updated="2025-11-19T04:51:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Spotted Lanternfly Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Spotted Lanternfly Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to include spotted lanternfly control research and development as a high-priority research and extension initiative, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000479"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2023-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3867" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-02T14:05:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Spotted Lanternfly Research and Development Act

This bill includes combatting the spotted lanternfly (Lycorma delicatula) as a Department of Agriculture (USDA) high-priority research and extension area.

The bill specifically allows grants for developing and disseminating research-based tools and treatments to combat the spotted lanternfly, which is an invasive species native to China that feeds on a wide range of crops and plants (e.g., grapes, apples, hops, walnuts, and hardwood trees).

Further, the bill reauthorizes USDA grants to support competitive specialized research and extension activities, including high-priority areas, through FY2028. The bill also specifically reauthorizes through FY2028

 the Pulse Crop Health Initiative; the Comprehensive Food Safety Training Network; pollinator protection research and extension grants; increased USDA capacity and infrastructure to address and conduct research on colony collapse disorder and other pollinator issues; and a USDA-conducted nationwide honey bee pest, pathogen, health, and population status surveillance program.</summary>
</bill>
