<bill session="118" type="h" number="5215" updated="2024-12-20T09:06:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Beef Origin Labeling Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Beef Origin Labeling Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the United States Trade Representative, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, to determine a means of reinstating mandatory country of origin labeling for beef that is in compliance with all applicable rules of the World Trade Organization, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000301"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-06T17:31:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Beef Origin Labeling Accountability Act

This bill directs the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative (USTR), in consultation with the Department of Agriculture, to determine a means of reinstating mandatory country-of-origin labeling (COOL) for beef that is compliant with World Trade Organization rules. (COOL is a labeling law that requires retailers, such as full-line grocery stores, supermarkets, and club warehouse stores, to notify their customers of information regarding the source of certain foods.)

The USTR must submit a report to specified congressional committees that includes (1) a description of its progress in determining a means of reinstating mandatory COOL for beef, and (2) recommendations for legislation that may be necessary and any engagement with other governments on this matter.

The USTR must also seek to enter into consultations with the governments of Canada and Mexico to resolve outstanding trade disputes related to COOL for beef.</summary>
</bill>
