<bill session="119" type="h" number="4490" updated="2025-09-24T17:35:18Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-02T17:04:37-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-02T17:04:37-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PARTNER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">PARTNER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act</title>
    <title type="short">PARTNER Act</title>
    <title type="short">Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act</title>
    <title type="display">PARTNER Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the International Organizations Immunities Act to extend diplomatic privileges and immunities to certain additional international and regional organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To amend the International Organizations Immunities Act to extend privileges and immunities to certain additional international and regional organizations, and for other purposes</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000301" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000176" joined="2025-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000600" joined="2025-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02T16:52:01-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Baumgartner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02T16:52:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3734-3736" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02T16:52:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4490.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-09-02T17:04:37-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3734" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02T17:04:40-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-02T17:04:43-04:00">
      <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3678" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3865" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="ASEAN countries"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-03T15:19:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Appropriate Recognition and Treatment Needed to Enhance Relations Act or the PARTNER Act

This bill authorizes the President to extend diplomatic immunities and privileges provided by the International Organizations Immunities Act, including immunity from certain lawsuits and exemption from property taxes, to specified international regional and research organizations.&#160;

Specifically, the bill authorizes the President to extend these immunities and privileges to

the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN), a regional organization with 10 members including Brunei, Indonesia, Singapore, and Vietnam;the Pacific Islands Forum, a regional organization with 18 members including Australia, Fiji, New Zealand, and Papua New Guinea;the Caribbean Community (CARICOM), a regional organization with 15 members and 6 associate members including Barbados, Grenada, Jamaica, and Saint Lucia; andthe European Organization for Nuclear Research (CERN), an international research organization focused on particle physics.The bill also authorizes the President to extend to the permanent observer mission of the African Union to the United Nations the privileges and immunities provided to permanent missions to the United Nations of member states.</summary>
</bill>
