<bill session="119" type="s" number="443" updated="2025-11-18T19:08:00Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fire Management Assistance Grants for Tribal Governments Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire Management Assistance Grants for Tribal Governments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to allow Indian tribal governments to directly request fire management assistance declarations and grants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="3957" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="4669" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-13T19:38:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fire Management Assistance Grants for Tribal Governments Act

This bill allows Indian tribal governments to directly participate in the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) Fire Management Assistance Grant (FMAG) program, as opposed to participating through states.

Currently, only states may submit requests to FEMA for declarations authorizing FMAG assistance, and Indian tribal governments affected by a fire must use a state&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s authorization to receive FMAG assistance. The bill authorizes Indian tribal governments to submit FMAG declaration requests directly to&#160;FEMA and receive FMAG assistance under their own declarations. Indian tribal governments may still choose instead to receive&#160;FMAG assistance under an authorization requested by a state.

Also, the bill requires FEMA to update its FMAG regulations within one year after enactment to carry out the bill.</summary>
</bill>
