<bill session="108" type="s" number="1085" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reclamation Rural and Small Community Water Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a Bureau of Reclamation program to assist states and local communities in evaluating and developing rural and small community water supply systems, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclamation Rural and Small Community Water Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2003-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000432" joined="2003-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6709-6710"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6710-6711" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-539.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-17T19:25:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reclamation Rural and Small Community Water Enhancement Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to undertake a program to investigate and identify opportunities for ensuring safe and adequate regional rural water supply systems (serving areas with populations not exceeding 40,000, with exceptions) for use in small communities and rural areas through the construction of new regional systems and the enhancement of existing ruralsystems. Limits participation in such program to the States and areas (and Indian reservation lands within such States and areas) referred to in the Reclamation Act of 1902.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) submit to specified congressional committees a report setting forth the status of all rural water projects within the Secretary's jurisdiction authorized prior to enactment of this Act and the Secretary 's plan for completing such projects within their respective time frames; and (2) take steps to complete such projects within such time frames.

Authorizes the Secretary to undertake appraisal investigations to identify opportunities for the construction of new systems and enhancement of existing systems for small communities and rural areas; and (2) participate with appropriate Federal, State, tribal, regional, and local authorities in studies to determine the feasibility of such projects where such an investigation so warrants.</summary>
</bill>
