<bill session="117" type="s" number="3146" updated="2022-12-30T08:33:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">WALL Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">WALL Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to appropriate $25,000,000,000 for the construction of a border wall between the United States and Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2021-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2022-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-11-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-15T20:30:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">WALL Act of 2021 

This bill appropriates $25 billion for the construction of a wall on the U.S.-Mexico border and addresses other issues related to immigration.

As offsets to this spending, the bill restricts the child tax credit, earned income credits, and lifetime learning credits to those with Social Security numbers and not prohibited from employment in the United States. Also, individuals who file taxes using an individual taxpayer identification number (ITIN) instead of a Social Security number must pay a fee ($300 for each individual on the tax return who was issued an ITIN).

The bill restricts eligibility for certain federally-funded benefits, including unemployment compensation, supplemental nutrition assistance, and housing benefits, to those eligible to work in the United States. Agencies administering such benefits must use the E-Verify program to confirm the eligibility of applicants for such benefits.

This bill also sets fines for aliens who improperly enter the United States or overstay their visas.</summary>
</bill>
