<bill session="117" type="h" number="3609" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trust in Public Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve public trust in the Federal Government by establishing customer experience as a central measure of performance for agencies and the Federal Government, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trust in Public Service Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2021-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2021-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2022-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Appropriations, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1934" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civics education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-03T21:23:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Trust in Public Service Act

This bill incorporates customer experience as a central measure of performance for federal agencies.

Specifically, the bill requires each agency to develop a high-quality customer experience by

 allocating sufficient resources to and prioritizing customer experience capabilities and initiatives, adapting government-wide and global good practices, streamlining the process for soliciting voluntary customer feedback and requiring limited internal review if the collection is within the scope of Office of Management and Budget (OMB) guidance, and using human-centered design practices. Each agency shall

 develop and use tools to experiment with different approaches to improve customer experience, ensure the privacy of federal customers, use the data collected to continually improve customer experience and agency performance, and share the data collected with research entities to permit external analysis. The bill sets forth agency communication responsibilities.

In addition, the OMB must issue guidance for agencies in collaboration with specified entities. It may establish programs that annually recognize individuals and teams across the federal workforce meeting customer service-related goals.

The bill (1) integrates customer experience provisions into the U.S. code and the Federal Citizen Services Fund, (2) directs the OMB to establish an Office of Customer Experience, and (3) integrates customer experience into the responsibilities of key agency officials.

The OMB, in coordination with the Office of Customer Experience, must establish the Participatory Government and Civic Dialogue Advisory Council.

The Government Accountability Office shall report to Congress, assessing agency efforts and examining best practices.</summary>
</bill>
