<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>728</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:17:57Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-03-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2009-09-02T17:39:44Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2009-05-21T14:48:54Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Hearings by</name>
            <date>2009-04-29T17:35:47Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-03-26T21:02:26Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-71</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>1037</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-10-08</actionDate>
          <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related document</type>
            <identifiedBy>Senate</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
            <identifiedBy>Senate</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Procedurally-related</type>
            <identifiedBy>Senate</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>See also H.R. 1037.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Returned to the Calendar. Calendar No. 155. (consideration: CR S10251)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 1037 in lieu of this measure by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 1037 as an amendment.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The bill was read the third time.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>The committee substitute as amended agreed to by Unanimous Consent.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent. (consideration: CR S10245-10251; text of measure as reported in Senate: CR S10245-10251)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-09-02</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 155.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-09-02</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Akaka under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/07/2009 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-71.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-09-02</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Akaka under authority of the order of the Senate of 08/07/2009 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-71.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-05-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-04-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 111-81.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3927-3930)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-26</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S3926-3927)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>A000069</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Akaka, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>AKAKA</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KOHIKINA</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-08-25T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 728, Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/41235</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs on May 21, 2009&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-08-25T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 728, Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/41235</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs on May 21, 2009</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Afghanistan</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Asia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Bankruptcy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Cemeteries and funerals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Veterans Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disability and paralysis</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Emergency medical services and trauma care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Employment discrimination and employee rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government lending and loan guarantees</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing finance and home ownership</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Inflation and prices</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Iraq</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Life, casualty, property insurance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Middle East</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military operations and strategy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Motor vehicles</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Neurological disorders</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Philippines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' medical care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' pensions and compensation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wages and earnings</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-03-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-11-18T17:46:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Veterans' Insurance and Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009 - Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to grant level-premium term life insurance to veterans under age 65 with service-connected disabilities.</p> <p>Increases from $20,000 to $30,000 the maximum amount of supplemental insurance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for totally disabled veterans.</p> <p>Removes a condition on the qualification of certain individuals for retroactive benefits from traumatic injury coverage under Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance.</p> <p>Increases the maximum loan guarantee amount under the veterans' mortgage life insurance program from $90,000 to $150,000, then to $200,000 after January 1, 2012.</p> <p>Establishes an annual cost-of-living adjustment for the temporary payment of dependency and indemnity compensation (DIC) to a veteran's surviving spouse with one or more children under the age of 18.</p> <p>Provides eligibility requirements for the payment of a special monthly pension based on disability for veterans who already qualify for a service pension based upon age.</p> <p>Increases amounts of DIC payable to surviving spouses and parents of deceased veterans.</p> <p>Increases, and authorizes the annual adjustment of, pension amounts payable to hospitalized veterans and certain children of veterans of a period of war.</p> <p>Authorizes and directs the Secretary to pay a: (1) supplemental benefit for the funeral and burial expenses of veterans, making such amount $900 with respect to a non-service-connected death and $2,100 with respect to a service-connected death; and (2) supplemental burial plot allowance for veterans eligible for the current allowance.</p> <p>Authorizes the provision of specially adapted housing assistance for disabled veterans whose disability is due to a severe burn injury.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to pay a supplemental benefit, for assistance in the purchase of automobiles and other conveyances, for disabled veterans currently eligible for such assistance.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-09-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-12-29T21:39:04Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009 - <b>Title I: Insurance Matters </b>- (Sec. 101) Increases from $20,000 to $30,000 the maximum amount of supplemental insurance provided through the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) for totally disabled veterans.</p> <p>(Sec. 102) Limits the duration of a dependent's coverage under Servicemembers' Group Life Insurance (SGLI) to 120 days after the member's separation or release from service or assignment.</p> <p>(Sec. 103) Amends the Veterans' Housing Opportunity and Benefits Improvement Act of 2006 to remove the requirement of service in either Operation Iraqi Freedom or Enduring Freedom as a condition for retroactive benefits under the traumatic injury coverage of SGLI.</p> <p>(Sec. 104) Permits the VA to distinguish, in specifying payments for qualifying SGLI traumatic injury losses, between the severity of a qualifying loss of a dominant hand and a qualifying loss of a nondominant hand.</p> <p>(Sec. 105) Increases the maximum loan guarantee amount under the veterans' mortgage life insurance program from $90,000 to $150,000, then to $200,000 after January 1, 2012.</p> <p><b>Title II: Compensation and Pension Matters </b>- (Sec. 201) Establishes an annual cost-of-living adjustment, based on increases in amounts payable under title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act, for the temporary payment of dependency and indemnity compensation (DIC) to a veteran's surviving spouse with one or more children under the age of 18.</p> <p>(Sec. 202) Revises eligibility requirements for the payment of a special monthly pension based on disability for veterans of a period of war who already qualify for a service pension based and who are over age 65.</p> <p>(Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to promulgate regulations which recognize circumstances, consistent with the place, conditions, dangers, or hardships associated with particular military service, that do not require confirming or documenting evidence in order to establish the occurrence of an event or exposure during active military service.</p> <p>(Sec. 204) Extends through FY2014 the expiration date for the reduction of VA pensions for certain beneficiaries with no dependents who are covered by Medicaid plans for services furnished by nursing facilities.</p> <p>(Sec. 205) Authorizes higher levels of veterans' disability compensation for certain veterans who experience difficulty using prostheses after the loss of hands, arms, or legs and those in need of regular aid and attendance after suffering a severe traumatic brain injury.</p> <p>(Sec. 206) Requires that, in the case of a veteran who is retired or separated from active duty due to a catastrophic disability, payment of VA disability benefits based on an original claim shall be made on the date the award becomes effective (thereby eliminating certain procedural delays in such payments).</p> <p>(Sec. 207) Requires a reduction in VA death pension benefits with respect to surviving adult-disabled children of veterans who are Medicaid recipients residing in nursing homes.</p> <p>(Sec. 208) Requires the payment of DIC to the survivors of former prisoners-of-war (POWs) who died on or before September 30, 1999, on the same basis as survivors of former POWs who die after such date. (Expands payment of such benefits to provide the same coverage regardless of the date of death.)</p> <p><b>Title III: Readjustment and Related Benefit Matters </b>- (Sec. 301) Repeals the current limitation (2600 per year) on the number of veterans who may enroll in a VA program of independent living services and assistance.</p> <p>(Sec. 302) Authorizes the VA to provide automobile and adaptive equipment assistance to disabled veterans and veterans with severe burn injuries.</p> <p>(Sec. 303) Increases from $11,000 to $22,500 per veteran the VA authority to assist severely disabled veterans in purchasing automobiles or other equipment to accommodate such disabilities. Requires such amount to be adjusted annually to coincide with new automobile cost increases.</p> <p>(Sec. 304) Authorizes the Secretary, in the event that a VA-guaranteed home loan is modified under bankruptcy proceedings, to pay the mortgagor the unpaid balance of the loan, but only upon the assignment and delivery to the Secretary of all rights, interests, and claims with respect to the loan.</p> <p><b>Title IV: Employment and Reemployment Rights of Members of the Uniformed Services </b>- (Sec. 401) Provides that a state's receipt or use of federal financial assistance for any program or activity shall constitute a waiver of state sovereign immunity with respect to actions brought to enforce employment or reemployment rights or benefits under the Uniformed Services Employment and Reemployment Rights Act of 1994 (USERRA).</p> <p>(Sec. 402) Provides additional factors for determining whether an entity is a &quot;successor in interest&quot; for purposes of USERRA enforcement against employers.</p> <p>(Sec. 403) Includes within USERRA a specific prohibition against wage discrimination against members of the Armed Forces.</p> <p>(Sec. 404) Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to require non-military federal agencies to notify their contractors of potential USERRA obligations.</p> <p>(Sec. 405) Directs the Comptroller General to study and report to Congress on the effectiveness of federal programs of education and outreach on employer obligations under USERRA.</p> <p><b>Title V: Burial and Memorial Matters </b>- (Sec. 501) Authorizes and directs the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds specifically provided for purposes of this section in advance appropriations, to pay a supplemental benefit for the funeral and burial expenses of veterans, making such amount $900 with respect to a non-service-connected death and $2,100 with respect to a service-connected death. Requires the annual adjustment of such amounts (based on increases in the Consumer Price Index) with respect to deaths that occur after FY2010. Requires the Secretary to estimate, and report to the veterans and appropriations committees on, the amount of fiscal year funding necessary to make such supplemental payments. Authorizes appropriations.</p> <p>(Sec. 502) Authorizes the Secretary, subject to the availability of funds specifically provided for purposes of this section in advance appropriations, to pay a supplemental burial plot allowance of $445 for veterans eligible for the current allowance. Requires the annual adjustment of such amount (based on increases in the Consumer Price Index) with respect to deaths that occur after FY2010. Directs the Secretary to estimate, and report to the veterans and appropriations committees on, the amount of fiscal year funding necessary to make such supplemental payment. Authorizes appropriations.</p> <p><b>Title VI: Other Matters </b>- (Sec. 601) Directs the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) to: (1) conduct a comprehensive review of the best treatments for Gulf War Illness; and (2) report review results to the Secretary and the veterans committees.</p> <p>(Sec. 602) Amends the Persian Gulf War Veterans Act of 1998 to extend until October 1, 2015, an NAS review and evaluation concerning associations between illnesses and exposure of Gulf War veterans to toxic agents, environmental or wartime hazards, or preventive medicines or vaccines. Amends the Veterans Programs Enhancement Act of 1998 to extend until October 1, 2018, an NAS report on the health effects of such exposure.</p> <p>(Sec. 603) Extends through 2011 VA authority to operate a regional office in the Republic of the Philippines.</p> <p>(Sec. 604) Permits an aggregate period of 81 months for the use of VA educational assistance for individuals who receive both survivors' and dependents' educational assistance and other veterans and related educational assistance. Revives any benefit entitlement reduced by prior utilization of survivors' and dependents' educational assistance.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to enhance veterans' insurance benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Veterans' Insurance and Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <amendments>
      <amendment>
        <number>2654</number>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <type>SAMDT</type>
        <purpose>To improve the bill.</purpose>
        <updateDate>2022-02-03T06:03:54Z</updateDate>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
          <text>Amendment SA 2654 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
          <links>
            <link>
              <name>SA 2654</name>
              <url>https://www.congress.gov/amendment/111th-congress/senate-amendment/2654</url>
            </link>
          </links>
        </latestAction>
        <sponsors>
          <item>
            <bioguideId>A000069</bioguideId>
            <fullName>Sen. Akaka, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
            <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
            <lastName>AKAKA</lastName>
            <party>D</party>
            <state>HI</state>
            <middleName>KOHIKINA</middleName>
          </item>
        </sponsors>
        <proposedDate>2009-10-07T04:00:00Z</proposedDate>
        <submittedDate>2009-10-07T04:00:00Z</submittedDate>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <amendedBill>
          <congress>111</congress>
          <type>S</type>
          <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
          <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
          <number>728</number>
          <title>Veterans' Benefits Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
          <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:57Z</updateDateIncludingText>
        </amendedBill>
        <actions>
          <count>6</count>
          <actions>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 2654 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>0</code>
                <name>Senate</name>
              </sourceSystem>
              <text>Amendment SA 2654 proposed by Senator Bennet for Senator Akaka. (consideration: CR S10251; text: CR S10251) To improve the bill.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2654 proposed by Senator Bennet for Senator Akaka.(consideration: CR S10251; text: CR S10251)</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>93000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 2654 agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>94000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
            <item>
              <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
              <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
              <type>Floor</type>
              <actionCode>91000</actionCode>
              <sourceSystem>
                <code>9</code>
                <name>Library of Congress</name>
              </sourceSystem>
            </item>
          </actions>
        </actions>
      </amendment>
    </amendments>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2009-09-02T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s728rs/xml/BILLS-111s728rs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-03-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s728is/xml/BILLS-111s728is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-10-07</actionDate>
      <text>See also H.R. 1037.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
