<bill session="116" type="h" number="4001" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:22Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bikeshare Transit Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, with respect to bikeshare projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bikeshare Transit Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000574"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E990"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians and bicycling"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-11-05T19:26:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Bikeshare Transit Act of 2019

This bill allows bikeshare projects to be eligible for federal funding.

Specifically, the bill makes a bikeshare project eligible to be an associated transit improvement project, including projects that (1) facilitate a bicycle rental operation that makes bicycles available for public transportation, (2) allow riders to pick up and drop off bicycles, (3) serve a defined geographic area, and (4) facilitate the transit of individuals between various points in the area.

Public transportation capital projects must include any project for the acquisition or replacement of bicycles and related equipment, including technology and vehicles needed to restock stations, and the construction of bicycle-related facilities to facilitate a bikeshare project.

The bill also makes bikeshare projects eligible for funds if they shift traffic demand to non-peak hours or other transportation modes, increase vehicle occupancy rates, or otherwise reduce demand for roads.</summary>
</bill>
