<bill session="118" type="s" number="2791" updated="2025-11-19T03:20:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pay Our Coast Guard Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Our Coast Guard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 14, United States Code, to make appropriations for Coast Guard pay in the event an appropriations Act expires before the enactment of a new appropriations Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2023-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2024-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5842" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2693" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-28T10:57:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pay Our Coast Guard Act

This bill provides continuing appropriations to the Coast Guard for pay and benefits when there is a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse.

Under the bill, a&#160;Coast Guard-specific funding lapse occurs when (1) a bill providing appropriations for the Coast Guard for a fiscal year has not been enacted before the beginning of that fiscal year, and no joint resolution providing continuing appropriations for the Coast Guard is in effect; and (2) a bill providing appropriations for the Department of Defense (DOD) for the fiscal year has been enacted before the beginning of the fiscal year, or a joint resolution providing continuing appropriation for DOD is in effect.&#160;

If a Coast Guard-specific funding lapse occurs, the bill provides appropriations to the Coast Guard for

pay and allowances for military members of the Coast Guard who perform active service or inactive-duty training;pay and benefits for certain civilian employees and contract employees;the payment of a death gratuity;payments for travel related to funerals, the dignified transfer of remains, and unit memorial services; andthe temporary continuation of the basic allowance for housing for dependents of members of the Coast Guard dying on active duty.The bill generally provides the appropriations to the Coast Guard until the earlier of (1)&#160;the enactment of specified Coast Guard appropriations legislation, or (2)&#160;the termination of the availability of appropriations for DOD.</summary>
</bill>
