<bill session="108" type="s" number="522" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:21Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Native American Energy Development and Self-Determination Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to assist Indian tribes in developing energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Energy Development and Self-Determination Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000077"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000407" joined="2003-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000162" joined="2003-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3172"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3172-3175" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gas industry"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Native American Energy Development and Self-Determination Act of 2003 - Amends the Energy Policy Act of 1992 to require the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) establish an Indian Energy Resource Development Program to revise the program of grants and low-interest loans to Indian tribes and tribal consortia to develop the managerial and technical capacity to develop energy resource on Indian lands and promote the vertical integration of such resources.Repeals the Indian tribes energy assistance demonstration program.Authorizes Indians or Indian tribes to enter into leases or business agreements for the purpose of energy development.Authorizes Indian tribes to grant rights-of-way over tribal land for pipelines or electric transmission or distribution lines without specific approval by the Secretary under specified conditions.Specifies that Federal employees on the Indian Energy Resource Commission are to serve the Commission without additional compensation.Authorizes the Chairperson of the Commission to: (1) appoint and terminate an executive director and other personnel as necessary; and (2) set compensation for such personnel within specified limitations. (Currently, the Commission appoints the executive director, who appoints other personnel; and compensation is specified according to the Federal Executive Schedule.)Revises specified detail requirements for Federal employees on the Commission.Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, in cooperation with Indian tribes or tribally-designated housing entities of Indian tribes, to provide to eligible nonprofit and community organizations, technical assistance to initiate and expand the use of energy saving technologies in housing construction and rehabilitation.Directs the Secretary of the Interior to review and report to the Secretary (who shall report to specified congressional committees) on all activities being conducted under the Indian Mineral Development Act of 1982.Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees on energy development potential on Indian land.</summary>
</bill>
