<bill session="108" type="s" number="1582" updated="2023-01-15T07:03:00Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Valles Caldera Preservation Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Valles Preservation Act to improve the preservation of the Valles Caldera, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Valles Caldera Preservation Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Valles Caldera Preservation Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2003-09-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-196.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-269.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="524">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 524.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9327-9328" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9327-9328" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:03:27-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest products"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Renewable natural resources"/>
    <term name="Research natural areas"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-29T19:25:53Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Valles Caldera Preservation Act of 2004 - Amends the Valles Caldera Preservation Act to require the Secretary of Agriculture to negotiate a price for buying the remaining mineral interests of the Valles Caldera Preserve in New Mexico. Directs that any difference between the sum estimated to be just compensation by the Secretary and the amount awarded be paid from the permanent judgment appropriation.

Requires the Trust to determine the character of, and the necessity for, any obligations and expenditures of the Trust and the manner in which obligations and expenditures shall be incurred, allowed, and paid.

Grants authority to use monies received from claims, judgments, or settlements arising from activities occurring on the Baca Ranch or the Preserve after October 27, 1999, for specified purposes.

Provides for the rate of compensation of the chairperson of the Trust.

Authorizes the Trust to dispose of forage, forest products, or marketable renewable resources as part of its resource management authority.

Directs the Secretary to develop a plan to carry out fire preparedness, suppression, and emergency rehabilitation services on the Preserve. Authorizes the Secretary to provide presuppression and non-emergency rehabilitation and restoration services for the Trust, to the extent generally authorized at other National Forest System units, at any time on a reimbursable basis.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-269</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
