<bill session="118" type="h" number="5933" updated="2025-11-19T04:19:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-06T17:21:40-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-12-06T17:21:40-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DETERRENT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require additional information in disclosures of foreign gifts and contracts from foreign sources, restrict contracts with certain foreign entities and foreign countries of concern, require certain staff and faculty to report foreign gifts and contracts, and require disclosure of certain foreign investments within endowments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001314" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001316" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001135" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000632" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001093" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000307" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000401" joined="2023-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000595" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001136" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000828" joined="2023-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2023-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-24">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 118-278.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-11-24" calendar="Union" number="223">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 223.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-11-24">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Education and the Workforce. H. Rept. 118-278.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-04T17:52:31-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 906 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4468, H.R. 5933 and H.J. Res. 88. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4468 and H.R. 5933 under a structured rule and H.J. Res. 88 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T13:44:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 906.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6166-6184" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6171-6175" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T13:44:10-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4468, H.R. 5933 and H.J. Res. 88. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4468 and H.R. 5933 under a structured rule and H.J. Res. 88 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T13:46:12-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 906 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T13:46:13-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James C. Moylan to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T13:47:32-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5933.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:17:53-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:24:28-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fallon amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:28:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fallon amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:35:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Molinaro amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:39:17-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Molinaro amendment No. 5, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Molinaro demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:40:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:49:57-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 6, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:50:33-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T14:58:15-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 906, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T15:09:27-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Mr. Scott (VA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T15:09:49-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Foxx moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T15:10:02-05:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise. Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T15:10:13-05:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5933 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T16:30:26-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6184-6187" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T16:30:46-05:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T17:13:48-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5933.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T17:14:37-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T17:14:51-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="701" datetime="2023-12-06T17:21:40-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 246 - 170 (Roll no. 701).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T17:21:42-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-06T19:04:22-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5933.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3362" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5902" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6165" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="906" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h833"/>
    <amendment number="h832"/>
    <amendment number="h831"/>
    <amendment number="h830"/>
    <amendment number="h829"/>
    <amendment number="h828"/>
    <amendment number="h827"/>
    <amendment number="h826"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-12-04T19:15:36Z" status="Reported to House">Defending Education Transparency and Ending Rogue Regimes Engaging in Nefarious Transactions Act or the DETERRENT Act

This bill expands oversight and disclosure requirements related to foreign sources and institutions of higher education (IHEs).

Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to annually disclose to the Department of Education (ED) any year in which the IHE

 receives a gift from a foreign country of concern (e.g., China or Russia) or foreign entity of concern of any dollar amount; receives a gift or contract from a foreign source (other than a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern) that is valued at $50,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts or contracts within a calendar year (current disclosure threshold is $250,000 or more), or which has an undetermined monetary value; enters into a contract with a foreign country of concern or foreign entity of concern after receiving a waiver for such contract; or is substantially controlled by a foreign source. Additionally, the bill

 prohibits IHEs from entering into contracts with a foreign country of concern or with a foreign entity of concern without obtaining a waiver, requires certain IHEs to disclose gifts or contracts between covered individuals (e.g., researchers) and foreign sources, and requires private IHEs with specified assets or investments to file annual investment disclosure reports. The bill requires ED to investigate possible violations of this bill and outlines the various penalties for each violation.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-278</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
