<bill session="117" type="h" number="2115" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:05Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFER Pipelines Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to apply certain procedures before granting a certificate of public convenience and necessity for a proposed pipeline project, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe and Accountable Federal Energy Review for Pipelines Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFER Pipelines Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000822"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001203" joined="2021-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-14T18:29:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe and Accountable Federal Energy Review for Pipelines Act of 2021 or the SAFER Pipelines Act of 2021

This bill revises the process used by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to review a pipeline expansion project.

Before granting a certificate for a proposed pipeline expansion project, FERC must conduct (1) a full evidentiary hearing on any contested issue of need for the expansion; or (2) a cumulative review of major energy infrastructure projects planned throughout the region of the expansion, their purported purpose and need, and their prospective impacts on state and regional energy goals. In addition, the bill outlines criteria FERC must consider before granting such a certificate. In addition to existing environmental review requirements, FERC must meet new environmental review requirements for interstate natural gas pipeline projects, including the requirement to consider the cumulative impacts of other natural gas pipeline projects as specified by this bill.Finally, FERC must monitor approved pipeline projects for five years to ensure that environmental mitigation steps have been implemented.</summary>
</bill>
