<bill session="111" type="h" number="828" updated="2022-02-03T06:08:23Z">
  <state datetime="2009-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FERS Redeposit Act</title>
    <title type="display">FERS Redeposit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 84 of title 5, United States Code, to allow individuals who return to Government service after receiving a refund of retirement contributions to recapture credit for the service covered by that refund by repaying the amount that was so received, with interest.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000933"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2009-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2009-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E185"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, Post Office, and the District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-27T20:59:39Z" status="Introduced in House">FERS Redeposit Act - Allows each individual who has returned to government service and who has received a refund of retirement contributions under the Federal Employees' Retirement System (FERS) or any other retirement system established for federal employees covering service for which such individual may be allowed credit under FERS to deposit the amount that was so received, with interest, to the credit of the Civil Service Retirement and Disability Fund. Allows deposits in one or more installments.

Disallows the recapture of credit for service covered by the refund until such a deposit is made.</summary>
</bill>
