<bill session="116" type="s" number="4427" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:20Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Authorization for Vaccines during Emergencies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for transparency in emergency use authorization of vaccine products, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2020-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2020-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T16:25:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safe Authorization for Vaccines during Emergencies Act or the SAVE Act

This bill imposes requirements related to the emergency authorization of a vaccine during a declared public health emergency.

If a sponsor of a product seeks Food and Drug Administration (FDA) authorization to use the product as a vaccine to address the threat causing the declared public health emergency, both the FDA and the product sponsor must meet with, and present product-related data and information to, the Vaccines and Related Biological Products Advisory Committee. The Department of Health and Human Services may make an exception to this requirement if convening a meeting would not be in the public interest.

To receive an emergency authorization, the product sponsor must agree to seek FDA market approval for the vaccine within a certain time period.

After an emergency authorization, the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices shall report recommendations regarding the vaccine to Congress and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</summary>
</bill>
