<bill session="111" type="h" number="6195" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:34Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Justice Along the Southwest Border Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for additional district court judges for certain judicial districts, and to provide for the cross-designation of special assistant United States attorneys to prosecute certain border-related offenses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Justice Along the Southwest Border Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001139"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts and Competition Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-19T18:53:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Justice Along the Southwest Border Act of 2010 - Directs the President to appoint additional district judges for certain judicial districts in Arizona, California, New Mexico, and Texas, including temporary judgeships in Arizona and California.

Directs the Attorney General to allocate any amounts appropriated pursuant to this Act for the hiring and training of special assistant U.S. attorneys.

Requires such funds to be used to: (1) train local prosecutors in techniques used to prosecute border-related offenses cases; (2) train local prosecutors in federal and state laws relating to border-related offenses; (3) cross-designate local prosecutors as special assistant U.S. attorneys; and (4) hire additional local prosecutors who, with the approval of the U.S. attorney, shall be cross-designated to prosecute both federal and state border-related offenses cases.</summary>
</bill>
