<bill session="118" type="h" number="2372" updated="2025-11-19T02:57:54Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STAND with Taiwan Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sanctions Targeting Aggressors of Neighboring Democracies with Taiwan Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STAND with Taiwan Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the imposition of sanctions with respect to the People's Republic of China if the People's Liberation Army initiates a military invasion of Taiwan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000598" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committees on Financial Services, Ways and Means, the Judiciary, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1027" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4789" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-08T22:16:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Sanctions Targeting Aggressors of Neighboring Democracies with Taiwan Act of 2023 or the STAND with Taiwan Act of 2023

This bill requires the imposition of sanctions in the event of a military invasion of Taiwan by China and addresses related issues.

If the President determines that China or any of its proxies has initiated a military invasion of Taiwan, or if a joint resolution making such a determination is enacted, the bill requires

 the President to impose visa- and property-blocking sanctions on certain senior officials of China's government and the Chinese Communist Party (CCP); the Department of the Treasury to impose property-blocking sanctions on specified foreign financial institutions, including banks under the jurisdiction of China and in which China's government holds an interest; Treasury to impose property-blocking sanctions on any entity affiliated with China's government or the CCP; the Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC) to prohibit the trading of the securities of an issuer affiliated with China's government or the CCP on a national securities exchange; Treasury to prohibit U.S. financial institutions from making certain investments, such as investments in an entity owned or controlled by China's government, the CCP, or China's military; the prohibition of the importation of certain goods, including goods produced wholly or in part in China or by certain entities owned or financed by China's government or the CCP; and a prohibition on any depository institution or SEC-registered securities broker or dealer processing funds transfers to or from China or for the benefit of Chinese government officials or CCP members.</summary>
</bill>
