<bill session="110" type="s" number="1378" updated="2023-01-11T16:47:42Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dextromethorphan Distribution Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the distribution of the drug dextromethorphan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dextromethorphan Distribution Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="970" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug adulteration"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-08-09T12:58:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dextromethorphan Distribution Act of 2007 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to deem to be adulterated any unfinished dextromethorphan that is possessed, received, or distributed in violation of this Act.

Prohibits a person from: (1) possessing or receiving unfinished dextromethorphan unless the person is registered with the Secretary of Health and Human Services as a producer of a drug or device or otherwise registered, licensed, or approved pursuant to federal or state law to engage in the practice of pharmacy, pharmaceutical production, or manufacture or distribution of pharmaceutical ingredients; or (2) distributing unfinished dextromethorphan to any person other than a registered or otherwise authorized person. Excludes from such prohibitions common carriers that possess, receive, or distribute unfinished dextromethorphan for purposes of distributing it between authorized persons.</summary>
</bill>
