<bill session="117" type="h" number="5882" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:38Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHELTER Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding Homes by Ensuring Licensing and Transparency with Eligibility Requirements Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHELTER Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to improve the process for awarding grants under section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 with respect to opening or funding shelter facilities for unaccompanied alien children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000523"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2021-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3182" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-17T13:19:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding Homes by Ensuring Licensing and Transparency with Eligibility Requirements Act of 2021 or the SHELTER Act of 2021

This bill imposes certain requirements on applicants for certain Office of Refugee Resettlement grants to open or fund shelter facilities for unaccompanied alien children.

Specifically an applicant for such a grant must (1) disclose in the application any adverse action (generally an adverse criminal or regulatory action relating to a government contract or the care of children) taken against the applicant in the five-year period before the application, and (2) be licensed under state law to operate the facility in question.

The Department of Health and Human Services must collaborate with state agencies to review state databases for information about adverse actions taken against such applicants.</summary>
</bill>
