<bill session="117" type="h" number="5059" updated="2023-01-01T20:19:03Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 83 of title 41, United States Code, to increase the requirement for American-made content, to strengthen the waiver provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Make It in America Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Make It in America Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000559"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E907"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="363" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1303" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-19T21:18:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Make It in America Act

This bill addresses domestic content requirements and narrows instances in which waivers may be granted.

Specifically, the bill directs the Office for Federal Procurement Policy of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to promulgate regulations to standardize and simplify how federal agencies comply with, report on, and enforce the Buy American Act, including guidelines to ensure that a project is not disaggregated for purposes of avoiding the applicability of such requirements.

Before granting a waiver in the public interest with respect to a product sourced from a foreign country, a federal agency shall assess whether a significant portion of the cost advantage of the product is the result of the use of dumped steel, iron, or manufactured goods or the use of injuriously subsidized steel, iron, or manufactured goods.

The OMB shall establish within it a Made in America Office to maximize and enforce compliance with domestic preference statutes, develop and implement procedures to review waiver requests, ensure that contracting personnel, financial assistance personnel, and nonfederal recipients are regularly trained on obligations under such statutes, and ensure the development of a domestic supply base to meet federal procurement requirements.

The bill directs the Department of Transportation to enter into a technical assistance partnership with the Department of Commerce to ensure the development of a domestic supply base to support intermodal transportation and to ensure compliance with domestic preference statutes.</summary>
</bill>
