<bill session="117" type="s" number="1550" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:25Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Foreign Service Families Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support Foreign Service families, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Service Families Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2021-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4306" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-01T16:53:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Foreign Service Families Act of 2021

This bill increases access to career and educational opportunities for eligible family members of foreign service employees.

Specifically, the Department of State must use additional hiring preferences and apply appropriate hiring standards to eligible family members seeking employment in certain civil service positions overseas. Additionally, the State Department may take other steps to improve job portability and otherwise support employment of eligible family members who work in the federal civil service or private sector jobs. The State Department must also report on the implementation of the Foreign Service Family Reserve Corps, a program that expedites hiring and onboarding processes for family members who are eligible for appointment to positions overseas.

Furthermore, each federal agency must include in its telework policy the circumstances under which an employee may temporarily work from an approved location overseas.

The bill also makes foreign service employees (or their spouses and dependent children) who are domiciled or assigned to a duty station in a given state eligible for in-state tuition at public institutions of higher education in that state. Such individuals retain their eligibility for in-state tuition provided they maintain continuous enrollment even if their domicile or duty station changes. Additionally, the bill entitles members of the Foreign Service who are posted abroad to terminate residential and motor vehicle leases and telephone service contracts without being subject to early termination fees.</summary>
</bill>
