<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1083" updated="2022-02-03T05:20:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="6003" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-06-11T13:28:42-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001168"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-06-11"/>
  <description>Amendment requires Amtrak, within one year of enactment, to report to Congress on the results of an evaluation of passenger rail between Cornwells Heights, PA, and New York City, NY, and between Princeton Junction, NJ, and New York City, NY, to determine whether to expand passenger rail service by increasing the frequency of stops or reducing commuter ticket prices for this route.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 110-703 to require Amtrak, within one year of enactment, to report to Congress on the results of an evaluation of passenger rail between Cornwells Heights, PA, and New York City, NY, and between Princeton Junction, NJ, and New York City, NY, to determine whether to expand passenger rail service by increasing the frequency of stops or reducing commuter ticket prices for this route.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-06-11T13:28:42-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Murphy, Patrick amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T13:21:10-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Murphy, Patrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5259-5260" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5259" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T13:28:42-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T13:21:10-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A007) offered by Mr. Murphy, Patrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5259-5260" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5259" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11T13:28:42-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Murphy, Patrick amendment (A007) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-11">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
