<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1606" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:40Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10T13:46:09-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-08-10T13:46:09-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1586) to modernize the air traffic control system, improve the safety, reliability, and availability of transportation by air in the United States, provide for modernization of the air traffic control system, reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1586) to modernize the air traffic control system, improve the safety, reliability, and availability of transportation by air in the United States, provide for modernization of the air traffic control system, reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-09">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-584, by Ms. Slaughter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-09T19:14:39-04:00">
      <text>It shall be in order to take from the Speaker's table the bill H.R. 1586 and to consider in the House, without intervention of any point of order, a motion offered by the Chair of the Committee on Appropriations or his designee that the House concur in the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill. The Senate amendment and the motion shall be considered as read and the motion shall be debatable for one hour equally divided and controlled. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to final adoption.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-08-09" calendar="House" number="231">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 231.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T10:55:44-04:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6589-6597" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T10:55:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1606.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T11:58:34-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 1606, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Dreier demanded the Yeas and Nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on ordering the previous question on H.Res. 1606 until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T13:18:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6603" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T13:37:57-04:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 244 - 164 (Roll no. 516).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6597, H6603" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T13:39:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6604" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="517" datetime="2010-08-10T13:46:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 229 - 173 (Roll no. 517).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6590" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10T13:46:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1586" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-08-10T08:09:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the Senate amendment to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to the bill (H.R. 1586) to modernize the air traffic control system, improve the safety, reliability, and availability of transportation by air in the United States, provide for modernization of the air traffic control system, reauthorize the Federal Aviation Administration.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-584</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
