<bill session="108" type="s" number="531" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:21Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Missouri River Enhancement and Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish the Missouri River Monitoring and Research Program, to authorize the establishment of the Missouri River Basin Stakeholder Committee, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Missouri River Enhancement and Monitoring Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2003-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3186"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3186-3187" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Biological research"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Missouri River Enhancement and Monitoring Act of 2003 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Biological Resources Division of the U.S. Geological Survey, to establish the Missouri River monitoring and research program to: (1) coordinate the collection of information on the biological and water quality characteristics of the Missouri River and evaluate how those characteristics are affected by hydrology; (2) coordinate the monitoring and assessment of biota (including threatened or endangered species) and habitat of the River; and (3) make recommendations on means to assist in restoring the River's ecosystem.Designates the River Studies Center of that Division, located in Columbia, Missouri, to administer the program. Directs the Center to: (1) assist in the recovery of the threatened and endangered species of the River; (2) establish a scientific database; (3) enter into contracts with Indian tribes that have reservations along the River for activities supporting this Act; (4) provide financial assistance to the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service and State agencies to monitor and recover threatened and endangered species; and (5) carry out a competitive grant program for research on the impacts of the operation and maintenance of the River's mainstem reservoirs on the health of fish and wildlife.Requires the Center, the Directors of the Fish and Wildlife Service and of the Geological Survey, and the Missouri River Natural Resources Committee to: (1) prioritize research needs; (2) issue a request for grant proposals; and (3) award grants.Directs the Governors of specified States and the governing bodies of the Indian tribes of the Missouri River Basin to establish a Missouri River Basin Stakeholder Committee to make recommendations to Federal agencies on means of restoring the River's ecosystem.</summary>
</bill>
