<bill session="116" type="s" number="2046" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:50Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Health Care for Retired Public Safety Officers Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Health Care for Retired Public Safety Officers Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to protect the health care benefits of retired public safety officers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-30T14:04:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect Health Care for Retired Public Safety Officers Act of 2019

This bill directs the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), under the State Homeland Security Grant Program, to require each state to include in its grant application a certification for the protection of health care benefits for retired public safety officers. A public safety officer is a law enforcement officer, firefighter, or an emergency medical services provider whose conditions of employment are determined by a collective bargaining agreement.

Such certification must provide that the state will not (1) unilaterally modify or eliminate health care benefits for a public safety officer retiree, or (2) allocate grant funds to a local government or Indian tribe that has not certified to the state that such benefits will not be unilaterally modified or eliminated.</summary>
</bill>
