<bill session="109" type="h" number="6129" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:18Z">
  <state datetime="2006-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Credit Monitoring Clarification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Credit Repair Organizations Act to clarify the applicability of certain provisions to credit monitoring services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Credit Monitoring Clarification Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000013" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001253" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001247" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000008" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000591" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2006-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2006-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-10-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Domestic and International Monetary Policy, Trade, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA19" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="3662" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-08-27T19:40:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Credit Monitoring Clarification Act - Amends the Credit Repair Organizations Act to cite conditions under which provision to a consumer of credit reports, credit score analysis, and assistance in a case of identity theft shall not be considered as an activity to improve a consumer's credit status, which is subject to regulation under such Act.

Exempts from regulation under such Act any person (credit repair organization, or CRO) representing that it can modify or remove, or assist the consumer in modifying or removing, any information in the consumer's credit report if the CRO gives clear and conspicuous notice, before the consumer pays or agrees to pay it, that: (1) neither the consumer nor anyone else has the right to have accurate and current information removed from a credit report; and (2) the consumer has the right to dispute any inaccurate information by contacting the credit bureau directly. Requires a CRO, to qualify for this exemption from regulation, also to give the consumer, before payment or agreement to pay, a specified disclosure entitled "Your Rights Concerning Your Consumer Credit File."</summary>
</bill>
