<bill session="111" type="h" number="2829" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:50Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recidivism Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure prompt access to supplemental security income, Social Security disability, and Medicaid benefits for persons released from certain public institutions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recidivism Reduction Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000455" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2009-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000113" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000336" joined="2009-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000053" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2009-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000462" joined="2009-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2009-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2009-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-11">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6622"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-07T19:45:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Recidivism Reduction Act - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income for Aged, Blind, and Disabled) (SSI) of the Social Security Act (SSA) to require the reinstatement upon release of an otherwise eligible disabled inmate for SSI benefits which were terminated owing to the inmate's incarceration in a jail, prison, penal institution, or correctional facility for a period of 12 or more consecutive months.

Requires the inmate to apply for reinstatement and resumption of such benefits within 36 months after release. Allows application for reinstatement even before release. Permits provisional benefits to such an individual until the application is acted upon.

Requires the reinstatement of SSI benefit eligibility for such an individual's spouse if the spouse was previously an SSI-eligible spouse.

Amends SSA title II (Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Benefits) (OASDI) to direct the Commissioner of Social Security to develop a system for prerelease application for resumption of suspended OASDI disability insurance benefits, or other benefits based on disability.

Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to require state Medicaid plans to provide that in the case of any individual enrolled for medical assistance immediately before becoming an inmate of a public institution: (1) the enrollment shall be reinstated upon the individual's release from such institution unless and until there is a determination that the individual is no longer eligible to be so enrolled; and (2) any period of continuous eligibility in effect on the date the individual became such an inmate shall be reinstated as of the release date and the duration of such period shall be determined without regard to the period in which the individual was such an inmate.

Increases from 90% to 95% the federal matching rate for any state implementing a Medicaid reinstatement system.

Authorizes case management services in order to engage in planning for services following an individual's release from a public institution.</summary>
</bill>
