<bill session="119" type="s" number="3005" updated="2025-11-06T14:37:41Z">
  <state datetime="2025-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Non-Essential Workers Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Non-Essential Workers Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Executive agencies to submit reports to Congress and to the Office of Personnel Management regarding employees who are furloughed during any period during which there is a lapse in appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-10-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-10-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="5908" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-10-27T19:27:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Non-Essential Workers Transparency Act

This bill requires federal agencies to submit reports to Congress and the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) regarding employees who were furloughed during a lapse in appropriations (i.e, government shutdown), the total number of employees, and the cost of salaries.&#160;

Specifically, each federal agency&#160;must submit a report to specified congressional committees and OPM within 30 days of the end of a lapse in appropriations. The report must include specified details regarding

the total number of employees (including contract employees) employed by the agency before the lapse began,the total number of employees who were furloughed during the lapse,the total number of employees who were not furloughed during the lapse, and&#160;the total annual cost of the salaries for each group of employees.&#160;The report must be submitted in an unclassified form, but it may include a classified annex. Each congressional committee that receives a report must publish the report on its website within 30 days.&#160;

OPM must consolidate all of the reports submitted with respect to a lapse in appropriations and publish the consolidated report on its website.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
