<bill session="118" type="s" number="2678" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Outbound Investment Transparency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Outbound Investment Transparency Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for an investment screening mechanism relating to covered sectors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2024-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2670" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2226" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-07T12:50:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Outbound Investment Transparency Act of 2023

This bill requires U.S. persons to notify the Department of the Treasury when making investments in or engaging in other economic activity associated with North Korea, China, Russia, or Iran. This requirement applies to U.S. persons in certain sectors, including advanced semiconductors and microelectronics, artificial intelligence, and satellite-based communications. Covered activities that trigger the notification requirement include investing in an entity, establishing a venture or subsidiary, or acquiring certain positions in an entity in these countries.

U.S. persons must notify Treasury 14 days before engaging in a covered activity. However, if the covered activity is a secured transaction, notification must be provided not later than 14 days after the transaction.&#160;

Specific information or documentary material provided to Treasury is not subject to public disclosure, with certain exceptions.

Treasury must at least annually report to Congress a summary of the notifications received under this bill.

The Department of State must engage with allied countries to coordinate protocols, procedures, and information sharing regarding these investments. The Department of Justice has the authority to enforce this bill. &#160;</summary>
</bill>
