<bill session="117" type="h" number="5633" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-05T12:32:52-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-05T12:32:52-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Inspector General Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Homeland Security Inspector General Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Inspector General Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Inspector General Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to enhance transparency regarding reports conducted by the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001193" joined="2021-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-21">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Homeland Security. H. Rept. 117-233.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-01-21" calendar="Union" number="168">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T12:22:40-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Payne moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T12:22:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4162-4164" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T12:23:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5633.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-04-05T12:32:52-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4162-4163" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05T12:32:55-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-20T19:11:58Z" status="Passed House">Department of Homeland Security Inspector General Transparency Act

This bill addresses reports conducted by the Office of Inspector General (OIG) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Specifically, the bill requires the OIG to submit to Congress any report finalized on or after 30 days after the enactment of this bill that substantiates

 a violation of specified provisions regarding prohibited personnel practices, protected communications, or retaliatory personnel actions; a violation of Presidential Personnel Directive-19 (protecting whistleblowers with access to classified information); or an allegation of misconduct, waste, fraud, abuse, or a violation of policy within DHS involving a member of the Senior Executive Service or politically appointed official of DHS. The OIG must make each report publicly available on its website, with exceptions.

The bill requires the OIG's semiannual reports to include specified information regarding

 ongoing audits, inspections, and evaluations; significant changes to the narrative description of each such audit, inspection, or evaluation; certain delays; and data with respect to tips and complaints made to the OIG Hotline or otherwise referred to DHS. The OIG must report within one year on the policies, procedures, and internal controls established that ensure compliance with the Quality Standards for Federal Offices of Inspector General from the Council of Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency. The Government Accountability Office must evaluate such report within one year after receipt of the report.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-233</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
