<bill session="116" type="h" number="5294" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Student Borrower Protections Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Truth in Lending Act to establish a postsecondary education loan borrower bill of rights and to require certain creditors to obtain private loan certifications from institutions of higher education, to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection to issue rules to establish standards for reporting information related to student loans to consumer reporting agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Borrower Protections Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000370"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2019-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2020-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 32 - 26.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1354" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer Financial Protection Bureau"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit and credit markets"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Interest, dividends, interest rates"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-06T18:28:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Borrower Protections Act of 2019

This bill places requirements on lenders, servicers, or assignees of postsecondary education loans, establishes standards for reporting student loan information to consumer reporting agencies, and requires certification of certain educational lenders.

Specifically, the bill establishes rules for lenders, servicers, or assignees of postsecondary education loans, including requirements related to (1) the sale, transfer, or assignment of such loans; (2) interest rate and term changes for such loans; (3) payment information required to be included with each billing cycle; and (4) application and allocation of payments.

The Consumer Financial Protection Bureau (CFPB) must develop and issue model forms to allow borrowers to compare alternative repayment options, forbearance, and deferment options. The CFPB must also establish a student loan servicing interagency working group, which shall make recommendations for the regulations required under the bill.

Further, the CFPB must issue rules to establish standards for the furnishing of information related to student loans to a consumer reporting agency, and any furnisher of such information must comply with such rules.

A private educational lender must, in general, obtain a private loan certification from an institution of higher education before consummating any loan with a student attending such institution.</summary>
</bill>
