<bill session="118" type="s" number="1495" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEAT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heat pump Energy Assistance and Training Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a program to provide support on the use of industrial heat pumps, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-28T16:47:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Heat pump Energy Assistance and Training Act or the HEAT Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish an industrial heat&#160;pump program. Among other things, the program must provide technical support to farmers, ranchers, and rural small businesses on (1) the use of industrial heat pumps, and (2) the availability of federal programs to assist in the adoption to using industrial heat pumps. An industrial heat pump is a vapor compression device that transforms low grade production waste heat by increasing the temperature of air or process fluid, such as water, to meet the heating needs of agricultural, industrial, or commercial processes.

The bill also amends USDA's Rural Energy for America Program (REAP) to specifically include the purchase and installation of industrial heat pumps. Under REAP, USDA provides (1) loan guarantees and grants to agricultural producers and rural small businesses to purchase renewable energy systems and make energy efficiency improvements, and (2) loan guarantees to agricultural producers to purchase and install energy efficient equipment and systems for agricultural production and processing.

USDA must submit an annual report to Congress describing progress made in building awareness, creating materials, and providing support for farmers, ranchers, and rural small businesses under the bill.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
