<bill session="111" type="h" number="1787" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Low Carbon Fuel Standard Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Low Carbon Fuel Standard Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act regarding transportation fuels and establishment of a low carbon fuel standard.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2009-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2009-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Motor fuels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-25T21:32:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Low Carbon Fuel Standard Act of 2009 - Amends the Clean Air Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to issue regulations that: (1) determine the lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions of all transportation fuels; (2) determine the fuel emission baseline (i.e., average lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions per unit of energy of all transportation fuels sold in the United States in 2005); (3) apply to refineries, blenders, and importers of transportation fuel; (4) ensure that, for 2014-2022, annual average lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions do not exceed the fuel emission baseline; and (5) ensure that, for 2023 and thereafter, transportation fuel providers make specified reductions in the annual average lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions for transportation fuel sold in the United States.

Grants the Administrator authority to waive emission reduction requirements of this Act to prevent economic or environmental harm. Requires the Administrator to study the environmental and resource conservation impacts of the regulations required by this Act and their effect on energy security.</summary>
</bill>
