<bill session="116" type="s" number="2125" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:37Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bot Disclosure and Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bot Disclosure and Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect the right of the American public under the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States to receive news and information from disparate sources by regulating the use of automated software programs intended to impersonate or replicate human activity on social media.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4536" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-20T14:45:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bot Disclosure and Accountability Act of 2019 This bill requires social media providers to establish and implement policies that require their users to publicly disclose the use of any automated software program or process intended to impersonate or replicate human activity (i.e., bots) on the provider&#8217;s social media website. Social media providers also must establish processes for identifying and removing the online activity of a user or profile making use of an automated software program that intended to impersonate or replicate human activity online and does not comply with the disclosure requirements. In addition, political candidates and political parties are prohibited from using automated software programs for public communications and from soliciting, accepting, purchasing, or selling such programs. Further, political committees, corporations, and labor organizations are prohibited from using automated software programs to communicate messages that advocate for the election or defeat of a candidate or in any other electioneering communication.</summary>
</bill>
