<bill session="118" type="h" number="8152" updated="2025-05-27T14:11:57Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-09T18:24:08-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-09T18:24:08-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Remote Access Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Remote Access Security Act</title>
    <title type="short">Remote Access Security Act</title>
    <title type="display">Remote Access Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to provide for control of remote access of items, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000599"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000308" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001218" joined="2024-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2024-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T18:20:29-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barr moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T18:20:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5077-5078" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T18:20:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 8152.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-09-09T18:24:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5077-5078" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-09-09T18:24:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-16T16:06:18Z" status="Passed House">Remote Access Security Act

This bill broadens the scope of the U.S. export control system to include remote access of controlled items if such access&#160;poses a serious risk to U.S. national security or foreign policy.

Remote access means access to an item subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and included on the Commerce Control List by a foreign person through a network connection, including the internet or a cloud computing service, from a location other than where the item is physically located, to use the functions of the item if such use may pose a serious risk to U.S. national security or foreign policy. This includes (1) training an artificial intelligence model that could, among other actions,&#160;substantially lower the barrier of entry for experts or nonexperts to design&#160;or use weapons of mass destruction&#160;or to enable offensive cyber operations through automated vulnerability discovery and exploitation; (2) accessing a quantum computer that could enable offensive cyber operations or other risks to national security; or (3) accessing hacking tools.

The Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (ECRA), which is implemented through the Export Administration Regulations, provides a permanent statutory basis for controlling the export of dual-use goods (e.g., items with both civilian and military uses) and certain military&#160;parts and components. This bill applies export controls under&#160;ECRA to remote access of items, thereby allowing the Department of Commerce's Bureau of Industry and Security to issue licenses and impose penalties related to remote access of controlled items.</summary>
</bill>
