<bill session="108" type="h" number="4935" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:19Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medicaid and CHIP Safety Net Preservation Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend titles XIX and XXI of the Social Security Act to clarify and ensure that the authority granted to the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 1115 of that Act is used solely to promote the objectives of the Medicaid and State children's health insurance programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid and CHIP Safety Net Preservation Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000355"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001036" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2004-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Rural health"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Welfare waivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-09-16T20:58:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Medicaid and CHIP Safety Net Preservation Act of 2004 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act (SSA) with respect to the authority of the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) conduct research and demonstration projects under several programs, including Medicaid and SCHIP (State Children's Health Insurance) under SSA title XXI; and (2) waive certain statutory requirements for conducting these projects without congressional review.

Prohibits the Secretary from imposing or approving under such authority: (1) a cap, limitation, or other restriction on payment to a State for amounts expended as medical assistance under the Medicaid program; (2) an elimination of, or modification limiting, the entitlement of an individual to receive any medical assistance for which Federal financial participation is claimed under Medicaid; (3) an elimination or modification of the amount, duration, or scope of early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services; or (4) an elimination or modification of the amount, duration, or scope of certain safety-net services, including those of a rural health clinic and a federally-qualified health center.

Amends SSA title XI to establish public notice and comment requirements for States and the Secretary with respect to any State proposal for an experimental, pilot, or demonstration project (or project modification) to assist in promoting Medicaid or SCHIP objectives that would result in a substantive change in eligibility, enrollment, benefits, financing, or cost-sharing under a State program.</summary>
</bill>
