<bill session="118" type="s" number="1839" updated="2025-01-14T19:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LGBTQI+ Data Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LGBTQI+ Data Inclusion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve Federal population surveys by requiring the collection of voluntary, self-disclosed information on sexual orientation, gender identity, and variations in sex characteristics in certain surveys, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2024-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2024-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3970" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-30T00:02:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">LGBTQI+ Data Inclusion Act

This bill addresses federal data collection of voluntary, self-disclosed information on sexual orientation, gender identity, and variations in sex characteristics.

Specifically, the bill requires federal agencies that collect information through a survey for statistical purposes that includes demographic data (where subjects self-report information or a proxy provides information about the subject or responds for all persons in a household) to review existing data sets to determine which data sets do not include information about sexual orientation, gender identity, and variations in sex characteristics.

Such agencies must assess needed changes in survey methods related to asking questions on such matters.

Agencies that publish reports relying on survey demographic data must include information on sexual orientation, gender identity, and variations in sex characteristics.

Agencies may waive this publication requirement on a case-by-case basis if the confidentiality of the information cannot be maintained or if adding such information to the survey would impair the agency's ability to preserve the utility, accuracy, or objectivity of the survey while also generating relevant evidence about the LGBTQI+ community.

The Government Accountability Office must report to Congress on the implementation of this bill's requirements by agencies.</summary>
</bill>
