<bill session="118" type="h" number="425" updated="2024-07-24T15:24:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">History and Tradition Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">History and Tradition Protection Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Revised Statutes of the United States to prevent the use of the legal system in a manner that extorts money from State and local governments, and the Federal Government, and inhibits such governments' constitutional actions under the first, tenth, and fourteenth amendments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000578" joined="2023-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-01-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Legal fees and court costs"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-26T12:06:13Z" status="Introduced in House">History and Tradition Protection Act of 2023 This bill limits the types of relief that may be awarded in civil suits that involve violations of the Constitution's Establishment Clause, which prohibits the government from establishing a religion.

Current law provides a statutory civil cause of action against state and local government actors for violations of constitutional rights, also known as Section 1983 lawsuits. The bill limits relief for Section 1983 lawsuits that involve violations of the Establishment Clause to injunctive and declaratory relief (i.e., nonmonetary relief) and prohibits the award of attorneys' fees in these cases, including those that involve monuments, public buildings, official seals, and government proceedings. The bill applies the same restrictions to similar lawsuits against federal agencies.</summary>
</bill>
