<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3022</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-14T22:48:29Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-14T22:48:29Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2004-11-20</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2004-11-20T18:35:19Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-11-20</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-11-20</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000303</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. McCain, John [R-AZ]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>MCCAIN</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <middleName>SIDNEY</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Technological innovations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-11-20</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-01-25T21:47:48Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Innovation Competitiveness Act of 2004 - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to designate a Technology Transfer Director within the Technology Administration to perform oversight and policy and development for technology transfer activities at the Department of Commerce.</p> <p>Requires the Director to: (1) coordinate activities of the Interagency Working Group on Technolgy Transfer; (2) coordinate with certain technology partnership ombudsmans; and (3) establish procedures for coordinating the Commerce Department's technology transfer outreach activities between appropriate Federal agencies, including the National Technical Information Service and the Federal Laboratory Consortium for Technology Transfer.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a research program within the Technology Administration that: (1) involves consultation with the various units of the Commerce Department; (2) builds upon ongoing private sector efforts; and (3) involves consortia.</p> <p>Instructs the Director to work with industry, trade associations, professional societies, and others to: (1) develop improved technology transfer research tools and practices; and (2) conduct a specified study.</p> <p>Requires the Director to oversee a dissemination and technical assistance program for the immediate dissemination and implementation of the practices, standards, and codes developed by the Technology Administration.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to designate a small business advocate within the Commerce Department to: (1) increase the participation of small business concerns; and (2) establish guidelines for a small business program under this Act.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to establish a State and Industry Task Force to highlight areas where the Federal Government can help States to provide a complementary research and development environment. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Innovation Competitiveness Act of 2004</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Innovation Competitiveness Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to enhance the Federal investment in research and development and the development of innovative technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Innovation Competitiveness Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2004-11-20T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-11-20</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
