<bill session="108" type="h" number="4388" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:01Z">
  <state datetime="2004-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Special Exposure Cohort Fairness Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include certain nuclear weapons program workers in the Special Exposure Cohort under the compensation program established by that Act.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Special Exposure Cohort Fairness Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H897"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation victims"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-06-09T19:14:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Special Exposure Cohort Fairness Act of 2004 - Amends the Energy Employees Occupational Illness Compensation Program Act of 2000 to include within its Special Exposure Cohort for compensation purposes certain employees who, during their employment at Los Alamos National Laboratory, Los Alamos, New Mexico, during the period 1945 through 2000: (1) were monitored through the use of dosimetry badges for exposure at the plant of the external parts of an employee's body to radiation; (2) were monitored through the use of bioassays, in vivo monitoring, or breath samples for exposure at the plant to internal radiation; or (3) worked in a job that had exposures comparable to a job that is monitored under certain DOE standards through the use of dosimetry badges for monitoring external radiation exposures, or bioassays, in vivo monitoring, for internal radiation exposures.

Defines Cohort-Eligible Los Alamos Worker as one employed: (1) as a security guard or construction worker; (2) in Area G or at the linear accelerator; or (3) in any area of Los Alamos National Laboratory and in any capacity, if all records necessary for radiation dose reconstruction with respect to such employee have not been received by the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health from the Department of Energy or its contractors within 200 days after receipt of a claim under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
