<bill session="116" type="s" number="1482" updated="2022-02-09T02:12:10Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an integrated national approach to respond to ongoing and expected effects of extreme weather and climate change by protecting, managing, and conserving the fish, wildlife, and plants of the United States, and to maximize Government efficiency and reduce costs, in cooperation with State, local, and Tribal governments and other entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2019-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2748" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Scientific communication"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-29T16:49:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safeguarding America's Future and Environment Act or the SAFE Act 

The bill requires the development of strategies to help fish, wildlife, and plants adapt to extreme weather changes and climate change.

Specifically, the bill requires the President to establish an interagency National Fish, Wildlife, and Plants Climate Adaptation Strategy Joint Implementation Working Group. The working group must adopt the 2013 National Fish, Wildlife, and Plants Climate Adaptation Strategy, which addresses the effects of extreme weather and climate change on fish, wildlife, and plants.

After the Committee on Earth and Environmental Sciences releases a periodic scientific assessment required under the U.S. Global Change Research Program, the working group must use sound science to review and revise the strategy to incorporate new information and advances in the development of strategies to help fish, wildlife, and plants adapt.

Each federal agency must integrate the strategy into agency plans, environmental reviews, and programs.

The Department of the Interior must establish a National Climate Change and Wildlife Science Center to assess and develop scientific information, tools, strategies, and techniques to support the working group and other interested parties in addressing the effects of extreme weather and climate change.

Interior must establish an Advisory Committee on Climate Change and Natural Resource Sciences to advise the working group.</summary>
</bill>
