<bill session="119" type="s" number="586" updated="2025-09-29T14:44:53Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Flood Insurance Affordability Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Insurance Affordability Tax Credit Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an advance refundable credit to offset certain flood insurance premiums, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001075"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2025-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-29T14:44:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Flood Insurance Affordability Tax Credit Act

This bill establishes a new refundable tax credit for up to 33% of the flood insurance premiums paid (or incurred) under the National Flood Insurance Program to insure a principal residence. The bill also requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to establish a program for paying the tax credit in advance.

Under the bill, the tax credit for flood insurance premiums may be reduced depending on the taxpayer&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s household income in relation to the federal poverty line (FPL). The tax credit begins to phase out once a taxpayer&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s household income is 350% of the FPL and is completely phased out once a taxpayer&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s household income reaches 435% of the FPL. (Other limitations may apply.)

Further, the tax credit for flood premiums may not be claimed by a married taxpayer who files a separate federal income tax return or a taxpayer who may be claimed as a dependent.

Finally, the bill requires the IRS to establish a program that allows a taxpayer to receive the allowable tax credit amount for flood insurance premiums (based on tax return information for the most recent tax year available) in advance.</summary>
</bill>
