<bill session="118" type="h" number="6242" updated="2024-12-18T22:20:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VOTES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VOTES Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voting Overseas Treated Equally for Servicemembers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act to expand coverage of the definition of absent uniformed services voter, under such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2024-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2024-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000388" joined="2024-08-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000381" joined="2024-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000394" joined="2024-08-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000597" joined="2024-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001216" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001206" joined="2024-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2024-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-23T16:13:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Voting Overseas Treated Equally for&#160;Servicemembers Act of 2023 or the VOTES Act of 2023

This bill expands the definitions of absent uniformed services voter and overseas voter for purposes of the Uniformed and Overseas Citizens Absentee Voting Act (UOCAVA).&#160;

UOCAVA requires that states and jurisdictions allow certain groups of citizens to register and vote absentee in federal elections. Absent uniformed services voters under UOCAVA are primarily active duty service members who are away from their voting residence. These include members of the U.S. Air Force, Army, Coast Guard, Marine Corps, and Navy. The current definition of absent uniformed services voter also includes (1) members of the merchant marine and commissioned officers of the U.S. Public Health Service and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and (2) spouses or dependents who also are absent from their voting residence due to the member's active duty or service.

This bill expands the definition of absent uniformed services voter&#160;to include (1) members on active service or inactive duty training who are absent from their voting residence, and (2) spouses or dependents who are absent from their voting residence due to the member's active service or inactive duty training.

The bill also expands the definition of overseas voter to include an absent uniformed services voter who, by reason of active service or inactive duty training, is absent from the United States on the date of the election involved.</summary>
</bill>
