<bill session="108" type="h" number="4657" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2004-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to improve the administration of Federal pension benefit payments for District of Columbia teachers, police officers, and fire fighters, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000874" joined="2004-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2004-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T19:54:04-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davis, Tom moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T19:54:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7705-7708" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T19:54:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4657.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-28T20:02:30-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7705-7707" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28T20:02:40-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12027-12028" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-12-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-12-23" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-489" type="public" datetime="2004-12-23">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-489.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Chief financial officers"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Embezzlement"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Larceny"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-04T19:49:01Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on September 28, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

District of Columbia Retirement Protection Improvement Act of 2004 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Balanced Budget Act of 1997 to establish in the Treasury the District of Columbia Teachers, Police Officers, and Firefighters Federal Pension Fund (D.C. Federal Pension Fund) consisting of transfers of all: (1) District of Columbia Federal Pension Liability Trust Fund obligations to make Federal benefit payments; and (2) assets of such Trust Fund and the Federal Supplemental District of Columbia Pension Fund.

Specifies the use of the D.C. Federal Pension Fund, including but not limited to: (1) making Federal benefit payments; and (2) financing Federal obligations for future benefits.

Transfers as of October 1, 2004: (1) all obligations to make Federal benefit payments from the Trust Fund to the D.C. Federal Pension Fund; and (2) all assets of the Trust Fund and all assets of the Federal Supplemental Fund to the D.C. Federal Pension Fund.

Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make annual Federal payments into the D.C. Federal Pension Fund from the general fund of the Treasury.

Provides for the administration of the D.C. Federal Pension Fund by a Pension Fund Trustee selected by the Secretary.

Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with the Pension Fund Trustree to provide for the auditing of the D.C. Federal Pension Fund's assets, the making of such Federal benefit payments, and such other matters as the Secretary deems appropriate.

Authorizes the Pension Fund Trustee, with the Secretary's approval, to enter into one or more subcontracts with the District government or any person to provide services to the Pension Fund Trustee in connection with its performance of the contract.

Permits the Secretary to determine, in the interest of economy and efficiency, with respect to any function otherwise to be performed by the Pension Fund Trustee, that such function shall be performed by the Secretary.

Applies the same specified Federal law to the D.C. Federal Pension Fund that applied to the Trust Fund before October 1, 2004.

Terminates the Trust Fund and the Federal Supplemental Fund upon transfer of all their assets and obligations to the D.C. Federal Pension Fund.

(Sec. 3) Sets forth procedures for resolving denied benefit claims with respect to the District of Columbia Judicial Retirement and Survivors Annuity Fund.

Treats misappropriation of the D.C. Federal Pension Fund as a Federal crime.

(Sec. 4) Amends the District of Columbia Home Rule Act to provide that the Chief Financial Officer shall not administer the retirement system for police officers, fire fighters, and teachers.</summary>
</bill>
