<bill session="111" type="h" number="1741" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:29Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-09T17:16:56-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-06-09T17:16:56-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by house">To require the Attorney General to make competitive grants to eligible State, tribal, and local governments to establish and maintain certain protection and witness assistance programs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Attorney General to make competitive grants to eligible State, tribal, and local prosecutors to establish and maintain certain protection and witness assistance programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000984"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2009-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2009-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2009-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001169" joined="2009-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2009-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 111-138.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-06-08" calendar="Union" number="70">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 70.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T13:08:57-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Johnson (GA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T13:08:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6325-6329" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T13:08:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1741.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T13:46:20-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T17:07:33-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6357" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="315" datetime="2009-06-09T17:16:56-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 412 - 11 (Roll no. 315).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6325-6326" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-09T17:16:57-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-25">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Leahy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-03-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="329">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 329.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-13T21:46:53Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Witness Security and Protection Grant Program Act of 2010 - Directs the Attorney General to: (1) make competitive grants to state, tribal, and local governments to establish or maintain programs to protect or assist witnesses in court proceedings involving homicide, a serious felony or drug offense, or gangs or organized crime; (2) evaluate grant applicants based on specified criteria, including such government's level of witness intimidation and level of serious crimes; (3) provide technical assistance to grant applicants for establishing or maintaining a witness protection plan; and (4) develop and disseminate within one year after development best practice models to assist states and other relevant entities in addressing witness safety, short-term and permanent witness relocation, financial and housing assistance, and other necessary services.

Expresses the sense of Congress that states and relevant entities should use the best practice models developed by the Attorney General to evaluate, improve, and develop witness protection or witness assistance programs.

Requires the Attorney General to: (1) ensure that grants funds under this Act are equitably distributed throughout the United States and that due consideration is given to applicants of rural and urban communities; and (2) report to Congress not later than December 31, 2012, on the implementation of this Act and not later than December 31, 2015, on the programs funded by grants awarded by this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-138</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
