<bill session="116" type="s" number="2972" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:07Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">UIGHUR Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uighur Intervention and Global Humanitarian Unified Response and Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UIGHUR Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restrict the export, reexport, and in-country transfers of certain items that provide a critical capability to the Government of the People's Republic of China to suppress individual privacy, freedom, and other basic human rights.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2019-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="178" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-06T14:22:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Uighur Intervention and Global Humanitarian Unified Response and Protection Act of 2019 or the UIGHUR Protection Act of 2019 

This bill directs the President to impose sanctions and export restrictions related to China's treatment of the Uyghurs, a predominantly Muslim Turkic ethnic group.

The President shall identify items that provide China with a critical capability to suppress basic human rights, including items that provide capability to (1) conduct surveillance, (2) monitor and restrict an individual's movement, (3) monitor and restrict access to the internet, and (4) identify individuals through facial or voice recognition. The President shall (1) place such items on the Commerce Control List (a list of items subject to export controls); and (2) require authorization for the export, reexport, or transfer of such items to or within China. The bill terminates certain prohibitions, such as a prohibition against obligating funds for U.S. Trade and Development Agency activities in China, upon a report by&#160;the President to Congress that China has taken specified actions, including ending the mass internment of Turkic Muslims in Xinjiang.</summary>
</bill>
