<bill session="108" type="s" number="967" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Equal Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to replace with a more equitable formula the current formula, known as the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation (VERA), for the allocation of funds appropriated to the Department of Veterans Affairs for medical care to different geographic regions of the Nation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Equal Treatment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Equal Treatment Act - Requires the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to: (1) discontinue the funding allocation formula for the Department of Veterans Affairs medical care system known as the Veterans Equitable Resource Allocation system at the end of the fiscal year in which this Act is enacted; and (2) develop a new formula for the allocation of funds to the national service regions, known as Veterans Integrated Service Networks (VISNs), that takes into account specified requirements, including additional costs incurred by a VISN because the age of veterans, or the number of veterans requiring complex care, in that VISN exceeds the median for all VISNs.Authorizes additional appropriations to be allocated to VISNs that have experienced funding reductions.</summary>
</bill>
