<bill session="116" type="s" number="2988" updated="2022-10-28T01:46:05Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veteran Pension Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veteran Pension Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to address the financial exploitation of veterans receiving pension from the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7952" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4511" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7105" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-02T17:09:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veteran Pension Protection Act of 2019

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) and Veterans Benefits Administration (VBA) to implement methods and systems to address potential financial exploitation of individuals who receive VA pensions for non-service-connected disability, death, or service.

Specifically, the bill requires the VA to develop a method for soliciting and collecting information on complaints received, referrals made, and actions taken by the VA pension management centers in cases of potential financial exploitation.

The VA must also (1) develop a plan to regularly assess the collected information to identify trends of potential financial exploitation, (2) and outline actions it can take to improve education and training to address those trends.

The bill requires the VBA to

 update guidance and training curriculum for claims processors regarding the evaluation of questionable medical expenses on pension applications, develop a method for identifying and tracking the number of individuals who have received pension overpayments, conduct an evaluation of the feasibility and advisability of requiring claims processors to take additional actions to verify direct deposit information, identify legislative or administrative actions that would ensure pension payments are provided to the correct recipients, ensure that specified pension documents include a notice that the VA does not charge a fee in connection with the filing of a pension application, and develop a plan for educating vulnerable individuals about potential financial exploitation relating to the receipt of the specified pensions.</summary>
</bill>
