<bill session="118" type="s" number="2140" updated="2025-09-03T20:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Patent Eligibility Restoration Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 35, United States Code, to address matters relating to patent subject matter eligibility, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patent Eligibility Restoration Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-23">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Intellectual Property. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-460.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSJU26" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Intellectual Property" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-05T15:18:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patent Eligibility Restoration Act of 2023

This bill amends the law relating to patent subject matter eligibility to establish that only specified subject matter (e.g., a natural process wholly independent of human activity) is ineligible for patenting. (Currently, subject matter eligibility is determined by examining whether the claimed invention is directed to certain ineligible categories, and if so, whether there is an inventive concept. Subject matter eligibility is one of several requirements that an invention must satisfy in order to receive patent protection.)

Under this bill, an invention shall be considered to involve patent-ineligible subject matter only if it falls within specified categories, such as (1) a mathematical formula that is not part of a useful process, machine, manufacture, or composition; (2) a mental process that is performed solely in the human mind; or (3) an unmodified human gene as the gene exists in the human body.</summary>
</bill>
