<bill session="117" type="h" number="7607" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:21Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HARVARD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HARVARD Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Applicants Receive Valid and Reasonable Decisions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct institutions of higher education to improve transparency with respect to the use of personality traits in admissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001135"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2022-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2022-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-03T14:37:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Applicants Receive Valid and Reasonable Decisions Act or the HARVARD Act

 This bill requires an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student-aid programs and considers personality traits of applicants in making admission determinations to publicly disclose specified information related to personality traits. Personality traits refer to the patterns of an individual with respect to behaviors, thoughts, and emotions and may include patterns relating to humor, sensitivity, grit, leadership, integrity, helpfulness, courage, and kindness.

Specifically, the IHE must make available on its public website and application materials (1) a statement informing applicants of the use of personality traits in making admission determinations, (2) the rationale for such use of personality traits, (3) a description of the process under which personality traits are considered, and (4) the standards and criteria used for rating personality traits.</summary>
</bill>
