<bill session="118" type="s" number="3130" updated="2025-06-20T19:33:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Indian Health Care Improvement Act to improve the recruitment and retention of employees in the Indian Health Service, restore accountability in the Indian Health Service, improve health services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2023-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8942" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8966" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8956" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8955" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-09T13:21:12Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Accountability in the Indian Health Service Act of 2023

This bill establishes a series of programs and requirements relating to recruitment and retention in the Indian Health Service (IHS), including provisions regarding pay, credentialing, and housing needs of workforce personnel.

Among other provisions, the bill

requires&#160;the establishment of a pay system for health care professionals employed by IHS that is based on the pay system for health care professionals employed by the Veterans Health Administration,authorizes a program&#160;to provide tenant-based rental assistance to certain IHS employees,requires IHS&#160;to establish a centralized medical credentialing system, andexpands&#160;eligibility for the IHS Loan Repayment Program.Additionally, the bill

outlines&#160;additional hiring requirements for IHS,requires&#160;employees and health care providers who enter into a contract with IHS to annually complete mandatory training on tribal&#160;culture and history,establishes&#160;a demonstration program to provide IHS units with additional staffing resources,&#160;requires the&#160;Department of Health and Human Services to establish best practices for governing boards and area offices,establishes&#160;a compliance assistance program for underperforming hospitals or outpatient facilities,establishes&#160;the Office of Patient Advocacy, andrequires IHS&#160;to establish regulations for standards to measure the timeliness of the provision of health care services in IHS facilities.The bill&#160;also outlines certain employee protections, including whistle-blower protections.

The bill&#160;establishes various reporting requirements. For example, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on the housing and staffing needs of IHS.</summary>
</bill>
