<bill session="117" type="s" number="3081" updated="2022-12-30T07:48:45Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tax Free Education Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Free Education Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to permit withdrawals from certain retirement plans for repayment of student loan debt, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-05T19:59:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tax Free Education Act of 2021

This bill permits tax-free distributions of up to $5,250 from 401(k) plans for qualified higher and elementary and secondary education expenses and penalty-free withdrawals from individual retirement accounts (IRAs) for student loan expenses.

The bill also excludes from gross income, for income tax purposes, distributions up to $5,250 from employer-sponsored student loan and tuition payment plans. It repeals the limitation on the deduction of interest on student loans and increases from $15,000 to $25,000 (adjusted for inflation) the maximum contribution amounts for certain tax-preferred retirement plans.

The bill allows employees an election to treat contributions to a 401(k) plan as Roth contributions (thus exempting withdrawals from such plans from tax at retirement).

Finally, the bill allows individual taxpayers a new tax deduction for their qualified higher and elementary and secondary education expenses.</summary>
</bill>
