<bill session="109" type="s" number="1461" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:24Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Identity Protection and Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish procedures for the protection of consumers from misuse of, and unauthorized access to, sensitive personal information contained in private information files maintained by commercial entities engaged in, or affecting, interstate commerce, provide for enforcement of those procedures by the Federal Trade Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Identity Protection and Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000320"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8680-8681"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-18T18:52:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Identity Protection and Security Act - Requires a consumer reporting agency to place a security freeze on a private information file upon consumer request, subject to waiver by such consumer with respect to limited or temporary access to such file to a particular third party.

Identifies federal, state, and local agencies permitted access to such frozen information files.

Grants the Federal Trade Commission and specified federal agencies enforcement powers for violations of this Act.

Empowers the consumer to file a civil action in any court if a consumer reporting agency violates the requirements of this Act.

Prohibits a consumer reporting agency from imposing service fees or charges for implementing the consumer security freeze requests authorized under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
