<bill session="117" type="h" number="7948" updated="2022-12-29T17:03:52Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To require any entity established to develop congressional redistricting plans for a State to hold public hearings at which individuals who are members of communities of interest have a meaningful opportunity to express their views on proposed redistricting plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require any entity established to develop congressional redistricting plans for a State to hold public hearings at which individuals who are members of communities of interest have a meaningful opportunity to express their views on proposed redistricting plans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2022-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-17T17:37:14Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires any entity other than the legislature of a state that develops a congressional redistricting plan for a state, including an independent redistricting commission, to

 hold multiple public hearings prior to the development of a final plan, ensure that individuals may attend such hearings virtually, hold such hearings in locations which are within a reasonable distance of the locations of communities of interest, and ensure that members of communities of interest have meaningful opportunities to express their views on any of the entity's plans. For purposes of this bill, communities of interest may include political subdivisions such as counties, municipalities, tribal lands and reservations, or school districts, but shall not include common relationships with political parties or political candidates.</summary>
</bill>
