<bill session="117" type="h" number="5362" updated="2022-12-31T08:58:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to require senior Government officials and their family members to divest foreign financial interests, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Stop Foreign Payoffs Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Foreign Payoffs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000592"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, and in addition to the Committee on House Administration, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-08T12:39:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Foreign Payoffs Act 

This bill prohibits certain government officials and their family members from holding foreign financial interests and also requires divestiture of any such interests in a prescribed manner and time frame.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the President, cabinet officials, and Members of Congress from holding any financial interest in, or receiving payment from, a foreign business. Such individuals must divest any such interest by either converting the interest into cash or another investment, or by placing the interest in a qualified blind trust or diversified trust; divestiture must occur no later than 30 days after either the issuance of implementing regulations or after the individual takes office. The bill's requirements apply to the spouses, children, sons-in-law, and daughters-in-law of such individuals.</summary>
</bill>
