<bill session="118" type="s" number="4130" updated="2025-01-14T17:07:58Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Access to Child Care for Military Families Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Access to Child Care for Military Families Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the establishment of a pilot program to expand early child care options for members of the Armed Forces and their families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001181"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2024-04-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-12T10:47:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanding Access to Child Care for Military Families Act of 2024

This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to direct the military departments to implement a pilot program to improve the access of members of the Armed Forces and their families to high quality early child care opportunities. Under the pilot program, the military departments must establish partnerships with 12 child care providers to (1) increase the capacity of the providers, (2) improve early child care workforce development, and (3) increase recruitment and retention of employees for eligible child care providers.

Child care providers under the program may not&#160;reduce early child care slots for nonmilitary families after entering into the partnership or&#160;enter into the construction of new child care facilities.

DOD must direct the military departments to provide annual briefings to Congress on the implementation of the pilot program.

The Government Accountability Office must submit an interim and a final report on the progress and results of the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
