<bill session="117" type="s" number="4510" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:22Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect clean air and public health by expanding fenceline and ambient air monitoring and access to air quality information for communities affected by air pollution, to require hazardous air pollutant monitoring at the fenceline of facilities whose emissions are linked to local health threats, to ensure the Environmental Protection Agency promulgates rules that require hazardous air pollutant data measurement and electronic submission at fencelines and stacks of industrial source categories, to expand and strengthen the national ambient air quality monitoring network, to deploy air sensors in communities affected by air pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8352" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9386" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-08T22:59:42Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Public Health Air Quality Act of 2022

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency to take specified actions related to monitoring and improving air quality, including by implementing a program to administer or conduct emissions measurement and quantification, promulgating regulations related to specified source categories, and deploying not fewer than 1,000 air quality sensors.</summary>
</bill>
