<amendment session="111" chamber="s" number="974" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:50Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="13" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-04-02">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <description>To provide that no additional estate tax relief beyone that which is already assumed in this resolution, which protects over 99.7 percent of estates from the estate tax, shall be allowed under any deficit-neutral reserve fund unless an equal amount of aggregate tax relief is also provided to Americans earning less than $100,000 per year.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-04-02" how="roll" result="pass" roll="147">
      <text>Amendment SA 974 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 147.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4278" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Amendment SA 974 proposed by Senator Durbin. (consideration: CR S4278) To provide that no additional estate tax relief beyone that which is already assumed in this resolution, which protects over 99.7 percent of estates from the estate tax, shall be allowed under any deficit-neutral reserve fund unless an equal amount of aggregate tax relief is also provided to Americans earning less than $100,000 per year.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 974 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 147.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4278" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 974 as modified agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56 - 43. Record Vote Number: 147.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4278" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 974 proposed by Senator Durbin.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4278" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
