<bill session="119" type="h" number="422" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No Subsidies for Wealthy Universities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Subsidies for Wealthy Universities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish Federal research award reimbursement limits for indirect costs for institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001118"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2025-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-02T14:56:09Z" status="Introduced in House">No Subsidies for Wealthy Universities Act

This bill limits the indirect costs that are allowable under federal research awards to institutions of higher education (IHEs) with endowments above specified thresholds.&#160;(Generally, indirect costs represent expenses that are not specific to a research project but are needed to maintain the infrastructure and administrative support for federally funded research.)

Specifically, the National Center for Education Statistics (NCES) must annually collect information regarding the endowments of each IHE that has entered into a program participation agreement with the Department of Education.

With this collected information,&#160;NCES must identify and make lists of (1) each IHE with an endowment of more than $5 billion, and (2) each IHE with an endowment of more than $2 billion (but not more than $5 billion). NCES must submit these lists to the Office of Management and Budget, which must then distribute the lists to federal agencies, Congress, and the public.

The bill establishes the following limits on the indirect costs allowable under federal research awards:

for an IHE with an endowment of more than $5 billion,&#160;the IHE is prohibited from using these awards for indirect costs;for an IHE with an endowment of more than $2 billion (but not more than $5 billion),&#160;the IHE is limited to&#160;an indirect cost rate of 8%; andfor all other IHEs, an&#160;indirect cost rate of 15%.The Government Accountability Office must annually report to Congress on indirect cost reimbursement on federal research awards for IHEs.</summary>
</bill>
