<bill session="118" type="h" number="8997" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:15Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-11">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for energy and water development and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2025, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000459"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-11">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-580, by Mr. Fleischmann.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-07-11" calendar="Union" number="480">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 480.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-07-22T20:08:51-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1370 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8997 and H.R. 8998. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8997 and H.R. 8998 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:08:02-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1370.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4743-4785" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4747-4755" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:08:07-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8997 and H.R. 8998. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8997 and H.R. 8998 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:08:42-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Brad R. Wenstrup to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:08:42-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1370 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:09:26-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 8997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:41:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Fleischmann amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:47:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Brecheen amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T11:52:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flood amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:01:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Beyer amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:06:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Beyer amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:18:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Griffith amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:24:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:33:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Houlahan amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:39:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson (TX) amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:46:47-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Luna amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T12:54:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:01:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:06:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:12:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:12:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:22:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:26:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 40.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:32:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:38:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:46:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 42, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Fitzpatrick demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:47:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:54:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 43, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T13:55:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:02:26-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 44, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:03:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:11:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 45, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Fleischmann demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:12:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:16:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 46, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:17:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:20:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 47, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:21:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:25:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 48, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:25:58-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:29:40-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 49, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:30:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:35:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 50, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:36:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:39:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 51, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:40:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:45:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 53, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Rosendale demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:45:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:55:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 54, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Roy demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T14:55:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:04:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:14:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 56, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Roy demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:15:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:20:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:25:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:35:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 62, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Van Drew demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:35:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:41:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 63, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Kaptur demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:42:09-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1370, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:48:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Van Drew amendment No. 64, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Van Drew demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:48:38-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Fleischmann moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:48:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T15:49:07-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 8997 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T16:30:10-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4785-4786" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T16:30:15-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T17:48:32-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 8997.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T17:49:15-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-23T17:49:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 8997 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7176" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1130" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="647" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1370" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="4927" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Delta Regional Authority"/>
    <term name="Denali Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Hybrid, electric, and advanced technology vehicles"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Lighting, heating, cooling"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Mississippi River"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="New Hampshire"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC)"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1122"/>
    <amendment number="h1121"/>
    <amendment number="h1120"/>
    <amendment number="h1119"/>
    <amendment number="h1118"/>
    <amendment number="h1117"/>
    <amendment number="h1116"/>
    <amendment number="h1115"/>
    <amendment number="h1114"/>
    <amendment number="h1113"/>
    <amendment number="h1112"/>
    <amendment number="h1111"/>
    <amendment number="h1110"/>
    <amendment number="h1109"/>
    <amendment number="h1108"/>
    <amendment number="h1107"/>
    <amendment number="h1106"/>
    <amendment number="h1105"/>
    <amendment number="h1104"/>
    <amendment number="h1103"/>
    <amendment number="h1102"/>
    <amendment number="h1101"/>
    <amendment number="h1100"/>
    <amendment number="h1099"/>
    <amendment number="h1098"/>
    <amendment number="h1097"/>
    <amendment number="h1096"/>
    <amendment number="h1095"/>
    <amendment number="h1094"/>
    <amendment number="h1093"/>
    <amendment number="h1092"/>
    <amendment number="h1091"/>
    <amendment number="h1090"/>
    <amendment number="h1089"/>
    <amendment number="h1088"/>
    <amendment number="h1087"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-09-30T16:23:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Energy and Water Development and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2025

This bill provides FY2025 appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, the Department of the Interior's Bureau of Reclamation, the Department of Energy (DOE), and several independent agencies.

The bill provides appropriations for U.S. Army Corps of Engineers civil works projects, including for

Investigations,Construction,Mississippi River and Tributaries,Operation and Maintenance,the Regulatory Program,the Formerly Utilized Sites Remedial Action Program,Flood Control and Coastal Emergencies,Expenses,the Office of the Assistant Secretary of the Army for Civil Works, andthe Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Program.The bill provides appropriations to the Department of the Interior for the Central Utah Project and the Bureau of Reclamation.

The bill provides appropriations to DOE for energy programs, including

Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy;Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response;Electricity;Grid Deployment;Nuclear Energy;Fossil Energy and Carbon Management;Naval Petroleum and Oil Shale Reserves;the Strategic Petroleum Reserve;the Northeast Home Heating Oil Reserve;the Energy Information Administration;Non-Defense Environmental Cleanup;the Uranium Enrichment Decontamination and Decommissioning Fund;Science;Nuclear Waste Disposal;Technology Transitions;Clean Energy Demonstrations;the Advanced Research Projects Agency&#226;&#8364;&#8221;Energy;the Title 17 Innovative Technology Loan Guarantee Program;the Advanced Technology Vehicles Manufacturing Loan Program;the Tribal Energy Loan Guarantee Program;Indian Energy Policy and Programs;Departmental Administration; andthe Office of the Inspector General.The bill also provides appropriations to DOE for

Atomic Energy Defense Activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration,Environmental and Other Defense Activities, andthe Power Marketing Administrations.The bill provides appropriations to several independent agencies, including the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission and the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.

The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-580</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
