<bill session="118" type="s" number="1552" updated="2025-11-19T03:43:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Coastal Fellowships Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coastal Fellowships Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Coastal Management Fellowship and the Digital Coast Fellowship, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001088"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5205" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-31T18:51:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Coastal Fellowships Act

This bill establishes the Coastal Management Fellowship and the Digital Coast Fellowship programs to be administered by the Department of Commerce. The fellowships aim to provide on-the-job training and to encourage public service that supports U.S. coastal resource management. In addition, the Digital Coast Fellowship will support the Digital Coast program, which is a platform that integrates geospatial data, training, and other tools in order to address coastal management issues.

The bill specifies that selected fellows must have completed a related graduate-level degree before the fellowship begins and have a demonstrated interest in a career in coastal or marine science, management, policy, or law. Commerce must award the fellowships in a manner that is geographically balanced. Each fellow may be selected for a term of up to two years, must receive an annual stipend of at least $47,000, and may be directly hired by a federal agency upon successful completion of a fellowship.</summary>
</bill>
