<bill session="108" type="sr" number="324" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:39Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate relating to the extraordinary contributions resulting from the Hubble Space Telescope to scientific research and education, and to the need to reconsider future service missions to the Hubble Space Telescope.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate relating to the extraordinary contributions resulting from the Hubble Space Telescope to scientific research and education, and to the need to reconsider future service missions to the Hubble Space Telescope.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000702"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000953" joined="2004-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2004-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3192"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3191-3192" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="hr" number="550" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Astronauts"/>
    <term name="Astronomy"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space shuttles"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Telescopes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-03T14:50:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recognizes the extraordinary contributions resulting from the Hubble Space Telescope to scientific research and education.

Recommends that the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) appoint an independent panel of expert scientists and engineers inside and outside of NASA to examine all possible options for safely carrying out the planned servicing mission to the Hubble Space Telescope.

Expresses the strong sentiment of the House of Representatives that NASA should continue all planning, preparation, and astronaut training activities for the SM-4 servicing mission without interruption until: (1) the expert panel issues its report; and (2) NASA provides a timetable of compliance with a recommendation of the Columbia Accident Investigation Board report which calls for a fully autonomous capability for all missions, since such compliance will allow both a Hubble servicing mission and missions to the International Space Station to be carried out safely.</summary>
</bill>
