<bill session="108" type="s" number="1584" updated="2021-09-30T00:40:23Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-09-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2004, HUD</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2004, Veterans Affairs</title>
    <title type="popular">Appropriations bill FY2004, Veterans Affairs and HUD</title>
    <title type="popular">Housing and Urban Development FY2004 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="popular">Veterans Affairs FY2004 Appropriations bill</title>
    <title type="display">Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill making appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and for sundry independent agencies, boards, commissions, corporations, and offices for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2004, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000611"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-06">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-20">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-01">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Subcommittee on VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-162.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-05">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Bond. With written report No. 108-143.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-09-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="273">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 273.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSAP05" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="VA, HUD, and Independent Agencies" activity="Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings, Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2673" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2681" relation="companion"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2861" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Brownfields"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Chemicals"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community development banking"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Corporation for National and Community Service"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Credit unions"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Enterprise zones"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Government National Mortgage Association"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government downsizing"/>
    <term name="Government insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government travel"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Human experimentation in medicine"/>
    <term name="Indian housing"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on the Homeless"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in astronautics"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lead"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="National service"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Paints and varnishes"/>
    <term name="Parking facilities"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Prosthesis"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Rescission of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Shelters for the homeless"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Space activities"/>
    <term name="Space flight"/>
    <term name="Space shuttles"/>
    <term name="Space stations"/>
    <term name="Storm drains"/>
    <term name="Toxicology"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Underground storage"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions"/>
    <term name="Vocational rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1785"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-06-23T19:51:31Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2004 - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for the Departments of Veterans Affairs and of Housing and Urban Development and for sundry independent agencies. Title I: Department of Veterans Affairs - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for the Department of Veterans Affairs for: (1) the Veterans Benefits Administration for veterans' compensation and pensions, readjustment benefits, veterans' insurance and indemnities, and veterans' housing, education, and vocational rehabilitation loan accounts, and Native American and homeless veterans; (2) the Veterans Health Administration for veterans' medical care, and medical and prosthetic research, and medical administration; and (3) departmental administration, including for the National Cemetery Administration, the Office of Inspector General, construction, the parking revolving fund, and grants to States for construction of extended care facilities and cemeteries. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds made available under this title.(Sec. 111) Requires approval by the congressional appropriations committees of any new lease of real property by the Department of Veteran Affairs exceeding $300,000. (Sec. 112) Prohibits the use of funds under this title for hospitalization or treatment of certain veterans unless they disclose current, accurate third-party reimbursement and annual income information. (Se. 113) Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to: (1) establish medical emergency preparedness centers; or (2) increase the number of Assistant Secretaries of Veterans Affairs. (Such provisions were authorized by the Department of Veterans Affairs Emergency Preparedness Act of 2002.) (Sec. 114) Deposits and transfers receipts that would otherwise be credited to the Veterans Extended Care Revolving Fund, the Medical Facilities Revolving Fund, the Special Therapeutic and Rehabilitation Fund, the Nursing Home Revolving Fund, the Veterans Health Services Improvement Fund, and the Parking Revolving Fund to the Medical Care Collections Fund and to the Medical Care account. Title II: Department of Housing and Urban Development - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) for: (1) public and Indian housing; (2) the Public Housing Capital and Operating Funds; (3) revitalization of severely distressed public housing (HOPE VI); (4) Native American housing block grants; (5) Indian and Native Hawaiian housing loan guarantees; (6) housing opportunities for persons with AIDS; (7) Office of Rural Housing and Economic Development; (8) empowerment zones and enterprise communities; (9) community development block grants and loan guarantees; (10) brownfields redevelopment; (11) the HOME investment partnerships program; (12) homeless assistance grants; (13) housing for special populations; (14) flexible subsidy fund; (15) manufactured housing fees trust fund; (16) the Federal Housing Administration; (17) the Government National Mortgage Association; (18) housing policy development and research; (19) fair housing activities; (20) the Office of Lead Hazard Control; (21) management and administration; (22) the Office of Inspector General; (23) Working Capital Fund; and (24) the Office of Federal Housing Enterprise Oversight. Cancels specified amounts from the urban development action program. Rescinds specified amounts: (1) of recaptured rental housing assistance budget authority; and (2) from the consolidated fee fund. (Sec. 201) Rescinds specified amounts from certain State-or locally-financed projects under the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Amendments Act of 1988. Authorizes the use of certain amounts of non-rescinded funds for project refinancing.

(Sec. 202) Prohibits funds under this Act from being used during FY 2004 to investigate or prosecute under the Fair Housing Act any otherwise lawful activities aimed at achieving or preventing government or court action. (Sec. 203) Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (Secretary) to make housing for persons with AIDS grants to any State that previously qualified but does not qualify in FY 2004 due to decreased AIDS cases in non-metropolitan areas of the State. (Sec. 204) Requires HUD to grant awards on a competitive basis. (Sec. 205) Makes HUD funds subject to the Government Corporation Control Act or other restrictions available, without regard to limitations on administrative expenses, for legal services and services and facilities of the Federal National Mortgage Association, Government National Mortgage Association, Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, Federal Financing Bank, Federal Reserve banks, Federal Home Loan banks, and any insured bank within the meaning of the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation. (Sec. 206) Limits HUD spending to amounts set forth in congressionally-submitted budget estimates. (Sec. 207) Authorizes HUD corporations and agencies subject to the Government Corporation Control Act to make necessary FY 2004 expenditures without regard to fiscal year limitations. Limits the use of collections of these corporations and agencies (with specified exceptions) to new loan or mortgage purchase commitments only to the extent expressly provided for in this Act, unless they are in support of other forms of assistance provided in this or prior appropriations Acts. (Sec. 208) Prohibits the obligation or expenditure by HUD of funds provided in this title for technical assistance, training, or management improvements unless HUD provides to the Committees on Appropriations a description of each proposed activity and detailed budget estimates of the costs associated with each program, project, or activity. (Sec. 209) Directs the Secretary to maintain section 8 housing rental assistance in managing and disposing of multifamily properties that are occupied primarily by elderly or disabled families. Authorizes the Secretary, where such assistance is not feasible, to: (1) contract for project-based rental assistance with an owner or owners of other existing housing properties; or (2) provide other rental assistance. (Sec. 210) Exempts Alaska, Iowa, and Mississippi from the requirement to have a public housing resident on the board of directors of a public housing authority or other administering body. Requires such authorities to establish an advisory board which shall have a specified number of resident members. (Sec. 211) Amends the Housing Act of 1937 to extend the HOPE VI program through September 30, 2006. (Sec. 212) Sets forth reporting requirements respecting: (1) unobligated and excess HUD funds; and (2) section 8 units. (Sec. 214) Directs, beginning in FY 2004: (1) the Secretary to allocate from certain housing funds for persons with AIDS in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, (on behalf of the Philadelphia, PA-NJ Primary Metropolitan Statistical Area) to New Jersey based upon the number of AIDS cases reported in the New Jersey-portion of such Area; and (2) New Jersey to use the allocation in such Area. Requires: (1) the Secretary to allocate to Wake County, North Carolina, certain FY 2004 housing for persons with AIDS funds that would otherwise be allocated to Raleigh, North Carolina, on behalf of the Raleigh-Durham-Chapel Hill, North Carolina, Metropolitan Statistical Area; and (2) that the allocation be used in such Area. (Sec. 215) Declares, with respect to FY 2004 assisted living facility section 8 rental payments, that a family residing in an assisted living facility in Oakland, Macomb, Wayne, or Washtenaw Counties, Michigan, may be required to pay rent in an amount exceeding 40 percent of its monthly adjusted gross income. (Sec. 216) Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 to make supportive housing for persons with disabilities eligible for service coordinators. (Sec. 217) Amends the National Housing Act revise the debenture interest calculation formula for certain mortgage insurance claims paid in cash. (Sec. 218) Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to rename the Interagency Council on the Homeless as the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness. (Sec. 219) Amends the National Housing Act to authorize specified mortgage alternatives for single family borrowers with impaired credit, which shall be Mutual Mortgage Insurance Fund obligations. (Sec. 220) Amends the Social Security Act to provide for limited information sharing between the National Directory of New Hires and specified housing assistance programs in order to determine the employment and income of housing program participants. (Sec. 221) Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to authorize loan guarantees for public housing agency project rehabilitation. (Sec. 222) Amends the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act to revise salary levels for the United States Interagency Council in Homelessness. (Sec. 223) States that: (1) Hawaii may elect by July 31, 2004, to distribute community development block grant funds to units of general local government located in nonentitlement areas (Hawaii, Kauai, and Maui Counties); and (2) if Hawaii fails to make such election, the Secretary shall beginning in FY 2005 make grants to such units. (Sec. 224) Directs the Secretary to issue a proposed rulemaking with respect to new requirements for the disposition of HUD-held multifamily housing projects, including dispositions made after a State or municipality has exercised its right of first refusal. (Sec. 225) Amends the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 2002 to permit the Housing Authority of Baltimore City to use certain rehabilitation funds for demolition and new construction purposes. Title III: Independent Agencies - Makes FY 2004 appropriations for: (1) the American Battle Monuments Commission; (2) the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board; (3) the Department of the Treasury, Community Development Financial Institutions Fund Program Account; (4) the Consumer Product Safety Commission; (5) the Corporation for National and Community Service; (6) the U.S. Court of Appeals for Veterans Claims; (7) the Department of Defense-Civil for cemeterial expenses, Army; (8) the Department of Health and Human Services, National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences; (9) the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; (10) the Environmental Protection Agency; (11) the Hazardous Substance Superfund, including transfers of funds; (12) the Executive Office of the President, Office of Science and Technology Policy, the Council on Environmental Quality, and the Office of Environmental Quality; (13) the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, Office of Inspector General; (14) the General Services Administration, Federal Citizen Information Center Fund; (15) the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness; (16) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA); (17) the National Credit Union Administration; (18) the National Science Foundation; (19) the Neighborhood Reinvestment Corporation; and (20) the Selective Service System. Sets forth authorized uses of, and limitations on, funds made available under this title. Title IV: General Provisions - Sets forth conditions and limitations on the obligation and expenditure of funds appropriated or made available under this Act.(Sec. 409) Expresses the sense of Congress that, to the greatest extent practicable, all equipment and products purchased with funds made available in this Act should be American-made.(Sec. 415) Encourages all Departments and agencies funded under this Act, within the limits of existing statutory authorities and funding, to expand their use of "E-Commerce" technologies and procedures in the conduct of their business practices and public service activities.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-143</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
