<bill session="117" type="hr" number="1000" updated="2022-12-29T22:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Calling on the President to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine, particularly the threat of nuclear, biological, or chemical attacks.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Calling on the President to deter further Russian aggression against Ukraine, particularly the threat of nuclear, biological, or chemical attacks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2022-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000795" joined="2022-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8465" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-20T10:39:01Z" status="Introduced in House">This resolution expresses that the House of Representatives

 calls upon the President to declare that the Russian employment of nuclear, chemical, or biological weapons of mass destruction that leads to a nuclear event, against or in connection with its war on Ukraine, would represent crimes against humanity; calls upon the President to treat such crimes against humanity as an urgent national and global security threat that may require, in concert with North Atlantic Treaty Organization allies, the employment of any available conventional means as necessary to secure the peace, including the potential need to degrade and destroy offending Russian forces in Ukraine; calls upon the President to make immediate efforts to provide the military and other material means needed for the Ukrainian government to be able to defend its national sovereignty; and stands ready to provide additional appropriations or enact other legislation to meet the needs of securing Ukraine's, Europe's, and the United States' common struggle against Russian fascism.</summary>
</bill>
