<bill session="118" type="h" number="1142" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require consideration of economic impact in making a listing decision with respect to the list of threatened and endangered species, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require consideration of economic impact in making a listing decision with respect to the list of threatened and endangered species, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2023-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2023-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-24T20:53:08Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill limits when the Department of the Interior or the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) may add a species to the endangered or threatened species list and revises the process to list species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973.

Specifically, Interior and NOAA may not add a species to the list if listing the species would cause significant economic harm to any state or locality.

In addition, the bill allows Interior and NOAA to prioritize the consideration of petitions to list a species as endangered or threatened other than in the order in which the petitions are received. However, Interior and NOAA may not give general priority to petitions to add species to the list over petitions to remove a species.</summary>
</bill>
