<bill session="116" type="h" number="5687" updated="2022-08-25T18:29:12Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-07T12:14:10-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-02-07T12:14:10-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief and Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief and Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief and Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief and Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief Act, 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committees on the Budget, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-05T18:14:37-05:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 833 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 826, H.R. 2474 and H.R. 5687. The resolution provides for consideration of H.Res. 826 under a closed rule with one hour of debate. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2474, under a structured rule and consideration of H.R. 5687, under a structured rule. Each bill shall be debated for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-06T14:27:44-05:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 833 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T09:17:00-05:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 833.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H941-962" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H947-953" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T09:17:05-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 826, H.R. 2474 and H.R. 5687. The resolution provides for consideration of H.Res. 826 under a closed rule with one hour of debate. Also, the resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 2474, under a structured rule and consideration of H.R. 5687, under a structured rule. Each bill shall be debated for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T09:17:26-05:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 833 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T09:17:28-05:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Kathy Castor to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T09:18:31-05:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5687.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T10:22:43-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Shalala amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T10:33:48-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Shalala amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment, and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mrs. Lowey demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T10:34:46-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Gonzalez-Colon (PR) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T10:44:22-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Plaskett amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T10:56:58-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Crenshaw amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:12:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Tlaib amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:17:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 833, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes on the Levin (MI) amendment No. 6.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:22:26-05:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was on adoption of amendments, which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:51:15-05:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5687.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:52:03-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:52:22-05:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:53:13-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Cole moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H960" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:53:21-05:00">
      <text>Floor summary: DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cole motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T11:59:23-05:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T12:06:19-05:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by recorded vote: 178 - 223 (Roll no. 53).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="54" datetime="2020-02-07T12:14:10-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 237 - 161 (Roll no. 54).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T12:14:11-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07T12:14:12-05:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 5687.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-02-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="416">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 416.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="409" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1786" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3307" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="833" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3101" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3883" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h788"/>
    <amendment number="h787"/>
    <amendment number="h786"/>
    <amendment number="h785"/>
    <amendment number="h784"/>
    <amendment number="h783"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-02-12T16:13:29Z" status="Passed House">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations for Disaster Relief and Puerto Rico Disaster Tax Relief Act, 2020 

This bill provides FY2020 supplemental appropriations and expands tax credits to respond to recent natural disasters and emergencies that affected Puerto Rico and other U.S. territories.

The funding provided by this bill is designated as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits.

The bill provides $4.89 billion in FY2020 supplemental appropriations for programs within

 the Department of Energy, the Department of Education, the Federal Highway Administration, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and the Department of Agriculture. The programs address issues such as

 cybersecurity, energy security, and emergency response; the electric grid; the educational needs of individuals affected by natural disasters and emergencies; repairs to roads affected by natural disasters and emergencies; community development; and disaster nutrition assistance. The bill also expands tax credits and modifies related requirements that affect the residents of Puerto Rico and other U.S. territories. The bill includes provisions regarding

 the child tax credit, the earned income tax credit, the low-income housing tax credit, the new markets tax credit, the amount of distilled spirits excise taxes covered over (paid) to the treasuries of Puerto Rico and the Virgin Islands, and an employee retention tax credit.</summary>
</bill>
