<bill session="111" type="s" number="3568" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:44Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to create a Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund to support research on diseases impacting the citrus industry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2010-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2010-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5746-5747"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Animal and plant health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Fruit and vegetables"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements and negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-10-27T15:26:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund Act of 2010 - Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to establish the Citrus Disease Research and Development Trust Fund, consisting of revenues from duties paid on imported citrus and citrus products, to support scientific research, technical assistance, and development activities to combat both domestic and invasive citrus diseases and pests harming the United States.

Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to issue an order to: (1) subject domestic citrus producers to the requirements of this Act; and (2) establish a Citrus Research and Development Board.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide grants to the Board to develop a coordinated program of research and product development relating to: (1) scientific research of both domestic and invasive diseases and pests afflicting the citrus industry; and (2) support for the dissemination and commercialization of relevant information, techniques, and technologies discovered through Fund research or other research projects intended to solve problems caused by citrus production diseases and invasive pests.

Requires the President to notify certain congressional committees before entering into a trade agreement that could result in a decrease in the amount of: (1) duties paid on imported citrus and citrus products; and (2) funds transferred into the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
