<bill session="118" type="s" number="4192" updated="2025-08-13T04:00:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">We Can't Wait Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">We Can't Wait Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to permit disabled individuals to elect to receive disability insurance benefits during the disability insurance benefit waiting period, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2024-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3400" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-12-19T19:34:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">We Can't Wait Act of 2024

This bill permits Social Security Disability Insurance (SSDI) beneficiaries to elect expedited payment of benefits in exchange for a reduction in the amount of their monthly benefit.&#160;

Specifically, the bill allows individuals to elect to receive SSDI benefits beginning the month after the onset of disability. Under current law, individuals generally must wait five months after the onset of disability to begin receiving SSDI benefits.

Individuals who opt to receive expedited payment during the first three years the bill is in effect must accept a 6.1% reduction in monthly benefits. At the three-year point and every five years thereafter, the Social Security Administration (SSA) must recalculate the applicable percentage to ensure no negative fiscal impact to the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund. Changes to the designated percentage may not impact the benefit amount received by existing beneficiaries.&#160;

SSA must make available an online tool for calculating the impact of electing to receive benefits during the waiting period on an individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s SSDI benefit.</summary>
</bill>
