<bill session="119" type="h" number="3743" updated="2025-11-22T09:06:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Healthy Mothers and Infants Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Healthy Mothers and Infants Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to support women, infants, and children impacted by substance use disorder, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000138"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000300" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000310" joined="2025-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2025-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2025-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001238" joined="2025-08-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001227" joined="2025-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001219" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000620" joined="2025-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000620" joined="2025-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2025-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2025-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2025-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2025-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2025-11-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T14:33:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Healthy Mothers and Infants Act of 2025

This bill modifies the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) to add requirements for supporting individuals impacted by a substance use disorder.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Agriculture to

collaborate with the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop and disseminate nutrition education materials for individuals impacted by a substance use disorder, including materials for infants impacted by prenatal substance exposure and neonatal abstinence syndrome;conduct outreach to individuals who are potentially eligible for the WIC program and who are impacted by such a disorder; andmake available to states through an online clearinghouse any nutrition education and training materials related to nutrition for individuals impacted by a substance use disorder or neonatal abstinence syndrome.In addition, the nutrition education materials developed in collaboration with HHS must be included in (1) Center for Substance Abuse Prevention-developed education materials, and (2) HHS guidance on improving care for infants with neonatal abstinence syndrome and their families.

Under current law, the WIC program includes certain education&#160;related to drug abuse. This bill replaces references to drug abuse with substance use disorder.</summary>
</bill>
