<bill session="112" type="h" number="6394" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:27Z">
  <state datetime="2012-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Housing Regulation Simplification Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="display">Affordable Housing Regulation Simplification Act of 2012</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate affordable workforce homeownership in, and develop the full-time resident communities of, high tourism areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2012-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2012-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Capital Markets and Government Sponsored Enterprises.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA16" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Capital Markets" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Federally chartered organizations"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Housing supply and affordability"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-09-26T15:26:27Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable Housing Regulation Simplification Act of 2012 - Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to authorize the Federal National Mortgage Association (Fannie Mae), and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to authorize the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation (Freddie Mac), to purchase, service, sell, lend on the security of, and otherwise deal in affordable workforce housing mortgages for one-family residences: (1) that shall be used as the mortgagor's residence at least 8 of any 12 months and 240 days of any 365 days; (2) located within, or are part of, a multifamily housing development meeting certain requirements; and (3) located in a high tourism area.

Prescribes mortgagor income and employment criteria.

Exempts such mortgages from any requirements and guidelines of such government sponsored entities (also known as GSEs) that are inconsistent with such authority.

Limits the application of this Act to such mortgages in a high tourism area.

Amends the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to insure any affordable workforce housing mortgage meeting certain requirements.

Requires the Secretary of HUD to provide a spot approval process for insurance of condominium unit mortgages that does not require prior approval of the entire project or of the homeowners association for the entire project.

Directs the Secretary of Commerce to determine high tourism areas.</summary>
</bill>
