<bill session="109" type="h" number="2733" updated="2018-11-21T20:19:48Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To prohibit the closure or adverse realignment of facilities of the reserve components that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines have a significant role in homeland defense.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the closure or adverse realignment of facilities of the reserve components that the Secretary of Homeland Security determines have a significant role in homeland defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000480"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Military base closures"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-20T21:31:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) review the list of military installations recommended for closure or realignment by the Defense Base Closure and Realignment Commission in the report transmitted to Congress by the President; and (2) prepare a report to Congress specifying each armory, readiness center, and other facility used for the development, training, operation, or maintenance of the reserve components of the Armed Forces that, while identified for closure or adverse realignment on such list, has a significant role in homeland defense.



Prohibits the Secretary of Defense from closing or realigning any armory, readiness center, or other facility of the reserve components identified in such report as an armory, readiness center, or other facility of the reserve components that has a significant role in homeland defense.</summary>
</bill>
