<bill session="117" type="s" number="4560" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Puerto Rico Status Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Puerto Rico Status Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable the people of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico to determine the political status of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-30T22:19:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Puerto Rico Status Act

This bill provides for a plebiscite to be held on November 5, 2023, to resolve Puerto Rico's political status. Specifically, the plebiscite shall offer eligible voters a choice of four options: independence for Puerto Rico, sovereignty in free association with the United States, statehood, or retaining the status of Puerto Rico as a commonwealth. The bill provides for a runoff plebiscite if no option receives a majority vote in the initial plebiscite.

The Puerto Rico State Commission on Elections shall carry out a nonpartisan voter education campaign through traditional paid media and make available at all voting locations voter education materials related to the plebiscites.

All voter educational materials and ballots used to carry out this bill shall be made available in English and Spanish.

The bill sets forth transition and implementation provisions for each choice offered in the plebiscite.</summary>
</bill>
