<bill session="116" type="h" number="5703" updated="2022-02-09T00:28:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRIVCY ACT</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 to update and expand the coverage of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRIVCY ACT</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Information of our Vulnerable Children and Youth Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2020-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2020-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2020-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2020-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2020-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-14T16:08:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting the Information of our Vulnerable Children and Youth Act or the PRIVCY ACT This bill modifies and expands the requirements for commercial entities with respect to information collected from young consumers under the age of 18 and children under the age of 13. Specifically, it applies the requirements for processing information reasonably linkable to a young consumer or child to any entity within the jurisdiction of the Federal Trade Commission, including nonprofit organizations. Additionally, the bill modifies the requirements for such processed information with respect to

 obtaining verifiable consent to process such information and the applicable exceptions; developing a publicly available privacy policy with respect to such information; consumers' access to, and requests to delete, such information; and securing such information and periodically testing such security measures. Among other things, it also adds provisions

 requiring the deletion of processed information that is no longer reasonably necessary to retain for the purpose for which it was processed, prohibiting targeted marketing to a specific young consumer or child based on processed information or using processed information in a manner inconsistent with the reasonable expectation of such consumers, and limiting the disclosure of processed information to third parties without a written agreement with the third party specifying and limiting the purposes for which the third party may process the information and requiring the third party to provide specified security and privacy protections.</summary>
</bill>
