<bill session="108" type="s" number="1307" updated="2023-01-15T16:48:42Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to assist in the implementation of fish passage and screening facilities at non-Federal water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Reclamation, to assist in the implementation of fish passage and screening facilities at non-Federal water projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8304"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-271.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-249.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-03-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="466">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 466.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9323-9325" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9323-9325" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:03:22-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries Conservation, Wildlife and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Columbia River development"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Salmon"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-19T20:21:53Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on March 29, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

 Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation (Reclamation), directly or through financial assistance to non-Federal parties, to plan, design, and construct fish passage and screening facilities or habitat improvements at any non-Federal water diversion or storage project located anywhere in the Columbia River Basin. Provides such authority when the Secretary determines that such facilities would enable Reclamation to meet its obligations under specified Federal law regarding the construction and continued operation and maintenance of all Federal reclamation projects located in the Columbia River Basin, excluding the Federal reclamation projects located in the Snake River Basin. Limits the Federal share to 75 percent of project costs, requiring the non-Federal party to pay the remaining share. Sets forth other limitations and requirements relating to the authority under this Act.

Makes the Reclamation Act of 1902 and other Federal reclamation laws inapplicable to the non-Federal water projects at which the fish passage and screening facilities authorized by this Act are located, and to the lands which such projects irrigate. Declares that expenditures made by the Secretary under this Act shall not be a project cost assignable to any Federal reclamation project and shall be non-reimbursable and non-returnable to the U.S. Treasury.

Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-249</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
