<bill session="118" type="s" number="3185" updated="2025-11-18T21:09:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Cultural Areas Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Cultural Areas Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Tribal Cultural Areas System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6147" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Historical and cultural resources"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-01T15:54:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Tribal Cultural Areas Protection Act

This bill provides for the preservation of tribal cultural sites on public land by establishing the Tribal Cultural Areas System.

Within three years of this bill's enactment, the Department of the Interior or the Department of Agriculture (USDA), as applicable, must

establish criteria for recommending tribal cultural sites for designation as tribal cultural areas for inclusion in the system, using specified factors;solicit recommendations from tribes, state historic preservation officers, and tribal historic preservation officers;review designations in local land management plans to identify tribal cultural sites that meet established criteria;consider any other relevant information;consider and evaluate tribal cultural sites for designation as a tribal cultural area for inclusion in the system; and&#160;make recommendations to Congress.The bill gives Congress the sole authority to (1) designate a tribal cultural site located on public land as a tribal cultural area for inclusion in the system, and (2) remove a tribal cultural area from the system. Congress must consider the recommendations of Interior and USDA when determining whether to make such a designation.

For each congressionally designated tribal cultural area, Interior or USDA must (1) establish a tribal commission to provide guidance and recommendations on the development of a management plan for the tribal cultural area, and (2) develop a comprehensive management plan.

The bill allows for self-determination contracts with tribes or tribal organizations to perform administrative or management functions within a tribal cultural area.</summary>
</bill>
