<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="652" updated="2022-02-08T17:27:59Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4754" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-07-08T16:19:48-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000033"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-07-08"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following new title: \   TITLE VIII--ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS \   SEC. 801. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to make an application under section 501 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (50 U.S.C. 1861) for an order requiring the production of library circulation records, library patron lists, library Internet records, book sales records, or book customer lists.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered two printed in the Congressional Record to add a new section to the bill prohibiting funds from being made available to make an application under section 501 of the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 for an order requiring the production of library circulation records, library patron lists, library Internet records, book sales records, or book customer lists.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-07-08T16:19:48-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="339">
      <text>On agreeing to the Sanders amendment (A021) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 210, 1 Present (Roll no. 339).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08T12:27:40-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A021) offered by Mr. Sanders.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5348-5356, H5373-5374" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5348" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08T12:27:40-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A021) offered by Mr. Sanders.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5348-5356, H5373-5374" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H5348" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08T16:19:48-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08T16:19:48-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08T16:19:48-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Sanders amendment (A021) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 210, 1 Present (Roll no. 339).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-08">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
