<bill session="118" type="h" number="3705" updated="2024-08-14T13:09:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HOWIE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Oversee and Ward off Infrastructure Emergencies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HOWIE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations requiring a rail carrier to report certain damage if such carrier has a reasonable suspicion that an action carried out by the carrier caused such damage.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-14T13:07:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Helping Oversee and Ward off Infrastructure Emergencies Act or the HOWIE Act

This bill requires the Federal Railroad Administration to issue regulations to require a railroad to report a train accident that results in damage if the railroad has a reasonable suspicion that an action carried out by the railroad caused the damage. An accident includes any incident that causes a fire, including a brush fire, alongside a railroad track.

Specifically, a railroad must report (1) a train accident resulting in damage (based on a preliminary gross estimate) of $150,000 or more to railroad and nonrailroad property; or (2) a train accident resulting in damage of $25,000 or more to a passenger train, including railroad and nonrailroad property.</summary>
</bill>
