<bill session="118" type="s" number="864" updated="2025-01-14T18:20:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TASK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TASK Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transaction and Sourcing Knowledge Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to require reporting of sourcing and due diligence activities of companies involving supply chains of products that are imported into the United States that are directly linked to products utilizing forced labor from Xinjiang, China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-21T15:26:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Transaction and Sourcing Knowledge Act or the TASK Act 

This bill requires the Securities and Exchange Commission to mandate the reporting of certain information by publicly traded companies. Specifically, companies must report on

 the sourcing and due diligence involving products imported into the United States utilizing forced labor from Xinjiang, China; transactions with companies on the Department of Commerce's trade restriction list or designated as Chinese military-industrial complex companies; and for U.S. companies with facilities in China, whether there is a Chinese Communist Party committee in the operations of the company, and a summary of that committee's activity.</summary>
</bill>
