<bill session="118" type="s" number="5098" updated="2025-08-20T17:07:35Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUE Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain agencies to develop plans for internal control in the event of an emergency or crisis, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2024-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-282.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="685">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 685.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7313" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7313" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:12:11-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-24T10:13:00-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-20T17:07:31Z" status="Passed Senate">Taxpayer Resources Used in Emergencies Accountability Act or the TRUE Accountability Act

This bill requires the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to issue guidance to certain executive branch agencies for the development of internal control plans that are available for immediate use in future emergencies or crises. (Internal control refers to a process that provides reasonable assurance of achieving effective and efficient operations, reliable financial reporting, and legal compliance.)

This guidance must be in alignment with the Government Accountability Office reports entitled A Framework for Managing Improper Payments in Emergency Assistance Programs and A Framework for Managing Fraud Risks in Federal Programs.&#160;

Periodically, the agencies subject to this guidance must submit their internal control plan to&#160;OMB and OMB must submit such agency plans to Congress.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-282</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
