<bill session="110" type="h" number="5678" updated="2022-02-03T05:17:57Z">
  <state datetime="2008-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Neighborhood Rescue and Stabilization Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Neighborhood Rescue and Stabilization Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide economic stimulus through emergency community development block grant assistance for the redevelopment of abandoned and foreclosed homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2008-04-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2008-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2008-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Metropolitan areas"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-05-16T21:43:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Neighborhood Rescue and Stabilization Act of 2008 - Authorizes for FY2008 appropriations for assistance to states and local governmental units for the redevelopment of abandoned and foreclosed homes.

Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to allocate the funds among the states according to a funding formula reflecting the ratio that home mortgage foreclosures occurring in a state bears to the aggregate number of such foreclosures occurring in all states. Requires states to allocate funds to qualified metropolitan cities according to a similar formula.

Requires states and local governmental units to give priority to those metropolitan areas, metropolitan cities, urban areas, rural areas, low- and moderate-income areas, and other areas with the greatest need, including those: (1) with the greatest percentage of home foreclosures; (2) with the highest percentage of homes financed by a subprime mortgage related loan; or (3) identified as likely to face a significant rise in the rate of home foreclosures.

Cites eligible uses and redevelopment financing mechanisms.

Sets forth low- and moderate-income requirements for the use of all funds made available under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
