<bill session="118" type="h" number="1459" updated="2024-11-14T09:05:23Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRECISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECISE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Producing Responsible Energy and Conservation Incentives and Solutions for the Environment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To leverage incentives for the adoption of precision agriculture technology, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2023-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001134" joined="2023-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001118" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2023-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2023-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000470" joined="2024-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000471" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001090" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2023-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001225" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000129" joined="2023-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="720" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T15:35:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Producing Responsible Energy and Conservation Incentives and Solutions for the Environment Act or the PRECISE Act

This bill incorporates support for precision agriculture into various programs of the Department of Agriculture (USDA). Precision agriculture refers to managing, tracking, or reducing crop or livestock production inputs, including seed, feed, fertilizer, chemicals, water, and time, at a heightened level of spatial and temporal granularity to improve efficiencies, reduce waste, and maintain environmental quality. Precision agriculture technology includes any technology and equipment that directly contributes to a reduction in, or improved efficiency of, inputs used in crop or livestock production.

Specifically, the bill makes changes to eligibility criteria, administrative procedures, and other aspects of the Conservation Loan Program, the Environmental Quality Incentives Program, and the Conservation Stewardship Program. These changes include allowing the programs to support the adoption of precision agriculture practices and acquisition of precision agriculture technologies.

In addition, the bill expands a program through which USDA makes and insures loans to for-profit and nonprofit organizations that invest in rural areas by allowing the loans to be used for precision agriculture practices.

 Also, USDA must emphasize the use of third-party providers when providing technical assistance on matters related to soil health for participants in certain USDA conservation programs.</summary>
</bill>
