<bill session="118" type="h" number="4023" updated="2025-11-19T04:24:35Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">UPDATED USPS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniform Postal Data Acquisition for Transparency and Early Detection within the United States Postal Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">UPDATED USPS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen the requirements relating to advance electronic information for cargo, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000235"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2023-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM04" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1711" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-26T12:35:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Uniform Postal Data Acquisition for Transparency and Early Detection within the United States Postal Service Act or the UPDATED USPS Act

This bill modifies requirements relating to advance electronic information for cargo.

Specifically, the bill eliminates

 a restriction on the use of advance electronic information for commercial enforcement, and waivers of the requirement to transmit advance electronic information for countries. U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) must refuse entry for any international mail shipments for which advance electronic information is not transmitted for shipments received after December 31, 2023.

By December 31, 2023, the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) must arrange for the transmission to CBP of information for all international mail shipments. The USPS, at least every 30 days, must publish the number of such shipments for which the information was not transmitted to CBP during the preceding 30-day period.

The bill requires monthly reports of specified information, including the volume of international mail shipments and other cargo received by the USPS and private sector importers for which advance electronic information is submitted.</summary>
</bill>
