<bill session="115" type="h" number="4787" updated="2023-01-11T13:39:01Z">
  <state datetime="2018-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Great Lakes Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose additional requirements on portions of petroleum pipelines that cross the waters of the Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes Oil Spill Prevention Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001293"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-01-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-19T14:13:53Z" status="Introduced in House">Great Lakes Oil Spill Prevention Act

This bill establishes requirements for petroleum pipelines that cross the navigable waters of the Great Lakes system.

The Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration and the Department of Transportation must meet certain reporting requirements regarding Great Lakes pipelines.

Owners and operators of Great Lakes pipelines must:

 adhere to certain maintenance standards, perform certain safety tests, report on violations of the standards and correct violations by specified deadlines, repair corroded pipelines and ensure that the pipelines cease to transmit petroleum until they are repaired, and replace aging pipelines by specified deadlines. The bill establishes civil penalties for a delay in correcting violations, a failure to report violations, and a failure to meet a deadline to replace aging pipes.

The bill increases the liability of pipeline operators or owners who are responsible for discharges of oil pollution from pipelines into the Great Lakes. Responsible parties must establish and maintain evidence of financial responsibility sufficient to meet the maximum amount of liability to which the party may be subjected.</summary>
</bill>
