<bill session="109" type="h" number="4832" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:01Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Electronic Health Information Technology Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to establish an Office of Health Information Technology for the purpose of creating a national interoperable health information infrastructure, to provide loans to health care entities seeking to implement such infrastructure, and to provide exceptions to certain health anti-kickback laws to encourage the dissemination of health information technology.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Health Information Technology Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000589" joined="2006-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Chairman.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Clinics"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health planning"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Loan defaults"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Welfare recipients"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-27T18:33:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Electronic Health Information Technology Act of 2006 - Amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services an Office of Health Information Technology, headed by the Chief Health Informatics Officer (CHIO) of Health Information Technology (HIT), who shall develop, maintain, and direct the implementation of an interoperable HIT strategic plan to guide the nationwide implementation of interoperable health information technology in the public and private health care sectors. Transfers to the CHIO functions, personnel, assets, and liabilities of the National Coordinator for HIT.

Requires the CHIO to award one-year grants to eligible HIT entities.

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out a demonstration program to determine methods by which contextual access criteria and analysis technologies for specific diseases and health criteria may be used to search patient electronic health records and aggregated health information without using personal identifying information of patients.

Amends SSA title XI part A to establish a health care provider HIT loan program.

Makes exceptions to certain health anti-kickback laws to encourage the dissemination of health information technology.

Directs the Secretary to study and report to Congress on state laws and regulations relating to the security and confidentiality of individually identifiable health information to determine how any variation among the states, and between state and federal law, may adversely impact the electronic exchange of clinical health information among states, the federal government, and private entities.</summary>
</bill>
