<bill session="118" type="h" number="912" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comparison of Sustainable Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct an analysis of the costs of converting light-duty vehicles in the Federal fleet to electric vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000475" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000474" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-18T13:55:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Comparison of Sustainable Transportation Act or the COST Act

This bill requires the federal government to analyze the costs and impacts of replacing vehicles fueled by gasoline with electric vehicles or flex-fuel ethanol vehicles (e.g., vehicles capable of using fuel that contains a percentage of ethanol). Specifically, the Government Accountability Office must analyze the costs of replacing light-duty vehicles (i.e., vehicles weighing 8,500 pounds or less, such as passenger cars, minivans, and sport utility vehicles) in the federal fleet that are fueled with gasoline with electric vehicles or flex-fuel ethanol vehicles. The federal fleet means vehicles owned or operated by the federal government.

In addition, the Department of Energy (DOE) must analyze the overall greenhouse gas impacts of the following types of vehicles: (1) a conventional gasoline vehicle, (2) an E85 (a fuel containing 85% ethanol and 15% gasoline) capable flex-fuel vehicle, or (3) a battery electric vehicle. In conducting the analysis, DOE must utilize the most recent Greenhouse gases, Regulated Emissions, and Energy use in Transportation model (commonly referred to as the GREET model) developed by Argonne National Laboratory.</summary>
</bill>
