<bill session="109" type="h" number="1137" updated="2020-02-14T19:14:08Z">
  <state datetime="2005-03-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-03-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-03-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Responding Equitably, Swiftly, Proportionally, and On-time to Natural Disasters Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Responding Equitably, Swiftly, Proportionally, and On-time to Natural Disasters Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to improve Federal response to disasters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000324"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000716" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000911" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000114" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001148" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000573" joined="2005-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000303" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2005-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2005-03-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-03-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local officials"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality of life"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State officials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-03-29T20:25:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Responding Equitably, Swiftly, Proportionally, and On-time to Natural Disasters Act of 2005 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to include among those methods by which Congress intends to provide Federal disaster assistance: (1) ensuring that assistance is adequate and allows individuals to maintain their pre-disaster quality of life; and (2) ensuring that minority and low-income individuals and households and those in underserved communities receive equitable assistance.

Makes State and local governments eligible for Federal disaster assistance for debris removal on private lands, retroactive to August 11, 2004, if: (1) such governments provide specified services to such lands; or (2) failure to remove the debris places the lives, health, and safety of those living in the community at immediate risk.

Makes individuals and households eligible to apply for Federal disaster assistance for a period of 18 months beginning on the date of declaration of a major disaster. Increases the amount of individual and household assistance.

Directs the Federal Coordinating Officer appointed by the President in response to a major disaster to designate a local coordinating officer for each affected county.

Requires: (1) Federal financial assistance for disaster relief and emergency assistance to be allocated, distributed, or approved only by employees of the Department of Homeland Security or other appropriate Federal agencies; and (2) preparation of a report (for submission to specified congressional committees) on the role and effectiveness of using private entities to deliver disaster assistance.

Establishes a disaster expert grant program, to be fully funded by the Federal Government.</summary>
</bill>
