<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="138" updated="2022-02-09T05:36:10Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3992" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-11-04T14:31:32-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000395"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part E of House Report 117-137 to require a GAO study to determine whether not allowing claims of disparate impact discrimination by applicants for employment under the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 has a significant negative impact on such applicants, and provides that if the results of the study show there is not a significant negative impact on such applicants, then the Act shall not take effect.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to require a GAO study to determine whether not allowing claims of disparate impact discrimination by applicants for employment under the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967 has a significant negative impact on such applicants.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-11-04T14:31:32-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="357">
      <text>On agreeing to the Keller amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 228 (Roll no. 357).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03T17:35:35-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A003) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03T17:25:38-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Keller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6166-6167" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6166" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03T17:25:38-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Keller.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6166-6167" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6166" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04T14:31:32-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed by House: On agreeing to the Keller amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 228 (Roll no. 357).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04T14:31:32-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Keller amendment (A003) Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 197 - 228 (Roll no. 357).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04T14:31:32-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
