<bill session="111" type="h" number="5132" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:05Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mine Communications Technology Innovation Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish a research initiative to support the development of technical standards and conformance architecture to improve emergency communication and tracking technologies for use in locating trapped individuals in confined spaces and other shielded environments where conventional radio communication is limited, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mine Communications Technology Innovation Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY19" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Emergency communications systems"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-08T20:08:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Mine Communications Technology Innovation Act of 2010 - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) to establish a research initiative for the development of emergency communication and tracking technologies for use in locating trapped individuals in confined spaces, such as underground mines, and other shielded environments, like high-rise buildings or collapsed structures, where conventional radio communication is limited.

Requires the Director to work with the private sector and appropriate federal agencies to perform needs assessments to identify and evaluate the measurement, technical standards, and conformity assessment needs required, as well as support the development of technical standards and conformance architecture, to improve the operation of emergency communication and tracking technologies.</summary>
</bill>
