<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1224</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:16:32Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:16:32Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-06-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2010-02-23T23:06:18Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2009-11-19T15:19:54Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-06-10T18:16:57Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-126</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>1771</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-10-01</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 272.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-126.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-126.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-11-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-10</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6454-6456)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-06-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000805</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Warner, Mark R. [D-VA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mark</firstName>
        <lastName>Warner</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000702</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Mikulski, Barbara A. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <lastName>MIKULSKI</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <middleName>ANN</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000141</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cardin, Benjamin L. [D-MD]</fullName>
        <firstName>Ben</firstName>
        <lastName>Cardin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MD</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>W000803</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Webb, Jim [D-VA]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Webb</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VA</state>
        <middleName>H. "Jim"</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-06-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-11-30T17:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1224, Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/41846</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on November 19, 2009&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-11-30T17:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 1224, Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/41846</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on November 19, 2009</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Aquatic ecology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Chesapeake Bay</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Climate change and greenhouse gases</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fishes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maryland</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Teaching, teachers, curricula</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Virginia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water resources funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Watersheds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-06-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-07-21T21:30:25Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992 to require the Director of the Chesapeake Bay Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to: (1) collaborate with constituents in the Bay's watershed to support the development of an integrated observations system for the Bay; (2) further the development and implementation of the Chesapeake Bay Interpretive Buoy System, including supporting the establishment and implementation of the Captain John Smith Chesapeake National Historic Trail and incorporating the Chesapeake Bay Interpretive Buoy System into the Integrated Ocean Observing System regional network of observatories; (3) establish a Chesapeake Bay watershed education and training program (authorizes related grants); and (4) establish a Chesapeake Bay coastal living resources management and habitat program.</p> <p>Requires peer review for projects funded under the Act.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations (at an increased level) for the Office for FY2011-FY2014.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-05-04T21:05:22Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Authorization Act of 1992 to expand the duties of the Chesapeake Bay Office to include programs and activities in: (1) coastal hazards, resilient coastal communities, and climate change; (2) research, scientific assessment, and adaptation to climate change; and (3) integrated ecosystem assessments.</p> <p>Removes provisions concerning the Chesapeake Bay fishery and habitat restoration small watershed grants program.</p> <p> Requires the Director of the Office to implement specified program activities to support the activity of the Chesapeake Executive Council.</p> <p>Requires the Director to: (1) establish and utilize an effective and transparent mechanism to ensure that projects funded under this section have undergone appropriate peer review, using, to the extent practicable, the capabilities of the Maryland and Virginia Sea Grant Program; (2) provide other appropriate means to determine that such projects have acceptable scientific and technical merit for the purpose of achieving maximum utilization of available funds and resources to benefit the Chesapeake Bay area; and (3) ensure that all data and other products generated by any project funded under this section be provided to the Director.</p> <p>Requires the Director to consult with the Chesapeake Executive Council to ensure that the activities of the Office are consistent with the purposes and priorities of the Chesapeake Bay Agreement and plans developed pursuant to the Agreement.</p> <p>Requires the Director to collaborate with scientific and academic institutions, state and federal agencies, nongovernmental organizations, and other constituents in the Chesapeake Bay watershed, to incorporate Chesapeake Bay observations into the U.S. integrated Ocean Observation System, and to coordinate coastal mapping requirements and projects. Sets forth specific requirements to support such actions.</p> <p>Requires the Director, to further the development and implementation of the Chesapeake Bay Interpretive Buoy System, to: (1) support the establishment and implementation of the Captain John Smith Chesapeake National Historic Trail; (2) delineate key waypoints along the trail and provide appropriate real-time data and information for trail users; (3) interpret data and information for use by educators and students to inspire stewardship of Chesapeake Bay; and (4) incorporate the Chesapeake Bay Interpretive Buoy System into the Integrated Ocean Observing System regional network of observatories.</p> <p>Requires the Director to establish a Chesapeake Bay watershed education and training program. Sets forth specific requirements for such program.</p> <p>Requires the Director, subject to the availability of appropriations, to award grants to support education and training projects that enhance understanding and assessment of a specific environmental problem in the Chesapeake Bay watershed or a goal of the Chesapeake Bay Program, or protect or restore living resources of the Chesapeake Bay watershed, including specified projects. Requires the Director to provide technical assistance to support such education and training program.</p> <p>Requires the Director to establish a Chesapeake Bay coastal living resources management and habitat program to support coordinated management, protection, characterization, and restoration of priority Chesapeake Bay habitats and living resources, including oysters, blue crabs, and submerged aquatic vegetation. Authorizes the Director, subject to the availability of appropriations, to out or enter into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements and provide technical assistance to support related specified activities.</p> <p>Requires specified reports to Congress from the Director, as well as an action plan.</p> <p>Authorizes the Director, subject to the availability of appropriations, to enter into and perform such contracts, leases, grants, or cooperative agreements as may be necessary.</p> <p>Permits the director to accept donations of funds, other property, and services for use in understanding, protecting, and restoring the Chesapeake Bay.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2014.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A  bill to reauthorize the Chesapeake Bay Office of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Chesapeake Bay Science, Education, and Ecosystem Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2010-02-23T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-06-10T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s1224is/xml/BILLS-111s1224is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-02-23</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 272.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
