<bill session="119" type="s" number="744" updated="2025-11-19T04:19:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maintaining American Superiority by Improving Export Control Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maintaining American Superiority by Improving Export Control Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 relating to licensing transparency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1316" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-20T10:55:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maintaining American Superiority by Improving Export Control Transparency Act

This bill requires the Department of Commerce's Bureau of Industry and Security (BIS) to annually report to Congress on export control licensing.

Under current law, BIS administers and enforces controls on the export of dual-use goods (e.g., items with both civilian and military uses) and certain military parts and components. These export controls are implemented primarily under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (ECRA) through the Export Administration Regulations (EAR).

Under this bill, BIS must annually report to Congress on license applications, enforcement actions, and other requests for authorization for the export, reexport, release, and in-country transfer of items subject to the&#160;EAR to covered entities. A covered entity is any entity that (1) is located or operating in a country listed in Country Group D:5 (countries that are identified by the Department of State as subject to U.S. arms embargoes), and (2) is included on the Entity List or the Military End-User List (two of the lists published by BIS containing information on the individuals, organizations, and addresses subject to restrictions involving items subject to the EAR).

The bill requires this report to include specified information, such as the name of the entity submitting the application, where the item is being exported, the decision with respect to the license application or authorization, and information on related enforcement activities to ensure&#160;compliance with U.S. export controls. The information shall be exempt from public disclosure (except for aggregate statistics).</summary>
</bill>
