<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>989</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T23:06:40Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-23T20:37:01Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-12</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-12T20:38:54Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-12</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-12</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000934</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Moran, Jerry [R-KS]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jerry</firstName>
        <lastName>Moran</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>KS</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-05-12</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Environmental Protection</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Air quality</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fires</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Kansas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Licensing and registrations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oklahoma</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Environmental Protection</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-12</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-06-09T14:20:20Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Flint Hills Preservation Act - Amends the Clean Air Act to require states and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), in determining whether an exceedance or violation of a national ambient air quality standard has occurred with respect to a specific air pollutant, to exclude data from a particular air quality monitoring location if emissions from prescribed fires in the Flint Hills Region cause a concentration of the air pollutant at the location to be in excess of the standard.</p> <p>Prohibits, if such emission data is excluded: (1) the Administrator from finding that a state has failed to enforce, or that a person has violated, a state implementation plan (SIP) for national primary or secondary ambient air quality standards as a result of such emissions; or (2) a state from finding that a person has violated, or from bringing an enforcement action for violation of, a SIP for such standards as a result of such emissions.</p> <p>Prohibits: (1) the Administrator from requiring, or a state from adopting, a smoke management plan under such Act in connection with any prescribed fire in such region; and (2) a building, structure, facility, or installation from being treated as a stationary source under new stationary source performance standards as a result of such prescribed fires.<br /></p> <p>Provides that no person shall be required to obtain or modify an operating permit under Title V of the Clean Air Act in connection with such a prescribed fire. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Flint Hills Preservation Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Flint Hills Preservation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Flint Hills Preservation Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to require the exclusion of data of an exceedance or violation of a national ambient air quality standard caused by a prescribed fire in the Flint Hills Region, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-12T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s989is/xml/BILLS-112s989is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-05-12</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
