<bill session="111" type="h" number="3679" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:02Z">
  <state datetime="2009-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACORN Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Federal Government from awarding contracts, grants, or other agreements to, providing any other Federal funds to, or engaging in activities that promote certain corporations or companies guilty of certain felony convictions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACORN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Against Corporations Organizing to Rip-off the Nation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000288" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000043" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000556" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000007" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2009-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2009-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2009-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2009-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10489-10490"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-23T19:50:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Against Corporations Organizing to Rip-off the Nation Act or the ACORN Act - Prohibits the federal government from awarding contracts, grants, or other agreements to, providing any other federal funds to, or engaging in activities that promote, any corporation or company that has been found guilty of a felony criminal violation under federal or state law, that had its state corporate charter terminated due to its failure to comply with federal or state lobbying disclosure requirements, or that employs or otherwise retains a director, officer, or executive of the corporation or company who has been found guilty of a felony in relation to the individual's conduct for that company, during the five-year period following such conviction or charter termination.

Prohibits such a corporation or director, officer, or executive, during such period, from: (1) contributing funds to a candidate for federal office, federal political action committee, or federal or state political party; or (2) using more than $1 million in any calendar year to lobby Congress or federal employees.

Includes Pfizer, Pharmacia &amp; Upjohn Company Inc., and any Pfizer related affiliate as covered companies for purposes of this Act.

Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be revised to carry out the provisions of this Act relating to contracts. Authorizes the President to waive a prohibition under this Act in the national interest.</summary>
</bill>
