<bill session="116" type="s" number="4830" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:23Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness for Seniors and People with Disabilities During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness for Seniors and People with Disabilities During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide protections to Social Security and Supplemental Security Income beneficiaries relating to extra payments due to the COVID-19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2020-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7830" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-10T20:10:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness for Seniors and People with Disabilities During COVID-19 Act of 2020

This bill restricts the recovery by the Social Security Administration (SSA) of certain overpayments of benefits made between March 1, 2020, and December 31, 2020. The bill also specifies that an individual who received Supplemental Security Income (SSI), or similar payments from a state, for any month during that period shall not be deemed ineligible for Medicaid coverage for that month on the basis that the individual is later determined to be ineligible for SSI or similar payments.

Specifically, the SSA shall not recover any overpayments of Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance benefits, SSI benefits, or benefits for certain World War II veterans made during this period, unless the overpayments resulted from fraud or the misuse of benefits by a representative payee. For actions underway to recover overpayments, including those initiated before March 2020, the SSA must also notify individuals of their opportunity to request a reduction or suspension of adjustments to their benefits or a suspension of certain installment payments during the specified period. Additionally, the SSA must report on the time frame for resuming overpayment processing and collection activities.

Beginning in March 2020, the SSA has operated under modified work processes in response to the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2020) emergency, including the suspension of certain procedures for identifying changes to eligibility status and adjusting benefits to account for them. However, in August 2020, the SSA issued an interim final rule concerning the resumption of these procedures, which included a simplified waiver process for beneficiaries who incurred an overpayment between March 1, 2020, and September 30, 2020.</summary>
</bill>
