<bill session="115" type="h" number="2145" updated="2023-01-11T13:35:57Z">
  <state datetime="2017-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">No REX Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit licenses or other authorization for United States persons to engage in activities relating to deepwater, Arctic offshore, or shale projects that have the potential to produce oil in the Russian Federation, or in maritime area claimed by the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No REX Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">No Russia Exemptions for Oil Production Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2017-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000593" joined="2017-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="6437" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2018-02-12T22:01:22Z" status="Introduced in House">No Russia Exemptions for Oil Production Act or the No REX Act

This bill prohibits the Department of the Treasury from providing licenses or other authorization for U.S. persons to engage in activities relating to deepwater, Arctic offshore, or shale projects that may produce oil in Russia or within its maritime jurisdiction.Executive Order 13662 (relating to blocking property of additional persons contributing to the situation in Ukraine) authorized Treasury to prevent U.S. persons from engaging in business with Russia in various sectors, including the energy sector.

Additionally, the bill nullifies any license or other authorization to engage in prohibited activities issued before the enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
