<bill session="112" type="h" number="6608" updated="2019-11-15T21:18:15Z">
  <state datetime="2012-11-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-11-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Asthma Act</title>
    <title type="display">Family Asthma Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act with regard to research on asthma, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-11-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3641" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-01-17T20:26:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Family Asthma Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), to collaborate with state and local health departments to: (1) conduct activities regarding asthma, including deterring the harmful consequences of uncontrolled asthma, and disseminating health education and information regarding prevention of asthma episodes and strategies for managing asthma; and (2) develop state plans incorporating public health responses to reduce the burden of asthma, particularly regarding disproportionately affected populations.

 Revises and expands requirements for asthma surveillance activities.

 Requires the Director to coordinate data collection activities to maximize the comparability of results.

Requires the Secretary to submit an assessment of current activities related to asthma prevention, management and surveillance along with recommendations for the future direction of asthma activities.</summary>
</bill>
