<bill session="118" type="h" number="5094" updated="2025-03-21T14:53:55Z">
  <state datetime="2023-08-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-08-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-08-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SNAP Staffing Flexibility Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SNAP Staffing Flexibility Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 to allow for blended workforces to carry out the supplemental nutrition assistance program under certain conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000377" joined="2023-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001135" joined="2023-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000600" joined="2023-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-11-14" withdrawn="2024-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000603" joined="2023-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-08-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-08-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-27T15:33:31Z" status="Introduced in House">SNAP Staffing Flexibility Act of 2023

This bill allows a state agency to hire a contractor to perform Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP) certification or other state functions for SNAP&#160;under certain conditions.

Specifically, a state agency may hire a contractor when the state experiences an increase in SNAP applications or an inability to timely process such applications from causes that include&#160;(1) pandemics and other health emergencies, (2) seasonal workforce cycles, (3) temporary staffing shortages, and (4) weather or other natural disasters.&#160;The bill includes specific parameters for a state agency that hires a contractor based on&#160;temporary staffing shortages.

The bill requires that a contractor be part of a blended workforce (i.e., combines government employees and the employees of a for-profit or private nonprofit employer).&#160;

Further, a state agency must notify the Department of Agriculture (USDA) of the intent to hire a contractor and provide any information or data supporting state agency increases in SNAP applications or the inability to timely process applications. USDA must make the notification and accompanying information publicly available on the USDA website.

Finally, USDA must submit an annual report to Congress that includes specific information and recommendations, including information on the measures taken by USDA to address increases in SNAP applications.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
