<bill session="119" type="s" number="396" updated="2025-04-29T17:22:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop GREED Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Government Rewards Enriching Executives in the District Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop GREED Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to impose limitations on the provision of critical skill incentives to employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Senior Executive Services positions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="423" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-29T17:16:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Government Rewards Enriching Executives in the District Act of 2025 or the Stop GREED Act of 2025

This bill prohibits the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) from providing certain senior level employees with a critical skill incentive, which is generally a payment bonus for employees possessing a high-demand skill or skill that is at a shortage. Specifically, the VA may not provide such an incentive to an employee in a Senior Executive Service position or other comparable position at the central office of the VA (e.g., the Veterans Health Administration), regardless of the actual location where the employee performs the functions of the position.

The bill also provides that an incentive may be provided to senior-level employees on an individual basis and upon approval by specified officers (e.g., the Under Secretary for Health). Additionally, senior-level employees whose positions are primarily at the central office of the VA but perform some portion of the job function&#160;at other VA facilities are exempt from the prohibition.

The VA must report to Congress annually regarding senior-level employees who were provided a critical skill incentive.</summary>
</bill>
