<bill session="116" type="h" number="5009" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:33Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VET Extension Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide additional entitlement to Post-9/11 Educational Assistance to certain veterans and members of the Armed Forces who require extra time to complete remedial and deficiency courses, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Extension Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Education and Transfer Extension Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001066"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3279" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-29T14:48:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Education and Transfer Extension Act of 2019 or the VET Extension Act of 2019

This bill updates Post-9/11 GI Bill educational assistance for certain veterans or active duty military service members. Specifically, the bill increases the number of months of educational assistance available by the lesser of (1) 15 months, or (2) the amount of months needed to complete remedial and deficiency courses that may be needed prior to beginning a program of education.

Under the bill, individuals who do not currently have a dependent, but wish to elect to transfer educational assistance to a dependent, may do so at such a time when they do have a dependent. The bill removes a restriction on the timing of the transfer of educational assistance and also authorizes an individual to designate a new dependent or dependents to receive an unused entitlement.</summary>
</bill>
