<bill session="117" type="h" number="8540" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Developing and Nationalizing Key Cannabis Research Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing and Nationalizing Key Cannabis Research Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the designation of institutions of higher education as Centers of Excellence in Cannabis Research, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2022-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-05T17:59:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Developing and Nationalizing Key Cannabis Research Act of 2022 This bill directs the National Institutes of Health (NIH) and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to expand activities concerning cannabis research. The NIH must collaborate with specified agencies to develop a national cannabis research agenda. Among other topics, the agenda must address (1) the therapeutic benefits of cannabis, (2) how cannabis effects specified populations, and (3) other public safety considerations. Additionally, the NIH must designate centers of excellence in cannabis research at institutions of higher education to conduct interdisciplinary research about biomedical, behavioral, and social issues related to cannabis. The CDC must work with other agencies to collect population-wide data about cannabis use, including (1) demographic factors, (2) health outcomes, (3) product variety, and (4) other relevant health information.</summary>
</bill>
