<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2477</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-15T04:49:07Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-15T04:49:07Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2004-05-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2004-05-21T15:15:46Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-05-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6100-6105)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-05-21</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S6099-6100)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-05-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000122</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Reed, Jack [D-RI]</fullName>
        <firstName>John</firstName>
        <lastName>Reed</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>RI</state>
        <middleName>F.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001035</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Collins, Susan M. [R-ME]</fullName>
        <firstName>Susan</firstName>
        <lastName>Collins</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ME</state>
        <middleName>M.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-05-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000105</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kennedy, Edward M. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>EDWARD</firstName>
        <lastName>KENNEDY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>MOORE</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-05-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-05-21</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>D000563</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Durbin, Richard J. [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Richard</firstName>
        <lastName>Durbin</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <middleName>J.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-06-18</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000711</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Boxer, Barbara [D-CA]</fullName>
        <firstName>BARBARA</firstName>
        <lastName>BOXER</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>N000032</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Nelson, Bill [D-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>CLARENCE</firstName>
        <lastName>NELSON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>WILLIAM</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-09-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>College costs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Community and school</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Corporate philanthropy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Deaf</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Disabled</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Dislocated workers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education of the disadvantaged</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education savings accounts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electronic data interchange</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Electronic government information</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Elementary and secondary education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Financial disclosure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Food stamps</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Identification devices</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Indexing (Economic policy)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental fiscal relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Internet</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mentoring</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nonprofit organizations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Scholarships</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>School lunch program</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>State taxation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student aid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Student loan funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Students</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Supplemental security income program</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Taxation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Telephone</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Welfare recipients</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-05-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2004-06-29T21:00:38Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Accessing College through Comprehensive Early Outreach, State Partnerships, and Simplification Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to replace the current special leveraging educational assistance partnership program with a program of allotments to enable States to: (1) expand and enhance partnerships with institutions of higher education, early information and intervention, mentoring, or outreach programs, private corporations, philanthropic organizations, and other interested parties to carry out specified activities and provide coordination and cohesion among Federal, State, and local governmental and private efforts providing financial assistance to help low-income students attend college; (2) provide need-based grants for college access and increased college persistence to eligible low-income students; (3) provide early notification to low-income students of their eligibility for financial aid; and (4) encourage increased participation in early information and intervention, mentoring, or outreach programs.</p> <p>Sets 66.66 percent as the Federal share of the cost of establishing partnerships under the program. Requires partnerships for the award of grants between a State agency and: (1) at least one public and one private degree granting institution of higher education located in the State; and (2) new or existing early information and intervention, mentoring, or outreach programs also located in the State. Permits partnerships with philanthropic organizations located in, or which provide funding in, the State, as well as private corporations located in, or doing business in, the State. </p> <p>Prescribes requirements for the amounts of grants awarded in partnerships with institutions of higher learning: (1) serving less than a majority of students in the State; and (2) serving the majority of students in the State.</p> <p>Requires annual early notification of low-income students of their potential eligibility for student financial assistance.</p> <p>Prescribes minimum eligibility requirements for such students.</p> <p>Revises requirements for the simplified needs test to take into account dislocated workers and recipients of means-tested Federal benefits (such as the supplemental security income program under title XVI of the Social Security Act, the food stamp program, and the free and reduced price school lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act).</p> <p> Directs the Secretary of Education to develop and use a simplified paper application form of the Free Application for Federal Student Aid (FAFSA), to be called the FAFSA-EZ, for students who meet the requirements of the automatic zero expected family contribution.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to: (1) phase-out by the 2009-2010 award year the paper form (the long form or full FAFSA) for students who do not meet the requirements for a FAFSA-EZ; and (2) produce, distribute, and process common forms in electronic format, including a simplified electronic application form on the Internet.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to make every effort to provide students with early information about potential financial aid eligibility, both through a widely disseminated printed form and the Internet or other electronic means, including a system for individuals to determine easily, by entering relevant data, approximately the amount of grant, work-study, and loan assistance for which an individual would be eligible.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to make special efforts to notify: (1) students who qualify for specified means-tested Federal benefits of their potential eligibility for a maximum Federal Pell Grant; and (2) middle school and secondary school students of the availability of student financial assistance and of the approximate amounts of grant, work-study, and loan assistance for which they would be eligible.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to contract for or establish a toll-free telephone service to provide an application mechanism and timely and accurate information to the general public.</p> <p>Revises requirements for determining the income contribution of dependent students, independent students without dependents other than spouse, and independent students with dependents other than spouse (generally increasing allowances). Excludes qualified education benefits (prepayment and savings plans, State tuition programs, and Coverdell education savings accounts) from consideration as an asset in a needs analysis.</p> <p>Revises the purposes of the independent Advisory Committee on Student Financial Assistance to reflect this Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Accessing College through Comprehensive Early Outreach, State Partnerships, and Simplification Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Accessing College through Comprehensive Early Outreach, State Partnerships, and Simplification Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to expand college access and increase college persistence, to simplify the process of applying for student assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Accessing College through Comprehensive Early Outreach, State Partnerships, and Simplification Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2004-05-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-05-21</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. (text of measure as introduced: CR S6100-6105)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
