<bill session="118" type="h" number="799" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE CARS Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE CARS Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shielding All Federal Employees and Consumers from Actionable Recall Situations Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the sale, lease, or use of recalled motor vehicles by Federal agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2023-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-17T14:01:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Shielding All Federal Employees and Consumers from Actionable Recall Situations Act of 2023 or the SAFE CARS Act of 2023

This bill restricts the sale, lease, or use of recalled motor vehicles by federal agencies.

Specifically, if an agency has received notification that a motor vehicle or related equipment owned by the agency contains a defect related to motor vehicle safety or does not comply with an applicable motor vehicle safety standard, the agency may not sell or lease the vehicle unless specified steps are taken to remedy the defect or noncompliance or must notify the purchaser or individual leasing the vehicle.

The agency must make all reasonable efforts to prevent the use of such vehicle, subject to certain exceptions, until the defect or noncompliance has been remedied.</summary>
</bill>
