<bill session="117" type="h" number="2605" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Let It Go Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for a limitation on the time for the use of contributions or donations by candidates for election for Federal office, to prohibit candidates from using campaign funds to make contributions to charitable organizations which are owned or controlled by the candidate or immediate family members of the candidate, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Let It Go Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2093" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-02T20:10:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Let It Go Act

This bill establishes a time frame for the disposal of campaign contributions or donations. The bill also prohibits the donation of campaign funds to charitable organizations that are owned or controlled by the candidate or the candidate's immediate family members.

An individual must use contributions or donations before the individual becomes a registered lobbyist or within six years following the most recent federal election in which the individual was a candidate, whichever occurs first.

The remaining contributions or donations must be disposed of within 30 days following either occurrence, first by paying debts or obligations owed in connection with the campaign for that office. If funds are left over, the funds may only be disbursed in one or more of the following ways: (1) returning funds to donors; (2) making contributions to charitable organizations; and (3) transferring funds to a national, state, or local committee of a political party.

The bill prohibits the donation of campaign funds to a charitable organization if the candidate or the candidate's immediate family member (1) is an employee of the organization, (2) is a member of the board of directors, or (3) owns a majority of the voting shares.</summary>
</bill>
