<bill session="118" type="s" number="879" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Energy Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Freedom Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide greater output, price stability, and regulatory certainty with respect to domestic energy production in the United States and exports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-21T12:54:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Energy Freedom Act

This bill establishes requirements to provide for domestic energy production.

Specifically, the bill establishes deadlines to expedite the review of permits and other authorizations for natural gas transmission projects, natural gas interstate pipelines, and the exportation of natural gas. The bill also requires a minimum number of annual sales of leases on federal lands and waters for oil and gas development. It also requires sales of leases of federal land for wind, solar, and geothermal development.

The President and federal agencies must obtain the approval of Congress before (1) declaring a moratorium on the leasing of federal lands or waters for the drilling, mining, or collection of oil, gas, or coal; (2) prohibiting or substantially delaying certain new energy leases, mineral leases, or permits on federal lands; and (3) withdrawing certain federal lands from mineral and geothermal leasing activities. Further, the bill eliminates the requirement for certain cross-border energy projects to obtain presidential approval.

In addition, the bill allows the Department of the Interior to grant licenses for the exploration and mining of hardrock minerals on the Outer Continental Shelf.

Finally, the bill reinstates specified rules concerning waters of the United States, oil and gas, civil penalties, environmental review, and discharge and dredged materials.</summary>
</bill>
