<bill session="109" type="h" number="4029" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:55Z">
  <state datetime="2005-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fuel Price Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure fairness in gasoline, diesel fuel, and home heating oil prices.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fuel Price Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001227" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001049" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000339" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000557" joined="2005-11-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2005-11-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000523" joined="2005-11-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Energy shortages"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Futures trading"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Heating"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Profit"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Wholesale trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-10-25T17:36:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Fuel Price Fairness Act - Authorizes the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to declare a national or regional energy price emergency if it finds that the health, safety, welfare, or economic well-being of U.S. citizens, or a region of the United States, is at risk because of a shortage or imminent shortage of adequate supplies of crude oil, gasoline, diesel fuel, or home heating oil due to a disruption of distribution systems for crude oil, gasoline, natural gas, or petroleum distillates, or significant pricing anomalies in national or regional energy markets for those products are more than temporary.

Requires an integrated oil company or refinery to disclose to the FTC during such emergency: (1) the prevailing price of crude oil and wholesale price of refined gasoline, diesel, home heating oil, based on invoices, for each week during the period of 60 days immediately preceding the declaration of an energy emergency; and (2) the prevailing price of crude oil and wholesale price of refined gasoline, diesel, home heating oil, based on invoices, for each week of the period in which a national price emergency is in effect.

Declares unlawful during such a national energy price emergency: (1) for any person to sell at retail gasoline, diesel fuel, or home heating oil at an unreasonable price; and (2) for any integrated oil company or refinery to sell those products at an unreasonable price.

Subjects such integrated oil company or refinery to criminal penalties for violations of this Act.

Grants the FTC enforcement powers under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
