<bill session="118" type="s" number="116" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">The Hurricanes of 2022 Disaster Relief Rectification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">The Hurricanes of 2022 Disaster Relief Rectification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Disaster Relief Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2023 to improve disaster relief funding, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-01-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="662" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="180" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1180" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2672" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-31T20:04:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">The Hurricanes of 2022 Disaster Relief Rectification Act

The bill rescinds certain unobligated disaster relief funds that were provided by the Disaster Relief Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2023 and provides additional funding to assist states, territories, and federal facilities impacted by Hurricanes Fiona, Ian, or Nicole.

The bill also modifies various policies and programs related to disaster assistance, including to

 allow certain disaster relief funds to be provided as block grants to eligible states and territories, require the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to reimburse local governments and electric cooperatives for certain interest payments for loans related to disasters, establish a process for states to request waivers of restrictions related to the deployment of FEMA travel trailers or manufactured housing units in flood hazard areas, establish a pilot program under which FEMA may make grants to Florida for elevating structures located in areas that have special flood hazards or in other areas of flood risk, and require the Department of Agriculture to make specified revisions to the regulations for the Emergency Watershed Protection Program.</summary>
</bill>
