<bill session="108" type="s" number="1362" updated="2023-01-15T17:04:08Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFE Border Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Port Passenger Accelerated Service System (Port PASS) as a permanent program for land border inspection under the Immigration and Nationality Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFE Border Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Secure and Fast Entry at the Border Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000711"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8757-8758"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limited access highways"/>
    <term name="Pedestrians"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Secure and Fast Entry at the Border Act of 2003 or the SAFE Border Act of 2003 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make the Port Passenger Accelerated Service System (PortPASS) permanent.Provides for minimum two-year entry approvals under the Secure Electronic Network for Travelers Rapid Inspection (SENTRI) program along the United States-Mexico border. Precludes a person convicted of a felony or under active criminal investigation from program participation.Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Department of Homeland Security must ensure the permanence of PortPASS in its transition from the Department of Justice to the Department; (2) all land PortPASS programs should utilize interoperable technology to offer participants increased commuter lane access; (3) the Secretary of Homeland Security should increase SENTRI program staff, training, and resources; and (4) the Secretary should create a pre-inspection low-risk commuter lane for pedestrian land border crossers.</summary>
</bill>
