<bill session="110" type="s" number="473" updated="2023-01-11T19:59:12Z">
  <state datetime="2007-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the prohibitions on money laundering, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1523-1524"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1524-1526" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Cartels"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Extraterritoriality"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign banks and banking"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Indictments"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Obstruction of justice"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-02-26T19:54:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Combating Money Laundering and Terrorist Financing Act of 2007 - Amends money laundering provisions of the federal criminal code to redefine "specified unlawful activity" as: (1) any act constituting an offense in violation of the laws of the United States or any State punishable by imprisonment for a term exceeding 1 year; and (2) any act occurring outside of the United States that would constitute such an offense if committed within U.S. jurisdiction.

Revises the procedure for issuing subpoenas in money laundering cases.

Assigns a standard value to monetary instruments payable to bearer in blank (with no amount indicated on the instrument).

Increases the penalty for bulk cash smuggling in or out of the United States from five to 10 years.

Redefines money laundering transactions involving amounts greater than $10,000 to include commingling of funds from separate accounts and structured transactions designed to avoid reporting requirements.

Permits a single indictment for multiple money laundering violations that are part of the same scheme or continuing course of conduct.

Prohibits illegal (currently, unlicensed) money transmitting businesses.

Extends the jurisdiction of the United States in money laundering cases to include activities outside of the United States that have an effect in the United States.

Prohibits the possession of any material that can be used to counterfeit U.S. currencies.

Establishes funding authority for the U.S. Secret Service in FY2008-FY2010, including the authority to use funds obtained from any undercover investigative operation to offset expenses incurred in such operation.</summary>
</bill>
