<bill session="108" type="s" number="2656" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:23Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ponce de Leon Discovery of Florida Quincentennial Commission Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Commission on the Quincentennial of the discovery of Florida by Ponce de Leon.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Ponce de Leon Discovery of Florida Quincentennial Commission Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ponce de Leon Discovery of Florida Quincentennial Commission Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2004-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8132"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8132-8134" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on National Parks. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-739.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11183-11184" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-10-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16T14:03:05-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG04" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="National Parks" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="5310" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Fund raising"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Spain"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s4057"/>
    <amendment number="s4046"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-12-07T20:29:02Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Ponce de Leon Discovery of Florida Quincentennial Commission Act - Establishes the National Commission on the Quincentennial of the discovery of Florida by Ponce de Leon to plan, encourage, coordinate, and conduct the commemoration of the Quincentennial (500th anniversary) of the discovery of Florida by the Spanish explorer Ponce de Leon.

Sets forth the membership composition of the Commission. Requires the appointment of Commission members not later than 60 days after the enactment of this Act.

Directs the Commission to: (1) plan and develop activities for commemorating the Quincentennial; (2) consult with public and private agencies to organize and participate in Quincentennial activities; and (3) coordinate activities throughout the United States and internationally that relate to the history and influence of the discovery of Florida.

Directs the Commission to submit a comprehensive report to the President, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and the Committee on Resources of the House of Representatives not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, that includes specific recommendations for: (1) the allocation of financial and administrative responsibility among entities participating in the commemoration; and (2) the commemoration of the Quincentennial and related events through various publications, programs, and activities. Requires the Commission to submit annual reports on activities, programs, expenditures and donations, and a final report by December 31, 2013.

Enumerates the powers of the Commission, including powers to: (1) prepare and disseminate historical, commemorative, and informational materials and objects to promote awareness of, and interest in, the Quincentennial; (2) create competitions and awards for historical, artistic, and other works relating to the Quincentennial; and (3) establish a central clearinghouse for information relating to the Quincentennial.

Sets forth administrative provisions for the Commission, including the establishment of a principal office in St. Augustine, Florida, and a satellite office in Washington, D.C. Provides for the staffing of the Commission, compensation of Commission employees, procurement authority, and authority to solicit donations.

Directs the Secretary of the Interior to conduct a feasibility study for designating an area in the State of Florida as a unit of the National Park System to commemorate the discovery of Florida by Ponce de Leon, and to submit a report to Congress, with recommendations, on the findings of the study.

Authorizes appropriations.

Terminates the authority provided by this Act on December 31, 2013.</summary>
</bill>
