<bill session="117" type="s" number="3335" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Robocall Trace Back Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Robocall Trace Back Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide liability protection for the sharing of information regarding suspected fraudulent, abusive, or unlawful robocalls, illegally spoofed calls, and other illegal calls by or with the registered consortium that conducts private-led efforts to trace back the origin of suspected unlawful robocalls, and for the receipt of such information by the registered consortium, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000463" joined="2022-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2022-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2022-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2021-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2022-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2022-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2022-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9047-9048" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7598" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-06T14:37:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Robocall Trace Back Enhancement Act

This bill provides liability protection for specified information-sharing activities undertaken to trace the origins of unlawful robocalls, illegally spoofed calls, and other illegal calls.

Specifically, the bill protects a designated consortium that conducts private-led efforts to trace unlawful robocalls from liability for receiving, sharing, or publishing information about illegal calls, including their origin or source. The bill also applies liability protection to a voice service provider (i.e., a provider of any service that enables real-time, two-way voice communications) or other entity or person that shares information with the consortium.</summary>
</bill>
