<bill session="111" type="h" number="4470" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe Treatment, Avoiding Needless Deaths, and Abuse Reduction in the Detention System Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure that individuals detained by the Department of Homeland Security are treated humanely, provided adequate medical care, and granted certain specified rights.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Treatment, Avoiding Needless Deaths, and Abuse Reduction in the Detention System Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strong STANDARDS Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000794"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2010-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2010-02-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-19">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border, Maritime, and Global Counterterrorism.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="4321" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1550" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-22T16:30:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe Treatment, Avoiding Needless Deaths, and Abuse Reduction in the Detention System Act or the Strong STANDARDS Act - Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) to: (1) ensure that all individuals subject to detention under the Immigration and Nationality Act (detainees) are treated humanely and granted specified protections; and (2) comply with minimum requirements concerning detainees set forth in this Act.

Sets forth requirements concerning a wide range of issues, including: (1) detainee medical care, examinations, and records; (2) detainee releases, transfers, and transportation; (3) detainee access to telephones, legal information and representation, translation services, and recreational activities; (4) protection of detainees from abuse, the unique needs of vulnerable detainees, and the segregation of children; (5) limitations on solitary confinement, shackling, and strip searches; (6) detainee visits with religious individuals and children; (7) detention facility personnel training; (8) detainee grievances; and (9) facility compliance.

Sets forth specific requirements for short-term (72 hours or less) detention facilities, including concerning: (1) provision of basic needs, detainee access to consular officials and health care professionals, and the return of property; and (2) protections for children.

Requires the Secretary to appoint and convene an Immigration Detention Commission to conduct independent investigations of detention facility and DHS compliance with requirements under this Act. Establishes reporting requirements concerning any individual who dies while in DHS custody.</summary>
</bill>
