<bill session="117" type="s" number="3626" updated="2022-12-29T21:18:18Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PACE Expanded Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PACE Expanded Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Program of All-inclusive Care for the Elderly Expanded Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve access to the Program of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2022-02-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9209" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-11T21:40:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Program of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly Expanded Act or the PACE Expanded Act

This bill modifies requirements regarding Programs of All-Inclusive Care for the Elderly (PACE). PACE is a program under Medicare and Medicaid that provides in-home and community services for certain individuals as an alternative to nursing home care.

The bill allows Medicare beneficiaries to enroll in a PACE program at any time and provides states with the option to allow Medicaid beneficiaries to do the same. Entities may also apply to become PACE providers at any time, upon specified assurances relating to staffing and other requirements.

The bill also (1) allows the Center for Medicare and Medicaid Innovation to test a model for expanded PACE eligibility that targets high-need and high-cost populations, and (2) requires an evaluation of the effectiveness of PACE in rural and underserved areas.</summary>
</bill>
