<bill session="119" type="h" number="1393" updated="2025-06-24T20:18:43Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Response Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Response Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to conduct a review of the criteria for evaluating the cost-effectiveness of certain mitigation projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2025-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2025-02-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-24T20:17:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildfire Response Improvement Act

This bill expands certain wildfire management assistance to beyond the time when the fire occurs and requires the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to update various programmatic guidance relating to wildfire response and cost-effectiveness criteria for wildfire mitigation projects.

Currently, in general, government entities&#226;&#8364;&#8482; costs for fighting wildfires are only eligible for assistance under the Fire Management Assistance Grant (FMAG) Program if the costs are incurred during the incident period (i.e., time during which the fire occurs). The bill requires&#160;FEMA to modify the FMAG&#160;Program so that assessments and emergency stabilization to protect public safety are eligible for FMAG assistance regardless of when the incident period begins or ends.

The bill also requires&#160;FEMA to review and update its evaluation criteria for the cost-effectiveness of wildfire mitigation projects proposed under the Building Resilient Infrastructure and Communities program or Hazard Mitigation Grant Program and prioritize projects accordingly.

Additionally,&#160;FEMA must update its policy guide for the Public Assistance program to include guidance on challenges with wildfire recovery, including the resulting toxicity of drinking water resources.</summary>
</bill>
