<bill session="118" type="s" number="1423" updated="2025-11-18T21:53:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sickle Cell Care Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sickle Cell Care Expansion Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize a scholarship and loan repayment program to incentivize physicians to enter into the field of sickle cell disease research, treatment, and patient care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3100" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood and blood diseases"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hereditary and development disorders"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T13:07:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sickle Cell Care Expansion Act of 2023

This bill establishes programs to increase treatment and other services for populations with sickle cell disease. Sickle cell disease is an inherited blood disorder that can lead to pain, anemia, infections, and stroke.

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must award grants to federally qualified health centers, community-based organizations, or other nonprofits that treat or otherwise support populations with sickle cell disease for education and advocacy programs concerning the disease. HHS must also award grants to nonprofits, including hospitals or institutions of higher education, that provide comprehensive care to populations with sickle cell disease for programs to support the transition from pediatric to adult care for patients with the disease.

Additionally, the Health Resources and Services Administration must establish a program to provide scholarships or student loan repayment awards to individuals who commit to engage in clinical practice or research related to sickle cell disease for a period of obligated service as physicians.</summary>
</bill>
