<bill session="118" type="sr" number="472" updated="2025-01-14T19:00:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the 90th anniversary of the Ukrainian Famine of 1932-1933, known as the Holodomor, should serve as a reminder of repressive Soviet policies against the people of Ukraine, and that Vladimir Putin's brutal and unprovoked war against Ukraine once again threatens the existence of the Ukrainian people, while exacerbating the problems of global hunger.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that the 90th anniversary of the Ukrainian Famine of 1932-1933, known as the Holodomor, should serve as a reminder of repressive Soviet policies against the people of Ukraine, and that Vladimir Putin's brutal and unprovoked war against Ukraine once again threatens the existence of the Ukrainian people, while exacerbating the problems of global hunger.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-11-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5599-5600" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-20T21:07:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution

condemns Vladimir Putin's illegal war in Ukraine and his weaponization of hunger;calls upon Vladimir Putin and the Russian Armed Forces to immediately cease their attacks on Ukrainian civilians, to withdraw, and to respect Ukraine's independence;remembers the 90th anniversary of the Ukrainian Famine (Holodomor) of 1932-1933 and extends its deepest sympathies to the victims, survivors, and families of this tragedy;condemns the systematic violations of human rights of the Ukrainian people by the Soviet Union; andsupports the continuing efforts of the people of Ukraine to defend themselves against Russian aggression.</summary>
</bill>
