<bill session="118" type="h" number="731" updated="2025-11-18T18:23:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Workforce Mobility Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Workforce Mobility Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit certain noncompete agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000215" joined="2023-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000579" joined="2023-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000048" joined="2024-08-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="220" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-24T21:37:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Workforce Mobility Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the use of noncompete agreements in the context of commercial enterprises except under certain circumstances.

The first exception is that the seller of a business entity may enter into an agreement to refrain from engaging in a similar business in the geographic area where the business being sold has conducted business prior to the agreement. This exception extends to agreements by senior executive officials who have a severance agreement as part of the conditions of sale (i.e., a buyout provision). Second, a partner of an enterprise may enter into an agreement that, upon dissolution of the partnership or dissociation of the partner from the partnership, the partner will refrain from engaging in a similar business in the geographic areas where the partnership has conducted business prior to the agreement.

Commercial enterprises must post notice of the prohibition of noncompete agreements under this bill in a conspicuous area of the workplace and conduct a public awareness campaign to inform the public of the provisions of this bill.

The Federal Trade Commission or the Department of Labor shall investigate or enforce the provisions of the bill. Individuals and state attorneys general may also bring civil actions to enforce the provisions of the bill.</summary>
</bill>
