<bill session="117" type="s" number="606" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESPOND Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Securities and Exchange Commission to issue an annual report to Congress projecting and accounting for the economic costs directly and indirectly caused by the impacts of climate change, to require the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board to establish a Federal Advisory Panel on the Economics of Climate Change, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESPOND Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restructuring Environmentally Sound Pensions in Order to Negate Disaster Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1618" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-14T15:13:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restructuring Environmentally Sound Pensions in Order to Negate Disaster Act of 2021 or the RESPOND Act of 2021 

This bill addresses issues related to the impact of climate change on the economy, including federal retirement plans.

The Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board must establish an advisory panel on the economics of climate change to advise on how the board may invest in clean and renewable energy and make investments in a manner that helps ensure net zero greenhouse gas emissions in the United States by 2050. The board must then assess whether implementing low-carbon investment strategies is profitable and consistent with its duties.

 If the board cannot implement such strategies, the bill establishes the Climate Choice Stock Index Fund as part of the Federal Employees Retirement System's Thrift Savings Plan. This fund is established as an investment portfolio that performs similarly to other plan index funds, but does not invest in fossil fuels.

 Finally, the Federal Reserve Board and the Securities and Exchange Commission must annually report on the economic costs of climate change.</summary>
</bill>
