<bill session="117" type="h" number="4415" updated="2022-12-31T05:07:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to release certain reversionary interests of the United States in and to a parcel of land located in Henderson, Tennessee.</title>
    <title type="display">Chester County Reversionary Interest Release Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chester County Reversionary Interest Release Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1199" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-03T22:22:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Chester County Reversionary Interest Release Act

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to release the reversionary interest of the United States in a 0.62-acre parcel of land in Chickasaw State Forest in Tennessee (the state forest land), if, as consideration for the release, Tennessee agrees to transfer to the United States a vested future interest in the 0.90-acre parcel known as the Webb property that is similar to the reversionary interest in order to facilitate a land exchange between Bethel Baptist Church in Henderson, Tennessee, and the state.

As soon as the state has complied with specified requirements concerning the deed for the state forest land, USDA shall convey to the state the undivided mineral interest of the United States in such land.

Additionally, USDA must determine the mineral character of the state forest land and the fair market value of the U.S. mineral interests&#160;no more than 90 days after enactment of this bill. Tennessee must pay the United States the fair market value of the mineral interests.</summary>
</bill>
