<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="970" updated="2022-02-03T05:21:24Z">
  <amends type="hc" number="312" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-03-13T13:16:01-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000180"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-03-13"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to provide an alternative budget that balances the budget in FY 2012. The CBC budget funds programs and services in the areas of health care, education, veterans benefits and services for low-income families. It also provides for additional services for the administration of justice and funds the recommendations of the House Committee on Homeland Security.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment in the nature of a substitute numbered 1 printed in House Report 110-548 and submitted on behalf of the Congressional Black Caucus, to seek an alternative budget that balances the budget in FY 2012. The CBC budget funds programs and services in the areas of health care, education, veterans benefits and services for low-income families. It also provides for additional services for the administration of justice and funds the recommendations of the House Committee on Homeland Security.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-03-13T13:16:01-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="137">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kilpatrick amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 126 - 292 (Roll no. 137).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T11:50:51-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Kilpatrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1633-1646" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1634-1635" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T11:50:51-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A001) in the nature of a substitute offered by Ms. Kilpatrick.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1633-1646" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1634-1635" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T13:16:01-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T13:16:01-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Kilpatrick amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 126 - 292 (Roll no. 137).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13T13:16:01-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-13">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
