<bill session="110" type="h" number="2733" updated="2023-01-12T17:53:00Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trinity River Restoration Fund Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Trinity River Restoration Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trinity River Restoration Fund Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000460"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000188" joined="2007-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2007-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Central Valley Reclamation Project (California)"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-07-31T22:07:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Trinity River Restoration Fund Act of 2007 - Establishes in the Treasury the Trinity River Restoration Fund to be available to the Secretary of the Interior for use solely for the purpose of implementing the preferred alternative identified in the Record of Decision issued by the Secretary with the concurrence of the Hoopa Valley Tribe on December 19, 2000, on Trinity River Mainstem Fishery Restoration. Authorizes the Secretary to accept and expend funds from public and private sources to assist in the implementation of the Record of Decision.

Provides that amounts deposited into the Fund for specific purposes shall be expended for those purposes only and shall not be subject to appropriation. Requires specified deposits to the Fund from: (1) the capital component of payments made pursuant to long-term contracts with the Bureau of Reclamation by Central Valley Project (CVP) water and power contractors; and (2) non-federal funds contributed to the United States for implementation of the Record of Decision or federal funds appropriated to the Trinity River Restoration Fund.

Makes federal costs of implementing this Act nonreimburseable under federal reclamation law.

Sets forth provisions regarding: (1) funding in the event Central Valley Project (CVP) capital repayments fall below necessary levels; (2) biennial summary reports from the Secretary; (3) required cost of living adjustments; and (4) a reduction of CVP's capital repayment obligation by the amount paid into the Fund.</summary>
</bill>
