<bill session="117" type="h" number="8290" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Make American Flags in America Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Make American Flags in America Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require certain flags of the United States to be made in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Z000017" joined="2022-08-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-06T18:04:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Make American Flags in America Act of 2022

This bill addresses the display and procurement of U.S. flags.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the display on federal property and the procurement by a federal agency of a U.S. flag unless it has been made in the United States.

Further, the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) must conduct a study that (1) assesses and describes the enforcement scheme for country-of-origin labeling for U.S. flags; (2) determines how many fines or penalties, if any, have been imposed for violations of such scheme; and (3) identifies the percentage of violations that are subsequent violations committed by an entity that has previously been found to have violated such scheme.

Additionally, the FTC must report to Congress the results of the study and any recommendations to improve the enforcement scheme and its deterrent effect.</summary>
</bill>
