<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="998" updated="2022-02-03T06:01:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3309" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-03-27T17:23:12-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000215"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  <description>Page 22, after line 24, insert the following (and redesignate the subsequent section accordingly):    SEC. 4. COMMUNICATIONS OF FIRST RESPONDERS.    Nothing in subsection (a) of section 13 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 2 of this Act, shall be construed to impede the Federal Communications Commission from acting in times of emergency to ensure the availability of efficient and effective communication systems for State and local first responders.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 10 printed in House Report 112-422 to express that nothing in this Act shall impede the FCC from providing efficient and effective communication systems for state and local first responders.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-03-27T17:23:12-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Eshoo amendment (A007) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:22:17-04:00">
      <text>Eshoo amendment (A007) modified by unanimous consent. Amendment inserts a new section regarding communications of first responders.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1624" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:21:45-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Eshoo.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1624" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1624" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:21:45-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A007) offered by Ms. Eshoo.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1624" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1624" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:23:12-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Eshoo amendment (A007) as modified Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:23:12-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
