<bill session="116" type="s" number="319" updated="2022-11-01T15:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the reproductive assistance provided by the Department of Defense and the Department of Veterans Affairs to severely wounded, ill, or injured members of the Armed Forces, veterans, and their spouses or partners, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2019-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2020-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2019-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2019-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2019-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2019-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="955" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-27T15:51:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Women Veterans and Families Health Services Act of 2019

This bill addresses fertility treatments, counseling, and other health-related programs for veterans and members of the Armed Forces.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide fertility treatments and counseling to covered veterans and active duty servicemembers or a spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate of such veteran or servicemember. A covered veteran or service member is a severely wounded, ill, or injured former or current member of the Armed Forces who has an infertility condition incurred or aggravated while serving on active duty.

DOD must establish procedures related to gamete retrieval and storage.

 Fertility counseling and treatment are included within authorized VA medical services.

The VA may pay the adoption expenses (for up to three adoptions) for a covered member who is enrolled in the VA health care system.

 The VA must facilitate specified reproduction and infertility research conducted collaboratively by DOD and the Department of Health and Human Services.

 The VA shall enhance the capabilities of the VA women veterans contact center to respond to assistance requests and refer such veterans to federal or community resources.

 The bill permanently extends and expands a VA pilot program related to group reintegration and readjustment services for certain women veterans.

 The bill provides child care assistance to qualified veterans receiving (1) mental health care services or intensive health care services, and (2) readjustment counseling and related mental health services.</summary>
</bill>
