<bill session="116" type="s" number="3736" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Increasing Access to SNAP Delivery During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Increasing Access to SNAP Delivery During COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase access to food delivery under the supplemental nutrition assistance program to address the Coronavirus Disease 2019, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2020-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2020-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6904" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-23T15:36:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Increasing Access to SNAP Delivery During COVID-19 Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to increase access to food delivery under the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program (SNAP, formerly known as the food stamp program) during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) national emergency.

Specifically, the bill

 requires USDA to notify authorized program retailers of existing opportunities through which they can deliver food to SNAP participants, including allowing an electronic benefit transfer card to be swiped on delivery of food to the home (with a mobile device); authorizes public-private partnerships between USDA, authorized program retailers, and community-based organizations to support food delivery, including through the use of private funds; provides funding, which USDA must use to reimburse certain retailers for the costs of delivering food to program participants who are seniors, immunocompromised individuals, or other individuals who are unable to travel safely to a program retailer; and requires each state to submit a plan that describes how it will coordinate with program retailers and community-based partners to expand delivery, administer reimbursements, and ensure retailers meet eligibility requirements. Authority for USDA to carry out the bill with respect to each state shall terminate on the later of (1) the date on which the national emergency declared by the President with respect to COVID-19 is terminated, and (2) the date on which the state emergency declared in such state with respect to COVID-19 is terminated.</summary>
</bill>
