<bill session="116" type="h" number="355" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:23Z">
  <state datetime="2019-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TRUST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to extend the basis for the denial of retirement credit, for service as a Member of Congress, to include conviction of any felony under Federal or State law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRUST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trust Returned to the United States Taxpayer Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-01-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-09T15:49:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Trust Returned to the United States Taxpayer Act or the TRUST Act This bill expands the types of felony convictions that result in the loss of creditable service as a Member of Congress under the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees Retirement System. Currently, certain felony convictions result in the loss of credit toward a federal retirement annuity for any time served as a Member of Congress. This bill makes any felony conviction under federal or state law result in the loss of credit toward a federal retirement annuity for any time served as a Member of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
