<bill session="108" type="h" number="4239" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Parents' Empowerment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide a civil action for a minor injured by exposure to an entertainment product containing material that is harmful to minors, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parents' Empowerment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000981"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000358" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000081" joined="2004-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Pornography"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Punitive damages"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Video games"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-13T18:26:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Parents' Empowerment Act - Authorizes a minor, through a person acting on the minor's behalf, to obtain relief in a civil action in U.S. district court against anyone who knowingly sells or distributes in interstate or foreign commerce an entertainment product containing material that is harmful to minors if: (1) a reasonable person would expect a substantial number of minors to be exposed to the material; and (2) the minor, as a result of exposure to that material, is likely to suffer personal or emotional injury or injury to mental or moral welfare. Provides for recovery of compensatory and punitive damages.

Declares it to be an affirmative defense to such action that an act of a parent or guardian who owned the entertainment product was the proximate cause of the minor's exposure to the harmful material.

Defines "material that is harmful to minors" as any pornographic communication, picture, image, graphic image file, article, recording, writing, or other pornographic matter of any kind that: (1) is obscene; or (2) violates specified community standards with respect to suitability for minors and lacks sufficient literary, artistic, political, or scientific value to overcome its pernicious effects.</summary>
</bill>
