<bill session="117" type="s" number="2875" updated="2023-08-23T22:00:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Cyber Incident Review Office in the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Cyber Incident Reporting Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cyber Incident Reporting Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Cyber Incident Reporting Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2021-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2021-10-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-13">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-249.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="633">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 633.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-23T21:53:26Z" status="Reported to Senate">Cyber Incident Reporting Act of 2021

This bill requires reporting and other actions to address cybersecurity incidents, including ransomware attacks.

Entities that own or operate critical infrastructure must report cyber incidents and ransom payments within specified time frames while other entities may voluntarily report incidents. The Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must establish an office to receive and analyze such reports.

The bill limits the use and disclosure of reported information. The information may be shared (subject to protections) with federal agencies or to address cybersecurity threats. However, shared information may not be used as a basis for certain regulatory enforcement. Additionally, an entity may not be liable for submitting required reports. Further, reports do not constitute waivers of applicable protections against disclosure (e.g., attorney-client privilege) and are not subject to laws governing release of federal records.

The bill authorizes CISA to take specified action (e.g., issuing subpoenas) if an entity fails to submit a required report. CISA may share subpoenaed information with a regulator or the Department of Justice for regulatory enforcement or criminal prosecution.

A federal agency must share any information it receives about cyber attacks with CISA.

The bill also establishes (1) an interagency council to standardize federal reporting of cybersecurity threats, (2) a task force on ransomware attacks, and (3) a pilot program to identify information systems vulnerable to ransomware attacks.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-249</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
