<bill session="117" type="h" number="4547" updated="2022-12-31T05:06:02Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to establish additional criteria for determining when employers may join together in a group or association of employers that will be treated as an employer under section 3(5) of such Act for purposes of sponsoring a group health plan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Association Health Plans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Association Health Plans Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001248" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000628" joined="2021-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001058" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001156" joined="2021-08-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000467" joined="2021-08-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2021-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="896" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8588" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-25T19:18:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Association Health Plans Act of 2021

This bill provides statutory authority for certain short-term, limited-duration health insurance plans and association health plans.

The bill permits short-term, limited-duration plans to provide coverage for a period of less than 12 months, not including extensions. Under current law, such plans are exempt from certain market requirements of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, such as coverage of individuals with preexisting conditions.

The bill further permits groups or associations of employers to sponsor fully insured group health plans as if they were employers. Such plans may not discriminate based on the health factors of any prospective plan participant for the purpose of granting an employer's membership in the association or determining a participant's eligibility for benefits or premium amounts.</summary>
</bill>
