<bill session="116" type="h" number="8458" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:51Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protections and Transparency in the Workplace Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protections and Transparency in the Workplace Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require public companies to provide sexual harassment claim disclosures in certain reports, to require public companies to implement mandatory sexual harassment training, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000582"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Retail and wholesale trades"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-04T19:47:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Protections and Transparency in the Workplace Act 

This bill requires issuers of securities to disclose regularly information related to claims of

 discrimination because of race, color, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), or national origin; discrimination because of age; discrimination on the basis of disability; discrimination because of genetic information; discrimination on the basis of status concerning service in a uniformed service; sexual harassment; and sexual assault or abuse. In investigating claims of discrimination or harassment, an issuer must hire an independent, third-party law firm agreed to by all parties involved.

Issuers must implement discrimination and harassment training programs for employees, conduct an annual survey of employees to determine whether employees feel safe, and establish an anonymous whistleblower tip line.</summary>
</bill>
