<bill session="116" type="h" number="4528" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:48Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To increase the participation of historically underrepresented demographic groups in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education and industry.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2578" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-25T03:28:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Women and Minorities in STEM Booster Act of 2019

 This bill requires the National Science Foundation to award competitive grants to enable eligible entities to carry out the activities specified below in order to increase the participation of women and underrepresented minorities in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (STEM).

 An eligible entity that receives a grant shall use grant funds to carry out one or more of the following activities designed to increase the participation of women or minorities underrepresented in science and engineering, or both:

 online workshops, mentoring programs that partner STEM professionals with students, internships for undergraduate and graduate students in STEM fields, outreach programs providing elementary and secondary school students with opportunities to increase their exposure to STEM fields, and programs to increase the recruitment and retention of underrepresented faculty.</summary>
</bill>
