<bill session="111" type="h" number="6099" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:40Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Automatic IRA Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand personal saving and retirement savings coverage by enabling employees not covered by qualifying retirement plans to save for retirement through automatic IRA arrangements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Automatic IRA Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000015"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001047" joined="2010-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2010-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000287" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001162" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2010-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1567-1568"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Ways and Means</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-11-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED02" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Health, Employment, Labor, and Pensions" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="3760" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-29T21:25:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Automatic IRA Act of 2010 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to: (1) require certain employers who do not maintain qualifying retirement plans or arrangements to make available to their eligible employees a payroll deposit individual retirement account (IRA) arrangement (automatic IRA arrangement) which grants such employees the right to opt-out of participation; (2) require the Secretary of the Treasury to provide employers with a model notice for notifying employees of their opportunity to participate in such an arrangement and to provide participants with an annual statement setting forth arrangement payments, earnings, value, and other specified information; (3) impose a penalty on employers who fail to provide eligible employees access to such an arrangement; (4) establish an Automatic IRA Advisory Group to make recommendations regarding investment options; (5) allow employers who do not have more than 100 employees a tax credit for costs associated with establishing an automatic IRA arrangement; and (6) increase the tax credit for small employer pension plan startup costs.

Requires the Secretary and the Secretary of Labor to jointly conduct feasibility studies on extending spousal consent requirements to automatic IRAs, promoting the use of low-cost lifetime income arrangements, and using investment data to notify individuals with multiple small balance retirement accounts of consolidation options.</summary>
</bill>
