<bill session="117" type="s" number="4685" updated="2023-03-09T17:45:31Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for financial services and general government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8254" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8294" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2617" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-03T14:36:06Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2023

This bill provides FY2023 appropriations for several federal departments and agencies, including

 the Department of the Treasury, the Executive Office of the President, the judiciary, the District of Columbia, and several independent agencies. The independent agencies funded in the bill include

 the Administrative Conference of the United States, the Barry Goldwater Scholarship and Excellence in Education Foundation, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Election Assistance Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Permitting Improvement Steering Council, the Federal Trade Commission, the General Services Administration, the Harry S. Truman Scholarship Foundation, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the Morris K. Udall and Stewart L. Udall Foundation, the National Archives and Records Administration, the National Credit Union Administration, the Office of Government Ethics, the Office of Personnel Management, the Office of Special Counsel, the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, the Public Buildings Reform Board, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Selective Service System, the Small Business Administration, the U.S. Postal Service, and the U.S. Tax Court. The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
</bill>
