<bill session="117" type="s" number="3270" updated="2022-12-30T02:48:56Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maritime Administration Reauthorization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Administration Reauthorization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Maritime Technological Advancement Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Sustainable Port Infrastructure Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reauthorize the Maritime Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4357" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-13T14:25:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maritime Administration Reauthorization Act of 2022

This bill revises provisions related to the Maritime Administration (MARAD).

Among other things, the bill

 reauthorizes MARAD programs, including programs associated with maintaining the U.S. Merchant Marine; sets aside funding to support the maritime environmental and technical assistance program of MARAD, including for activities related to technologies that support port and vessel air emissions reductions and to support zero emissions technologies; directs the Department of Transportation to develop and and deliver to Congress a strategy to assist state maritime academies and the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy to improve the representation of women and underrepresented communities in the next generation of the mariner workforce; authorizes MARAD to award maritime career training grants to eligible institutions (e.g., postsecondary educational institutions or postsecondary vocational institutions) for the purpose of developing, offering, or improving educational or career training programs for workers in the United States related to the maritime workforce; and addresses sexual harassment and sexual assault at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy and provides for greater diversity and inclusion at the academy and within the maritime transportation system workforce.</summary>
</bill>
