<bill session="111" type="h" number="4381" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:55Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">H-2B Program Reform Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the H-2B program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">H-2B Program Reform Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2009-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Judiciary</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-16">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-03-29T16:07:20Z" status="Introduced in House">H-2B Program Reform Act of 2009 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make any alien seeking to enter the United States as an H-2B visa (nonagricultural temporary/seasonal worker) inadmissible unless the Secretary of Labor (Secretary) certifies to the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Homeland Security (DHS) that: (1) there are not sufficient U.S. workers to perform such temporary labor or services; and (2) such alien's employment will not adversely affect similarly-employed U.S. workers' wages and working conditions.

Requires H-2B employers to file an application with the Secretary which shall include information regarding: (1) the numbers, occupational classifications, and employment locations of such nonimmigrants; (2) the recurring and temporary need for such labor and the inability to secure U.S. workers to meet such labor needs; and (3) instances of employment-related violations within the previous three years.

Limits labor contracting and construction entities registration eligibility.

 Directs the Secretary to set the number of H-2B visas each employer would be approved to use. Requires an employer to pay a $100 application fee and a $100 per-worker fee.

Sets forth: (1) labor certification application provisions; (2) H-2B and U.S. worker protections; and (3) penalties, including temporary program removal, for compliance failures. 

Establishes in the Treasury the Employment Certification Fee Account.

States that forest, conservation, and logging workers shall be considered: (1) H-2A nonimmigrant agricultural workers for employment purposes; and (2) seasonal agricultural workers under the Migrant Seasonal Worker Protection Act.</summary>
</bill>
