<bill session="111" type="h" number="5334" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:10Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rio Grande del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2010-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="874" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-26T13:47:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area Establishment Act - Establishes the Rio Grande Del Norte National Conservation Area in New Mexico, consisting of approximately 235,980 acres of public land in Taos and Rio Arriba Counties.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to ensure the protection of religious and cultural sites in the Conservation Area and to provide access to them by tribal members for traditional cultural and customary uses.

Requires the Secretary to develop a management plan for the Conservation Area.

Bars the changing of the management status of any area within the boundary of the Conservation Area that is: (1) designated as a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; or (2) managed as an area of critical environmental concern.

Designates the Cerro Del Yuta Wilderness and Rio San Antonio Wilderness as wilderness and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

Releases the public land within the San Antonio Wilderness Study Area not designated as wilderness from further study for designation as wilderness.

Requires the Conservation Area and the wilderness areas designated by this Act to be administered as components of the National Landscape Conservation System.</summary>
</bill>
