<bill session="116" type="h" number="4582" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:45Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Alaska, is and shall be recognized as an eligible Native village under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Alaska, is and shall be recognized as an eligible Native village under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Small towns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-01T22:37:39Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill recognizes the Alaska Native group corporation of Alexander Creek as an Alaska Native village corporation eligible for certain land and benefits.

Alexander Creek must file any amendments to its corporate charter that are necessary to convert from a Native group corporation to a Native village corporation.

The Department of the Interior must open negotiations with Alexander Creek to settle Alexander Creek's aboriginal land claims and any other claims it has against the United States.

Alexander Creek must notify its members that (1) they will cease to receive benefits from Cook Inlet Region Incorporated (CIRI) individually as at-large shareholders, and (2) all future resource payments from CIRI will be made to the village. CIRI is not liable under any state, federal, or local law for damages related to that payment cessation.</summary>
</bill>
