<bill session="119" type="s" number="39" updated="2025-11-19T04:34:18Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP MADURO Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing Timely Opportunities for Payment and Maximizing Awards for Detaining Unlawful Regime Officials Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP MADURO Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the maximum reward amount for information leading to the arrest and conviction of Nicolas Maduro Moros to $100,000,000, which shall be paid out by the Federal Government from all assets being withheld from Nicolas Maduro Moros, officials of the Maduro regime and their co-conspirators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001244" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000618" joined="2025-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="268" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-24T13:52:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing Timely Opportunities for Payment and Maximizing Awards for Detaining Unlawful Regime Officials Act of 2025 or the STOP MADURO Act

This bill authorizes the Department of State to pay a reward of up to $100 million for certain information directly leading to the arrest and conviction of Nicolas&#160;Maduro Moros.

For example,&#160;under the bill, the State Department may pay such a reward to one or more individuals who furnish information directly leading to Maduro's arrest and conviction in any country for specified narcotics-related offenses.

The bill also requires that any such payment come solely from the liquidation of assets that the U.S. President or the Department of the Treasury's Office of Foreign Assets Control has withheld pursuant to specified laws and executive orders from Maduro, officials of the Maduro regime, and their co-conspirators.</summary>
</bill>
