<bill session="117" type="h" number="966" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Save Voters Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 to prohibit a State from removing the name of any registrant from the official list of voters eligible to vote in elections for Federal office in the State unless the State verifies, on the basis of objective and reliable evidence, that the registrant is ineligible to vote in such elections.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Save Voters Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001281"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000486" joined="2021-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2093" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2747" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5746" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4886" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-07T18:09:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Save Voters Act 

This bill prohibits a state from removing registrants from the official list of eligible voters unless it meets certain verification and notice requirements.

Specifically, the bill prohibits a state from removing a registrant from the official list of eligible voters unless it verifies, on the basis of objective and reliable evidence, that the registrant is ineligible to vote in federal elections. Further, a state is prohibited from considering failure to vote in an election or failure to respond to a notice as evidence of ineligibility to vote.

Additionally, the bill requires a state to provide individual registrants who are removed with a notice, which must include the grounds for the removal and information on contesting the removal. Public notice must be provided after conducting any general program to remove the names of ineligible voters.</summary>
</bill>
