<bill session="117" type="h" number="2438" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice in Forensic Algorithms Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of trade secrets privileges to prevent defense access to evidence in criminal proceedings, provide for the establishment of Computational Forensic Algorithm Testing Standards and a Computational Forensic Algorithm Testing Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice in Forensic Algorithms Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2021-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets and economic espionage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-26T16:42:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice in Forensic Algorithms Act of 2021 This bill establishes a federal framework to govern the use of computational forensic software. The term computational forensic software means software that relies on an automated computational process to assess evidence in a criminal investigation (e.g., facial recognition technology).

The framework contains various elements, including the following:

 requirements for the establishment of testing standards and a testing program for computational forensic software, requirements for the use of computational forensic software by federal law enforcement agencies and related entities (e.g., crime labs), a ban on the use of trade secret evidentiary privilege to prevent federal criminal defendants from accessing evidence collected using computational forensic software or information about the software (e.g., source code), and limits on the admissibility of evidence collected using computational forensic software.</summary>
</bill>
