<bill session="111" type="s" number="785" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:25Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Southeast Alaska Timber Industry Retooling and Restructuring Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a grant program to encourage retooling of entities in the timber industry in Alaska, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Southeast Alaska Timber Industry Retooling and Restructuring Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4315-4316"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy and productivity"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-13T18:30:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Southeast Alaska Timber Industry Retooling and Restructuring Act - Establishes a two-year grant program for retooling projects that are designed to facilitate the economic adjustment of specified timber entities by allowing them to: (1) improve or alter their business and practices to become more competitive within the timber industry; or (2) shift to a type of business that is not related to the timber industry.

Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to provide grants under such program to any entity that operated in the timber industry in Alaska on January 1, 2009, that, prior to such date, operated in Alaska for not less than 10 years.

Sets forth provisions concerning eligible uses of grant funding.

Treats a grant recipient as a small business concern owned or controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals (as that term is defined in the Small Business Act) for three years after the grant was approved.</summary>
</bill>
