<bill session="117" type="h" number="7257" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Humanitarian Standards for Individuals in Customs and Border Protection Custody Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Humanitarian Standards for Individuals in Customs and Border Protection Custody Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require U.S. Customs and Border Protection to perform an initial health screening on detainees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Border Security, Facilitation, and Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight, Management, and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM11" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Border Security and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4096" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-28T18:35:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Humanitarian Standards for Individuals in Customs and Border Protection Custody Act

This bill imposes requirements and standards related to the care of aliens in U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) custody.

CBP must conduct an initial health screening of each individual in custody to identify those with acute conditions and high-risk vulnerabilities and to provide appropriate healthcare. CBP must conduct the screening within 12 hours of each&#160;individual's arrival at a CBP facility, and within 6 hours for certain priority individuals such as children and individuals with disabilities.

The bill imposes various requirements related to providing such screenings, such as providing interpreters, chaperones, and mental health treatment when necessary.

CBP must ensure detainees have access to drinking water, toilets, sanitation facilities, hygiene products, food, and shelter. The bill imposes certain standards relating to such requirements, such as the minimum amount of drinking water for each detainee and the acceptable temperature range of the shelters.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) must enter into memoranda of understanding with various government agencies to address instances when surge capacity is necessary.

The DHS Office of the Inspector General must conduct unannounced inspections of ports of entry, border patrol stations, and detention facilities and report the results to Congress. The Government Accountability Office must assess CBP's management of such facilities, whether CBP and DHS processes are in compliance with this bill's requirements, and the behavior of CBP personnel in carrying out this bill.

DHS shall publicly release on its website, on a quarterly basis, aggregate data on complaints of sexual abuse at CBP facilities.</summary>
</bill>
