<bill session="119" type="s" number="253" updated="2025-03-03T19:24:39Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Abortion Is Not Health Care Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Abortion Is Not Health Care Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that amounts paid for an abortion are not taken into account for purposes of the deduction for medical expenses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001299" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2025-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2025-01-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="73" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-03T19:23:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Abortion Is Not Health Care Act of 2025

This bill excludes amounts paid for an abortion from the itemized tax deduction for qualified medical and dental expenses, subject to exceptions.&#160;

Under current law, individuals who itemize their tax deductions may deduct qualified medical and dental expenses to the extent that such expenses exceed 7.5% of the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s adjusted gross income for the tax year. Further, under current law, the calculation of the itemized tax deduction for medical and dental expenses may include amounts paid for a legal abortion.

Under the bill, amounts paid for an abortion may not be claimed as part of the itemized deduction for medical and dental expenses. However, under the bill, amounts paid for an abortion may be included in the itemized deduction for medical and dental expenses if (1) the pregnancy is the result of rape or incest; or (2) a woman is suffering from a physical disorder, injury, or illness (including a life-endangering&#160;physical condition caused by or arising from&#160;the pregnancy itself) that&#160;would, as certified by a physician,&#160;place the woman in danger of death if an abortion were not performed.</summary>
</bill>
