<bill session="109" type="s" number="1274" updated="2018-02-03T21:25:00Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improve Interoperable Communications for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Improve Interoperable Communications for First Responders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen Federal leadership, provide grants, enhance outreach and guidance, and provide other support to State and local officials to achieve communications inter-operability, to foster improved regional collaboration and coordination, to promote more efficient utilization of funding devoted to public safety communications, to promote research and development for first responder communications, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000304"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2005-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6911-6912"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6912-6915" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-27T22:45:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improve Interoperable Communications for First Responders Act of 2005 - Establishes an Office for Interoperability and Compatibility (OIC), headed by a Director, within the Directorate of Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Requires the OIC Director to: (1) assist the Secretary in developing and implementing the program to enhance public safety interoperable communications at all levels of government; (2) carry out DHS responsibilities and authorities relating to the SAFECOM Program; and (3) conduct extensive, nationwide outreach and foster the development of interoperable communications systems by state, local, and tribal governments and public safety agencies, and by regional consortia thereof.

Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary to conduct a nationwide assessment to determine the degree to which communications interoperability has been achieved to date, and to ascertain the needs that remain for interoperability to be achieved.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a comprehensive research and development program to promote communications interoperability among first responders; and (2) make grants to states and eligible regions for initiatives necessary to achieve short-tern or long-term solutions to statewide, regional, national, and where appropriate, international interoperability.</summary>
</bill>
