<bill session="108" type="h" number="4170" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-19T15:25:24-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-07-19T15:25:24-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to recruit volunteers to assist with, or facilitate, the activities of various agencies and offices of the Department of the Interior.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000419"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-613.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-19" calendar="Union" number="372">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 372.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:22:05-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Hayworth moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:22:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5942-5943" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:22:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4170.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-07-19T15:25:24-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H5942" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-19T15:25:27-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Employee selection"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Geology"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Ocean mining"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Surveying"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-07T20:50:24Z" status="Passed House amended">Department of the Interior Volunteer Recruitment Act of 2004 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to recruit, train, and accept, without regard to the civil service classification laws, rules, or regulations, the services of individuals, contributed without compensation as volunteers, for aiding in or facilitating the activities administered by the Secretary through the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the U.S. Geological Survey, the Bureau of Reclamation, and the Office of the Secretary.

Prohibits: (1) the Secretary, in accepting such services of individuals as volunteers, from permitting the use of such volunteers in law enforcement work, in regulatory and enforcement work, in policy-making processes, or to displace any employee; and (2) volunteer services authorized by this Act from being conducted on private property unless the officer or employee charged with supervising the volunteer obtains appropriate consent to enter the property from the property owner. Authorizes the Secretary to accept the services of individuals in hazardous duty only upon a determination by the Secretary that such individuals are skilled in performing hazardous activities. Directs the Secretary to ensure that an appropriate U.S. officer or employee provides adequate and appropriate supervision of each volunteer whose services the Secretary accepts.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide for services and costs incidental to the utilization of volunteers. Provides that a volunteer shall not be deemed a Federal employee and shall not be subject to Federal employment law including those provisions relating to hours of work, rates of compensation, leave, unemployment compensation, and Federal employee benefits. Provides for volunteers under this Act to be subject to the provisions of Federal criminal law concerning bribery, graft, and conflicts of interest, except under certain conditions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-613</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
