<bill session="116" type="h" number="8149" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VA Precision Medicine Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VA Precision Medicine Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out an initiative to identify and validate brain and mental health biomarkers among veterans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2020-09-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001209" joined="2020-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-10">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="785" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-30T18:09:15Z" status="Introduced in House">VA Precision Medicine Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement the Precision Medicine for Veterans Initiative to identify and validate brain and mental health biomarkers among veterans, with specific consideration for depression, anxiety, post-traumatic stress disorder, bipolar disorder, and traumatic brain injury.

The VA must develop data privacy and security measures to ensure the information of veterans participating in the initiative is kept private and secure. Additionally, the VA must make de-identified data collected under the initiative available for research purposes both within and outside of the VA. Data collected under the initiative may not be sold.

The VA must also assess the feasibility and advisability of coordinating efforts of the initiative with the Million Veterans Program.</summary>
</bill>
