<bill session="116" type="s" number="2518" updated="2022-11-01T13:49:56Z">
  <state datetime="2019-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Economic Infrastructure Equity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Economic Infrastructure Equity Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to establish an Assistant Secretary for Rural Economic Investment and an Office of Rural Economic Investment, to ensure that rural communities are adequately represented in Federal decisionmaking for transportation policy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2019-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-09-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5606-5607" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-10T16:45:30Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Economic Infrastructure Equity Act of 2019

This bill revises existing rural infrastructure functions within the Department of Transportation (DOT) by creating an Assistant Secretary for Rural Economic Investment and an Office of Rural Economic Investment.

Specifically, the bill

 sets forth the duties of the Assistant Secretary for Rural Economic Investment and the mission and goals of the Office of Rural Economic Investment, including to improve coordination of DOT policies, programs, and activities in a manner that expands economic development in rural communities and regions; provides for a rural stakeholder consultation process during the development of any regulation, guidance, or policy that would have substantial direct effects on one or more rural areas; and establishes a rural transportation advisory council to consult with and advise the Office of Rural Economic Investment.</summary>
</bill>
