<bill session="117" type="h" number="7542" updated="2022-12-29T23:18:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-04-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Congressional Accountability Act Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Accountability Act Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Congressional Accountability Act of 1995 to require Members of Congress to reimburse the Treasury for amounts paid as settlements and awards under such Act in all cases of employment discrimination acts committed personally by Members, to permit individuals who file claims under such Act to file an amended claim if the preliminary review of the individual's claim by a hearing officer includes the determination that the individual filing the claim is not a covered employee under such Act or has not stated a claim for which relief may be granted under title IV of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001286" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2022-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2022-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2022-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001205" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000040" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2022-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-29T19:33:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Congressional Accountability Act Enhancement Act

This bill extends the liability of Members of Congress for employment discrimination settlements and awards and expands certain employment protections for congressional employees.

Current law requires that a Member who commits an act of harassment in violation of employment-based civil rights protections must reimburse the Treasury for amounts paid as settlements or awards resulting from the act. This bill also requires that Members reimburse the Treasury for amounts paid resulting from any unlawful discrimination and related retaliation.

Additionally, the bill grants congressional employees a 10-day period to amend a filing alleging employment discrimination if the hearing officer determines the initial filing failed to state a claim for which relief could be granted.

The bill also allows the Office of Employee Advocacy to continue to assist a congressional employee with investigations and proceedings related to a claim of workplace discrimination even after the employee begins federal court proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
