<bill session="118" type="h" number="4600" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:09Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Retail Investors&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Savings Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Retail Investors&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 to specify requirements concerning the consideration of pecuniary and non-pecuniary factors, to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to conduct a study on climate change and other environmental disclosures in the municipal bond market, and to require the Securities and Exchange Commission to conduct a study on the solicitation of municipal securities business.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4767" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-03T19:23:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Retail Investors' Savings Act 

This bill further defines the best interest of a customer for purposes of the standard of conduct for all brokers, dealers, and investment advisers. Currently, these professionals must act in the best interest of the customer without regard to the financial or other interests of the professional providing the advice. The bill adds that the best interest standard must be based on pecuniary factors (i.e., a factor that a fiduciary determines will have a material effect on an investment's performance) unless the customer otherwise directs.

In addition, the Securities and Exchange Commission must report on (1) municipal bond disclosures regarding climate change and environmental matters, and (2) the effectiveness of specified rules in preventing the payment of government officials or candidates in exchange for government business in connection with the sale or offer of municipal securities.</summary>
</bill>
