<bill session="116" type="h" number="5422" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Modernizing Agricultural and Manufacturing Bonds Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify certain rules applicable to qualified small issue manufacturing bonds, to expand certain exceptions to the private activity bond rules for first-time farmers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Modernizing Agricultural and Manufacturing Bonds Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000096" joined="2020-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2019-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5007" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agricultural equipment and machinery"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-08T15:03:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Modernizing Agricultural and Manufacturing Bonds Act

This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code, with respect to qualified small issue bonds for manufacturing purposes, to expand the definition of "manufacturing facility" to include a facility that (1) is used in the creation or production of intangible property; or (2) is functionally related, subordinate to, and located on the same site as a facility used in the manufacturing or production of tangible or intangible personal property. The bill also increases from $10 million to $30 million the maximum bond size limitation.

The bill also modifies requirements for private activity bond financing for first-time farmers. The modified provisions (1) increase from $450,000 to $552,500 (adjusted annually for inflation) the amount of bond proceeds that may be used by a first-time farmer to acquire land for farming purposes, (2) repeal the separate dollar limitation on the use of bond proceeds for used farm equipment, and (3) modify the definition of "substantial farmland" to determine farm size by reference to the average (instead of median) size of a farm in the county in which the farm is located.</summary>
</bill>
