<bill session="117" type="s" number="303" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Essential Transportation Employee Safety Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Transportation to support the efforts of State and local governments to provide for priority testing of certain transportation workers with respect to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID-19) and require the owners and operators of equipment and facilities used by passenger or freight transportation employers to clean, disinfect, and sanitize that equipment and provide personal protective equipment to certain employees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Essential Transportation Employee Safety Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2021-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2021-02-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-19T13:05:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Essential Transportation Employee Safety Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to support the efforts of state and local governments to prioritize COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) testing of transportation workers who are categorized as essential critical infrastructure workers. Essential critical infrastructure employees include those who work in industries such as medical and health care, telecommunications, information technology systems, defense, food and agriculture, transportation and logistics, energy, water and wastewater, law enforcement, and public works.

Additionally, during the COVID-19 pandemic, DOT must require (1) the owners and operators of equipment or facilities used by passenger or freight transportation employers to implement personal protective equipment and disinfection and sanitization procedures; and (2) an air carrier to submit to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) a proposal to permit pilots to wear masks or protective face coverings in the flight deck, including a safety risk assessment with respect to such proposal.

The bill sets forth requirements for owners or operators who cannot acquire necessary personal protective equipment due to market unavailability.

For the duration of the COVID-19 national emergency, the FAA must (1) provide certain employees, including air traffic controllers and airway transportation systems specialists, with personal protective and sanitizing equipment; (2) ensure that air traffic control facilities are cleaned, disinfected, and sanitized frequently; and (3) ensure its contractors provide their employees with personal protective equipment.</summary>
</bill>
