<bill session="110" type="h" number="5530" updated="2021-09-29T17:04:20Z">
  <state datetime="2008-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Government Homeland Security Coordination and Integration Act</title>
    <title type="display">Tribal Government Homeland Security Coordination and Integration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To ensure the coordination and integration of Indian tribes in the National Homeland Security strategy and to establish an Office of Tribal Government Homeland Security within the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2008-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Management, Investigations, and Oversight.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM09" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Oversight, Investigations, and Accountability" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear terrorism"/>
    <term name="Paramedical personnel"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-03T18:15:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal Government Homeland Security Coordination and Integration Act - Establishes the Office of Tribal Government Homeland Security (Office) within the Department of Homeland Security (DHS). Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security to appoint a Director to head the Office.

Prescribes the Secretary's and the Director's duties of coordination, infrastructure and equipment readiness, training, and inclusion of Indian tribes in homeland security preparedness.

Requires the Secretary to treat Indian tribes as states, as appropriate, for the purpose of homeland security. Authorizes the Secretary to delegate to Indian tribes primary responsibility for homeland security activities within their respective jurisdictions. Requires the Secretary to integrate the roles of the Bureau of Indian Affairs and Indian Health Services with regard to homeland security.

Requires the Secretary to provide assistance to enhance information technology capabilities of tribes and ensure the participation of Indian tribes in the coordination with governments and the private sector as related to homeland security activities.

Declares Indian tribes to be eligible to apply for, receive, direct, and supervise any homeland security-related federal grant program.

Authorizes the Secretary to award grants to Indian tribes for specified homeland security purposes.

Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide Indian tribes with technical assistance in developing, implementing, and managing emergency response plans; (2) ensure that DHS expertise and legal, financial, or technical assistance programs are made available to Indian tribes; and (3) facilitate cooperation with the heads of appropriate federal agencies working on homeland security initiatives.</summary>
</bill>
