<bill session="117" type="h" number="5912" updated="2023-09-01T12:31:37Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Close the ILC Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Close the ILC Loophole Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform the regulation of industrial loan companies and their parent companies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2022-01-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2022-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2022-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 28 - 25.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-06T14:39:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Close the ILC Loophole Act 

This bill limits the exemption from certain banking regulations applicable to industrial loan companies to those companies approved to receive Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation insurance before September 23, 2021, or companies with an application pending as of September 23, 2021. Industrial loan companies are state chartered institutions that provide several services similar to banks, such as originating loans and processing payments.

Parent companies of such industrial loan companies are subject to the supervision of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System.

The bill also sets forth procedures regarding a change in control of an industrial loan company.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the effects of industrial loan companies, industrial banks, and other similar institutions on the economy, including the effect on competitiveness, market structure, and different industries.</summary>
</bill>
