<bill session="117" type="h" number="548" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Labor to make a determination on whether to approve an occupation as an apprenticeable occupation in a timely manner, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2021-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="447" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-26T19:02:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Fast Track Advanced Apprenticeships Now Act

This bill requires the Department of Labor to make a determination on whether to approve an application for certain occupations as apprenticeable occupations within 45 days after its receipt or else provide the applicant with a written explanation for the delay and offer an estimated timeline for a determination within 90 days after the explanation.

Furthermore, Labor must convene&#8212;on an ongoing basis and take into consideration recommendations of the National Advisory Committee on Apprenticeships&#8212;certain industry sector leaders and experts to establish or update specific frameworks of industry-recognized occupational standards for current and potential apprenticeable occupations that (1) meet federal regulations governing safety and health standards and equal employment opportunity in apprenticeships; and (2) describe program scope and length, related instructions, on-the-job training, recognized postsecondary credentials, and competencies, and relevant timelines for review of such frameworks.</summary>
</bill>
