<bill session="112" type="h" number="3816" updated="2022-03-02T15:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2012-01-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-01-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pilot's Bill of Rights</title>
    <title type="display">Pilot's Bill of Rights</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to provide rights for pilots, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000546"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000652" joined="2012-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2012-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2012-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001051" joined="2012-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001053" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001059" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000290" joined="2012-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2012-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2012-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000602" joined="2012-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2012-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1335" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="3268" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB)"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-02-06T21:57:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Pilot's Bill of Rights - Requires National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) proceedings for the review of decisions of the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to deny, amend, modify, suspend, or revoke an airman's certificate to be conducted, to the extent practicable, in accordance with the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure and Federal Rules of Evidence.

Requires the Administrator to: (1) advise the subject of an investigation involving the approval, denial, suspension, modification, or revocation of an airman certificate of specified information pertinent to the investigation; and (2) provide him or her with access to relevant air traffic data.

Allows an individual to elect to file an appeal of a certificate denial, a punitive civil action, or an emergency order of revocation in the U.S. district court in which individual resides, in which the action in question occurred, or the district court for the District of Columbia. Allows an adversely affected individual who elects not to file an appeal in a federal district court to file such appeal with the NTSB.

Directs the Administrator to begin a Notice to Airmen (NOTAM) Improvement Program to improve the system of providing airmen with pertinent and timely information before a flight in the national airspace system.

Makes Flight Service Station briefings and other air traffic services performed by any government contractor available to airmen under the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA).

Requires the Administrator to review the FAA system for the medical certification of airmen in order to: (1) revise the medical application form, (2) align medical qualification policies with present-day qualified medical judgment and practices, and (3) publish objective medical standards to advise the public of the criteria determining an airman's medical certificate eligibility.</summary>
</bill>
