<bill session="108" type="s" number="3028" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:29Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-21">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to provide authority for the Attorney General to authorize the export of controlled substances from the United States to another country for subsequent export from that country to a second country, if certain conditions and safeguards are satisfied.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000338"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000444" joined="2004-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11840-11842" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR 11/20/2004 S11842" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24T14:03:36-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-12-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4882" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Psychotropic drugs"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-11T14:02:37Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Controlled Substances Export Reform Act of 2004 - Amends the Controlled Substances Import and Export Act to authorize the Attorney General to allow any controlled substance that is in schedule I or II or that is a narcotic drug in schedule III or IV to be exported from the United States to a country (first country) for subsequent export to another country (second country) if: (1) both such countries are parties to the Single Convention on Narcotic Drugs, 1961, and the Convention on Psychotropic Substances, 1971; (2) each of such countries has maintained an adequate system of substance import controls; (3) the substance is consigned to a holder of permits or licenses required under the first country's laws and a permit to import the substance has been issued; (4) substantial evidence that the substance is to be consigned to a permit holder as required under the second country's laws is furnished, a permit to import it is to be issued, the substance is to be applied exclusively to legitimate uses within that country, and it will not be re-exported; (5) within 30 days after export from the first country, the person who exported it from the United States certifies that re-export has occurred; and (6) the Attorney General has issued a permit to export the substance from the United States.</summary>
</bill>
