<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="866" updated="2022-02-25T17:33:56Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2838" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-11-15T14:16:27-05:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000596"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-11-15"/>
  <description>Amendment Sought to clarify the application of the Passenger Vessel Services Act to vessels operating in Puerto Rico that are not otherwise qualified to transport passengers for hire and that are more than 100 gross tons. Would allow such vessels to transport passengers between ports in Puerto Rico--a non-contiguous jurisdiction of multiple islands.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 15 printed in House Report 112-267 to clarify the application of the Passenger Vessel Services Act to vessels operating in Puerto Rico that are not otherwise qualified to transport passengers for hire and that are more than 100 gross tons. Would allow such vessels to transport passengers between ports in Puerto Rico--a non-contiguous jurisdiction of multiple islands.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-11-15T14:16:27-05:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="840">
      <text>On agreeing to the Pierluisi amendment (A011) Agreed to by recorded vote: 322 - 100 (Roll no. 840).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15T13:42:04-05:00">
      <text>Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Pierluisi.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7605-7606, H7606-7607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15T14:16:27-05:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15T14:16:27-05:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15T13:42:04-05:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A011) offered by Mr. Pierluisi.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7605-7606, H7606-7607" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7605" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15T14:16:27-05:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Pierluisi amendment (A011) Agreed to by recorded vote: 322 - 100 (Roll no. 840).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-11-15">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
