<bill session="112" type="h" number="2172" updated="2022-03-02T05:20:15Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Utilizing America's Federal Lands for Wind Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utilizing America's Federal Lands for Wind Energy Act</title>
    <title type="display">Utilizing America's Federal Lands for Wind Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate the development of wind energy resources on Federal lands.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000461" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000329" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000573" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000564" joined="2011-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000574" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001177" joined="2011-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001186" joined="2011-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2011-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Energy, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 112-300, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-12-01">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2011-12-01" calendar="Union" number="200">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 200.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="h" number="2173" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2013-04-01T19:18:44Z" status="Reported to House amended, Part I">Utilizing America's Federal Lands for Wind Energy Act - Exempts projects determined by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) or the Forest Service to be meteorological site testing and monitoring projects from environmental impact statement requirements under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA).

Defines a "meteorological site testing and monitoring project" as a project that is carried out on land administered by BLM or the Forest Service to test or monitor weather using towers or other devices, that is decommissioned within five years of its commencement, that provides meteorological information to such agencies, that causes less than one acre of soil or vegetation disruption at the location of each meteorological tower or other device and no more than five acres of soil or disruption within the proposed right-of-way for the project, and that is installed: (1) using existing access roads, (2) in a manner that does not require off-road motorized access other than one installation activity and one decommissioning activity along an identified off-road route approved by the BLM Director or the Chief of the Forest Service, (3) without construction of new roads other than upgrading of existing minor drainage crossings for safety purposes, and (4) without the use of digging or drilling equipment vehicles other than rubber-tired vehicles with gross weight ratings under 8,500 pounds.

Requires the BLM Director or Chief of the Forest Service: (1) to decide whether to issue a permit for such a project within 30 days after receiving an application for such permit; (2) during such period, to provide an opportunity for public comments and to consult with the heads of agencies that would be affected by issuance of the permit; and (3) to provide&#160;to&#160;the applicant reasons why an application is denied and an opportunity to remedy any deficiencies.

 Requires BLM and the Forest Service to treat the meteorological information provided under this Act as proprietary information and to protect it against disclosure.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 112-300</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
