<bill session="109" type="s" number="1084" updated="2018-02-03T21:05:52Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-19">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Child Poverty Act</title>
    <title type="display">End Child Poverty Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to eliminate child poverty, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2005-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2005-05-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5539"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-05-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="110">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 110.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2504" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wealth tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-17T15:44:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Child Poverty Act - Establishes the Child Poverty Elimination Board to develop a plan for: (1) cutting child poverty in half within a decade; and (2) eliminating child poverty entirely as soon as possible. Requires the plan to include recommendations for allocations from a Child Poverty Elimination Trust Fund. Directs the President to review the Board's plan, issue a plan which is the same as the Board's except where there is good cause for a modification that would be more effective, ensure plan implementation, and work with Congress to insure funding of plan implementation.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code to establish the Child Poverty Elimination Trust Fund. Transfers to such Fund an amount equal to revenue from a surtax which increases by one percent the tax imposed on that portion of adjusted gross income that exceeds the threshold amount of: (1) $1 million in the case of a joint return; or (2) $500,000 in the case of any other individual income tax return.</summary>
</bill>
