<bill session="116" type="s" number="4507" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GET CARE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GET CARE Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Getting Early Treatment and Comprehensive Assessments Reduces Emergencies Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a national campaign to raise awareness of the importance of seeking preventive health services and the utilization of such services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001184" joined="2020-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-22T22:17:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Getting Early Treatment and Comprehensive Assessments Reduces Emergencies Act of 2020 or the GET CARE Act of 2020

This bill directs the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) to undertake actions to increase the number of individuals seeking recommended preventive care services, particularly during the COVID-19 (i.e, coronavirus disease 2019) pandemic. It also authorizes the Department of Health and Human Services to award grants to states, other jurisdictions, and certain nonprofits for activities and research related to preventive care services.

Specifically, the CDC must award competitive grants to carry out a national campaign to increase awareness of, and disseminate information about, preventive care services. In carrying out the campaign, the CDC must consult with relevant public health and health care experts.

The campaign must focus particularly on medically underserved communities, communities of color, and communities disproportionately affected by COVID-19. It must address, among other topics, misinformation about seeking preventive care during the COVID-19 emergency and the safety of health care facilities.</summary>
</bill>
