<bill session="116" type="h" number="7725" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PARENTS Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PARENTS Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Adequate Resources to Enhance Needed Time with Sons and Daughters Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend part D of title IV of the Social Security Act to allow States to use incentive payments available under the child support enforcement program to improve parent-child relationships, increase child support collections, and improve outcomes for children by supporting parenting time agreements for noncustodial parents in uncontested agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001160"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2020-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000597" joined="2020-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3283" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="3325" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Separation, divorce, custody, support"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-14T20:28:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Providing Adequate Resources to Enhance Needed Time with Sons and Daughters Act of 2020 or the PARENTS Act of 2020

This bill expands the use of federal incentive payments to states under the Child Support Enforcement Program to include establishing agreements for how much time a child spends with each parent as agreed to by the parents under a child support or medical support order. Generally, the incentive payments program provides funding based on a state's performance measures related to (1) establishing paternity, (2) the number of cases with child support orders in place, (3) the collection of current and past-due support payments, and (4) cost-effectiveness.</summary>
</bill>
