<bill session="116" type="s" number="4627" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:44Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FEMA Assistance Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FEMA Assistance Relief Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the Federal cost share of certain emergency assistance provided under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, to modify the activities eligible for assistance under the emergency declaration issued by the President on March 13, 2020, relating to COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2020-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="925" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6669" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8406" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8266" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4800" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-07T15:44:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">FEMA Assistance Relief Act of 2020

This bill modifies the federal cost share of certain emergency assistance relating to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill provides for (1) a 100% federal cost share of assistance provided under the emergency declaration issued by the President on March 13, 2020, relating to COVID-19 and any subsequent major disaster declaration that supersedes it; and (2) at least a 90% federal cost share of assistance provided for any emergency or major disaster declared by the President from January 1-December 31, 2020.

With respect to the emergency declaration issued on March 13, 2020, the President may provide assistance for activities, costs, and purchases of states or local governments or the owners or operators of eligible private nonprofits, including, among other things

 backfill costs for first responders and other essential employees who are ill or quarantined; increased operating costs for essential government services due to such emergency; costs associated with maintaining alternate care facilities or related facilities currently inactive but related to future needs tied to the ongoing pandemic event; personal protective equipment and other critical supplies and services for first responders and other essential employees; and costs of procuring and distributing food to individuals affected by the pandemic through networks established by state, local, or tribal governments or other organizations.</summary>
</bill>
