<bill session="117" type="h" number="1437" updated="2023-09-05T17:28:33Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-16">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Further Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 to direct the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to provide comprehensive and regularly updated Federal precipitation information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="enacted">Making further continuing appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short">Further Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Further Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">PRECIP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">United States Parole Commission Further Extension Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001207"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2022-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2022-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001111" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000380" joined="2021-11-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2021-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2021-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001186" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2021-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2021-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000515" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2021-11-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000826" joined="2021-11-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environment Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 117-304.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-05-03" calendar="Union" number="224">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 224.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10T15:13:37-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Stevens moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10T15:13:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4736-4738" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10T15:13:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1437.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-10T15:21:58-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T16:20:27-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4834-4835" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="154" datetime="2022-05-11T16:31:03-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 333 - 81 (Roll no. 154).</text>
      <reference ref="05/10/2022 CR H4736-4737" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T16:31:04-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-12">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6769-6770" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2022-11-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6769-6770" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-11-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T14:44:53-05:00">
      <text>Ms. DeLauro moved that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T14:44:54-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1518, Ms. DeLauro called up H.R. 1437 and moved that the House agree to the Senate amendment with an amendment.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9811, H9813-9815" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T14:45:37-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T14:53:18-05:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T14:53:26-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437, the Chair put the question on concurring the in the Senate amendment with an amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Granger demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on concurring in the Senate amendment with an amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T19:19:08-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9839-9840" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="pingpong" roll="523" datetime="2022-12-14T20:11:15-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion that the House agree with an amendment to the Senate amendment Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 224 - 201 (Roll No. 523).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9811-9813" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14T20:11:16-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and at desk: House amendment to Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 75 - 20. Record Vote Number: 393.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7219-7226, S7237-7242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7220"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6534) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7220"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to refer to Senate Committee on Appropriations the House message to accompany H.R. 1437 with instructions to report back forthwith with the following amendment (SA 6536) made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Lee to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6541 as modified) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7238"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Scott of Florida to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6540) made in Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7240"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Scott of Florida to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6540) under the order of 12/15/22, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was not agreed to by Yea-Nay Vote. 45 - 47. Record Vote Number: 397.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Lee to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6541 as modified) was not agreed to by Yea-Nay Vote. 35 - 56. Record Vote Number: 398.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to refer to Senate Committee on Appropriations the House message to accompany H.R. 1437 with instructions to report back forthwith with the following amendment (SA 6536) withdrawn in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7220" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Motion by Senator Schumer to concur in the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 with an amendment (SA 6534) withdrawn in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Senate agreed, under the order of 12/15/22, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, to the House amendment to the Senate amendment to H.R. 1437 by Yea-Nay Vote. 71 - 19. Record Vote Number: 399.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-16">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2022-12-16" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-229" type="public" datetime="2022-12-16">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-229.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY18" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Environment" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3053" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="hc" number="123" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s6541"/>
    <amendment number="s6540"/>
    <amendment number="s6538"/>
    <amendment number="s6537"/>
    <amendment number="s6536"/>
    <amendment number="s6535"/>
    <amendment number="s6534"/>
    <amendment number="s6485"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-01-04T18:44:07Z" status="Public Law">Further Continuing Appropriations and Extensions Act, 2023 

This act provides continuing FY2023 appropriations for federal agencies through December 23, 2022, and extends several expiring programs and authorities. (Unless otherwise specified, the extensions referred to in this summary are also effective through December 23, 2022.) The act also requires the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to develop guidance and take other actions to update precipitation estimates. (Sec. 3) This section provides that references to this Act included in any division of this act refer only to the provisions of the division unless the act expressly provides otherwise. (Sec. 4) This section provides appropriations for a payment to Colette Wallace McEachin, the beneficiary of the late Representative Aston Donald McEachin. (A gratuity equal to one year's salary has long been given to the heirs or beneficiaries of Members of Congress who die in office.) DIVISION A--FURTHER CONTINUING APPROPRIATIONS ACT, 2023 Further Continuing Appropriations Act, 2023 This division provides continuing FY2023 appropriations to federal agencies through the earlier of December 23, 2022, or the enactment of the applicable appropriations act. It is known as a continuing resolution (CR) and prevents a government shutdown that would otherwise occur if the FY2023 appropriations bills have not been enacted when the existing CR expires on December 16, 2022. The CR funds most programs and activities at the FY2022 levels. It also extends several exceptions that provide funding flexibility or additional appropriations for various programs. The division also extends the Department of Homeland Security's federal intrusion detection and prevention system and a related reporting requirement. DIVISION B--OTHER MATTERS TITLE I--EXTENSIONS (Sec. 101) This section extends the authority of the Federal Communications Commission to conduct auctions for electromagnetic spectrum licenses. (Sec. 102) This section extends a special assessment on nonindigent persons or entities convicted of certain offenses involving sexual abuse or human trafficking. The assessment funds programs for human-trafficking survivors. United States Parole Commission Further Extension Act of 2022 (Sec. 103) This section extends the U.S. Parole Commission. (Sec. 104) This section extends the Commodity Futures Trading Commission Customer Protection Fund expenses account. TITLE II--BUDGETARY EFFECTS This title exempts the budgetary effects of this division and each succeeding division from (1) the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010 (PAYGO), (2) the Senate PAYGO rule, and (3) certain budget scorekeeping rules. DIVISION C--HEALTH AND HUMAN SERVICES TITLE I--MEDICARE AND MEDICAID (Sec. 101) This section extends certain increased payment adjustments for low-volume hospitals under Medicare's inpatient prospective payment system. (Sec. 102) This section extends the Medicare-Dependent Hospital Program, which provides additional payments to certain small rural hospitals that have a high proportion of Medicare patients. (Sec. 103) This section extends the increased Medicaid federal matching rate (also known as the Federal Medical Assistance Percentage) for U.S. territories. (Sec. 104) This section decreases funding for the Medicare Improvement Fund. TITLE II--HUMAN SERVICES (Sec. 201) This section extends and provides additional funding for the Maternal, Infant, and Early Childhood Home Visiting Program, which supports pregnant individuals and parents of young children in certain communities through home visits and partnerships with health, social service, and child development professionals. (Sec. 202) This section extends and provides additional funding for the Stephanie Tubbs Jones Child Welfare Services Program and the MaryLee Allen Promoting Safe and Stable Families Program (i.e., Title IV-B child and family services programs). TITLE III--EXTENSION OF FDA AUTHORIZATIONS (Sec. 301) This section reauthorizes the Critical Path Public-Private Partnerships, through which the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) may enter into collaborative agreements with eligible entities to develop projects designed to achieve certain goals, such as fostering medical product innovation and accelerating medical product development. (Sec. 302) This section reauthorizes a National Institutes of Health program to (1) develop and publish a priority list of needs in pediatric therapeutics, and (2) award funds to entities with expertise in conducting research regarding such needs. (Sec. 303) This section reauthorizes through December 24, 2022, the humanitarian device exemption program, which authorizes the FDA to, for the purposes of an application for approval to market a medical device, waive certain effectiveness requirements for an eligible device designed to treat or diagnose a disease or condition that affects no more than 8,000 individuals in the United States. Specifically, a request for such an exemption must be submitted on or before December 24, 2022. (Sec. 304) This section reauthorizes a program that provides grants or contracts to nonprofit consortia for demonstration projects to promote pediatric device development. (Sec. 305) This section reauthorizes until December 24, 2022, a provision that allows an applicant for market approval for an eligible single-enantiomer drug to make an election that may qualify the drug for a five-year market exclusivity period. (Sec. 306) This section extends through December 24, 2022, a provision requiring the FDA to accredit persons to inspect facilities that manufacture certain classes of medical devices. (Sec. 307) This section reauthorizes an FDA program that provides grants to defray the costs of developing drugs, medical devices, and medical foods for rare diseases or conditions. (Sec. 308) This section reauthorizes a provision requiring the FDA to post on its website quarterly reports with information on received generic drug applications and priority review applications. (Sec. 309) This section reauthorizes through December 24, 2022, a program that allows accredited persons to review reports and make recommendations to the FDA pertaining to the initial classification of medical devices. TITLE IV--INDIAN HEALTH This title extends until December 24, 2022, provisions that prohibit the Indian Health Service from disbursing funds to Alaska Native villages or corporations that are located in areas served by Alaska Native regional health entities. DIVISION D--PRECIP ACT Providing Research and Estimates of Changes In Precipitation Act or the PRECIP Act This division directs the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to take actions regarding precipitation estimation. NOAA must seek to enter an agreement with the National Academies of Science, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a study on the state of practice and research needs for precipitation estimation, including probable maximum precipitation estimation. NOAA, in consideration of the study's recommendations, shall consult with relevant partners on the development of a plan to update probable maximum precipitation estimates. NOAA shall develop guidance regarding probable maximum precipitation estimates that (1) provides best practices for federal and state regulatory agencies, private meteorological consultants, and other users that perform probable maximum precipitation studies; (2) considers the recommendations provided in the National Academies study; (3) facilitates review of probable maximum precipitation studies by regulatory agencies; and (4) provides confidence in regional and site-specific probable maximum precipitation estimates.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-304</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
