<bill session="118" type="s" number="3301" updated="2025-04-23T11:41:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DOE and USDA Interagency Research Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DOE and USDA Interagency Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for Department of Energy and Department of Agriculture joint research and development activities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000570"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2023-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2023-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1713" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-30T17:03:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">DOE and USDA Interagency Research Act

This bill requires the Department of Energy and Department of Agriculture to carry out cross-cutting and collaborative research and development activities through the establishment of an interagency agreement.

The agencies are authorized to (1) carry out reimbursable agreements in order to maximize research and development effectiveness, and (2) collaborate with other federal agencies. Further, the interagency agreement must require the use of a competitive, merit-reviewed process, which considers applications from federal agencies, national laboratories, institutions of higher education, and nonprofit institutions.

Research and development activities may include

 collaborative research in a variety of focus areas such as integrated natural resources and the energy-water nexus, biofuels and biobased products, invasive species management, grid modernization and security, and rural technology development; developing methods to accommodate large voluntary standardized and integrated data sets on agricultural, environmental, supply chain, and economic information; supporting research infrastructure and workforce development; and conducting collaborative research and development on ways to improve agriculture operations and processing efficiencies, and reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</summary>
</bill>
