<bill session="111" type="s" number="3865" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:23Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate nationwide availability of volunteer income tax assistance for low-income and underserved populations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2010-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-06T15:33:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Volunteer Income Tax Assistance (VITA) Act of 2010 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, through the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), to establish a Community Volunteer Income Tax Assistance Matching Grant Program (VITA grant program) for the development, expansion, or continuation of volunteer tax preparation programs to assist low-income taxpayers and members of underserved populations.

Establishes the National Center to Promote Quality, Excellence, and Evaluation in Volunteer Income Tax Assistance. Requires such Center to: (1) promote the adoption of a universally accessible volunteer training platform for the preparation of federal income tax returns; (2) provide technical assistance to tax return preparation program managers; (3) identify and disseminate best practices related to tax site management; (4) support outreach and marketing efforts; and (5) provide evaluation of programs and activities funded under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
