<bill session="111" type="h" number="4864" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ensuring Worker Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require a heightened review process by the Secretary of Labor of State occupational safety and health plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ensuring Worker Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001040" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2010-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000172" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2010-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2010-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2010-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Workforce Protections.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED10" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Workforce Protections" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-13T19:03:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Ensuring Worker Safety Act - Amends the Occupational Safety and Health Act to revise requirements for the Secretary of Labor's continuing evaluation of approved state occupational safety and health plans.

Requires: (1) the review of state plans to include an assessment of whether a state continues to meet certain conditions for the approval of such plans; and (2) the Secretary to determine whether a state that fails to comply substantially with the provisions of a plan should be given the opportunity to remedy such deficiencies. Prescribes general requirements for the provision to a state of such an opportunity.

Requires the Comptroller General periodically to review and assess: (1) whether state plans to develop and enforce safety and health standards are at least as effective as federal occupational safety and health (OSHA) program standards in preventing occupational injuries, illnesses and deaths, and investigating discrimination complaints; (2) the effectiveness of the Secretary's oversight of such plans; and (3) the adequacy of the Secretary's investigations in response to Complaints About State Plan Administration (CASPA) as well as whether policy issues have been identified and corrective actions fully implemented by each state.</summary>
</bill>
