<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>668</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:17:22Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:17:22Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-03-23</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
        <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported by</name>
            <date>2009-10-21T17:56:15Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Markup by</name>
            <date>2009-07-08T18:03:52Z</date>
          </item>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-03-23T20:19:59Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <committeeReports>
      <committeeReport>
        <citation>S. Rept. 111-90</citation>
      </committeeReport>
    </committeeReports>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>1672</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2009-12-08</actionDate>
          <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 221.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Identical bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-21</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 185.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-90.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-10-21</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Rockefeller with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 111-90.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-07-08</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-23</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sscm00</systemCode>
            <name>Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. (text of measure as introduced: CR S3615-3616)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-03-23</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001111</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murray, Patty [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patty</firstName>
        <lastName>Murray</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000127</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Cantwell, Maria [D-WA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Maria</firstName>
        <lastName>Cantwell</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>WA</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-03-23</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <cboCostEstimates>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-07-22T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 668, Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
        <url>http://www.cbo.gov/publication/20950</url>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on July 8, 2009&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      </item>
      <item>
        <pubDate>2009-07-22T04:00:00Z</pubDate>
        <title>S. 668, Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
        <url>https://www.cbo.gov/publication/20950</url>
        <description>Cost estimate for the bill as ordered reported by the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation on July 8, 2009</description>
      </item>
    </cboCostEstimates>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Ecology</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal-Indian relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intergovernmental relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Marine and coastal resources, fisheries</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Washington State</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wildlife conservation and habitat protection</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-03-23</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-07-14T18:37:29Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to: (1) set forth the membership of the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission; (2) direct the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, to appoint an employee of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to serve as a liaison among the Commission and the Department of Commerce and to attend the Commission's events; (3) state the goal of the Commission as the protection and restoration of the marine waters, habitats, and species of the Northwest Straits region in Washington to achieve ecosystem health and sustainable resource use; (4) enumerate the duties of the Commission and establish benchmarks for its work; (5) authorize the Manager of the Shorelands and Environmental Assistance Program of Washington's Department of Ecology, upon the recommendation of the Commission and the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve, to appoint and terminate a Director of the Commission; (6) require the Director to be confirmed by the Commission; (7) provide for the establishment of marine resources committees in specified counties of Washington; and (8) authorize the Director of the Commission and the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve to establish the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Foundation as a nonprofit foundation to support the Commission and the marine resources committees established by this Act. </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>01</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-10-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate with amendment(s)</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-02-03T20:58:59Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009 - Amends the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to define &quot;Northwest Straits&quot; as the marine waters of the Strait of Juan de Fuca and of Puget Sound from the Canadian border to the south end of Snohomish County, Washington. </p> <p>Sets forth the membership of the Northwest Straits Advisory Commission. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary for Oceans and Atmosphere, to appoint an employee of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to serve as a liaison between the Commission and the Department of Commerce and to attend the Commission's meetings and events as a nonvoting participant. States the goal of the Commission as the protection and restoration of the marine waters, habitats, and species of the Northwest Straits region in Washington to achieve ecosystem health and sustainable resource use. Enumerates the duties of the Commission and establish benchmarks for its work. Requires the Commission to submit annual reports to Congress and the Under Secretary on its activities and its progress in achieving specified benchmarks.</p> <p>Authorizes the Manager of the Shorelands and Environmental Assistance Program of Washington's Department of Ecology, upon the recommendation of the Commission and the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve, to appoint and terminate a Director of the Commission. Requires the Director to be confirmed by the Commission. </p> <p>Provides for the establishment of marine resources committees in specified counties of Washington. </p> <p>Authorizes the Director of the Commission and the Director of the Padilla Bay National Estuarine Research Reserve to establish the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Foundation as a nonprofit foundation to support the Commission and the marine resources committees established by this Act. </p> <p>Authorizes appropriations.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to reauthorize the Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Act to promote the protection of the resources of the Northwest Straits, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Northwest Straits Marine Conservation Initiative Reauthorization Act of 2009</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Reported to Senate</type>
        <date>2009-10-21T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-03-23T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s668is/xml/BILLS-111s668is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-10-21</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 185.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
