<bill session="111" type="s" number="704" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:41Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the use of Civil Air Patrol personnel and resources to support homeland security missions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on the use of Civil Air Patrol personnel and resources to support homeland security missions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2009-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2010-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000194" joined="2010-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001049" joined="2010-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2010-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2010-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2010-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Legislative Interest"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="1178" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military civil functions"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-12T19:43:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Comptroller General of the United States to study and report to specified congressional committees on the functions and capabilities of the Civil Air Patrol to support the homeland security missions of state, local, and tribal governments and the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Requires the Comptroller General to review the process by which the Civil Air Patrol may provide assistance to DHS, other federal agencies, and states to support homeland security missions, including by providing: (1) aerial reconnaissance or communications capabilities for border security; (2) capabilities for collective response to an act of terrorism, natural disaster, or other man-made event by assisting in damage assessment and situational awareness, conducting search and rescue operations, assisting in evacuations, or transporting time-sensitive medical or other materials; or (3) assistance in the exercise and training of departmental resources responsible for the interception of aviation threats to designated restricted areas.

Directs the Comptroller General's report to include assessments of: (1) the feasibility and cost-effectiveness of using Civil Air Patrol assets; and (2) whether existing mechanisms for requesting support from the Civil Air Patrol are sufficient.

Requires the Secretary to analyze the study and submit a report, including any recommendations for action that could affect DHS's organization and administration.</summary>
</bill>
