<bill session="117" type="s" number="4233" updated="2023-08-24T18:30:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Platte River Basin Critical Maintenance and Repair Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Platte River Basin Critical Maintenance and Repair Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act to provide for critical maintenance and repair of certain Bureau of Reclamation reserved or transferred works, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Nebraska"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-24T18:21:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Platte River Basin Critical Maintenance and Repair Act

This bill expands federal government funding to allow for the critical maintenance and repair of certain Bureau of Reclamation-owned facilities located within the Platte River Basin in Colorado, Nebraska, and Wyoming. The bill applies to those basin facilities that have had a structural failure resulting in a declaration of emergency in the 3-year period ending on the date the bill is enacted (e.g., the Fort Laramie Canal in both Wyoming and Nebraska, which had a tunnel collapse in July 2019).

Current law limits funding eligibility to certain Reclamation-owned facilities that suffered a critical failure during a 2-year period ending on November 15, 2021.</summary>
</bill>
