<bill session="116" type="h" number="5725" updated="2022-02-08T23:17:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hong Kong Be Water Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To impose sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act to combat the suppression of the freedoms of speech, association, assembly, procession, and demonstration of the people of Hong Kong, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hong Kong Be Water Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2758" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-29T21:38:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Hong Kong Be Water Act

This bill directs the President to impose sanctions on, and freeze assets belonging to, individuals and entities responsible for suppression of freedoms in Hong Kong.

The President shall impose property- and visa-blocking sanctions on any foreign person who is an official of Hong Kong's government or China's government and who knowingly suppressed the freedom of speech, association, procession, or demonstration in Hong Kong. These sanctions shall also apply to foreign individuals or entities acting on behalf of or cooperating with such a government official.

The President shall also block property transactions involving a Chinese national, an entity owned or controlled by China's government, or an officer or senior official of such an entity, if that individual or entity has attempted to undermine the autonomy, basic liberties, and human rights of the people of Hong Kong.</summary>
</bill>
