<bill session="117" type="h" number="1936" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Climate Resilient Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Comptroller General to evaluate and issue a report on the structural and economic impacts of climate resiliency at the Federal Emergency Management Agency, including recommendations on how to improve the building codes and standards that the Agency uses to prepare for climate change and address resiliency in housing, public buildings, and infrastructure such as roads and bridges.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Climate Resilient Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000191"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-28T18:28:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Climate Resilient Communities Act

This bill directs the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to evaluate and issue a report on the structural and economic impacts of climate resiliency at the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).

Specifically, GAO, within one year of this bill's enactment and every five years thereafter, must evaluate and report to Congress on the economic benefits, including avoided impacts on property and life, of the use of model, consensus-based building codes, standards, and provisions that support resilience to climate risks and impacts.

The report shall include

 an assessment of the status of adoption of building codes, standards, and provisions within the states, territories, and tribes at the state or jurisdictional level; analysis of the extent to which pre-disaster mitigation measures provide benefits to the nation and individual states, territories and tribes; an assessment of the building codes and standards referenced or otherwise currently incorporated into federal policies and programs, and the extent to which such codes and standards contribute to increasing climate resiliency; and recommendations for FEMA on how to better incorporate climate resiliency into efforts to rebuild after natural disasters.</summary>
</bill>
