<bill session="119" type="s" number="1474" updated="2025-09-29T15:27:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Vehicle Safety Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vehicle Safety Research Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to codify the PARTS program of the Department of Transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-29T15:26:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Vehicle Safety Research Act of 2025

This bill provides statutory authority for the Partnership for&#160;Analytics Research in Traffic Safety (PARTS) program in the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration (NHTSA). PARTS is an accord among&#160;automakers&#160;and NHTSA, which enables participants to voluntarily share safety-related data, via an independent third party, for collaborative safety analysis.

The bill specifies that

NHTSA&#160;must develop a governing charter for the program;&#160;NHTSA must contract with an external organization (i.e., a qualified nonprofit organization or institution of higher education) to conduct research to gather, analyze, and share certain traffic safety data and information;&#160;andany report, data, communications, work product, or other information voluntarily submitted to NHTSA or an external organization&#160;under the program&#160;shall not be disclosed to the public.Further, the bill specifies that NHTSA is not required to promulgate any regulations to carry out the PARTS program.</summary>
</bill>
