<bill session="109" type="h" number="5646" updated="2023-01-31T21:11:58Z">
  <state datetime="2006-12-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To study and promote the use of energy efficient computer servers in the United States.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To study and promote the use of energy efficient computer servers in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000572"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-28">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 109-538.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-06-28" calendar="Union" number="302">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 302.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:42:31-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (MI) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:42:47-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5001-5003" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:42:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5646.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11T13:55:00-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed until July 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:22:46-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5094-5095" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="369" datetime="2006-07-12T15:30:10-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 417 - 4 (Roll no. 369).</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/11/2006 H5001-5002" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:30:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-12T15:30:12-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 2990.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-08-04">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11537-11543" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2006-12-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-12-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2006-12-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2006-12-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="109-431" type="public" datetime="2006-12-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 109-431.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer industry"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy consumption"/>
    <term name="Energy demand"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fuel cells"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Superconductivity"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-31T00:27:18Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the House on July 12, 2006. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), through the Energy Star program, to analyze and report to Congress on the growth and energy consumption of computer data centers by the federal government and private enterprise.

Requires such study to include: (1) growth trends associated with data centers and the utilization of servers in the federal government and private sector; (2) analysis of the industry migration to the use of energy efficient microchips and servers designed to provide energy efficient computing and reduce the costs associated with large and medium scale data centers; (3) analysis of the potential cost savings available through the adoption of energy efficient data centers and servers; (4) analysis of the potential impacts of energy efficiency on product performance; (5) analysis of the potential cost savings and benefits to the energy supply chain through the use of stationary fuel cells for backup power and distributed generation; (6) an overview of current government incentives offered for energy efficient products and services; (7) recommendations for incentives and voluntary programs to encourage the use of energy efficient data centers and computing; and (8) an opportunity for stakeholders to comment and provide information on the study.

Expresses the sense of Congress that it is in the United States' best interest for purchasers of computer servers to give high priority to energy efficiency as a factor in determining best value and performance for purchases of servers.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-538</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
