<bill session="117" type="h" number="7721" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hermit&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Peak Fire Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hermit&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Peak Fire Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide compensation for victims of the fire initiated as a prescribed burn by the Forest Service in the Sante Fe National Forest in San Miguel County, New Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001084" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000191" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution, Civil Rights, and Civil Liberties.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4186" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5118" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6833" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-13T16:13:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Hermit's Peak Fire Assistance Act

This bill provides for monetary compensation to the victims of the prescribed fire burn in the Santa Fe National Forest in New Mexico that became a wildfire known as the Hermit's Peak Fire or the Hermit's Peak Fire/Calf Canyon Fire.

Each victim of the Hermit's Peak Fire shall be entitled to receive monetary compensation from the United States, including for personal injury, loss of property, business loss, or financial loss.

An Office of Hermit's Peak Fire Claims is established within the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) to receive, process, and pay claims to victims of the fire.

FEMA or the independent claims manager (which FEMA may appoint) shall, on behalf of the United States, investigate, consider, ascertain, adjust, determine, grant, deny, or settle any claim for money damages asserted by a victim of the Hermit's Peak Fire.

Any claimant aggrieved by a final decision of FEMA concerning compensation may, not later than 60 days after the date on which the decision is issued, bring a civil action in the U.S. District Court for the District of New Mexico, to modify or set aside the decision.</summary>
</bill>
