<amendment session="111" chamber="s" number="980" updated="2022-02-03T06:10:49Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="13" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-04-02">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000352"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <description>To deny funding for federal government expenditures to companies that are obtaining at least $1,000,000 in revenue from the sale of goods or services to or investment in Iran's energy sector, including, but not limited to: the exploration, development or exploitation of Iran's natural gas or crude oil fields; the import of refined petroleum products, including but limited to liquefied natural gas and petroleum bi-products into Iran; the enhancment or maintenance of Iran's oil refineries; and assistance in the import or export of energy products to or from Iran, including the provision of shipment, insurance, and reinsurance services.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-04-02" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 980 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4284" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Amendment SA 980 proposed by Senator Conrad for Senator Kyl. (consideration: CR S4284-4285) To deny funding for federal government expenditures to companies that are obtaining at least $1,000,000 in revenue from the sale of goods or services to or investment in Iran's energy sector, including, but not limited to: the exploration, development or exploitation of Iran's natural gas or crude oil fields; the import of refined petroleum products, including but limited to liquefied natural gas and petroleum bi-products into Iran; the enhancment or maintenance of Iran's oil refineries; and assistance in the import or export of energy products to or from Iran, including the provision of shipment, insurance, and reinsurance services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 980 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4284" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 980 proposed by Senator Conrad for Senator Kyl.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4284-4285" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
