<bill session="116" type="h" number="8719" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:27Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CASE-IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CASE-IT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Curbing Abuse and Saving Expression In Technology Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 to limit the immunity of providers and users of interactive computer services under such section, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001214"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001082" joined="2020-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-23T16:42:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Curbing Abuse and Saving Expression In Technology Act or the CASE-IT Act

This bill limits the protections for a user or provider of an interactive computer service (e.g., social media company) related to content that is published on or removed from its platform.

The bill removes for one year the protection from being treated as the publisher of information provided by another content provider if a user or provider facilitates (1) illegal online content; (2) certain exploitive contact between adults and minors; or (3) content that is indecent, obscene, or otherwise harmful to minors.

Further, to avoid being treated as the publisher of third-party content or subject to liability for screening and blocking content on its platform, an interactive computer service that is dominant in its market (i.e., has gained substantial, sustained market power over any competitors) must make content moderation decisions pursuant to policies or practices that are consistent with the First Amendment.</summary>
</bill>
