<bill session="117" type="h" number="8324" updated="2023-08-01T13:30:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Share Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Share Transparency Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to establish requirements for the disclosure of certain information relating to health care sharing ministries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000382" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000607" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2022-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-01T13:29:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Share Transparency Act of 2022

This bill requires a health care sharing ministry (HCSM) to disclose specific information to individuals enrolling in the HCSM and to designated government agencies. (An HCSM is a faith-based organization with members who share a common set of ethical or religious beliefs and who contribute regular payments to cover the medical expenses of other members.)

The bill requires an HCSM to disclose to an enrolling individual information such as (1) the average out-of-pocket expenses an enrollee incurs, (2) how to file a complaint or appeal a coverage determination, and (3) a list of the HCSM's non-reimbursable items and services.

The bill also requires that an HCSM submit annual financial disclosures and program information to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), the Internal Revenue Service, and the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau. HHS is required to publicly post this information.

Additionally, health insurance brokers contracting with an HCSM are required to provide an enrolling individual with information about health insurance coverage that is available through Medicare, Medicaid, or a health insurance exchange, as appropriate.

HHS may apply civil monetary penalties to an HCSM that fails to comply with the bill's requirements.

Further, the bill requires the Federal Trade Commission to publicly disclose information about consumer complaints regarding HCSMs.</summary>
</bill>
