<bill session="117" type="s" number="2553" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to protect employees of the Federal judiciary from discrimination, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Judiciary Accountability Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judiciary Accountability Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001042"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2022-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2022-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2021-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2022-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2021-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5180" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4827" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-14T15:23:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Judiciary Accountability Act of 2021

This bill applies certain civil rights and employee protection laws to judicial branch employees.

Specifically, the bill applies to judicial branch employees laws that prohibit discrimination based on race, color, religion, sex (including sexual orientation or gender identity), national origin, age, or disability.

 Further, the bill prohibits retaliation against whistleblowers within the judicial branch.

Additionally, the bill establishes (1) the Commission on Judicial Integrity to oversee a program to prevent workplace misconduct; (2) the Office of Judicial Integrity to oversee confidential reporting systems regarding workplace misconduct, training programs on workplace behavior and bystander intervention, and other reporting initiatives regarding employee metrics and demographics; (3) the Special Counsel for Equal Employment Opportunity to investigate alleged workplace misconduct and complaints; and (4) the Office of Employee Advocacy to provide legal assistance, representation, and consultation to judicial employees.

Finally, the bill establishes workplace discrimination, harassment, and retaliation as judicial misconduct.</summary>
</bill>
