<bill session="111" type="hr" number="1147" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:18Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner to hold an explanatory public meeting prior to the submission of congressional earmark requests.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to require a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner to hold an explanatory public meeting prior to the submission of congressional earmark requests.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001175"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Ethics" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="General taxation matters"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-13T15:27:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends Rule XXIII (Code of Official Conduct) of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit a Member, Delegate, or Resident Commissioner (Member) from submitting a request for a congressional earmark without first holding a public meeting to review such request.

Requires such meeting to: (1) be open to coverage by the press; and (2) provide a forum for constituent participation, either in person or through teleconference, web conference, or internet chat.





Requires a Member requesting a congressional earmark or limited tax or tariff benefit in any bill or joint resolution (or an accompanying report) or in any conference report (or joint explanatory statement) to provide a written statement to the chair and ranking minority member of the committee of jurisdiction certifying that the Member has complied with the requirements of this resolution.</summary>
</bill>
