<bill session="119" type="s" number="590" updated="2025-11-04T23:04:02Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Flood and Agricultural Forecasts Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Flood and Agricultural Forecasts Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to maintain the National Mesonet Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="613" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T18:31:10Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Flood and Agricultural Forecasts Act of 2025

This bill provides statutory authority for the National Mesonet Program (NMP) maintained by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA). (Mesonets are networks of automated weather and soil observation stations that collect data used in measuring, tracking, and forecasting weather and its effects. The NMP is a national network of local mesonets that collects and disseminates non-federal atmospheric weather observations in the United States.)

The bill sets forth certain requirements for the NMP, including that the program must obtain weather observations in order to improve understanding and forecasting of atmospheric, drought, fire, and water events, and establish means to integrate increased numbers and types of environmental observations into the program annually. However, NOAA may obtain data under the program only when it is demonstrably cost effective and meets or exceeds certain data quality standards.&#160;

Of funds appropriated to the program annually, NOAA must award at least 15% to state, tribal, private, and academic entities seeking to build, expand, or upgrade mesonet system equipment and capacity. Entities receiving funds must agree to provide data to the NMP. In allocating funding, NOAA must prioritize providing funds to entities in remote areas and areas that lack environmental monitoring stations.&#160;

NOAA must also ensure the NMP has an active advisory committee, comprised of subject matter experts, to make recommendations on data needs and procurement, among other topics.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
