<bill session="117" type="s" number="4986" updated="2022-12-29T13:18:34Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SHORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHORT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Harassing Owners of Rifles Today Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to remove short-barreled rifles, short-barreled shotguns, and certain other weapons from the definition of firearms for purposes of the National Firearms Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2022-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2022-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2022-12-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="9033" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-02T19:59:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stop Harassing Owners of Rifles Today Act or the SHORT Act

This bill removes certain short-barreled rifles, short-barreled shotguns, and other weapons from the definition of a firearm for purposes of regulation under the National Firearms Act (NFA).

The bill also eliminates certain restrictions that apply to the sale or transportation of such rifles and shotguns in interstate commerce.

If a state or local registration or licensing requirement is determined by reference to the NFA, the bill treats persons who acquire or possess a short-barreled rifle, short-barreled shotgun, or other weapon in accordance with the Gun Control Act of 1968 as meeting the registration and licensing requirements.

The bill preempts certain state or local laws that tax or regulate these rifles, shotguns, and weapons.

The Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives must destroy records relating to the registration, transfer, or manufacture of applicable weapons described by this bill within one year after the enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
