<bill session="117" type="h" number="2101" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ZERO WASTE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to award grants for projects that are consistent with zero-waste practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ZERO WASTE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zeroing Excess, Reducing Organic Waste, And Sustaining Technical Expertise Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000173"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1512" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Biological and life sciences"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-10T21:20:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Zeroing Excess, Reducing Organic Waste, And Sustaining Technical Expertise Act or the ZERO WASTE Act

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish grant programs for reducing waste.

Specifically, the EPA must establish a program to award grants to nonprofit organizations and state, local, and tribal governments for projects that utilize specified zero-waste practices. Zero-waste means the conservation of all resources by means of responsible production, consumption, reuse, and recovery of products, packaging, and materials without (1) burning or otherwise destroying embodied energy; and (2) a discharge to land, water, or air that results in adverse human health or environmental effects.

In addition, the EPA must establish a program to award grants for developing and implementing new requirements that reduce the amount of waste disposed of in landfills.</summary>
</bill>
