<bill session="108" type="h" number="206" updated="2023-01-15T21:04:28Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Security Decedent's Family Relief Act of 2001</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide that an individual's entitlement to any benefit thereunder shall continue through the month of his or her death (without affecting any other person's entitlement to benefits for that month) and that such individual's benefit shall be payable for such month only to the extent proportionate to the number of days in such month preceding the date of such individual's death.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Decedent's Family Relief Act of 2001</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001149"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001240" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000392" joined="2004-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000258" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000127" joined="2003-09-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Death"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social security beneficiaries"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Security Decedent's Family Relief Act of 2001 (sic) - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to continue an individual's entitlement to benefits through the month of his or her death, without affecting any other person's entitlement to benefits for that month.Provides that such individual's benefit shall be payable for such month only in proportion to the number of days preceding the date of such individual's death.Provides for disregard of such benefits for the individual for the month of death under provisions for determining maximum family benefits.</summary>
</bill>
