<bill session="117" type="s" number="4811" updated="2023-09-01T17:00:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BLUE Pacific Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BLUE Pacific Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boosting Long-term U.S. Engagement in the Pacific Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a comprehensive, long-term United States strategy and policy for the Pacific Islands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2967" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-01T16:46:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Boosting Long-term U.S. Engagement in the Pacific Act or the BLUE Pacific Act

This bill requires and authorizes activities related to U.S. foreign policy in the Pacific Islands, including the Cook Islands, Fiji, the Marshall Islands, Papua New Guinea, and Vanuatu.

The bill requires specified departments and agencies to develop and implement strategies in the region to

 expand the coverage of the International Law Enforcement Academies program; help build the capacity of local civilian and national security institutions; expand trade capacity and promote regional development; assist in preparing for natural disasters and other emergencies; assist in building public health capacity and improving outcomes, including in response to COVID-19; address climate change, with a focus on improving critical infrastructure and supporting ecosystem conservation efforts; provide expanded media content to the Pacific Islands and partner with journalists; support efforts to reduce gender-based violence and promote gender equality; promote educational and professional development of young adult leaders and professionals; and promote the development of civil society. The bill also requires the Department of State to prioritize efforts to help the Pacific Islands ratify and implement international legal conventions related to transnational crime. The State Department must also coordinate with regional allies and partners in providing assistance to the Pacific Islands.

The President may provide assistance to the Pacific Islands to promote quality basic education and to promote the dissemination of free and accurate information.</summary>
</bill>
