<bill session="117" type="h" number="775" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Disability Voting Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to promote access to voter registration and voting for individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disability Voting Rights Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="954" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2358" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Voting rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-08T16:19:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Disability Voting Rights Act

This bill requires each state to allow individuals with disabilities to use absentee registration procedures and to vote by absentee ballot in federal elections.

The bill requires each state to

 accept and process any otherwise valid voter registration and absentee ballot applications from individuals with disabilities if the applications are received within the deadline for the federal election; establish procedures for individuals with disabilities to request, and for the state to send, voter registration and absentee ballot applications by mail and through electronic means; create procedures for securely transmitting blank absentee ballots by mail and through electronic means to individuals with disabilities; designate a single office to provide information on voter registration and absentee ballot procedures for individuals with disabilities; and specify a means of electronic communication for individuals with disabilities to request, and for the state to send, voter registration and absentee ballot applications. Further, each state must transmit a validly requested absentee ballot to an individual with a disability within 45 days of an election. However, the bill establishes a procedure for a state to apply to the Department of Justice for a waiver of this requirement.

 The bill also permanently reauthorizes and expands a program under which the Department of Health and Human Services makes payments to eligible states and units of local government to assure voting access for individuals with disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
