<bill session="118" type="h" number="4665" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:31-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:31-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-146, by Mr. Diaz-Balart.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-17" calendar="Union" number="115">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 115.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26T10:29:47-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 723 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26T20:16:47-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 723 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T09:05:01-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 723.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4719-4791" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4725-4758" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T09:05:06-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368 and H.R. 4665. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4365, H.R. 4367, H.R. 4368, and H.R. 4665, under a structured rule for each bill. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate for each bill and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T09:20:48-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 723 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T09:20:49-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jennifer A. Kiggans to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T09:21:35-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4665.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:08:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Diaz-Balart amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:11:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 8.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:15:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crane amendment No. 8, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:16:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:23:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crane amendment No. 10, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:24:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:33:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crane amendment No. 13, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:34:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:39:14-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:40:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson Lee amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:50:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:57:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 17, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T10:58:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:04:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 18, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:05:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:13:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:14:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:18:15-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 22, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:18:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:25:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 23, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:26:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kelly (MS) amendment No. 27.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:29:26-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kelly (MS) amendment No. 27, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:30:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Plaskett amendment No. 36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:41:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Plaskett amendment No. 36, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Ms. Plaskett demanded a recorded vote, and the Ch air postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:42:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:47:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T11:54:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 40.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:02:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:16:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 42, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Ms. Greene (GA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:16:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:25:09-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 43, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Ms. Greene (GA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:26:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:36:23-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steube amendment No. 44, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Mr. Steube demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:37:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:47:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steube amendment No. 45, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Mr. Steube demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:48:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:56:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 46, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T12:57:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:02:52-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 47, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:03:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:07:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 48, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:08:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 49.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:18:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 49, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:19:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:22:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 50, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:24:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:35:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 51, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jackson Lee demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:36:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gooden (TX) amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:40:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gooden (TX) amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:45:49-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gooden (TX) amendment No. 54, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:46:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T13:55:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mooney amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:01:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:10:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Spartz amendment No. 57, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:11:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:18:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 58, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:19:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:24:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Foxx amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:32:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Foxx amendment No. 61, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Foxx demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:32:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Issa amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:40:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:42:03-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 63, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:42:55-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:45:41-04:00">
      <text>PROCEEDINGS POSTPONED - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 64, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:46:50-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Diaz-Balart moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:47:31-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T14:47:44-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4665 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:51:28-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T16:51:41-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:22:44-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Calvert moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:23:02-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:23:13-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4665 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:52:19-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:52:32-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:59:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T18:59:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 65, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:00:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:04:39-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:11:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burchett amendment No. 67, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:12:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:17:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 69.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:21:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tenney amendment No. 69, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Tenney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:22:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:30:03-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 70, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:30:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:36:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 71, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:43:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:47:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steube amendment No. 73, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:48:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:56:19-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 74, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Lee (CA) demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T19:57:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 76.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:01:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 76, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Ogles demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:02:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Massie amendment No. 77.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:10:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Massie amendment No. 77, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:10:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 723, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:16:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 78, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Diaz-Balart demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:16:56-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Diaz-Balart moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:17:09-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T20:17:44-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4665 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T21:30:31-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4802-4820" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T21:30:49-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:31:18-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4665.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:32:15-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:32:29-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:33:34-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Salinas moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:33:36-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:40:23-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 210 - 217 (Roll no. 499).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="500" datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:31-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 216 - 212 (Roll no. 500).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T22:46:36-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-28T23:30:19-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4665.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-10-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="222">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 222.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2438" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="723" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2882" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1102" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="African Development Foundation"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arab-Israeli relations"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Burma"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Costa Rica"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cultural exchanges and relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Egypt"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Gaza Strip"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Georgia (Republic)"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Human trafficking"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Inter-American Foundation"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International monetary system and foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Jordan"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lebanon"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Malawi"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military education and training"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Morocco"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="Nepal"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Palestinians"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Peru"/>
    <term name="Philippines"/>
    <term name="Policy sciences"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Reconstruction and stabilization"/>
    <term name="Refugees, asylum, displaced persons"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Saudi Arabia"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling and trafficking"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="South Sudan"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="Sri Lanka"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Sudan"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="Trade and Development Agency"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
    <term name="Tunisia"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for Global Media"/>
    <term name="U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID)"/>
    <term name="Ukraine"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
    <term name="War crimes, genocide, crimes against humanity"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="West Bank"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
    <term name="Yemen"/>
    <term name="Zimbabwe"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h485"/>
    <amendment number="h484"/>
    <amendment number="h483"/>
    <amendment number="h482"/>
    <amendment number="h481"/>
    <amendment number="h480"/>
    <amendment number="h479"/>
    <amendment number="h478"/>
    <amendment number="h477"/>
    <amendment number="h476"/>
    <amendment number="h475"/>
    <amendment number="h474"/>
    <amendment number="h473"/>
    <amendment number="h472"/>
    <amendment number="h471"/>
    <amendment number="h470"/>
    <amendment number="h469"/>
    <amendment number="h468"/>
    <amendment number="h467"/>
    <amendment number="h466"/>
    <amendment number="h465"/>
    <amendment number="h464"/>
    <amendment number="h463"/>
    <amendment number="h462"/>
    <amendment number="h461"/>
    <amendment number="h460"/>
    <amendment number="h459"/>
    <amendment number="h458"/>
    <amendment number="h457"/>
    <amendment number="h456"/>
    <amendment number="h455"/>
    <amendment number="h454"/>
    <amendment number="h453"/>
    <amendment number="h452"/>
    <amendment number="h451"/>
    <amendment number="h450"/>
    <amendment number="h449"/>
    <amendment number="h448"/>
    <amendment number="h447"/>
    <amendment number="h446"/>
    <amendment number="h445"/>
    <amendment number="h444"/>
    <amendment number="h443"/>
    <amendment number="h442"/>
    <amendment number="h441"/>
    <amendment number="h440"/>
    <amendment number="h439"/>
    <amendment number="h438"/>
    <amendment number="h437"/>
    <amendment number="h436"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-10-05T14:14:08Z" status="Passed House">Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 appropriations for the Department of State, foreign operations, and related programs.

The bill provides appropriations to the State Department for

 Administration of Foreign Affairs, International Organizations, and International Commissions. The bill provides appropriations for related agencies and programs, including

 the U.S. Agency for Global Media, the Asia Foundation, the U.S. Institute of Peace, the Center for Middle Eastern-Western Dialogue Trust Fund, the Eisenhower Exchange Fellowship Program, the Israeli Arab Scholarship Program, the East-West Center, and the National Endowment for Democracy. The bill provides appropriations for other commissions, including

 the Commission for the Preservation of America's Heritage Abroad, the U.S. Commission on International Religious Freedom, the Commission on Security and Cooperation in Europe, the Congressional-Executive Commission on the People's Republic of China, and the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission. The bill provides appropriations to

 the U.S. Agency for International Development (USAID), the State Department and the President for International Security Assistance, and International Financial Institutions for Multilateral Assistance. The bill provides appropriations for bilateral economic assistance, including programs and activities conducted by

 the President; the State Department; Independent Agencies, including the Peace Corps, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Inter-American Foundation, and the U.S. African Development Foundation; and the Department of the Treasury. The bill provides appropriations for export and investment assistance to

 the Export-Import Bank of the United States, the U.S. International Development Finance Corporation, and the U.S. Trade and Development Agency. The bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-146</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
