<amendment session="117" chamber="s" number="461" updated="2021-02-05T14:48:13Z">
  <amends type="sc" number="5" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-02-03">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001198"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-02-03"/>
  <description>To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to expanding natural gas as a vital fuel source to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and provide reliable and affordable heat, electricity, and transportation fuel for consumers.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Amendment SA 461 ruled out of order by the chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 461 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 49. Record Vote Number: 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Point of order that the amendment violates section 305(b)(2) of the CBA raised in Senate with respect to amendment SA 461.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Amendment SA 461 proposed by Senator Sullivan. (consideration: CR S458-459; text: CR S458) To establish a deficit-neutral reserve fund relating to expanding natural gas as a vital fuel source to reduce greenhouse gas emissions and provide reliable and affordable heat, electricity, and transportation fuel for consumers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03"/>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 461 proposed by Senator Sullivan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-05">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Motion to waive all applicable budgetary discipline with respect to amendment SA 461 rejected in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 51 - 49. Record Vote Number: 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-03">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
