<bill session="117" type="s" number="154" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:42Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reciprocity Ensures Streamlined Use of Lifesaving Treatments Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to provide for reciprocal marketing approval of certain drugs, biological products, and devices that are authorized to be lawfully marketed abroad, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reciprocity Ensures Streamlined Use of Lifesaving Treatments Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2021-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2021-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2021-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="724" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-17T20:43:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Reciprocity Ensures Streamlined Use of Lifesaving Treatments Act of 2021 

This bill establishes a reciprocal marketing approval process that allows for the sale of a drug, biological product, or medical device that has not been approved by the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) if the product is approved for sale in another country and there is an unmet need.

Specifically, the bill requires the product's sponsor to demonstrate, among other things, that (1) the product has been approved in one of the specified countries, (2) neither the FDA nor any of the specified countries have withdrawn approval for the product because of safety or effectiveness concerns, and (3) there is a public health or unmet medical need for the product.

The FDA may decline approval if the FDA determines that the product is not safe or effective. The FDA may condition reciprocal approval on the conduct of postmarket studies.

The FDA must issue a decision on whether to grant a request for reciprocal marketing approval within 30 days of receiving the request.

Congress may pass a joint resolution to grant reciprocal marketing approval of a product that the FDA declines to approve through the reciprocal process.</summary>
</bill>
