<bill session="118" type="s" number="872" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:41Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAFETY on Social Media Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFETY on Social Media Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stopping Attempts by Foreign Entities to Target Youths on Social Media Act Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify social media entities under the influence of certain foreign entities and to take measures to protect the United States from such entities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-02T20:30:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stopping Attempts by Foreign Entities to Target Youths on Social Media Act Act [sic] of 2023 or the SAFETY on Social Media Act of 2023

This bill restricts domestic access to computer or mobile apps or websites (e.g., TikTok) of social media companies owned or controlled by countries of concern (China, Iran, North Korea, and Russia).

The President must annually publish a list of these companies and block certain transactions involving them. A company must be listed if it

 is a foreign entity owned or controlled by a country of concern; has more than a specified number of users or downloads; and has altered or may alter the content of apps or websites at the request of, or shared data about U.S. persons (individuals or entities) with, a country of concern. Additionally, the Federal Communications Commission must prohibit access to listed companies' apps or websites through U.S. app stores and internet service providers.

Further, the bill requires agents of listed companies to register with the Department of Justice and restricts access to U.S. visas by foreign nationals employed by listed companies. Foreign nationals are ineligible for U.S. visas (1) while employed by a listed company, and (2) for three years after either they terminate that employment or their employer is removed from the list. A foreign national of a country of concern who is employed by a listed company is also permanently ineligible for an H-1B visa (nonimmigrant workers in specialty occupations and fashion models).</summary>
</bill>
