<bill session="118" type="h" number="1152" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Water Quality Certification and Energy Project Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Water Quality Certification and Energy Project Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water Quality Certification and Energy Project Improvement Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to make changes with respect to water quality certification, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2023-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000605" joined="2023-02-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 118-10.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-03-17" calendar="Union" number="5">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 5.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="947" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2811" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-22T16:38:46Z" status="Reported to House">Water Quality Certification and Energy Project Improvement Act of 2023

This bill revises the water quality certification process under Section 401 of the Clean Water Act (CWA) for any activity that requires a federal license or permit and may result in a discharge of pollutants into waters of the United States. Activities that require such federal licenses or permits include hydropower, natural gas pipeline, or mining projects.

Under the existing Section 401, an applicant for a federal license or permit to conduct such activities must provide the federal licensing or permitting agency with a certification. The certification must attest that the discharge will comply with enumerated sections of the CWA (i.e., Sections 301, 302, 303, 306, and 307) and with any other appropriate requirement of state law set forth in the certification. The certifying authority&#8212;usually the state in which the discharge originates, but sometimes an Indian tribe or the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)&#8212;may grant, grant with conditions, deny, or waive certification of a proposed federal license or permit.

This bill limits the scope of the certification process by eliminating the requirement that the discharge comply with appropriate state law set forth in the certification. It also requires decisions to grant or deny a request for certification to be based only on the enumerated sections of the CWA and provisions of state law that implement water quality criteria under Section 303. In addition, it also limits the certification process to activities that may directly result in a discharge into waters of the United States.

In addition, the bill requires certifying authorities to identify all materials or information that are necessary to grant or deny the request within 90 days of receiving a request for certification. They must also publish requirements for their water quality certifications.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-10</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
