<bill session="108" type="s" number="1574" updated="2023-01-15T07:03:00Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to replace the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service as the Federal agency responsible for the administration, protection and preservation of the Midway Atoll within 90 days after the enactment of this Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of the Interior to replace the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service as the Federal agency responsible for the administration, protection and preservation of the Midway Atoll within 90 days after the enactment of this Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000504"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Islands"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-17T18:01:25Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) review and report to the appropriate congressional committees on the administration of Midway Atoll and the designation of the Atoll as a National Memorial; and (2) designate another agency to replace the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service as administrator of Midway Atoll and developer of the Memorial.

Declares the intention of Congress that: (1) the National Memorial on Midway Atoll be given equal consideration with concerns over the preservation of wildlife in all matters related to the administration, development and preservation of the Atoll; (2) Midway's airport remain in use as an alternative emergency site in order to ensure the safety of civilian and military aircraft in the northern Pacific region; and (3) the public continue to have meaningful access to the Atoll so as to experience and benefit from its status as both a National Memorial to the Battle of Midway and a National Wildlife Refuge.</summary>
</bill>
