<bill session="118" type="h" number="5998" updated="2025-11-19T03:49:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-10-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-10-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s College Promise Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s College Promise Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish grants for tuition-free community colleges, student success grants, and grants for Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Tribal Colleges and Universities, and Minority-Serving Institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2023-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-07-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2023-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2023-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-10-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3086" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-10T12:59:12Z" status="Introduced in House">America's College Promise Act of 2023

This bill provides funding and establishes grant programs to expand access to higher education, including by providing free community college to students.

Specifically, the bill establishes a program to waive resident tuition and fees for community college students. The Department of Education (ED) must award grants to states and tribal colleges and universities to pay the federal share of the program.

As a condition of receiving such a grant, a state must (1) submit a plan to align the requirements for receiving a regular high school diploma with the requirements for entering credit-bearing coursework at community colleges; and (2) submit a plan to improve transfer pathways between institutions of higher education (IHEs), including by ensuring that associate degrees awarded by community colleges are fully transferable to four-year IHEs.

Next, the bill directs ED to award grants to states and tribal colleges and universities for implementing evidence-based institutional reforms and innovative practices to improve student outcomes.

In addition, ED must award grants to participating historically Black colleges and universities, tribal colleges and universities, and minority-serving institutions to waive or significantly reduce the first 60 credits of tuition and fees for low-income students.</summary>
</bill>
