<bill session="117" type="h" number="2951" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to modify Treasury Regulations relating to insurance-dedicated exchange-traded funds.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to modify Treasury Regulations relating to insurance-dedicated exchange-traded funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000815"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2021-04-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2954" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1770" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4808" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-12T16:50:15Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires the Department of the Treasury, within five years of the enactment of this bill, to modify its regulations relating to Income Tax; Diversification Requirements for Variable Annuity, Endowment, and Life Insurance Contracts to facilitate the use of exchange-traded funds as investment options under certain variable contracts.

 An exchange-traded fund means a regulated investment company, partnership, or trust (1) that is registered with the Securities and Exchange Commission as an open-end investment company or a unit investment trust, (2) the shares of which can be directly purchased or redeemed only by an authorized participant (i.e., a financial institution that is a member or participant of a registered clearing agency), and (3) the shares of which are traded throughout the day on a national stock exchange at market prices that may or may not be the same as the net asset value of the shares.</summary>
</bill>
