<bill session="116" type="h" number="3753" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:38Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting Graduate Medical Education at Community Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish rules for payment for graduate medical education (GME) costs for hospitals that establish a new medical residency training program after hosting resident rotators for short durations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Graduate Medical Education at Community Hospitals Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2019-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000613" joined="2019-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2116" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-31T21:18:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Graduate Medical Education at Community Hospitals Act of 2019

This bill revises payment rules under Medicare for graduate medical education (GME) costs with respect to a hospital that establishes a new medical residency training program.

If a hospital has not entered into a GME affiliation agreement, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) must establish the hospital's full-time equivalent (FTE) resident amount only after determining that the hospital's medical residency training program trains more than 1.0 FTE resident in a cost reporting period. If a hospital has an approved FTE resident amount that is based on other specified thresholds, the CMS must give the hospital the opportunity to have the amount reestablished when the hospital begins training FTE residents in excess of the applicable threshold.

The bill also establishes similar thresholds for new determinations of certain adjustments to hospital payment limitations regarding FTE residents in allopathic and osteopathic medicine; a hospital that has an adjustment has the opportunity to have it redetermined once the applicable threshold is exceeded.</summary>
</bill>
