<bill session="118" type="s" number="1817" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish in the Department of Transportation a drone infrastructure inspection grant program and a drone education and training grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2023-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3593" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3935" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-20T14:33:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act

This bill establishes programs within the Department of Transportation (DOT) to support the use of small, unmanned aircraft systems (commonly known as drones)&#160;when inspecting, operating,&#160;maintaining,&#160;repairing, modernizing, or constructing road infrastructure, electric grid infrastructure, water infrastructure, or other critical infrastructure.

Specifically, DOT must award grants to state, tribal, or local governments; metropolitan planning organizations; or groups of those entities to purchase or otherwise use drones to support the inspection, operation, construction, maintenance, modernization, or repair of critical infrastructure to&#160;increase efficiency, reduce costs,&#160;improve worker and community&#160;safety, or reduce carbon emissions related to critical infrastructure projects. Grant recipients must use domestically manufactured drones that are not made by certain foreign entities, including companies subject to influence or control from China or Russia.

DOT must also award grants to certain institutions of higher education for training students for careers using drones and related technologies.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
