<bill session="108" type="s" number="1713" updated="2023-01-15T08:03:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Business Credit Liquidity Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title IV of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958, relating to a pilot program for credit enhancement guarantees on pools of non-SBA loans.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Credit Liquidity Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000611" joined="2003-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2003-10-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12458-12460"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S12460-12461" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-11-04T21:08:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Business Credit Liquidity Act of 2003 - Amends the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA), in order to encourage lenders to increase the availability of small business financing by improving lender access to reasonable funding sources, to provide a credit enhancement guarantee of, or a commitment to guarantee, a portion of the principal and interest on securities issued and managed by not less than two qualified entities authorized and approved by the SBA. Requires the SBA to set and maintain standards for qualified entities, including standards relating to delinquency, default, liquidation, and loss rates.

Makes the SBA's credit enhancement guarantees second-loss guarantees, available only after the full payment of guarantees offered by the qualified entities authorized to act as issuers and managers of pools or trusts of loans. Provides loan pool or trust requirements and credit enhancement limits for FY 2004 through 2006. Directs the SBA to charge and collect a fee from issuers based on the SBA's guaranteed amount of issued securities.</summary>
</bill>
