<bill session="116" type="s" number="2838" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:32Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act to improve the transparency of the United States Center for Safe Sport, to provide grant accountability, and to protect victims of abuse from retaliation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Ted Stevens Olympic and Amateur Sports Act to improve the transparency of the United States Center for Safe Sport, to provide grant accountability, and to protect victims of abuse from retaliation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000612" joined="2019-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2019-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1245"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2020-06-15T19:27:39Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the U.S. Center for Safe Sport to provide grant funding accountability and protect victims of abuse from retaliation.

Amounts transferred to the center by the U.S. Olympic Committee (USOC) or a national governing body shall be used primarily for the investigation and resolution of allegations of sexual misconduct, or other misconduct, made by amateur athletes affiliated with the USOC, a national governing body, or a paralympic sports organization.

The center shall be audited at least annually and shall report to Congress annually.

The Department of Justice (DOJ) may petition in the U.S. District Court for the District of Columbia for removal of officers and directors of the center if the center (1) engages in any act, practice, or policy that is materially inconsistent with its purpose; or (2) refuses, fails, or neglects to discharge the obligations of the center to protect the safety of amateur athletes.

DOJ may not award a grant to an entity that supports oversight of the USOC if it holds amounts in an offshore account for the purpose of avoiding payment of tax on unrelated business income of charitable organizations.

The USOC, a national governing body, a paralympic sports organization, or any officer, employee, contractor, or agent may not retaliate against any protected individual, including amateur athletes, coaches, or trainers, because of a protected disclosure regarding abuse. National governing bodies must provide protection from retaliation to protected individuals.</summary>
</bill>
