<bill session="116" type="h" number="6085" updated="2022-02-09T00:41:35Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Postal Supervisors and Managers Fairness Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 39, United States Code, to modify procedures for negotiating pay and benefits of supervisory and other managerial personnel of the United States Postal Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Postal Supervisors and Managers Fairness Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2020-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-08T21:27:22Z" status="Introduced in House">Postal Supervisors and Managers Fairness Act of 2020

This bill modifies procedures for negotiating pay and benefits of supervisory and other managerial personnel of the U.S. Postal Service (USPS).

At least 60 days before the expiration of a pay decision, the USPS must propose to the supervisors' organization any changes in pay policies, pay schedules, or fringe benefit programs for members of such organization.

Not later than 60 days after the USPS agrees to a collective bargaining agreement that affects the pay or benefits of supervisors or managers who are members of the supervisors' organization, the USPS shall provide a proposal regarding such matters to the organization.

The bill makes binding the decision of the fact-finding panel appointed by the Federal Mediation and Conciliation Service in the event of an impasse between the USPS and a supervisors' organization over proposed changes in pay and benefits.</summary>
</bill>
