<bill session="117" type="h" number="313" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Targeted Federal Funding to Invest in Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide increased funding for States and communities in need, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeted Federal Funding to Invest in Communities Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-12T17:34:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Targeted Federal Funding to Invest in Communities Act

This bill supports state, territorial, tribal, and local governments in providing resources to residents, especially those in historically underserved communities, to improve measurable outcomes for health, education, and quality of life.

States are eligible for support if they are in the bottom 10 of all 50 states in combined ranking of average life expectancy, infant mortality rate, poverty rate, and percentage of state population with a college degree. Also eligible for support are U.S. territories, tribal governments, and the District of Columbia. A local government in an eligible state may receive direct support if it is in a county with persistent poverty.

Recipients shall use the funds to cover only those costs that

 are necessary expenditures to create or expand activity or programs consistent with the purposes of this bill, were not accounted for in the recipient's budget most recently approved as of enactment of this bill, and are incurred during the five year period beginning on enactment of this bill. The Office of Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall conduct monitoring and oversight of the receipt, disbursement, and use of funds.</summary>
</bill>
