<bill session="110" type="s" number="3392" updated="2022-02-03T05:12:02Z">
  <state datetime="2008-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FAST Redress Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Fair, Accurate, Secure, and Timely Redress Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish an appeal and redress process for passengers wrongly delayed or prohibited from boarding a flight, or denied a right, benefit, or privilege, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000250" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2008-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2008-09-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="4179" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer complaints"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-11-13T22:38:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fair, Accurate, Secure and Timely Redress Act of 2008 or the FAST Redress Act of 2008 - Amends the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish: (1) a timely and fair appeal and redress process for individuals delayed or prohibited from boarding a commercial aircraft because they were wrongly identified as a threat when screened against any terrorist watchlist or database used by the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) or any Department of Homeland Security (DHS) component; and (2) an Office of Appeals and Redress within DHS to implement the process.

Requires the process to include the establishment of a method for maintaining and disseminating a Comprehensive Cleared List of individuals who: (1) were misidentified; (2) complete an appeal and redress request approved by DHS and provided required additional information; and (3) permit their personally identifiable information to be shared among multiple DHS components for purposes of this Act.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) transmit the List and any other information necessary to resolve misidentifications, improve administration of the advanced passenger prescreening system, and reduce false positives to TSA, other governmental and tribal entities, and air carriers that use any terrorist watchlist or database; and (2) ensure that the List is considered by all DHS components assessing an individual's security risk. Terminates transmission of the List to air carriers when the government assumes terrorist watchlist screening functions.

Directs the Secretary to require that DHS employees complete mandatory privacy and security training before being authorized to handle personally identifiable information. Requires the Office to ensure that a TSA supervisor trained in the appeal and redress process is available at each airport at which DHS has a significant presence.</summary>
</bill>
