<bill session="118" type="s" number="1091" updated="2025-11-18T19:23:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Consumer Online Payment Transparency and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Online Payment Transparency and Integrity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for automatic renewal protections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2460" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-29T13:54:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Consumer Online Payment Transparency and Integrity Act

This bill requires the seller of a good or service that includes certain automatic renewal or free-to-pay conversion features to provide consumers with (1) advance notice of the renewal or conversion, (2) an online mechanism for canceling the contract for the good or service, and (3) additional contact information (e.g., toll-free telephone number) for canceling the contract.

Additionally, notwithstanding the consumer's consent to the initial term, the seller of a good or service that includes an automatic renewal contract must obtain the consumer's express informed consent to renew the contract on an annual basis prior to charging the consumer for the renewal.

Notwithstanding the consumer's consent to a free trial, the seller of a good or service that includes a free-to-pay conversion feature must obtain the consumer's express informed consent to renew the contract not less than seven days before the expiration of the free trial period and before charging the consumer for the renewal.

The bill provides for enforcement of these requirements by the Federal Trade Commission.</summary>
</bill>
