<bill session="108" type="s" number="783" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to expedite the granting of posthumous citizenship to members of the United States Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expedite the granting of posthumous citizenship to members of the United States Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001141"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on the Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5256" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2003-04-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5256" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11T10:03:01-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="1691" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s530"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed Senate amended">Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide that a request for the granting of posthumous citizenship to a member of the armed forces who died from an active service-related injury or disease incurred during a period of military hostilities may be filed: (1) upon locating the next-of-kin, and if so requested by the next-of-kin, by the Secretary of Defense (or designee) with the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services in the Department of Homeland Security immediately upon the death of that person; or (2) by the next-of-kin. (Current law provides for such filing only by the next-of-kin or other representative.)States that Director of the Bureau of Citizenship and Immigration Services shall approve a request for posthumous citizenship filed by the next-of-kin if: (1) the request is filed within two years after the later of enactment of this section or the date of the person's death; (2) the request is accompanied by a duly authenticated certificate from the executive department under which the person served attesting to the person's honorable service and service-related death; and (3) the Director finds that the person satisfied certain enlistment location or post-enlistment status requirements. (Current law provides for approval by the Attorney General within two years after the later of March 6, 1990, or the person's death.)States that the Director (currently the Attorney General) shall send the documentation of posthumous citizenship to the next-of-kin.States that this Act shall take effect as if enacted on September 11, 2001.</summary>
</bill>
