<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1963</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-13T04:49:35Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-13T04:49:35Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-11-04</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-11-04T17:58:44Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-11-04</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S12404-12406)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-11-04</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S12402-12404)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-11-04</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B000243</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Baucus, Max [D-MT]</fullName>
        <firstName>MAX</firstName>
        <lastName>BAUCUS</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MT</state>
        <middleName>SIEBEN</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001057</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Coleman, Norm [R-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Norm</firstName>
        <lastName>Coleman</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2006-01-26</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economic statistics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Farm income</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Farmers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government paperwork</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Labor and Employment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Trade adjustment assistance</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Foreign Trade and International Finance</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-11-04</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-01-23T20:57:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2005- Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to prohibit an adversely affected worker that would otherwise be entitled to a trade readjustment allowance (TRA) from being denied such allowance because of a pending judicial or administrative appeal regarding denial by the Secretary of Labor of a trade adjustment assistance (TAA) petition.<br> </p> <p>Establishes the Office of the Trade Adjustment Assistance Advisor in the Department of Labor.</p> <p>Requires an employer's legal counsel or officer to certify any TAA petitions submitted to the Secretary as well as the accuracy or completeness of any requested evidence or information regarding the petition.</p> <p>Modifies TAA certification requirements for a group of workers (including those in any agricultural firm or subdivision) where there has been a shift in production by such workers' firm or subdivision to a foreign country of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by such firm or subdivision. Repeals the additional requirements that: (1) such country be a party to a free trade agreement with the United States or a beneficiary country under the Andean Trade Preference Act, African Growth and Opportunity Act, or the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act; or (2) there has been or is likely to be an increase in imports of articles like or directly competitive with articles produced by such firm or subdivision.</p> <p>Changes eligibility requirements for the demonstration project for alternative trade adjustment assistance for older workers.</p> <p></p> <p>Revises TRA eligibility requirements for adversely affected workers to: (1) extend training enrollment deadlines and TRA to accommodate such training; (2) modify funding for TRA training; and (3) include integrated workforce and entrepreneurial training in TRA approved training programs.</p> <p>Trade Adjustment Assistance Accountability Act - Requires the Secretary to collect necessary data and establish an effective performance measuring system to evaluate: (1) TAA program performance and participation before and after the effective date of Trade Adjustment Assistance Reform Act of 2002; and (2) ensure state participation in the program.</p> <p></p> <p></p> <p>Makes fishermen who harvest wild stock eligible for TAA.</p> <p>Modifies TAA group eligibility requirements for agricultural commodity producers.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2005</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to make miscellaneous improvements to trade adjustment assistance.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Trade Adjustment Assistance Improvement Act of 2005</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Trade Adjustment Assistance Accountability Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2005-11-04T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s1963is/xml/BILLS-109s1963is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-11-04</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance. (text of measure as introduced: CR S12404-12406)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
