<bill session="108" type="s" number="917" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:08Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to require the use of a certain minimum amount of funds for winter motorized access trails.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to require the use of a certain minimum amount of funds for winter motorized access trails.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5377" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Snowmobiles"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Directs the Secretary of Transportation to annually estimate revenues to the Highway Trust Fund derived from fuel purchased in each State for use in a snowmachine (defined as a motorized off-road vehicle intended to operate on snow, propelled by means of a revolving track or tracks), using information submitted by the Departments of Commerce and Treasury, and the International Snowmobile Manufacturers Association.Requires not less than the amount of such estimated revenues for a State to made available to that State for motorized access under the recreational trails program for activities that enhance winter motorized recreational trails. Sets forth permissible uses of such funds.Directs that $50,000 of the sums available to the Secretary for the administration of and research and technical assistance under the recreational trails program and for administration of the National Recreational Trails Advisory Committee be used each fiscal year for public information campaigns educating the public about, and encouraging, the safe use of snowmachines.</summary>
</bill>
