<bill session="117" type="s" number="4786" updated="2023-08-30T17:15:20Z">
  <state datetime="2022-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PASS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PASS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Agriculture Safeguards and Security Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Defense Production Act of 1950 to include the Secretary of Agriculture on the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States and require review of certain agricultural transactions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000605"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8274" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural trade"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-30T16:59:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Agriculture Safeguards and Security Act of 2022 or the PASS Act of 2022 

This bill establishes requirements to address the national security risk to the agricultural sector of the United States.

Specifically, the bill prohibits persons who are acting on behalf of China, Russia, Iran, or North Korea from purchasing or investing in U.S. agricultural land and companies. The President may waive this prohibition, on a case-by-case basis, if the President determines that the waiver is vital to U.S. national security interests.

The bill also places the Secretary of Agriculture on the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) and requires CFIUS to review certain transactions involving investments by foreign persons in the U.S. agricultural sector.

Additionally, the Department of Agriculture must report on the risks that foreign purchases of U.S. businesses engaged in agriculture pose to the agricultural sector of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
