<bill session="108" type="h" number="1954" updated="2023-01-15T16:03:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:28-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:28-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Naturalization and Family Protection for Military Members Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To revise the provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act relating to naturalization through service in the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Naturalization and Family Protection for Military Members Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000244"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000556" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000492" joined="2003-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000535" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000329" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000082" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000255" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000361" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000274" joined="2003-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000588" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000586" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001153" joined="2003-05-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 108-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-19" calendar="Union" number="57">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:43:58-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Sensenbrenner moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:44:29-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4899-4910" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T14:44:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1954.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T15:32:20-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T17:11:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4921" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="239" datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:28-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 414 - 5 (Roll no. 239).</text>
      <reference ref=" CR H4899-4901" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-06-04T17:19:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-10">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-12">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-16">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="142">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 142.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Marriage"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Passed House amended">Armed Forces Naturalization Act of 2003 - (Sec. 2) Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act, with respect to naturalization through armed forces service during nonhostile periods, to reduce the required service from three years to one year.Prohibits imposition of naturalization application or certificate fees and related State documentation fees for armed forces members seeking to naturalize.Permits revocation of citizenship, including posthumous citizenship, for military separation under other than honorable conditions before an individual has served honorably for at least five years.Provides for overseas naturalization proceedings for members of the armed forces.(Sec. 3) Prohibits imposition of a fee from a person seeking posthumous citizenship for a member of the armed forces who died from injury or disease incurred while serving honorably on active military service during a period of hostilities.Retains immediate relative status for the alien spouse (until remarriage), child (under 21 years old and unmarried), or parent (lawfully authorized to be in the United States on the day of the armed forces member's death) of a person granted posthumous U.S. citizenship through death from injury or disease incurred while serving honorably on active military service during a period of hostilities (posthumous citizen). Permits family member self-petitions for immigrant status in instances where the armed forces member had not filed prior to death. (Requires a petition for a child under 18 years old to be filed by a parent or legal guardian.) Requires all related petitions to be filed within two years of the granting of posthumous citizenship. Converts previously filed petitions for family sponsored immigrant status to immediate relative status upon granting of posthumous citizenship. Waives public charge grounds of inadmissibility. Makes such provisions applicable to the surviving spouse, child, and parent of a person who died on or after September 11, 2001.Permits a permanent resident surviving spouse of a posthumous citizen who died on or after September 11, 2001, to immediately apply for naturalization.(Sec. 4) Treats the alien spouse (until remarriage), child (under 21 years old and unmarried), or parent of a U.S. citizen who died on or after September 11, 2001, from injury or disease incurred while serving honorably on active military service during a period of hostilities as a valid petitioner for immediate family status. (States that the military branch of the deceased citizen shall determine whether appropriate requirements were satisfied.) Maintains the validity of an immediate relative petition filed prior to the citizen's death. Permits surviving spouse, child, or parent (lawfully authorized to be in the United States on the day of the citizen's death) self-petitions for immigrant status. (Requires a petition for a child under 18 years old to be filed by a parent or legal guardian.) Requires all related petitions to be filed within two years of the citizen's death. Waives public charge grounds of inadmissibility.Replaces specified references to "Attorney General" with "Secretary of Homeland Security.".</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-111</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
