<bill session="111" type="s" number="762" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:25Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fire Safe Communities Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote fire safe communities and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire Safe Communities Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000038" joined="2009-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4175-4177"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-07-10T21:52:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fire-Safe Communities Act of 2009 - Authorizes the Under Secretary for Federal Emergency Management of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to reduce the amount of the share of nonfederal funds required by the Fire Management Assistance Grant Program to 10% of the grant amount for a municipality at risk if such municipality has adopted: (1) a national wildland fire code, standard, or ordinance; or (2) a local ordinance, standard, or code that requires the retrofit of existing construction that provides for increased protection for the municipality from the threat of wildfire, such as a requirement to replace combustible roofing material used in existing structures.

Directs the Under Secretary to award grants to municipalities at risk to: (1) encourage responsible development in such municipalities; (2) mitigate the catastrophic effects of fires; and (3) encourage the retrofit of existing wildfire-prone structures. Limits grant awards to $1 million. Directs the Under Secretary to require that a person awarded a grant provide nonfederal funds equal to 25% of the grant amount for the purpose of the award.

Amends the Cooperative Forestry Assistance Act of 1978 to: (1) include as a purpose of the Community and Private Land Fire Assistance Program to enhance the capacity of local governments to integrate fire-resistant community and home design into local planning, zoning, building codes, property maintenance codes, and brush clearing ordinances; and (2) authorize a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of awarding grants to fire-safe communities located near federal land to assist in federal efforts to prevent and manage fires.</summary>
</bill>
