<bill session="117" type="s" number="4646" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Faster Payments to Veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Survivors Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to shorten the timeframe for claims by beneficiaries and the payment of benefits under Department of Veterans Affairs life insurance programs, to improve the management of undisbursed life insurance benefits by the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Faster Payments to Veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; Survivors Act of 2022</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001236" joined="2022-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8260" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Life, casualty, property insurance"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-01-05T12:38:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Faster Payments to Veterans' Survivors Act of 2022

This bill modifies policies and procedures related to the payment of benefits under certain life insurance programs administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA).

If a primary beneficiary has not made a claim for payment within one year (currently two years) after the death of the insured under the National Service Life Insurance (NSLI) program or the United States Government Life Insurance (USGLI) program, the VA is authorized to make payment to another designated beneficiary as if the primary beneficiary had predeceased the insured. If no designated beneficiary makes a claim within two years (currently four years) after the death of the insured, the VA is authorized to make a payment to a person the VA deems to be equitably entitled to such benefit.

The bill also modifies the beneficiary designation process under NSLI and USGLI. Specifically, if a person does not designate a beneficiary for insurance, or if the designated beneficiary predeceases the insured person, the VA must determine the beneficiary in a specified order of succession.

Additionally, the bill requires the VA to improve its processes and procedures with respect to identifying, locating, and disbursing undisbursed life insurance benefits to hard-to-find beneficiaries, including by improving its website search tools.</summary>
</bill>
