<bill session="108" type="s" number="627" updated="2023-01-15T22:48:18Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent the use of certain payments instruments, credit cards, and fund transfers for unlawful Internet gambling, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Internet Gambling Prohibition bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000352"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2003-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000320" joined="2003-03-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3745-3747" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-317.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-27">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Reported by Senator Shelby with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-173.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-10-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="346">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 346.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="21" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2143" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Checks"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Credit cards"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Electronic commerce"/>
    <term name="Electronic funds transfers"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Financial institutions"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interactive media"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Money laundering"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
    <term name="Wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Unlawful Internet Gambling Funding Prohibition Act - Establishes within the Department of the Treasury the Office of Electronic Funding Oversight to coordinate Federal efforts to prohibit restricted transactions.Prohibits any person engaged in the business of betting or wagering from knowingly accepting in connection with another person's participation in Internet gambling: (1) credit; (2) electronic fund transfers or funds transmitted through money transmitting businesses; (3) any instrument drawn by or on behalf of another and payable through any financial institution; or (4) the proceeds of any other form of financial transaction involving a financial institution as payer or financial intermediary on behalf of another person.Grants Federal district courts exclusive jurisdiction to prevent or restrain violations. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties.Limits relief granted against an interactive computer service. Specifies circumstances for the liability of any creditor, issuer, institution, operator, business, network, stored value product transaction, participant, or any interactive computer or telecommunications service.Calls for the United States, in deliberations with a foreign governments, to: (1) encourage cooperation in identifying whether Internet gambling operations are being used for money laundering or other crimes; (2) advance policies that promote international cooperation in enforcement; and (3) encourage the Financial Action Task Force on Money Laundering to study the extent to which Internet gambling operations are being used for money laundering purposes.Modifies Federal criminal code provisions on gambling to: (1) include satellite and microwave communications and communications from fixed or mobile sources; and (2) increase the penalty for unlawful transmission of wagering information.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-173</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
