<bill session="109" type="hc" number="310" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:45Z">
  <state datetime="2005-11-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to unilateral altering, by the European Union, of the standards for imports of certain wood products.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Expressing the sense of the Congress with respect to unilateral altering, by the European Union, of the standards for imports of certain wood products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000262"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on International Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="European Union"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International law"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Plant protection"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wood"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-12-01T20:24:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Expresses the sense of Congress that the European Union's unilateral attempt to alter the International Standard for Phytosanitary Measures Number 15 (ISPM 15) as it applies to imports of wood packaging materials violates the International Plant Protection Convention (IPPC).

Urges the President to ask the European Commission to agree to: (1) suspend the requirement that all wood packaging be debarked until there is credible scientific evidence of the need for such a standard; (2) allow the processing of relevant scientific data through authorized IPPC channels; (3) develop a clear definition of "debarked" wood packaging for pallets and containers, if the relevant IPPC entities conclude that changing ISPM 15 is technically justified, and communicate it to all participating nations in a clear and unambiguous manner; (4) allow sufficient time for the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service of the U.S. Department of Agriculture to establish a system for using a "debark" mark or other stamp or indication for pallets and containers; and (5) establish an implementation date for the new requirement with which U.S. wood packaging manufacturers can reasonably comply.</summary>
</bill>
