<bill session="108" type="s" number="1104" updated="2021-09-29T22:15:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-22">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for parental involvement in abortions of dependent children of members of the Armed Forces.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to provide for parental involvement in abortions of dependent children of members of the Armed Forces.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000953"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000442" joined="2004-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read the first time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under Read the First Time.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-05-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="114">
      <text>Read the second time. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 114.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Guardian and ward"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military hospitals"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Parent and child"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-29T14:53:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prohibits physicians from using facilities of the Department of Defense (DOD) to perform an abortion on a pregnant unemancipated minor who is a child of a member of the armed forces unless: (1) the physician gives at least 24 hours actual notice to the member, another parent of the minor, or a court-appointed conservator or guardian; (2) the judge of an appropriate district court issues an order authorizing the minor to consent to the abortion; (3) the appropriate district court by its inaction constructively authorizes such consent; or (4) the physician concludes that a condition exists that necessitates immediate abortion and certifies to the appropriate medical officer of DOD, and in the patient's medical record, the medical indications supporting such judgment. Outlines provisions concerning: (1) alternative notification; and (2) physician penalties for violations.

Allows: (1) such a minor, under specified procedures, to file with the court an application for the performance of the abortion without parental or guardian notification; and (2) for judicial appeal of a denial of such application.</summary>
</bill>
