<bill session="119" type="h" number="1541" updated="2025-05-01T18:31:51Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wireless Broadband Competition and Efficient Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wireless Broadband Competition and Efficient Deployment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that a project for the collocation of a personal wireless service facility is not subject to requirements to prepare certain environmental or historical preservation reviews.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000619"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-01T18:29:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Wireless Broadband Competition and Efficient Deployment Act

This bill exempts&#160;projects that involve the installation or modification of certain wireless communications facilities&#160;from specified federal environmental and historic preservation review requirements.&#160;

Specifically, the bill exempts from review projects that involve&#160;(1) the mounting or installation of an eligible personal wireless service facility with an eligible personal wireless service facility that exists when an authorization request for the mounting or installation is filed with a state or local government or an Indian tribe; or (2) the modification of an eligible personal wireless service facility.&#160;To be exempt, the projects must also require a permit or other authorization from, or are otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Federal Communications Commission.&#160;

Under the bill, an eligible personal wireless service facility means an antenna, apparatus, or transmitting device and associated equipment for the provision of personal wireless communications service.&#160;

The bill specifies that these projects are not considered major federal actions under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 or undertakings under the National Historic Preservation Act, thus exempting such projects from the review procedures required under those acts.</summary>
</bill>
