<bill session="116" type="s" number="4087" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:08Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Carson City Public Land Correction Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Carson City Public Land Correction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the conveyance of certain Federal land in Carson City, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2020-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-27T14:52:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Carson City Public Land Correction Act

This bill provides for the conveyance of federal land in Carson City, Nevada.

The Department of the Interior must convey approximately 258 acres of identified federal land to Carson City.

The Department of Agriculture shall convey to Carson City, without consideration, a parcel of approximately 0.45 acres of identified Forest Service land for the expansion of a roadway in the city.

Interior shall dispose of approximately 28 acres of federal land identified as the Prison Hills Property. On the disposal of such land, Carson City shall retain (1) a public utility easement, concurrent with Koontz Lane and Conti Drive in the city, that provides waterlines and access to the water tank immediately east of such parcels of federal land; and (2) an existing drainage easement for a future detention basin.

If Carson City offers to convey to Interior the approximately 21 acres of land identified as Bennett Ave Properties and Pinion Hills Dr Property, Interior shall accept the offer and then dispose of the land conveyed to it.

Carson City may enter into an agreement to sell, lease, or otherwise convey all or a portion of the approximately 75 acres of identified city land in which the Bureau of Land Management has a reversionary interest to third parties for public purposes.

The bill provides for the disposition of the proceeds of the land sales conducted pursuant to this bill.</summary>
</bill>
