<bill session="116" type="s" number="2870" updated="2022-11-01T05:17:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restricting Solitary Confinement in Immigration Detention Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restricting Solitary Confinement in Immigration Detention Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the use of solitary confinement and other forms of restrictive housing in immigration detention, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2019-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2019-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001075" joined="2019-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6607-6610" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Immigrant health and welfare"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-10T14:52:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restricting Solitary Confinement in Immigration Detention Act of 2019

This bill places limits on solitary confinement in U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) facilities.

Solitary confinement shall be (1) limited to the shortest duration and least restrictive conditions necessary, and (2) consistent with the rationale for placing the alien in solitary confinement.

Administrative segregation (a type of solitary confinement) shall (1) be limited to where a substantial and immediate threat makes such segregation necessary; (2) be limited in duration, with certain exceptions; and (3) not be used to discipline.

An alien who requires protection (1) may be placed in solitary confinement upon the alien's request, and (2) shall be transferred to a safer alternative upon the alien's request.

The bill places additional restrictions on placing a vulnerable individual in solitary confinement, such as an individual who (1) is a minor; (2) has a serious disability or mental illness or; or (3) is pregnant or had just given birth. Generally, such individuals may not be placed in solitary confinement absent a substantial and immediate threat.

An alien may not be placed in solitary confinement based on (1) identification as lesbian, gay, bisexual, or transgender; (2) HIV status; (3) race, religion, or nationality; or (4) the alien's report of misconduct.

An alien in solitary confinement shall receive a weekly mental health evaluation. The Office for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties within the Department of Homeland Security shall have unrestricted access to ICE facilities, records, and personnel.

The bill imposes various training, reporting, and data collection requirements related to solitary confinement.</summary>
</bill>
