<bill session="117" type="h" number="3510" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Step Implementation Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To reform sentencing laws and correctional institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Step Implementation Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2021-12-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2022-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000194" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2021-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2021-12-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1014" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-28T10:30:57Z" status="Introduced in House">First Step Implementation Act of 2021

This bill makes various changes related to federal sentencing law and requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to establish procedures to ensure the prompt release and accuracy of employment-related background check records.

The bill

 allows certain reduced mandatory minimum sentences for drug offenses to be applied retroactively to offenders who committed their offenses on or before December 21, 2018; permits a court, in certain circumstances, to grant safety valve relief (i.e., impose a sentence without regard to the statutory mandatory minimum penalty for certain drug offenses) for an otherwise eligible defendant who does not meet the requirement pertaining to criminal history; permits a court to reduce a sentence imposed on a defendant convicted as an adult for an offense committed as a juvenile if the defendant has served at least 20 years of the sentence; establishes a process to seal and expunge certain records of juvenile nonviolent offenses; and requires DOJ to establish and enforce procedures to ensure that records exchanged for employment-related background checks are promptly released and accurate.</summary>
</bill>
