<bill session="113" type="h" number="1211" updated="2023-01-11T13:23:22Z">
  <state datetime="2014-02-25T19:01:57-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2014-02-25T19:01:57-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2013-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FOIA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FOIA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FOIA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2013</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FOIA Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2014</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 552 of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the Freedom of Information Act), to provide for greater public access to information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2013-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2013-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-03-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2013-07-16">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 113-155.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2013-07-16" calendar="Union" number="112">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 112.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:03:29-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Issa moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1887" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:03:43-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1887-1891" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:03:47-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1211.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T15:17:10-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2014-02-25T18:30:40-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1921-1922" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="63" datetime="2014-02-25T19:01:57-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 410 - 0 (Roll no. 63).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1887-1890" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2014-02-26">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="113" type="s" number="2520" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2014-08-25T17:34:08Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">FOIA Oversight and Implementation Act of 2013 or the FOIA Act - (Sec. 2) Amends the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) to:

 require federal agencies to make public information disclosed under FOIA available in an electronic, publicly accessible format; require the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to ensure the existence and operation of a single, free website for submitting requests for records and receiving automated information about the status of a FOIA request; revise the standard for exempting information under FOIA to require foreseeable harm from disclosure (presumption of openess); expand the functions and reporting requirements of the Office of Government Information Services; expand the rights of individuals making a FOIA request to appeal an adverse determination; require agencies to determine whether the release of agency records would contribute significantly to public understanding of the operations or activities of government; require agencies to document additional search or duplication fees; require agencies to submit annual FOIA reports to the Director of the Office of Government Information Services, in addition to the Attorney General; expand the duties of the Chief FOIA Officer of each agency to require an annual compliance review of FOIA requirements; establish the Chief FOIA Officers Council to develop recommendations for increasing compliance with FOIA requirements; and require each agency to update its FOIA regulations within 180 days of the enactment of this Act. (Sec. 3) Requires: (1) OMB to establish a three-year pilot program to review the benefits of FOIAonline (the electronic online portal FOIAonline.regulations.gov) to process requests and release information as required by FOIA, (2) OMB to establish a plan to evaluate FOIAonline at no less than three agencies that have not previously participated in FOIAonline, and (3) the head of each federal agency participating in the pilot program to report to Congress on the impact of the program on agency processes under FOIA and whether the agency will continue to participate in FOIAonline.

(Sec. 4) Requires the Inspector General of each federal agency to: (1) periodically review compliance with FOIA disclosure requirements, including the timely processing of requests, assessment of fees and fee waivers, and the use of disclosure exemptions; and (2) make recommendations to the head of an agency, including recommendations for disciplinary action. Makes the improper withholding of information under FOIA a basis for disciplinary action.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 113-155</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
