<bill session="108" type="h" number="177" updated="2023-01-15T21:04:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Social Security Strengthening and Protection Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To strengthen and protect Social Security.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Strengthening and Protection Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000487"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Debt limit"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Social Security Strengthening and Protection Act of 2003 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to require the Managing Trustee of the Board of Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (social security trust funds) to establish guidelines mandating the eventual investment by the Managing Trustee of such portion of each social security trust fund not required to meet current withdrawals only in certain marketable interest-bearing obligations of the United States.Prohibits disinvestment of such trust fund amounts from public debt obligations, any refraining from making such investments, or any delay in making normal deposits in such trust funds for public debt limit-related purposes. Authorizes the sale or redemption of social security trust fund public debt obligations for payment of cash benefits and administrative expenses, with conditions, including advance notification to each House of the Congress and the Comptroller General before such sale or redemption.</summary>
</bill>
