<bill session="118" type="s" number="1256" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Global Aircraft Maintenance Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Aircraft Maintenance Safety Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, to require certain air carriers to provide reports with respect to maintenance, preventative maintenance, or alterations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3935" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1716" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-11T18:46:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Global Aircraft Maintenance Safety Improvement Act 

This bill addresses safety standards related to foreign aircraft repair stations.

Specifically, the bill requires that all foreign aircraft repair stations be subject to at least one unannounced safety inspection each year.

Further, mechanics and others working on U.S. registered aircraft at foreign repair stations are required to meet certain minimum certification or licensing standards.

Air carriers must submit annual reports to the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) with respect to heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines) performed outside the United States.

The bill also prohibits FAA officials from traveling internationally if a previously mandated final rule on drug and alcohol testing of employees at repair stations has not been published, with specified exceptions. In addition, the bill requires the FAA to initiate rulemaking to require certain employees of foreign repair stations to undergo security threat assessments.</summary>
</bill>
