<bill session="119" type="h" number="289" updated="2025-11-19T04:55:07Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SAP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAP Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting All Producers Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agricultural Act of 2014 with respect to the Acer access and development program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001318" joined="2025-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001196" joined="2025-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2025-08-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="56" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-21T19:21:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting All Producers Act of 2025 or the SAP Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to solicit input from maple industry stakeholders with respect to the research and education priorities of the maple industry for the Acer Access and Development Program (Acer). Specifically, the bill amends Acer to require USDA to consider the information provided through consultation with the maple industry when making program grants.

The bill also extends the program's authorization through FY2030.

As background, Acer provides competitive grants to states, tribal governments, and research institutions to support their efforts to promote the domestic maple syrup industry through activities&#160;associated with, among other things,&#160;the promotion of (1) research and education related to maple syrup production, and (2) natural resource sustainability in the maple syrup industry.</summary>
</bill>
