<bill session="118" type="h" number="4142" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:07Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CCP Wrongful Death Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CCP Wrongful Death Accountability Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a cause of action for any United States national who lost a relative due to COVID-19.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001222"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-17T19:06:22Z" status="Introduced in House">CCP Wrongful Death Accountability Act of 2023

 This bill authorizes certain private lawsuits against the Chinese government for harm resulting from the COVID-19 pandemic. Specifically, the bill authorizes a case to be brought by (1) a U.S. national if their immediate relative died of COVID-19 (i.e., wrongful death), or (2) a U.S. citizen for harm suffered by the citizen. The harms for which a citizen may seek damages include, but are not limited to, expenditures for overtime wages paid to frontline workers, vaccine or medical equipment purchases, and research and development costs.

Such a case must be brought in a U.S. district court. If the Chinese government fails to pay a judgment under one of these provisions within one year, the plaintiff may obtain a court order directing the federal government to pay the amount owed. If the federal government is ordered to pay the judgment, the federal government must deduct an equivalent amount from (1) any interest or debt owed by the United States to China, or (2) any amounts made available to provide U.S. assistance to China.</summary>
</bill>
