<bill session="117" type="h" number="2643" updated="2023-08-24T18:15:23Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Offshore Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement to further develop, finalize, and implement updated regulations for offshore oil and gas pipelines to address long-standing limitations regarding its ability to ensure active pipeline integrity and address safety and environmental risks associated with decommissioning, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Pipeline Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Offshore Pipeline Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2021-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2021-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001163" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2021-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2022-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2022-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 25 - 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 117-633.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-14" calendar="Union" number="456">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-24T18:00:15Z" status="Reported to House">Offshore Pipeline Safety Act

This bill establishes requirements to address the environmental risks of decommissioned oil and gas pipelines on the seafloor.

Specifically, the bill requires the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement (BSEE) to finalize regulations proposed in 2007 related to offshore pipelines. The regulations must require owners of oil and gas pipelines to provide for biannual, third-party inspections of pipelines and to equip pipelines with leak detection systems or devices. Further, the BSEE must issue regulations to charge an annual fee on such owners for the purpose of providing the BSEE with funds to decommission or remove offshore pipelines in the event the owner files for bankruptcy.

When determining whether to permit an owner to decommission such pipelines, the BSEE must consider the navigational hazards, any interferences with other uses of the Outer Continental Shelf, and the environmental impacts of the pipelines.

In addition, the BSEE must continually monitor the condition and location of all oil and gas pipelines that have been decommissioned and remain in place. If the BSEE identifies an exposed segment of any active or decommissioned pipeline, then it must either remove the pipeline from the ocean or ensure it is properly decommissioned and does not pose a threat. If a segment of any active pipeline is exposed or shifts, then the BSEE must resecure the segment to the sea floor.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-633</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
