<bill session="117" type="s" number="1065" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:52Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Environmental Management Liability Reduction and Technology Development Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase collaboration between offices within the Department of Energy to develop and deploy technology to assist the mission of the Office of Environmental Management.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Management Liability Reduction and Technology Development Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001111"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001183" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-13T20:20:55Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Environmental Management Liability Reduction and Technology Development Act of 2021

This bill establishes programs and requirements concerning the development and deployment of technology to assist the Office of Environmental Management within the Department of Energy in managing and directing the cleanup of contaminated nuclear weapons manufacturing and testing sites.

Specifically, the office must obtain from the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers an independent assessment of the lifecycle costs and schedules of the office's cleanup programs. The office must use the assessment to reevaluate the major cleanup challenges faced by the office, make any adjustments to the programs that are necessary to address those challenges, and evaluate potential savings from the development of new technologies over the life of the cleanup programs.

 In addition, the office must design and implement a science and technology management process for identifying, prioritizing, selecting, developing, and deploying the new knowledge and technologies needed to address the cleanup challenges.

The office must also establish an Incremental Technology Development Program to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of the cleanup processes of the office. In carrying out the program, the office may provide grants for technology development, demonstration, and deployment projects to improve such technologies.

Additionally, the office must establish a High-Impact Technology Development Program and a Fundamental Research Program to award grants to address cleanup challenges. The office must also establish the Environmental Management University Program and may provide research grants under the program.</summary>
</bill>
