<bill session="108" type="s" number="177" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:10Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Montgomery GI Bill Revitalization Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve benefits under the Montgomery GI Bill by establishing an enhanced educational assistance program and by repealing the requirement for reduction in pay for participation in the program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Montgomery GI Bill Revitalization Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000596"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Military discharges"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Montgomery GI Bill Revitalization Act of 2003 - Amends Federal basic educational assistance provisions (the Montgomery GI Bill) to authorize enhanced educational assistance to a member of the armed forces who, after September 30, 2003: (1) first enters on active duty; (2) reenlists or continues to serve on active duty; (3) serves a continuous period of active duty of four years; or (4) serves and is discharged or released for a service-connected disability, at the convenience of the Government (after serving at least 42 months of such duty), or due to a reduction in force. Limits to 36 months the period for such enhanced assistance. Requires the payment of educational expenses under such program. Provides: (1) a monthly stipend for approved programs of education; and (2) tutorial assistance.Repeals, with respect to such assistance: (1) a required monthly reduction in pay for individuals who do not elect to participate in such assistance program; (2) a provision authorizing individuals to elect not to receive such assistance; (3) the requirement that participants complete the requirements of a high school diploma or equivalency certificate prior to the end of their initial obligated period of service in order to be eligible to receive such assistance; and (4) provisions limiting an individual's opportunity to withdraw an election not to enroll in such assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
