<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="316" updated="2022-09-16T07:16:19Z">
  <amends type="h" number="8326" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-09-15T15:06:17-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001071"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-09-14"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 2 printed in Part E of House Report 117-464 to eliminate for-cause removal requirements of the Director of the Census Bureau, strike the requirement that the Deputy Director position be a career-reserved candidate and certain qualifications for the position, and add that the Deputy act as the Director in the event of a vacancy in the Director position.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment sought to eliminate for-cause removal requirements of the Director of the Census Bureau, strike the requirement that the Deputy Director position be a career-reserved candidate and certain qualifications for the position, and add that the Deputy act as the Director in the event of a vacancy in the Director position.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-09-15T15:06:17-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="434">
      <text>On agreeing to the Hice (GA) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 222 (Roll no. 434).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:16:54-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Hice (GA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7839-7840" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7839" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:06:17-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Hice (GA) amendment (A002) Failed by recorded vote: 210 - 222 (Roll no. 434).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:06:17-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14T17:16:54-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A002) offered by Mr. Hice (GA).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7839-7840" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7839" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-15T15:06:17-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-14">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
