<bill session="117" type="h" number="3747" updated="2022-12-30T17:32:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing American Research from Cyber Theft Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a pilot project for a nationwide network of secure computing enclaves for federally funded research in universities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing American Research from Cyber Theft Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001291"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2021-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-20T16:53:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Securing American Research From Cyber Theft Act

This bill establishes a pilot program and modifies a current program related to cybersecurity for federally supported research and data.

The bill directs the National Science Foundation to award grants to establish a pilot program to ensure the security of federally supported research data and to assist regional institutions of higher education and their researchers in complying with regulations regarding the safeguarding of sensitive information and other relevant regulations and federal guidelines.

The bill requires the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program to provide for improving the security, reliability, and resiliency of computing and networking systems used by higher education and other nonprofit research institutions for the processing, storage, and transmission of sensitive federally funded research and associated data.</summary>
</bill>
