<bill session="116" type="s" number="3380" updated="2022-02-08T23:15:32Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve patient safety by supporting State-based quality improvement efforts and through enhanced data collection and reporting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000802"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Surgery and anesthesia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-05-28T19:00:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Patient Safety Improvement Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to undertake actions related to (1) health care-associated&#160;infections (HAI), (2) antimicrobial stewardship, and (3) patient safety.

With respect to HAI, HHS must award grants for state and regional infection control programs and must establish a pilot program related to HAI data reporting by long-term care facilities and others. HHS must also award grants to eligible entities for infection control during patient care transitions, and the Centers for Medicare &amp;&#160;Medicaid Services (CMS) must develop guidance regarding transfers or discharges of patients with HAI diagnoses. The Government Accountability Office must evaluate the adequacy of oversight and validation of specified HAI data reporting.

With respect to antimicrobial stewardship, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention&#160;must award grants to states to implement antimicrobial stewardship plans and must otherwise take steps to address antibiotic prescribing.

With respect to patient safety, the HHS&#160;must incentivize state medical boards to require education on patient safety topics as a condition of licensure, and the CMS must harmonize quality measure reporting requirements through a collaborative that includes representatives from, among other groups, insurers and patient groups. In addition, as a condition of a hospital's participation in Medicare,&#160;members of the hospital's board must periodically receive training on relevant patient safety topics.</summary>
</bill>
