<bill session="116" type="h" number="5864" updated="2022-02-09T02:44:07Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Energy Frontiers Through Carbon Innovation Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish and support the research, development, and demonstration of advanced carbon capture and utilization technologies at the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Energy Frontiers Through Carbon Innovation Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001120"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="3828" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-08T19:00:44Z" status="Introduced in House">New Energy Frontiers Through Carbon Innovation Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish and support the research, development, and demonstration of carbon capture, storage, and utilization technologies and techniques.

Specifically, DOE must

 establish and operate a national Carbon Utilization Energy Innovation Hub which must focus on early stage research and development activities, including post-combustion and pre-combustion capture of carbon dioxide; carry out a program to award competitive grants to certain entities for the capture of carbon dioxide produced during the generation of natural gas-generated power; accelerate the development of commercially viable carbon capture technologies to reduce carbon dioxide emissions, including to improve the thermodynamics, kinetics, scalability, durability, and flexibility of carbon capture technologies used during the generation of electricity from natural gas power systems; enter into cooperative agreements with certain entities to construct and operate no more than five facilities to capture carbon dioxide from natural gas generating power facilities; and identify any barriers to the commercial development of carbon capture technologies.</summary>
</bill>
