<bill session="116" type="h" number="6905" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIRST COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Care Delivery Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a program for granting lawful permanent resident status to alien health care professionals providing medical services during the COVID-19 emergency, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Implementation of Recruiting, Staffing, and Triage for COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Care Delivery Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIRST COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Care Delivery Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-15T18:03:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Implementation of Recruiting, Staffing, and Triage for COVID-19 Care Delivery Act of 2020 or the FIRST COVID-19 Care Delivery Act of 2020

This bill contains provisions to increase the number of health care professionals during an emergency period, in particular the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) emergency, such as by relaxing certain immigration requirements.

The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) shall provide lawful permanent resident status to a qualifying alien who served as a physician or nurse during the COVID-19 emergency and is not otherwise ineligible for such status. To qualify, the alien must have (1) received an H (specialty profession) or J (exchange visitor) visa, (2) received temporary protected status, or (3) been covered under the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals Program.

For an alien seeking lawful permanent resident status under this bill, DHS shall waive (1) certain eligibility requirements, such as any applicable foreign residency requirements; and (2) any annual numerical limitations.

During an emergency period, DHS shall waive (1) any annual numerical limitations for a qualified alien seeking admission under an H or J visa as a physician or nurse, and (2) the two-year foreign residency requirement for certain aliens seeking readmission as a physician or nurse.

During an emergency period, the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS) shall not impose any caps on the number of medical interns enrolled in any CMS-funded programs. In such a period, a state may waive licensing requirements for an alien physician or nurse admitted under an H or J visa.</summary>
</bill>
