<bill session="117" type="s" number="5346" updated="2023-11-19T04:17:03Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Brokered Deposit Affiliate-Subsidiary Modernization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Brokered Deposit Affiliate-Subsidiary Modernization Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to exclude affiliates and subsidiaries of insured depository institutions from the definition of deposit broker, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-06T16:18:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Brokered Deposit Affiliate-Subsidiary Modernization Act of 2022

This bill excludes affiliates&#160;and subsidiaries of an insured depository institution from certain limitations applicable to brokered deposits. (Brokered deposits are a type of deposit accepted by an institution from a third-party deposit broker for investment purposes. Institutions that accept brokered deposits are subject to additional regulatory requirements, including those related to liquidity.)

The bill also expands the definition of an employee of an insured depository institution, thereby exempting these individuals from treatment as a deposit broker. Specifically, the bill includes as an employee (1) an individual who receives compensation in any form from an insured depository institution or from an affiliate or subsidiary, and (2) a registered representative of a broker or dealer that is an affiliate or subsidiary of an insured depository institution.</summary>
</bill>
