<bill session="116" type="s" number="4016" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:12Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Maintaining United States National Security Interests in Europe Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maintaining United States National Security Interests in Europe Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reiterate the support of Congress for the relationship between the United States and the Federal Republic of Germany, to prevent the weakening of the deterrence capacity of the United States in Europe, to prohibit use of funds to withdraw the United States Armed Forces from Europe, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2020-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7246" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense spending"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-11T18:12:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Maintaining United States National Security Interests in Europe Act

This bill requires the President to take certain actions before reducing the overall presence of the Armed Forces in Europe, such as by withdrawing Armed Forces or Department of Defense personnel or closing a U.S. military base in Europe. The bill also contains other related provisions.

Generally, no later than 180 days before taking an action to reduce the U.S. presence in Europe, the President shall report to Congress (1) a justification for the action, (2) the scope and description of the reduction, (3) an explanation of the action's national security benefit, and (4) a plan to offset the reduction in conventional deterrence against Russian aggression stemming from the action. This requirement shall not apply if (1) a country hosting the U.S. forces requests the reduction in writing, or (2) Congress passes a joint resolution or act expressly authorizing the reduction.

The President shall report to Congress a detailed account of the decisionmaking process behind the decision to withdraw Armed Forces members from Germany that was announced on June 15, 2020.</summary>
</bill>
