<bill session="116" type="h" number="8034" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:26Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Infertility Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Infertility Treatment Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide coverage for infertility treatment and standard fertility preservation services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001285"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Family services"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-11T13:00:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Infertility Treatment Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to furnish infertility treatments, standard fertility preservation services, or both to a covered veteran, spouse, partner, or gestational surrogate if the individuals jointly apply for such treatments or services. A covered veteran is a veteran who has infertility and is enrolled in the VA health care system.

Under the bill, in vitro fertilization treatment may only be furnished for up to three completed cycles resulting in live birth or six attempted cycles, whichever occurs first.

The bill authorizes the VA to pay the adoption expenses (for up to three adoptions) for covered veterans.

 During the interim period before infertility treatment and adoption assistance regulations are in effect, the VA must ensure that fertility counseling and treatment for veterans may also be furnished to the partner of a veteran regardless of whether the veteran and the partner are married. Additionally, the VA may furnish such counseling and treatment using donated gametes or embryos.

The VA must facilitate research conducted collaboratively by the Department of Defense and the Department of Health and Human Services to improve the ability of the VA to meet the long-term reproductive health care needs of veterans who have infertility conditions.

Finally, the VA must ensure that useful information produced by such research is disseminated throughout the Veterans Health Administration.</summary>
</bill>
