<bill session="119" type="s" number="473" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:56Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to include screening for loneliness and coordination of supportive services and health care to address the negative health effects of loneliness, to require a report on loneliness, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SENIOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SENIOR Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Engagement and Network Initiatives for Older Relief Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2025-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2025-02-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-05T20:43:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Social Engagement and Network Initiatives for Older Relief Act or the SENIOR Act

This bill expands the scope of authorized&#160;Administration on Aging (AOA) grants to include&#160;services addressing loneliness in older individuals (i.e., aged 60 or older), and requires a report evaluating whether certain federal programs are adequately addressing this topic.

Under current law, the&#160;AOA provides grants to states for disease prevention and health promotion services for older individuals, including services addressing the negative health effects of social isolation.&#160;The bill expands the scope of the services eligible for&#160;these grants to include services addressing the negative health effects of loneliness.

Also, the bill requires the Department of Health and Human Services to submit to Congress a report (1)&#160;evaluating whether its programs for older individuals&#160;are adequately addressing loneliness,&#160;and (2)&#160;recommending measures for reducing the negative health effects of loneliness and fostering multigenerational family connections.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
