<bill session="108" type="h" number="1654" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:07Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Legislative Oversight of Significant Regulations Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 8 of title 5, United States Code, to require congressional approval of proposed rules considered by the Congress to be significant rules.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Oversight of Significant Regulations Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology and the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU01" name="House Rules" subcommittee="Technology and the House" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Executive orders"/>
    <term name="Expedited congressional procedure"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Right of petition"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-08-22T17:46:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Legislative Oversight of Significant Regulations Act of 2003 - Revises provisions governing the congressional review of agency rulemaking. Imposes review requirements upon only rules described as "significant" in the authorizing Act. Prohibits a significant rule from taking effect before the enactment of a joint resolution comprising solely of the text of such rule.

 Requires the report submitted by a Federal agency proposing a significant rule to include an explanation of the specific statutory interpretation under which a rule is proposed, including an explanation of whether the interpretation is expressly required by the text of the statute or, if not, an explanation that the interpretation is within the permissible range and an explanation of why the interpretation was selected. Provides that if Congress fails to enact a joint resolution approving a proposed significant rule, no court or agency may infer any intent of Congress from any action or inaction with regard to such rule or related statute.

 Sets forth: (1) the congressional approval procedure for significant rules (current law sets forth disapproval procedure for rules); and (2) provisions with respect to revising or revoking an existing rule by joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
