<bill session="108" type="s" number="803" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mobilized Reserve Savings Account Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a deduction to members of the Armed Forces reserves for contributions to savings accounts which may be used when the members are called to active duty.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mobilized Reserve Savings Account Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2003-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2003-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Financial statements"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mobilized Reserve Savings Account Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a qualified armed forces reservist to deduct annual contributions to an Armed Forces reserve savings account (as defined by this Act). Limits annual contributions to the lesser of $5,000, or $25,000 reduced by previous contributions to such accounts.Treats account distributions from deductible contributions as taxable income. Provides an additional ten percent tax unless the distribution is made: (1) while the account holder is serving on active duty (including the 60-day period immediately preceding or following such period); or (2) after the account holder ceases to be a member of a reserve component or is transferred to such component's retired list.Exempts an Armed Forces reserve savings account from taxation unless such account has ceased to be an Armed Forces reserve savings account due to a prohibited transaction by a contributor or a person for whose benefit such account was established.</summary>
</bill>
