<bill session="108" type="h" number="2168" updated="2023-01-15T15:33:24Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Guard and Reserves Reform Act for the 21st Century</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to revise the age and service requirements for eligibility to receive retired pay for non-regular service; to provide TRICARE eligibility for members of the Selected Reserve of the Ready Reserve and their families; to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow employers a credit against income tax with respect to employees who participate in the military reserve components and to allow a comparable credit for participating reserve component self-employed individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Guard and Reserves Reform Act for the 21st Century</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000057"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Total Force.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS27" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Total Force" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="2413" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="1000" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military pensions"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Retirement age"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-08T19:53:36Z" status="Introduced in House">National Guard and Reserves Reform Act for the 21st Century - Makes an individual eligible for retired pay for non-regular (reserve) military service if such individual: (1) satisfies one of specified combinations of minimum age (between 55 and 60) and years of service (between 20 and 30); (2) performed the last six years of qualifying service in currently authorized categories of military service, but not while a member of a regular component, the Fleet Reserve, or the Fleet Marine Corps Reserve; and (3) is not entitled to any other retirement pay from an armed force or as a member of the Fleet Reserves. Authorizes a member of the Selected Reserve to enroll for self or for self and family under the TRICARE program (a Department of Defense managed health care program).Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide a reserve component employment credit equal to the sum of the employment credit with respect to all qualified employees of the taxpayer and the self-employment credit of a qualified self-employed taxpayer. Limits the credit to $25,000 for each qualified employee. Disallows the credit for failure to comply with reserve member employment or reemployment rights, or when a reserve member is called or ordered to active duty for training.</summary>
</bill>
