<bill session="116" type="s" number="4462" updated="2023-11-17T20:58:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-11-16">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-11-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FLOODS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Flood Level Observation, Operations, and Decision Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FLOODS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Flood Level Observation, Operations, and Decision Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Flood Level Observation, Operations, and Decision Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">FLOODS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">FLOODS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Flood Level Observation, Operations, and Decision Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">FLOODS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a national integrated flood information system within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2020-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Wicker with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-269.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-09-24" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="556">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 556.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2020-11-16" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6694-6698" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S6694-6698" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17T17:50:45-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-11-17T18:07:29-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8882" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hydrology and hydrography"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-21T00:49:32Z" status="Passed Senate">Flood Level Observation, Operations, and Decision Support Act or the FLOODS Act

This bill addresses forecasting and the communication of flood, tornado, and hurricane events by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).

Among other provisions, the bill

 directs NOAA to establish a National Integrated Flood Information System to better inform and provide for more timely decision-making to reduce flood-related effects and costs; establishes partnerships with institutions of higher education and federal agencies to improve total water predictions; designates a service coordination hydrologist at each National Weather Service River Forecast Center to increase impact-based decision support services at the state and local level; requires NOAA to evaluate and improve flood watches and warnings and communication of information to support preparation and responses to floods; ensures that the tornado warning improvement and extension program periodically examines the value of incorporating innovative observations, such as acoustic or infrasonic measurements, observations from phased array radars, and observations from mesonets; requires NOAA to estimate and communicate the frequency of precipitation; establishes an Interagency Coordinating Committee on Water Management to ensure that federal agencies that engage in water-related matters, including water storage and supplies, water quality and restoration activities, water infrastructure, transportation on rivers and inland waterways, and water forecasting, work together where such agencies have joint or overlapping responsibilities; and directs NOAA to conduct an analysis of gaps in the availability of snow-related data to assess and predict floods and flood impacts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-269</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
