<bill session="111" type="h" number="2680" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:54Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Territorial Health Parity Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Social Security Act to provide for payment parity for Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa under the Medicaid Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Territorial Health Parity Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2009-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000248" joined="2009-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1301-1302"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-15T21:33:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Territorial Health Parity Act of 2009 - Amends title XI of the Social Security Act (SSA) to sunset at the end of FY2009 the limitation on Medicaid payments to Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, and American Samoa.

Amends SSA title XIX (Medicaid) to: (1) repeal, as of the end of FY2011, the federal medical assistance percentage (FMAP) of 50% that applies to such territories; and (2) set the new FMAP for such territories at one determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) in consultation with the Secretary of the Interior. Specifies a transitional FMAP for such territories for FY2010-FY2011.

Requires the Secretary to report to Congress on the per capita income data used to promulgate the FMAP in the territories and how such data differ from the per capita income data used to promulgate FMAPs for the 50 states and the District of Columbia. Requires the report to include recommendations on how FMAPs can be calculated for the territories to ensure parity with the 50 states and the District of Columbia.

Amends the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996 to extend the Medicaid program to the citizens of the Freely Associated States (Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, and the Republic of Palau).

Amends SSA title XIX to set a 100% FMAP for otherwise qualified services rendered to such citizens.</summary>
</bill>
