<bill session="116" type="s" number="332" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Agent Orange Exposure Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agent Orange Exposure Fairness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to remove the manifestation period required for the presumptions of service connection for chloracne, porphyria cutanea tarda, and acute and subacute peripheral neuropathy associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Reported by Senator Moran with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="535">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 535.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="566" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-21T15:15:07Z" status="Reported to Senate">This bill requires the Government Accountability Office (GAO) to brief Congress and report on the efforts of the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide benefits to veterans who served in the Republic of Vietnam between January 9, 1962, and May 7, 1975, and have specified diseases associated with exposure to certain herbicide agents (i.e., chloracne, porphyria cutanea tarda, or acute or subacute peripheral neuropathy).

The VA must implement recommendations from the GAO report related to the adjudication of claims for benefits for veterans with the specified diseases.</summary>
</bill>
