<bill session="117" type="h" number="2266" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">COLA Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide for a minimum annual cost-of-living increase for Social Security benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Certainty for Older Living Americans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COLA Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000798"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-30T14:49:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Certainty for Older Living Americans Act of 2021 or the COLA Act of 2021

This bill sets out an alternative method to calculate cost-of-living adjustments for Social Security benefits.

The current method is based on the annual change in the Consumer Price Index for Urban Wage Earners and Clerical Workers, which results in no or small increases to benefits following a year with deflation or low inflation. The alternative method established by this bill is based on a 10-year average of cost-of-living adjustments. The Social Security Administration must use whichever method results in the larger increase for a given year.

In addition, the Department of Labor and the Department of Commerce must establish a working group to make recommendations on incorporating specified economic data when producing relevant consumer price indexes.</summary>
</bill>
