<bill session="119" type="h" number="228" updated="2025-09-10T20:11:19Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase and adjust for inflation the above-the-line deduction for teachers.</title>
    <title type="display">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase and adjust for inflation the above-the-line deduction for teachers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Income tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-21T19:46:59Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill increases the&#160;above-the-line tax deduction for unreimbursed expenses incurred by an eligible educator for classroom supplies and certain professional development courses. (Above-the-line deductions are subtracted from gross income to calculate adjusted gross income.)

Under current law, an eligible educator may deduct up to $300 in 2025 (adjusted annually for inflation) for unreimbursed expenses for classroom supplies and certain professional development courses. An eligible educator is defined as a kindergarten through grade 12 teacher, instructor, counselor, principal, or aide who works at least 900 hours during a school year&#160;in a school that provides elementary or secondary education. &#160;

Under the bill, an eligible educator may deduct up to $1,000 in 2025 for unreimbursed expenses for classroom supplies and certain professional development. For tax years after 2025, the $1,000 limit on the tax deduction is adjusted annually for inflation.</summary>
</bill>
