<bill session="116" type="h" number="7118" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Vote From Home America Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to require States to conduct elections for Federal office held in 2020 solely through the use of mail-in absentee ballots, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vote From Home America Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000808"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001084" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2020-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6847" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-19T17:04:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Vote From Home America Act of 2020

This bill requires states to conduct federal elections held in 2020 through the use of mail-in absentee ballots. States are prohibited from operating any polling place during this time, except for elections that occur within 30 days of the bill's enactment (e.g., certain primary elections).

Specifically, states must (1) transmit absentee ballots to each registered voter at least three weeks before the date of the election; (2) provide self-sealing return envelopes with prepaid postage for absentee ballots; (3) allow voters to cure certain signature discrepancies; (4) permit certain individuals, such as voters with disabilities, to receive assistance to complete and submit their ballot; and (5) provide secured drop boxes at which individuals may drop off their completed absentee ballots. States are prohibited from imposing any additional requirements on the ability of an individual to vote by absentee ballot.

Further, the Election Assistance Commission must make payments to states to implement the provisions of the bill. States must pass through a portion of the payments to local jurisdictions and tribal governments.</summary>
</bill>
