<bill session="119" type="s" number="98" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-26">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Broadband Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Broadband Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Rural Broadband Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Rural Broadband Protection Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Communications Commission to establish a vetting process for prospective applicants for high-cost universal service program funding.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001047"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001114" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-01-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2025-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cruz without amendment. With written report No. 119-14.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-04-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="48">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 48.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-06-26" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3570" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3570" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-06-27">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-03T14:32:05-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-07-03T14:32:38-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1768" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-14T13:45:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Broadband Protection Act of 2025

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to establish a process to vet applicants for certain funding programs that support affordable broadband deployment in high-cost areas, including rural communities.

Specifically, the FCC must conduct a rulemaking to develop a vetting process for applicants seeking funding under high-cost universal service programs for the deployment of a broadband-capable network and the provision of supported services over the network. The FCC must require applications for such funding to document each applicant&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s technical, financial, and operational capabilities related to the proposed deployment, as well as a reasonable business plan.&#160;

The FCC must evaluate applications against reasonable and well-established standards and must consider each applicant&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s history of compliance with the requirements of other government broadband funding programs. After the rulemaking is finalized, funds may only be awarded to applicants that satisfy the standards established therein.&#160;

Finally, the FCC must set financial penalties for applicants that default in some manner during the evaluation process before they are authorized to begin receiving support. &#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 119-14</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
