<bill session="118" type="s" number="1248" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safer Detention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safer Detention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expand eligibility for and provide judicial review for the Elderly Home Detention Pilot Program, and make other technical corrections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-03-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2024-01-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2024-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2023-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2023-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1296-1297" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-01T15:27:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Safer Detention Act of 2023

This bill expands statutory authority for federal prisoners to be released before completing their sentences or to be placed in the community to serve the final portion of their sentences.

First, the bill makes changes to the early release pilot program. The early release pilot program authorizes the Bureau of Prisons to release early and place on home confinement elderly offenders and terminally ill offenders who meet eligibility criteria. This bill

 expands eligibility to offenders serving time for an offense under the laws of the District of Columbia, expands eligibility to offenders who have served at least one-half (currently, two-thirds) of their prison term, reduces the amount of time an offender must serve by the good time credits earned by the offender, and creates a judicial review process for prisoners. Second, the bill expands eligibility for the compassionate release process to prisoners sentenced before November 1, 1987. The compassionate release process authorizes federal courts to reduce a prisoner's sentence and impose a term of probation or supervised released in certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
