<bill session="108" type="h" number="2531" updated="2023-01-15T16:33:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-06-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-06-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Wetland Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act relating to wetlands mitigation banking, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Wetland Restoration Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000072" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000166" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000323" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000058" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000074" joined="2003-06-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Environmental law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Right of property"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-09T21:15:09Z" status="Introduced in House">American Wetland Restoration Act - Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to authorize the Secretary of the Army to issue mitigation bank (specified wetland resource restoration, creation, or enhancement projects or projects consisting solely of preservation of wetlands chartered by the Secretary for purposes of providing mitigation credits to offset wetland losses authorized by permits allowing activities in U.S. waters) charters.Authorizes a mitigation bank, upon receipt of its charter, to offer mitigation credits for sale and to provide compensatory mitigation for activities requiring authorization under the Act or provide required injunctive relief in an enforcement action by the Secretary or the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency. Directs the Secretary and the Administrator to establish standards and criteria applicable to the use of on-site mitigation, in lieu fees, and other off-site mitigation as compensatory mitigation that are similar to those applicable to a mitigation bank.Allows a State that operates an approved program regulating the discharge of dredged or fill material into navigable waters to administer a wetland mitigation banking program in accordance with State procedures if such banking program is approved by the Administrator as part of the State's dredged or fill material program.</summary>
</bill>
