<bill session="117" type="h" number="8088" updated="2022-12-29T17:18:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Prioritizing Clean Energy and Climate Cooperation with India Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prioritizing Clean Energy and Climate Cooperation with India Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the United States-India Climate and Clean Energy Partnership to facilitate clean energy cooperation with India, to enhance cooperation with India on climate mitigation, resilience, and adaptation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2022-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2719" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-05T11:26:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Prioritizing Clean Energy and Climate Cooperation with India Act of 2022 

This bill establishes the U.S.-India Climate and Clean Energy Agenda 2030 Partnership and addresses related issues.

The partnership shall serve as the primary forum and funding mechanism for U.S.-India cooperation on clean energy technology matters.

The Department of State must report to Congress a comprehensive multiyear strategy for implementing the partnership.

The bill requires programs to promote U.S.-India partnerships in (1) research and innovation for clean energy technologies, (2) initiatives for providing technical assistance for grid improvement and energy efficiency in India, and (3) initiatives to develop new renewable energy generation capacity in India.

The U.S. Agency for International Development must work cooperatively with India's government on integrating scientifically supported climate change risk reduction and building resilience capacities in India.

The State Department must report to Congress on the prospects for cooperation between U.S. states and states in India on clean energy issues.</summary>
</bill>
