<bill session="116" type="h" number="5736" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:04Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-30T13:22:01-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-09-30T13:22:01-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Transnational White Supremacist Extremism Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transnational White Supremacist Extremism Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transnational White Supremacist Extremism Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Transnational White Supremacist Extremism Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Under Secretary for Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security to develop and disseminate a threat assessment regarding threats to the United States associated with foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000613"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2020-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence and Counterterrorism.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Intelligence and Counterterrorism Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30T13:10:53-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Underwood moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30T13:12:34-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5077-5078" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30T13:12:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5736.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2020-09-30T13:22:01-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5077" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-09-30T13:22:05-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Hate crimes"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-23T15:54:10Z" status="Passed House">Transnational White Supremacist Extremism Review Act

This bill directs the Office of Intelligence and Analysis of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop and disseminate a threat assessment and reference aid regarding threats to the United States associated with foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations.

The threat assessment and reference aid (1) shall be developed in coordination with DHS's Office of Civil Rights and Civil Liberties and other appropriate agencies and may be informed by existing products developed by such office and agencies; and (2) shall include an overview of symbols, flags, or other references utilized by adherents of foreign violent white supremacist extremist organizations.

The office shall share the threat assessment and reference aid with (1) state, local, and tribal law enforcement officials; and (2) owners and operators of online platforms to assist in identifying content that may be associated with a foreign violent white supremacist extremist organization that may violate the terms of service of such platforms, upon request from such platforms. Such office shall ensure that the threat assessment and reference aid does not contain the name or other identifiable information of any individual or organization engaged in lawful political or public discourse in the United States protected under the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
