<bill session="117" type="s" number="3210" updated="2023-08-04T00:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend to Black veterans of World War II, and surviving spouses and certain direct descendants of such veterans, eligibility for certain housing loans and educational assistance administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2022-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2022-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5905" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-04T00:36:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sgt. Isaac Woodard, Jr. and Sgt. Joseph H. Maddox GI Bill Restoration Act of 2021

This bill expands eligibility for Post-9/11 GI bill educational assistance benefits and the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) home loan program. Specifically, the bill explicitly includes the following persons as eligible veterans:

 Black veterans who served on active duty during World War II who can certify they were denied a specific benefit on the basis of race; and the living surviving spouses, children, grandchildren, or other direct descendants of such veterans described above who can certify the veteran was denied a specific benefit on the basis of race. Such veterans described above must apply for educational or home loan benefits within the five-year period after the passage of this bill to be eligible for benefits.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the number of individuals who received educational or housing loan benefits and the total value of such benefits administered by the VA due to the amendments made by the bill.

Finally, the VA must appoint a panel of independent experts to develop recommendations regarding additional benefits and assistance for female and minority members of the Armed Forces.</summary>
</bill>
