<bill session="117" type="h" number="5964" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the policies, procedures, and training for the United States Merchant Marine Academy, to authorize infrastructure replacement and improvement projects at the United States Merchant Marine Academy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001201"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW07" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Maritime Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3196" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-02T15:48:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Improving Protections for Midshipmen Act

This bill addresses sexual harassment and sexual assault at the U.S. Merchant Marine Academy and provides for greater diversity and inclusion at the academy and within the maritime transportation system workforce.

The Department of Transportation (DOT) shall establish a Sexual Assault Advisory Council to review the academy's policy on sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking and other relevant matters related to sexual assault and sexual harassment.

The DOT's Maritime Administration shall (1) establish an information management system to track the number of sexual assault or sexual harassment incidents every fiscal year at the academy, and (2) implement comprehensive in-person sexual assault risk-reduction and response training for all midshipmen at the academy.

Additionally, the bill designates a Special Victims' Counsel to provide legal assistance to any cadet of the academy who is the victim of a sex-related offense.

Further, the Coast Guard shall assess the feasibility of implementing a program modeled on the Catch a Serial Offender program of the Department of Defense. The bill also expands the authority of the Coast Guard to suspend or revoke a mariner's license on grounds related to sexual harassment or assault.

With respect to diversity and inclusion, DOT shall establish an interagency task force to discuss and share tools and practices that promote diversity and inclusiveness within the maritime transportation system workforce. The Maritime Administration shall promulgate a Diversity and Inclusion Action Plan to increase recruiting efforts in historically underrepresented communities.</summary>
</bill>
