<bill session="118" type="hr" number="75" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:46Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-31T14:06:32-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-31T14:06:32-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-01-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 7) relating to a national emergency declared by the President on March 13, 2020; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 139) to require Executive agencies to submit to Congress a study of the impacts of expanded telework and remote work by agency employees during the COVID-19 pandemic and a plan for the agency's future use of telework and remote work, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 382) to terminate the public health emergency declared with respect to COVID-19; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 497) to eliminate the COVID-19 vaccine mandate on health care providers furnishing items and services under certain Federal health care programs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the joint resolution (H.J. Res. 7) relating to a national emergency declared by the President on March 13, 2020; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 139) to require Executive agencies to submit to Congress a study of the impacts of expanded telework and remote work by agency employees during the COVID-19 pandemic and a plan for the agency's future use of telework and remote work, and for other purposes; providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 382) to terminate the public health emergency declared with respect to COVID-19; and providing for consideration of the bill (H.R. 497) to eliminate the COVID-19 vaccine mandate on health care providers furnishing items and services under certain Federal health care programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-1, by Mr. Burgess.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T10:06:19-05:00">
      <text>All bills are considered under a closed rule with one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-01-31" calendar="House" number="1">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 1.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T12:14:58-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H520-529" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T12:18:08-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T13:17:10-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 75, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question on H. Res 75 and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McGovern demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T13:30:28-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H530-531" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T13:56:29-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 218 - 209 (Roll no. 95).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="96" datetime="2023-01-31T14:06:32-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 208 (Roll no. 96).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H520-521" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-01-31T14:06:33-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hj" number="7" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="139" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="382" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="497" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-22T19:25:21Z" status="Passed House">This resolution sets forth the rule for consideration of

 H.J. Res. 7 (terminates the national emergency concerning COVID-19 declared by the President on March 13, 2020), H.R. 139 (Stopping Home Office Work's Unproductive Problems Act of 2023 or the SHOW UP Act of 2023, which requires executive agencies to reinstate the telework policies that were in place on December 31, 2019, and restricts implementation of expanded telework policies), H.R. 382 (Pandemic Is Over Act, which terminates the COVID-19 public health emergency that was declared on January 31, 2020), and H.R. 497 (Freedom for Health Care Workers Act, which nullifies a rule issued by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services that requires health care providers, as a condition of Medicare and Medicaid participation, to ensure that staff are fully vaccinated against COVID-19).</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-1</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
