<bill session="117" type="s" number="129" updated="2023-03-08T20:11:50Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Responder Fair RETIRE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit disabled law enforcement officers, customs and border protection officers, firefighters, air traffic controllers, nuclear material couriers, members of the Capitol Police, members of the Supreme Court Police, employees of the Central Intelligence Agency performing intelligence activities abroad or having specialized security requirements, and diplomatic security special agents of the Department of State to receive retirement benefits in the same manner as if they had not been disabled.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responder Fair RETIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responder Fair Return for Employees on Their Initial Retirement Earned Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2022-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2022-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2022-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="521" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency (CIA)"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers and employees"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-24T20:01:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">First Responder Fair Return for Employees on Their Initial Retirement Earned Act of 2021 or the First Responder Fair RETIRE Act

This bill allows disabled federal first responders (e.g., law enforcement officers, customs and border protection officers, and firefighters) to continue receiving federal retirement benefits in the same manner as though they had not been disabled.

Under current law, federal first responders are subject to a mandatory retirement age of 57. To facilitate this earlier retirement, federal first responders are required to pay a greater percentage of their salary towards retirement. Additionally, their annuity amount is calculated at a higher rate than other federal employees.

This bill allows a federal first responder to remain in the accelerated retirement system if they are placed in another civil service position outside of that system after returning to work from a work-related injury or illness. Further, if such an employee is separated from service before they are entitled to receive an annuity, they may receive a refund of their accelerated contributions.</summary>
</bill>
