<bill session="116" type="s" number="3335" updated="2022-09-15T20:16:24Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to convey certain Federal property in the State of Ohio to the Friends of Barker House.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Army to convey certain Federal property in the State of Ohio to the Friends of Barker House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2020-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5960" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1811" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="133" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes and releases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-05T15:13:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill directs the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to convey to the Friends of Joseph Barker, Jr., House organization, by quitclaim deed and without monetary consideration, all interest of the United States in the Judge Joseph Barker, Jr., House and a specified road tract in Washington County, Ohio, situated along the Ohio River. The Corps must also provide the organization with a specified easement.

The Corps shall make improvements and alterations to the house to facilitate conveyance of the property, including carrying out the conveyance of the house and road tract, subject to the condition that the total cost of those improvements and alterations shall be not more than $90,000.

Before providing a conveyance or easement under this bill, the Corps must investigate and report to the organization on the environmental condition of the property, including any potential hazardous, toxic, and radioactive waste. On completion and review, the organization may elect to refuse any conveyance or easement of any of the property.

The Corps may reserve and retain from any conveyance under this bill a right-of-way or any other right necessary for the operation and maintenance of the authorized federal channel along the Ohio River.</summary>
</bill>
