<bill session="119" type="h" number="769" updated="2025-07-01T14:18:05Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">All Aboard Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">All Aboard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations under which Amtrak is responsible for refunding rail passengers the cost of certain rail transportation that was canceled or delayed due to a failure of Amtrak, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-01T14:17:26Z" status="Introduced in House">All Aboard Act

This bill requires Amtrak to issue refunds to rail passengers for the purchase price of rail&#160;passenger transportation that is cancelled or delayed due to a failure of Amtrak.

Specifically, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must issue regulations requiring Amtrak to issue full refunds to passengers&#160;for the purchase price of the covered rail passenger transportation if there is a cancellation or a delay of more than three hours in the journey completion time that is due to a failure of Amtrak.

Under the bill,&#160;covered rail passenger&#160;transportation&#160;means (1) rail passenger transportation provided by, or on behalf of, Amtrak; or (2) commuter rail passenger transportation&#160;that travels over Amtrak-owned rails, regardless of whether it is&#160;provided by Amtrak or other rail carriers.

The regulations must include procedures for (1) determining if a cancellation or delay is due to a failure of Amtrak, and (2) Amtrak to dispute that a cancellation or delay is subject to the refund requirements.

The bill&#160;prohibits Amtrak from receiving federal funds for any period during which DOT determines that Amtrak is&#160;noncompliant with these requirements.

Amtrak must submit a report to Congress on alternative asset maintenance strategies to replace&#160;the run-to-fail maintenance model (i.e., using passenger rail equipment and infrastructure until it no longer works or exceeds its estimated lifespan), including the cost of the strategies. Within two years of this bill's enactment,&#160;Amtrak must (1) stop using a run-to-fail maintenance model, and (2) implement a new asset maintenance strategy.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
