<bill session="116" type="s" number="376" updated="2022-11-01T15:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2019-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to clarify the definition of navigable waters, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2019-02-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Army Corps of Engineers"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-17T20:47:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Defense of Environment and Property Act of 2019 

This bill revises the scope, jurisdiction, and requirements of the Clean Water Act.

It specifies the types of water bodies that are navigable waters and therefore receive protection. It defines navigable waters as waters of the United States that are (1) navigable-in-fact; or (2) permanent, standing, or continuously flowing bodies of water that form geographical features commonly known as streams, oceans, rivers, and lakes that are connected to waters that are navigable-in-fact.

The bill limits the jurisdiction of the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers and the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) over such waters, including by stating that ground water is under the jurisdiction of states. The bill prohibits the EPA from using a significant nexus test to determine federal jurisdiction over navigable waters and waters of the United States.

The bill nullifies the 2015 Waters of the United States (WOTUS) rule, the Migratory Bird rule, and a related guidance document issued in 2008. The bill prohibits the EPA and the Corps from issuing new rules or guidance that expands or interprets the definition of navigable waters unless expressly authorized by Congress.

Federal agencies must obtain consent from private property owners to collect information about navigable waters on their land. If regulations relating to navigable waters or waters of United States diminish the value of a property, then the federal government must pay the property owner an amount equal to twice the value of the loss.</summary>
</bill>
