<bill session="117" type="h" number="9099" updated="2022-12-29T12:48:51Z">
  <state datetime="2022-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanding Representation at HHS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanding Representation at HHS Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for establishment of an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion within each covered agency of the Department of Health and Human Services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001224" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2022-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2022-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-09-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-10-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-16T16:22:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Expanding Representation at HHS Act of 2022

This bill requires certain agencies and offices within the Department of Health and Human Services to address diversity in their procurement activities and workforce. The bill specifically covers offices and agencies that are authorized to award grants or other financial assistance, such as the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.

Each covered entity must establish an Office of Minority and Women Inclusion that is responsible for managing diversity within the entity and with respect to the entity's activities. This new office is not, however, responsible for enforcing civil rights statutes, regulations, or executive orders.

In addition, an entity subject to the bill's requirements must modify its evaluation, award, and termination of grants and contracts to ensure, to the maximum extent feasible, the inclusion of minorities; women; and minority-led and women-led grantees, contractors, subgrantees, and subcontractors. Each entity must also undertake actions to increase diversity in its workforce, including by recruiting at institutions of higher education where the majority of the students are members of minority populations.</summary>
</bill>
