<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3032</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-14T22:48:28Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-14T22:48:28Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2004-12-07</introducedDate>
    <congress>108</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2004-12-07T23:11:38Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-12-07</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2004-12-07</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>H000338</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Hatch, Orrin G. [R-UT]</fullName>
        <firstName>ORRIN</firstName>
        <lastName>HATCH</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>UT</state>
        <middleName>GRANT</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Leahy, Patrick J. [D-VT]</fullName>
        <firstName>Patrick</firstName>
        <lastName>Leahy</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>VT</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2004-12-07</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Law</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Claims</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Courts of special jurisdiction</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Judges</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Law</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2004-12-07</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-01-10T14:58:04Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States Court of Federal Claims Special Trial Judges Act of 2004 - Amends the Federal judicial code to establish within the U.S. Court of Federal Claims special trial judges (currently, special masters) to conduct proceedings on petitions under the National Vaccine Injury Compensation Program. </p> <p>Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services' participation in such proceedings. </p> <p>Establishes an office of special trial judges within the U.S. Court of Federal Claims. Requires the judges of such court to appoint special trial judges, one of whom shall serve as chief special trial judge.</p> <p>Establishes guidelines for the conduct of proceedings on petitions. </p> <p>Authorizes review of special trial judge decisions by the U.S. Court of Federal Claims and further appeal by the Secretary or an aggrieved petitioner to the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit.</p> <p>Amends the Public Health Service Act to reflect the above changes to the Program.</p> <p>Sets forth transition provisions for: (1) persons exempted from specified civil service programs by operation of this Act; and (2) persons currently serving as special masters.</p> <p>Establishes a retirement annuity system for special trial judges and addresses their participation in existing retirement programs.</p> <p>Amends the Federal judicial code, the Organic Act of Guam, the Act of November 8, 1977, and the Revised Organic Act of the Virgin Islands to include bankruptcy, magistrate, and territorial judges in the definition of &quot;judge&quot; for purposes of Federal employees' life insurance benefits.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United States Court of Federal Claims Special Trial Judges Act of 2004</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United States Court of Federal Claims Special Trial Judges Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for special trial judges of the United States Court of Federal Claims, make technical and conforming amendments relating to the transition of special masters to special trial judges, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States Court of Federal Claims Special Trial Judges Act of 2004</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2004-12-07T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2004-12-07</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
