<bill session="117" type="s" number="2496" updated="2023-01-01T23:42:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration and the Administrator of the Federal Highway Administration to implement certain recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board relating to pedestrian safety, bicyclist safety, and speeding-related crashes involving passenger vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Vulnerable Road Users Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Vulnerable Road Users Safety Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001194"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-15T15:39:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Vulnerable Road Users Safety Act

This bill addresses road safety, with a particular focus on the safety of vulnerable road users (e.g., pedestrians, bicyclists, and users of scooters and other micromobility vehicles.)

The National Highway Traffic Safety Administration and the Federal Highway Administration must implement specified recommendations of the National Transportation Safety Board (NTSB) to improve safety for vulnerable road users. Additionally, if a state experiences an increase in the rate of fatalities and injuries of vulnerable road users, it must prioritize in its highway safety improvement program the implementation of NTSB pedestrian safety recommendations.

The bill also requires the Intelligent Transportation System Joint Program Office of the Department of Transportation to incorporate bicyclists and other vulnerable road users into research concerning the safe deployment of connected vehicle systems (i.e., systems that use data from short-range communication broadcasts and exchanges with other vehicles to sense other vehicles and road users and identify potential hazards).</summary>
</bill>
