<bill session="117" type="h" number="1870" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20T12:25:57-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-07-20T12:25:57-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to prioritize strengthening of local transportation security capabilities by assigning certain officers and intelligence analysts to State, local, and regional fusion centers in jurisdictions with a high-risk surface transportation asset and improving the timely sharing of information regarding threats of terrorism and other threats, including targeted violence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001300"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2021-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20T12:21:07-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Barragan moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20T12:21:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3681-3683" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20T12:21:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 1870.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2021-07-20T12:25:57-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3681-3682" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20T12:25:59-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1605" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-23T18:07:39Z" status="Passed House">Strengthening Local Transportation Security Capabilities Act of 2021

This bill addresses threat information sharing and law enforcement training regarding the enhancement of security for surface transportation assets. A surface transportation asset includes facilities, equipment, or systems used to provide transportation services by a public transportation carrier, railroad carrier, or an entity offering scheduled, fixed-route transportation services by bus.

Specifically, the bill directs the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to prioritize the assignment of officers and intelligence analysts from the Transportation Security Administration and the Office of Intelligence and Analysis to locations with fusion centers in jurisdictions with high-risk surface transportation assets to enhance the security of such assets, including by improving timely sharing of classified information regarding terrorism and other threats.

The bill also authorizes DHS to develop a training program to enhance the protection, preparedness, and response capabilities of law enforcement agencies with respect to terrorism and other threats at a surface transportation asset.</summary>
</bill>
