<bill session="109" type="s" number="770" updated="2018-02-03T20:21:36Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Aquatic Invasive Species Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">National Aquatic Invasive Species Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to reauthorize and improve that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000261"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2005-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000206" joined="2005-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2005-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000064" joined="2005-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2006-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2005-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000154" joined="2005-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3558-3559"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="1591" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic animals"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Aquatic plants"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Biological diversity"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Ecological surveys"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Ecosystem management"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Exotic animals"/>
    <term name="Exotic plants"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine fouling organisms"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Non-native species"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pests"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="Weeds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-05-03T19:43:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Aquatic Invasive Species Act of 2005 - Amends the Nonindigenous Aquatic Nuisance Prevention and Control Act of 1990 to establish aquatic invasive species reduction and prevention requirements for vessels (including towed vessels and structures) operating in U.S. waters. Requires the Secretary of Homeland Security (Secretary) to promulgate ballast water management regulations and certification procedures.

Directs the Aquatic Invasive Species Task Force to establish a priority pathway management program that identifies those pathways that pose the highest risk for the introduction of aquatic invasive species. Prohibits the importation of a live aquatic organism of a species not in trade without specified screening and approval. Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA), and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to implement a national system of ecological surveys for rapid early detection and monitoring of invasive species. Establishes the Emergency Rapid Response Fund to assist States in implementing rapid response measures for aquatic invasive species. Requires the Task Force to review and approve State rapid response contingency strategies. Requires the Invasive Species Council to establish a Federal rapid response team for each of the ten Federal regions. Requires the Assistant Secretary of the Army (Civil Works) to upgrade and make permanent the existing Chicago sanitary and ship canal dispersal barrier in Chicago, Illinois, constructed as a demonstration project to prevent the spread of aquatic invasive species in U.S. waterways. Directs the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to construct, at full Federal expense, the Chicago sanitary and ship canal dispersal barrier authorized by the Water Resources Development Act of 1986. Requires NOAA, the Smithsonian Environmental Research Center, and the U.S. Geological Survey (Administering Agencies) to develop and conduct a marine and freshwater research program to assess rates of, patterns of, and conditions surrounding introductions of nonindigenous aquatic species in aquatic ecosystems and efforts to prevent the introduction of, and detect and eradicate, such species. Requires the EPA Administrator to develop an environmentally sound, cost-effective technology development, demonstration and verification grant program. Requires the Secretary and the EPA to develop a vessel pathway standards research program. Requires the National Science Foundation to establish a grant program for researchers at institutions of higher education and museums to carry out research in systematics and taxonomy. Requires the Invasive Species Council to coordinate with the Task Force to combat aquatic invasive species. Requires the Task Force to recommend to appropriate Federal agencies additions to the list of aquatic invasive species. Requires the Task Force, the Council, and the Secretary of State to ensure that international efforts to prevent and manage aquatic invasive species are coordinated with U.S. policies.</summary>
</bill>
