<bill session="111" type="s" number="3573" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:44Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Lake Thunderbird Efficient Use Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to allow the storage and conveyance of nonproject water at the Norman project in Oklahoma, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lake Thunderbird Efficient Use Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-01T15:05:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Lake Thunderbird Efficient Use Act of 2010 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to amend an existing contract or enter into one or more new contracts with the Central Oklahoma Master Conservancy District for the storage and conveyance of nonproject water in Norman project facilities to augment municipal and industrial supplies for the cities served by the District, if the Secretary determines that there is enough excess capacity in the reservoir on the Little River known as Lake Thunderbird that nonproject water can be stored there.

Makes the costs of constructing, operating, and maintaining any additional infrastructure needed to enable the storage and conveyance of nonproject water in Norman project facilities under any provision of this Act the responsibility of the non-federal entity contracting with the Secretary for storage and conveyance rights.</summary>
</bill>
