<bill session="118" type="s" number="1647" updated="2025-11-19T01:27:57Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad International Terrorism Support Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad International Terrorism Support Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose sanctions with respect to foreign support for terrorist organizations in Gaza and the West Bank, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2023-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000601" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="340" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3874" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-09T20:33:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Hamas and Palestinian Islamic Jihad International Terrorism Support Prevention Act of 2023

This bill imposes sanctions targeting Hamas, the Palestinian Islamic Jihad, and any affiliate or successor groups.

The President must impose sanctions on foreign persons and on agencies or instrumentalities of foreign states that knowingly provide significant support or services to or are involved in a significant transaction with a senior member or supporter of the targeted groups.

The President must impose property-blocking restrictions on such persons and must impose two or more sanctions on such agencies or instrumentalities. Specifically,&#160;the agency or instrumentality may be (1) denied credit and services from the Export-Import Bank, (2) barred from purchasing certain controlled defense articles, (3) denied exports of items on the U.S. Munitions List, (4) prevented from receiving exports of certain goods or technology controlled for national security reasons, or (5) prohibited from receiving financing of more than $10 million from any U.S. financial institution.

The President must periodically report to Congress a list of foreign governments that have repeatedly provided material support for the targeted groups' terrorist activities. The President shall bar these governments from receiving for one year (1) U.S. assistance, or&#160;(2) exports of controlled munitions. The Department of the Treasury must instruct U.S. leadership of&#160;international financial institutions to oppose providing assistance to an identified government for one year.

The bill provides for certain exceptions and waivers, such as for transactions that would serve U.S. national interests.

The President must report to Congress and periodically provide briefings on other specified topics related to the targeted groups, such as the disposition of assets and group activities.</summary>
</bill>
