<bill session="117" type="h" number="7851" updated="2023-08-09T17:00:32Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to disclose certain ties to China-affiliated organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to disclose certain ties to China-affiliated organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2022-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2022-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000597" joined="2022-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2022-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001180" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2022-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000478" joined="2022-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2022-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4756" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-09T16:45:17Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires institutions of higher education (IHEs) to disclose information regarding gifts from and contracts with China-affiliated organizations. China-affiliated organization refers to any entity that receives support directly or indirectly from the Chinese government, including certain educational institutes or programs, think tanks, and business entities.

Under current law, an IHE must disclose to the Department of Education (ED) a gift or contract from a foreign source that is valued at $250,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that foreign source in a calendar year. This bill establishes a special disclosure rule relating to China-affiliated organizations. Specifically, the bill requires an IHE to disclose a gift from or contract with a China-affiliated organization that is valued at $5,000 or more, considered alone or in combination with all other gifts from or contracts with that organization in a calendar year.

Additionally, the bill requires an IHE that receives federal grants to annually file a report with ED that identifies any activities conducted pursuant to a contract or other agreement between the IHE and a China-affiliated organization, including any joint research or academic exchanges. Such a contract or other agreement must be made available on a publicly accessible website of the IHE.</summary>
</bill>
