<bill session="108" type="s" number="786" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:13Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Business Links Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the temporary assistance to needy families program under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide grants for transitional jobs programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Business Links Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000468"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000780" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2003-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2003-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000035" joined="2003-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2003-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4837"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4838-4839" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-06T22:25:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Business Links Act of 2003 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) (TANF) of title IV of the Social Security Act to replace bonus grants to reward high performance States with innovative business link partnership grants. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Secretary of Labor, under such program, to jointly award grants to eligible applicants for programs to enable eligible individuals with limited English proficiency or other barriers to employment to: (1) increase their wages, especially by providing supports and services at or near work sites and to identify and strengthen career pathways by expanding and linking work and training opportunities for such individuals in collaboration with employers (to promote business linkages); or (2) provide for transitional jobs programs which combine publicly subsidized time-limited employment in the public or nonprofit private sector with skill development and activities to remove barriers to employment. Adds antidisplacement protections for workers.</summary>
</bill>
