<bill session="117" type="h" number="8269" updated="2022-12-29T18:05:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PATH Data Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parity, Accountability, and Transparency in Housing Data Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PATH Data Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To bring parity to the collection of housing data with respect to key demographics not currently captured in Federal data sets and thereby to enhance accountability and transparency in the evaluation of housing and housing programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000553"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-02T19:20:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Parity, Accountability, and Transparency in Housing Data Act of 2022 or the PATH Data Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to annually collect data on sexual orientation and gender identity in housing-related programs and activities. Specifically, HUD must

 survey and report on the levels of discrimination against members of protected classes (including classes based on relationship status, sexual orientation, and gender identity) in housing practices; and include (and require entities that receive funds through HUD to include) sexual orientation and gender identity when collecting demographic data concerning housing programs.</summary>
</bill>
