<bill session="111" type="h" number="2931" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:47Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Kyle Barthel Veterans and Service Members Mental Health Screening Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to adopt a program of professional and confidential screenings for members of the armed forces on active duty to detect mental health conditions for the purpose of reducing the incidence of suicide among such members and veterans, and to detect traumatic brain injuries, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kyle Barthel Veterans and Service Members Mental Health Screening Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001039" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2009-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000368" joined="2009-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001173" joined="2009-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001178" joined="2009-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000600" joined="2009-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000568" joined="2009-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Armed Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-17">
      <text>Referred to House Veterans' Affairs</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-09T18:55:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Kyle Barthel Veterans and Service Members Mental Health Screening Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to ensure that each member of the Armed Forces on active duty is required to participate in confidential, in-person screenings for mental health conditions by a licensed mental health professional to reduce the prevalence of suicide among service members, future veterans, and veterans.

Prohibits the Secretary from using the results of such a screening to prohibit a member from returning to the United States, prohibit a member from being discharged from the Armed Forces, or involuntarily discharge a member.

Directs the Secretary to require that each member on active duty is screened for a traumatic brain injury by a licensed professional who is qualified to conduct such screening.

Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a joint protocol to share existing and future reports concerning screenings conducted under this Act to help aid members and veterans who are transitioning from receiving health care and treatment through the Department of Defense to receiving such care and services through the Department of Veterans Affairs.</summary>
</bill>
