<bill session="118" type="h" number="4690" updated="2025-02-11T13:22:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Gray Zone Defense Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gray Zone Defense Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To assess the capacity of the United States to effectively marshal disparate elements of national power to counter adversary political warfare campaigns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001287" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2023-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000071" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000193" joined="2023-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2023-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000815" joined="2024-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-11T13:18:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Gray Zone Defense Assessment Act

This bill requires the President, the Department of State, and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) to each provide reports to Congress related to gray zone campaigns or assets. (Gray zone campaigns involve advancing a nation's interests through activities that fall between ordinary statecraft and open warfare without provoking a kinetic military conflict. Gray zone assets are entities or proxies used in gray zone activities.)

Specifically, the bill

requires the President to submit a report to Congress on the processes and capabilities by which the United States responds to gray zone campaigns and recommendations to enhance such processes and capabilities;requires the State Department to submit a report to Congress on the department's understanding of the gray zone threat environment and capacity to contribute to coordinated U.S. responses to adversary gray zone campaigns; andexpands a required Intelligence Community Assessment regarding Russian gray zone assets to include the gray zone assets of China, Iran, North Korea, Cuba and Syria.&#160;(ODNI must submit this expanded assessment to Congress annually.)</summary>
</bill>
