<bill session="117" type="h" number="4474" updated="2023-04-28T13:15:16Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an intercity passenger rail service investment grant program.</title>
    <title type="display">BRAIN TRAIN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRAIN TRAIN Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Rail Across Intercity Networks To Ride Around Interior of the Nation Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000312"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1852" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-10T19:44:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Building Rail Across Intercity Networks To Ride Around Interior of the Nation Act or the BRAIN TRAIN Act

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish an intercity passenger rail service investment program to promote high-performance rail transportation options.

DOT may award competitive grants under the program to finance capital projects for high-performance rail, including grants awarded in installments for projects lasting longer than one year.

In awarding grants, DOT must select high-performance rail projects (1) that are anticipated to result in significant improvements to intercity rail passenger service, (2) for which there is a high degree of confidence that the proposed projects are feasible and will result in the anticipated benefits, and (3) for which the level of the anticipated benefits compares favorably to the amount of federal funding requested.

The federal share of the cost of a capital project shall not exceed 90% of the project's net capital cost.</summary>
</bill>
