<bill session="118" type="h" number="4049" updated="2024-08-14T08:05:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Access and Dignity for All People Who Travel Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access and Dignity for All People Who Travel Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide seating accommodations for qualified individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2024-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001221" joined="2023-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1939" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Service animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-09T14:39:02Z" status="Introduced in House">Access and Dignity for All People Who Travel Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to issue a rule regarding flight seating accommodations for qualified individuals with a disability. The bill also requires DOT to establish a pilot program for known service animal users.

In carrying out the flight seat accommodations rulemaking, items DOT must consider include the scope and anticipated number of individuals with a disability who (1) may need to be seated with a companion to receive assistance during a flight, and (2) should be afforded bulkhead seats or other seating considerations.

DOT must also establish a pilot program to exempt certain known service animal users&#160;from current documentation requirements for air travel with a service animal. An individual with a disability may participate in the voluntary program if the individual (1) requires the use of a service animal because of a disability, and (2) submits an application to DOT. In establishing the pilot program, DOT must consult with disability advocacy entities, air carriers, and accredited service animal training programs. DOT may award a grant or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement to carry out the program.&#160;

Further, DOT must maintain and publish a list of accredited service animal training programs and authorized registrars that evaluate service animals.

Finally, in consultation with the Air Carrier Access Act Advisory Committee, DOT must issue guidance on how to improve training for airline personnel (including contractors) in recognizing when an individual with a disability is traveling with a service animal.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
