<bill session="109" type="s" number="2450" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:49Z">
  <state datetime="2006-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeland Security Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen national security by encouraging and assisting in the expansion and improvement of educational programs in order to meet critical needs at the elementary, secondary, and higher education levels, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeland Security Education Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000069"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2006-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2338-2340"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Distance education"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Engineers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="Mentoring"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientific instruments and apparatus"/>
    <term name="Scientists"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teacher supply and demand"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-03-27T19:34:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeland Security Education Act - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require the Secretary of Education to award scholarships for the pursuit of bachelor degrees in science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and critical foreign languages.

Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary to award grants to: (1) school districts which upgrade their mathematics and science programs and work with private or state or local government entities willing to donate equipment, mentoring personnel, and higher education scholarships for students participating in the programs; (2) scientists and engineers who return to school to become teachers in their fields in needy schools; (3) partnerships between school districts and institutions of higher education working to enhance the recruitment and professional development of foreign language teachers; and (4) institutions of higher education which develop programs to immerse students in a foreign language while they study science, technology, or engineering here or abroad.

Amends the David L. Boren National Security Education Act of 1991 to alter the terms of the work agreements required of recipients of scholarships and graduate fellowships in studies or languages critical to national security. Includes the Department of Homeland Security and Department of State among the agencies where service may be rendered. Sets federal employment and teaching alternatives when priority positions are unavailable.

Directs the Secretary to award grants enabling institutions of higher education, in collaboration with elementary and secondary schools, to establish language learning pathways training students from elementary through graduate education to be proficient in critical foreign languages.

Requires the Secretary to award scholarships to individuals proficient in critical foreign languages who return to school to become foreign language teachers in needy elementary or secondary schools.

Amends federal law to create a student loan repayment pilot program for federal employees with critical science, technology, engineering, mathematics, and foreign language skills.</summary>
</bill>
