<bill session="111" type="h" number="5871" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SEED Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to allow non-debt financing for for-profit companies in business incubators.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SEED Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Entrepreneurial Economic Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Transportation and Infrastructure</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Financial Services</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-01T19:39:31Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Entrepreneurial Economic Development Act or SEED Act - Amends the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 to allow a recipient of an economic adjustment grant to directly expend or redistribute grant funds to public and private organizations in the form of non-debt financing of for-profit companies in business incubators.

Defines: (1) "business incubator" to mean an organization or entity, including an academic institution, established to foster the startup of businesses or accelerate the growth of fledgling companies by providing entrepreneurs with resources and services to produce viable businesses that can help create jobs and restore vitality to distressed areas; and (2) "non-debt financing" to mean funding used to help business incubators develop an idea and create the first product to be brought to market for the first time.</summary>
</bill>
