<bill session="119" type="h" number="92" updated="2025-02-13T14:38:46Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Strategic Production Response and Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Strategic Production Response and Implementation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the development of a plan to increase oil and gas production under oil and gas leases of Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense in conjunction with a drawdown of petroleum reserves from the Strategic Petroleum Reserve.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-13T14:28:38Z" status="Introduced in House">Strategic Production Response and Implementation Act

This bill modifies the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prohibit&#160;the Department of Energy (DOE) from drawing down petroleum products in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve until DOE develops and implements a plan to increase the percentage of federal lands leased for oil and gas production. The increase must be equal to&#160;the percentage of petroleum in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve that is to be drawn down. However, the bill does not apply to a drawdown of&#160;petroleum products in the case of a severe energy supply interruption, which is permitted under current law.&#160;

The plan must not provide for a total increase in the percentage of federal lands leased for oil and gas production in excess of 10%.</summary>
</bill>
