<bill session="118" type="h" number="6848" updated="2025-08-05T15:09:11Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit institutions of higher education from requiring ideological oaths or similar statements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to prohibit institutions of higher education from requiring ideological oaths or similar statements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001120"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2024-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-05T15:09:09Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prohibits an institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs from requiring a student enrolled at the IHE, an employee or contractor of the IHE, or an applicant for admission to or employment or contracting at the IHE to make certain&#160;ideological oaths or similar statements.

Specifically, the bill prohibits an IHE from compelling, requiring, inducing, or soliciting such an individual to (1) endorse an ideology that promotes the differential treatment of an individual or group of individuals based on race, color, or ethnicity; or (2) provide a statement indicating certain information about the individual, including the individual's views on efforts involving diversity, equity, and inclusion&#160;or other specified concepts.

Additionally, the bill prohibits an IHE from providing preferential consideration to a student, employee, or contractor based on&#160;the individual's unsolicited support for an ideology that promotes the differential treatment of an individual or group of individuals based on race, color, or ethnicity.</summary>
</bill>
