<bill session="116" type="s" number="4994" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:48Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Intimate Imagery and Privacy Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intimate Imagery and Privacy Protection Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide civil relief for victims of the disclosure of certain intimate images, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2020-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2020-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2020-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-19T16:41:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Intimate Imagery and Privacy Protection Act of 2020

This bill establishes a civil cause of action against a person that discloses an intimate image of an individual without the depicted individual's consent, if the person disclosed the image knowing about or with reckless disregard for the lack of consent.

Under the bill, a depicted individual may recover damages and obtain other relief, such as an injunction ordering the defendant to stop disclosing the image. A court may use a pseudonym to protect a depicted individual's confidentiality when granting an injunction.

Evidence that a depicted individual consented to the capturing of the intimate image shall not by itself constitute consent for disclosure of the image. Similarly, evidence that a depicted individual provided an intimate image to a person shall not by itself constitute consent to further disclosure of that image.</summary>
</bill>
