<bill session="116" type="h" number="3995" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VET Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit an annual report to Congress relating to the use of official time by employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to limit the instances in which official time may be granted for certain purposes to employees of the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VET Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000375"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-08-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Oversight and Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR08" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-14T14:52:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans, Employees, and Taxpayers Protection Act of 2019 or the VET Protection Act of 2019

This bill directs the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to track the use of official time by VA employees without using estimates or time ranges.

Official time is time granted to an employee under federal labor-management relations provisions to perform representational or consultative functions, during which the employee would otherwise be in a duty status.

The bill prohibits (1) a VA employee from using official time to carry out political or lobbying activities; (2) specified health care employees, probationary employees, or employees above a certain salary level from using official time for any purpose without a waiver; and (3) any VA employee from spending more than 25% of the time such employee would otherwise be in a duty status on official time without a waiver.

The authority provided to the VA to grant a waiver shall not be subject to bargaining, and the exercise of (or failure to exercise) such authority shall not be an unfair labor practice.

An exclusive bargaining agreement shall allow a VA employee to terminate a voluntary dues allotment at any time.

A covered VA employee shall serve a two-year probationary period, after which the employee's supervisor shall determine within 90 days whether or not the appointment is permanent. A covered employee is any individual appointed to a permanent position within the competitive service or the Senior Executive Service and does not include specified health care practitioners.</summary>
</bill>
