<bill session="119" type="h" number="2307" updated="2025-05-30T10:48:12Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization to modernize the data collection and reporting processes of the National Agricultural Statistics Service, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To establish the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service Modernization to modernize the data collection and reporting processes of the National Agricultural Statistics Service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000230" joined="2025-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2025-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-05-30T10:45:54Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill establishes the Commission on National Agricultural Statistics Service (NASS) Modernization to study and provide recommendations on modernizing and streamlining data collection at NASS. As background, NASS conducts the Census of Agriculture and provides official statistics on agricultural production and other farm sector indicators.

The 11-member commission must include 4 specified members from the Department of Agriculture, 1 member from the Bureau of Labor Statistics, and 6 members appointed by the House and Senate Agriculture Committees.

At the request of the commission chair, federal agencies must provide the commission information related to the study.

The commission must submit a report to the President and Congress on the results of the study within two years of the bill's enactment. The report must include (1) an inventory of surveys conducted by NASS and their frequency; and (2) recommendations for administrative, regulatory, and legislative changes.</summary>
</bill>
