<bill session="118" type="s" number="1511" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Campus Free Speech Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Campus Free Speech Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure that public institutions of higher education eschew policies that improperly constrain the expressive rights of students, and to ensure that private institutions of higher education are transparent about, and responsible for, their chosen speech policies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000355" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2023-05-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2508" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-24T12:53:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Campus Free Speech Restoration Act

This bill addresses expressive activities (e.g., peacefully assembling, distributing literature, or carrying signs) on college campuses.

First, the bill generally prohibits a public institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student-aid programs from restricting noncommercial expressive activities in outdoor areas on campus.

Further, the bill prohibits a public IHE from receiving federal funds if the Department of Education determines that the public IHE (1) maintains a policy that infringes upon the expressive rights of students; or (2) maintains or enforces time, place, or manner restrictions on expressive activities, except in limited circumstances.

In addition, the bill prohibits retaliation against an individual because the individual reported or complained about restrictions on expressive activities or participated in an investigation or hearing.

The bill also requires a private IHE that receives federal funds to provide students with its policies related to expressive rights.

The bill also establishes a framework for investigating complaints and for IHEs to regain eligibility for federal funds.</summary>
</bill>
