<bill session="116" type="h" number="7847" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:47Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HELP Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HELP Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Housing Emergencies Lifeline Program Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create a database of eviction information, establish grant programs for eviction prevention and legal aid, and limit use of housing court-related records in consumer reports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2020-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2020-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000216" joined="2020-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001165" joined="2020-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2020-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4399" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="HIV/AIDS"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing for the elderly and disabled"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Low- and moderate-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-09T14:41:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Housing Emergencies Lifeline Program Act of 2020 or the HELP Act of 2020

This bill requires the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to establish&#160;a database of information regarding evictions from federally assisted dwellings, limits the inclusion of information relating to landlord-tenant actions in consumer reports, and otherwise provides eviction-related assistance and services.

Specifically, the bill requires states and local entities receiving federal housing assistance to submit to HUD, for inclusion in&#160;the database,&#160;certain information regarding evictions from assisted dwelling units in the past year. Such information must include, among other things, the reason for eviction and whether the household was represented by legal counsel in the proceedings.

Additionally, consumer reporting agencies may include an adverse item of information relating to a landlord-tenant action in a consumer report only if the landlord prevailed in the action and the tenant was an adult on the date the court claim was filed. Any such information must be removed from a consumer report one year after the date of the action.

Further, the bill authorizes additional Emergency Solutions Grants to provide legal counsel and pay court fees for tenants subject to or at risk of eviction.

Finally, HUD must require owners of federally assisted rental units to annually provide information to each tenant regarding the rights and responsibilities of the owner&#160;with respect to&#160;eviction and local organizations and resources that can provide assistance in eviction-related matters. HUD must also establish an eviction hotline to provide assistance to tenants&#160;of&#160;these units.</summary>
</bill>
