<bill session="118" type="h" number="4943" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enabling Farmers to Benefit from Processing Nutrition Programs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enabling Farmers to Benefit from Processing Nutrition Programs Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Agriculture to streamline applications from farmers to be vendors under certain nutrition programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001221"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000599" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2023-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000130" joined="2023-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition, Foreign Agriculture, and Horticulture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing and promotion"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-11-20T18:04:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Enabling Farmers to Benefit from Processing Nutrition Programs Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to establish a streamlined process for farmers and ranchers to provide benefits under certain federal nutrition programs (i.e., the Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program; the Senior Farmers Market Nutrition Program; the Special Supplemental Nutrition Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC); and the Gus Schumacher Nutrition Incentive Program).

Specifically, USDA must establish a streamlined application process&#160;for farmers and ranchers to apply to be vendors under the nutrition programs, including by developing a single application for the programs or an information sharing system. USDA must also develop a streamlined process for these vendors to use standardized technology&#160;to process program benefits&#160;(such as a single piece of equipment or a mobile application).

Further, USDA must ensure that the program benefit processing equipment and systems made available by a state agency is appropriate for the entity. For example, this includes ensuring wireless or mobile processing equipment and technology systems are appropriate&#160;for farmers markets and other direct-to-consumer markets.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
