<bill session="117" type="h" number="5836" updated="2022-12-30T08:03:40Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Enhancing DIVERSITY Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing Diversity and Inclusion by Verifying and Ensuring the Reporting required by Statute Is Transpiring and Yielding Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Enhancing DIVERSITY Data Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for certain requirements with respect to media employment, ownership, and diversity reporting, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001067"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-03T15:30:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Enhancing Diversity and Inclusion by Verifying and Ensuring the Reporting required by Statute Is Transpiring and Yielding Data Act or the Enhancing DIVERSITY Data Act

This bill requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to carry out rulemaking, data collection, and reporting about the demographic composition of the broadcast industry workforce.

Specifically, the FCC must complete a specified rulemaking process related to equal employment opportunity rules and policies that apply to broadcast stations and multichannel video programming distributors (e.g., cable operators). Part of this rulemaking addresses reporting of workforce demographics by broadcast license holders.

Within one year of completing the rulemaking, the FCC must begin collecting demographic data pertaining to the broadcast industry workforce. The FCC may not use the collected data in its reviews of broadcast license applications or renewals or to assess compliance with applicable equal employment opportunity rules.

Further, the FCC must (1) include analyses of the demographic composition of the broadcast industry workforce in certain reports, and (2) maintain a database that includes publicly available ownership data of broadcast licensees.</summary>
</bill>
