<bill session="117" type="h" number="8502" updated="2022-12-29T18:18:44Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tribal Nutrition Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tribal Nutrition Improvement Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to improve nutrition in tribal areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000273"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2022-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2022-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2022-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2022-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4625" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-03T16:23:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Tribal Nutrition Improvement Act of 2022

This bill expands access to free and reduced school meals in tribal areas.

Specifically, the bill makes a child who is an enrolled member (or who has one or more parents who are enrolled members) of an Indian tribe categorically eligible for free school breakfasts or lunches.

Additionally, the bill allows the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to adjust reimbursement rates for breakfasts, lunches, suppers, and supplements served in Bureau-funded schools and elementary and secondary schools on or near an Indian reservation.

The bill also directs USDA to establish a pilot program to award grants to 10 tribal entities for operating and implementing the National School Lunch Program, the School Breakfast Program, the Summer Food Service Program, and the Child and Adult Care Food Program in Bureau-funded schools and elementary and secondary schools on or near an Indian reservation.</summary>
</bill>
