<bill session="108" type="s" number="1935" updated="2023-01-15T09:03:29Z">
  <state datetime="2003-11-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-11-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-11-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Universal Secure Access to Health Care Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to require employers to offer health care coverage for all employees, to amend the Social Security Act to guarantee comprehensive health care coverage for all children born after 2001, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Universal Secure Access to Health Care Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001042"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15652-15653"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S15653-15663" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Age"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Case management"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional investigations"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in insurance"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in medical care"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employee health benefits"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Health insurance continuation"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Interstate relations"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local employees"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medically uninsured"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare Payment Advisory Commission"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Payroll deductions"/>
    <term name="Poor children"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="State employees"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Working poor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-25T22:41:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Universal Secure Access to Health Care Act of 2003 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to add a new title XXVIII (Universal Health Insurance Coverage). Requires each employer of at least 50 full-time employees to offer to enroll each of its employees and their families in a standard health benefit plan providing benefits for health care items and services that are actuarily equivalent to or greater in value than the benefits offered as of January 1, 2000, under the Blue Cross/Blue Shield Standard Option Plan provided under the Federal Employees Health Benefit Program (FEHBP).

Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a Federal program to award grants to States for State premium assistance programs for low-income workers and small business employers.

Authorizes a small business employer of at least 75 full-time employees to enroll its employees in an FEHBP plan or the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (SSA) if such employees are at least 50 years of age.

Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to allow a tax deduction for self-employed individuals equal to 100 percent of the amount paid during the taxable year for insurance which constitutes medical care for the taxpayer, the taxpayer's spouse, and the taxpayer's dependents.

Amends SSA to add a new part D (Purchase of Medicare Benefits by Certain Individuals Age 62-to-65 Years of Age).

Creates in the Treasury the Medicare Early Access Trust Fund for collected premiums and other revenues for use in funding the new part D program.

Provides access to Medicare benefits for displaced workers 55 to 62 years of age.

Amends Federal civil service law to make FEHBP coverage available for the self-employed.

Establishes a MediKids Program under a new SSA title XXII to allow certain eligible individuals born after December 31, 2002, who have not attained age 23, to enroll for benefits specified by the Secretary, including early and periodic screening, diagnostic services, and treatment services under Medicaid (SSA title XIX), and prescription drugs and biologicals.

Creates in the Treasury the MediKids Trust Fund for collected premiums and other revenues for use in funding the MediKids Program.

Amends SSA title XVIII to increase the membership of the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission, with the initial terms of additional members staggered.

Amends the IRC to: (1) impose a MediKids premium tax in the case of any taxpayer (with certain exceptions) required to pay a premium under the MediKids Program for an eligible individual; and (2) provide for a refundable tax credit for 50 percent of cost-sharing expenses under the MediKids Program.

Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to propose a gradual schedule of progressive tax changes to fund the MediKids Program as the number of enrollees grows in the out-years.</summary>
</bill>
