<bill session="119" type="s" number="76" updated="2025-04-03T19:28:32Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SMART Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Setting Manageable Analysis Requirements in Text Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMART Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to improve the effectiveness of major rules in accomplishing their regulatory objectives by promoting retrospective review, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Competitiveness, trade promotion, trade deficits"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-03T19:26:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Setting Manageable Analysis Requirements in Text Act of 2025 or the SMART Act of 2025

This bill requires agencies, when publishing a proposed or final major rule, to include a framework for assessing whether the rule achieves its regulatory objective. An agency must assess a rule in the time frame included in the framework. The assessment must compare the rule's anticipated and actual benefits and costs.

Additionally, the assessment must determine whether&#160;(1) the rule has been rendered unnecessary because of changes to the subject area affected by the rule or it overlaps with, duplicates, or conflicts with other rules, or&#160;state and local government regulations; (2)&#160;the rule should be expanded, streamlined, or otherwise modified to accomplish the rule's objective; and (3) other alternatives or modifications to the rule could better achieve the rule's&#160;objective.&#160;

The bill defines a&#160;major rule&#160;as a rule likely to cause (1)&#160;an annual effect on the economy of $100 million or more; (2) a major increase in costs or prices; or (3) significant adverse effects on competition, employment, investment, productivity, innovation, health, safety, the environment, or the ability of U.S.-based enterprises to compete with foreign-based enterprises.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
