<bill session="116" type="h" number="7000" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:50Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Holding Foreign Companies Accountable Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Sarbanes-Oxley Act of 2002 to require certain issuers to disclose to the Securities and Exchange Commission information regarding foreign jurisdictions that prevent the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board from performing inspections under that Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Holding Foreign Companies Accountable Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2020-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000588" joined="2020-08-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="945" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4629" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-19T15:30:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Holding Foreign Companies Accountable Act 

This bill requires certain issuers of securities to establish that&#160;they are&#160;not owned or controlled by a foreign government. Specifically, an issuer must make this certification if the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board is unable to audit specified reports because the issuer has retained a foreign public accounting firm not subject to inspection by the board. Furthermore, if the board is unable to inspect the issuer's public accounting firm for three consecutive years, the issuer's securities are banned from trade on a national exchange or through other methods.

Foreign issuers of securities&#160;that use&#160;such a firm to prepare an audit report must disclose&#160;for each&#160;non-inspection year

 the percentage of shares owned by governmental entities where the issuer is incorporated, whether these governmental entities have a controlling financial interest, information related to any board members who are officials of the Chinese Communist Party, and whether the articles of incorporation of the issuer contain&#160;any charter of the Chinese Communist Party.</summary>
</bill>
