<bill session="108" type="s" number="2790" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:46Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-09-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bisti PRLA Dispute Resolution Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide the conveyance of certain public land in northwestern New Mexico by resolving a dispute associated with coal preference right lease interests on the land.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bisti PRLA Dispute Resolution Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9077"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9077-9078" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mineral reserves"/>
    <term name="Mining claims"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-01-19T21:05:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Bisti PRLA Dispute Resolution Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management, if any of specified coal preference right lease applications are withdrawn by the holder or holders of those applications, to issue to each such holder a certificate of bidding rights that constitutes the combined fair market value of the coal reserves for each coal preference right lease application withdrawn by the holder. Provides that such withdrawals and issuances shall occur without any further adjudication of coal preference right lease applications.

Directs the Secretary to establish a panel to determine the fair market value of the coal reserves of any coal preference right applications withdrawn under this Act. Instructs the Secretary to contract with a qualified coal reserve appraiser to assist the panel.

Directs the Secretary, after the withdrawal of a coal preference right lease application, to: (1) issue to the Navajo Nation patents to the land, including the mineral estate, subject to such withdrawn application in full and final satisfaction of the right of the Navajo Nation to select land in New Mexico and to facilitate land consolidation and mineral development in northwest New Mexico; and (2) issue a certificate of bidding rights in the amount of the fair market value of the coal reserves of such application. Provides that the Secretary's duties in issuing such patents and certificates shall be considered nondiscretionary and enforceable in a mandamus proceeding.

Sets forth provisions regarding the use of exchange bidding rights.</summary>
</bill>
