<bill session="117" type="s" number="3067" updated="2022-12-30T07:48:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NEXT in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New, Emerging, and Exciting Technologies in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEXT in Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to provide for new and emerging technologies in transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001113"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3310" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3684" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1681" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2016" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-09T14:37:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">New, Emerging, and Exciting Technologies in Transportation Act or the NEXT in Transportation Act

This bill establishes and expands activities concerning electrification of transportation systems and intelligent transportation systems and technology.

Regarding transportation electrification, the Department of Transportation (DOT) and the Department of Energy must (1) establish a temporary working group to make recommendations about incorporating electric vehicles into U.S. transportation and energy systems, and (2) develop a transportation electrification strategy based on those recommendations.

The bill also

 provides funding for states to develop electric vehicle charging infrastructure; includes programs to increase transportation energy efficiency and the use of alternative fuels or electric vehicles in state energy conservation plans; and allows the use, subject to limits, of public transportation funds to install charging equipment for privately owned vehicles. Regarding intelligent transportation systems and technology, DOT must establish an internet-based resource for states and localities to use when developing intelligent transportation and related programs.

DOT must also award grants to improve transportation efficiency and safety through advanced smart city or community technologies and systems. Eligible recipients include states, Indian tribes, localities, public transit agencies, and groups of such entities.

Additionally, DOT must support workforce development in the intelligent transportation technologies and systems industry. This includes (1) contracting with the National Academies of Sciences to assess workforce needs, (2) establishing a working group to implement a workforce development plan, and (3) increasing public awareness of career opportunities in the transportation sector.</summary>
</bill>
