<bill session="116" type="s" number="4238" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:38Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cracking Down on Gangs and Deporting Criminals Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cracking Down on Gangs and Deporting Criminals Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, relating to criminal street gangs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000594"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2020-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2020-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4351" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-03T15:39:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cracking Down on Gangs and Deporting Criminals Act of 2020

This bill provides for additional instances when the prison sentence may be increased by up to ten years for an individual involved in a criminal street gang and is convicted of certain crimes, and contains other related provisions.

Currently, the increased prison sentence applies to certain offenses related to (1) controlled substances, (2) violence involving physical force, or (3) human trafficking or sexual abuse. The bill establishes that certain offenses related to deriving income from or participating in a pattern of racketeering activity or collection of unlawful debt shall also be eligible for the sentence increase.

The bill also expands the circumstances in which an individual may be considered to be involved in a criminal street gang and thus be eligible for the sentence increase.

In addition, the Department of Justice (DOJ) shall establish and maintain a national criminal street gang database. If an individual who is convicted and eligible for such a sentence enhancement is an alien, DOJ shall report the sentence enhancement to the Department of Homeland Security and the individual shall be subject to removal proceedings.</summary>
</bill>
