<bill session="118" type="h" number="881" updated="2025-06-06T14:17:56Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safeguarding the U.S. Armed Forces and Service Academies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safeguarding the U.S. Armed Forces and Service Academies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish certain protections for a member of the Armed Forces, or a cadet or midshipman at a Federal service academy, who refuses to receive a vaccination against COVID-19.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001214"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Armed Services, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-05T16:33:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Safeguarding the U.S. Armed Forces and Service Academies Act

This bill prohibits the use of federal funds to enforce or establish a mandate requiring a member of the Armed Forces, or a cadet or midshipman at a federal service academy, to receive a COVID-19 vaccination. Additionally, no such individuals may be subject to adverse action solely on the basis of a refusal to receive a COVID-19 vaccination.

At the request of an individual who was involuntarily separated from an Armed Force or federal service academy solely because of a refusal to receive a COVID-19 vaccination, the military department concerned must

 reinstate the individual as a member of the Armed Force in the same rank and grade the individual held at the time of separation, or reinstate the individual as a cadet or midshipman with the credits the individual had completed at the time of separation; expunge from the individual's military service record any reference to adverse action related to the refusal to receive a COVID-19 vaccination; and include the period between the involuntary separation and reinstatement in the computation of retired or retainer pay of the individual. Such individuals must be entitled to back pay for the period between the separation and the reinstatement.

The bill requires that the discharge of members due to the failure to obey a lawful order to receive a COVID-19 vaccination must be categorized as an honorable discharge, including for individuals who were discharged prior to the enactment of this bill.</summary>
</bill>
