<bill session="116" type="s" number="3181" updated="2022-02-08T23:22:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-01-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-01-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspiring Nationally Vibrant Economies Sustaining Tribes Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INVEST Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to expand the new markets tax credit to assist Native American communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2020-01-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2020-01-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-11T20:27:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Inspiring Nationally Vibrant Economies Sustaining Tribes Act of 2020 or the INVEST Act

This bill expands the definition of low-income community for purposes of the new markets tax credit to include lands held in trust for Native Americans, lands that enclose all or part of a Native American village, or Indian tribal lands. It also prioritizes the allocation of credit amounts for investment in American Indian, Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian communities and requires an allocation of at least 10% of credit amounts to certain Indian community development entities for investments that primarily serve low-income communities.

The bill directs the Bureau of Indian Affairs in the Department of the Interior to provide technical assistance to qualified Indian community development entities regarding applications for allocations of the new markets tax credit and to work with the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund to provide assistance to such entities.</summary>
</bill>
