<bill session="118" type="s" number="1212" updated="2025-11-19T03:42:05Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize notaries public to perform, and to establish minimum standards for, electronic notarizations and remote notarizations that occur in or affect interstate commerce, to require any Federal court to recognize notarizations performed by a notarial officer of any State, to require any State to recognize notarizations performed by a notarial officer of any other State when the notarization was performed under or relates to a public Act, record, or judicial proceeding of notarial officer's State or when the notarization occurs in or affects interstate commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2023-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2023-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001061" joined="2023-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2023-05-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2023-05-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1059" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-12T20:58:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Securing and Enabling Commerce Using Remote and Electronic Notarization Act of 2023

This bill allows a notary public commissioned under state law to remotely notarize electronic records and perform notarizations for remotely located individuals. The bill provides technical requirements for the notarizations, including the creation and retention of video and audio recordings and the use of communication technologies (i.e., video chat).

Additionally, the bill requires U.S. courts and states to recognize notarizations&#8212;including remote notarizations of electronic records and notarizations of remotely-located individuals&#8212;that occur in or affect interstate commerce and are performed by a notary public commissioned under the laws of other states.

The bill also allows a notary public to remotely notarize electronic records involving an individual located outside of the United States, subject to certain requirements.</summary>
</bill>
