<bill session="108" type="s" number="946" updated="2023-01-15T23:33:07Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drug Competition Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance competition  for prescription drugs by increasing the ability of the Department of Justice and Federal Trade Commission to enforce existing antitrust laws regarding brand name drugs and generic drugs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Competition Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2003-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2003-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5493-5494"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Drug approvals"/>
    <term name="Drug industry"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Generic drugs"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Pharmaceutical research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Drug Competition Act of 2003 - Sets filing requirements for a generic drug applicant that has submitted an Abbreviated New Drug Application (ANDA) and a brand name drug company that enter into an agreement, before a drug enters the market, regarding: (1) the manufacture, marketing, or sale of the brand name or the generic drug; or (2) the 180-day semi-exclusivity period referred to in the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act as it applies to such ANDA or any other ANDA based on the same brand name drug. Requires each such party to file such agreement and any related agreements with the Assistant Attorney General and the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Makes an exception for agreements that solely concern purchase orders for raw material supplies, equipment and facility contracts, or employment or consulting contracts. Requires such agreements to be filed not later than ten business days after the date they are executed.Exempts any such information or documentary material filed from disclosure under the Freedom of Information Act. Prohibits such information or material from being made public, except as relevant to any administrative or judicial action or proceeding.Subjects an applicant or company to a civil penalty of up to $11,000 for each day such entity fails to comply with this Act, recoverable in a civil action brought by the United States or the FTC. Authorizes a U.S. district court to order compliance and grant equitable relief.</summary>
</bill>
