<bill session="108" type="h" number="506" updated="2023-01-15T21:19:35Z">
  <state datetime="2004-03-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for the protection of archaeological sites in the Galisteo Basin in New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000789" joined="2003-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 108-346.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-04" calendar="Union" number="203">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 203.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T17:19:17-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Renzi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T17:20:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309-10311" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T17:20:44-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 506.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2003-11-04T17:25:44-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H10309-10310" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2003-11-04T17:25:46-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2003-11-05" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="368">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 368.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-03-04" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2253" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-03-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-03-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-03-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-208" type="public" datetime="2004-03-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-208.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="210" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Spain"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Galisteo Basin Archaeological Sites Protection Act - Designates specified archaeological sites in New Mexico as the Galisteo Basin Archaeological Protection Sites. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) continue to search for additional Native American and Spanish colonial sites in the Galisteo Basin area; and (2) submit to the Congress recommendations for additions to, deletions from, and modifications of the boundaries of such sites.Requires the Secretary to submit to specified congressional committees a general management plan for the identification, research, protection, and public interpretation of the archaeological protection sites located on Federal lands, and those sites located on private and State lands for which the Secretary has entered into discretionary Cooperative Agreements with their owners for the protection, preservation, maintenance, and administration of their archaeological resources and associated lands.Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands and interests within the boundaries of the archaeological protection sites, and access to them, by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, or by exchange. Limits to donation or exchange the Secretary's acquisition authority for lands or interests owned by the State of New Mexico or a local government, except that State trust land may be acquired only by exchange.Withdraws all Federal lands within the sites, subject to valid existing rights, from: (1) all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws; (2) location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and (3) disposition under all laws relating to mineral and geothermal leasing.States that this Act shall not: (1) authorize regulation of privately owned lands within an archaeological protection site; or (2) restrict or limit an Indian tribe from protecting cultural or religious sites on tribal land.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-346</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
