<bill session="109" type="h" number="4642" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:22Z">
  <state datetime="2005-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wired for Health Care Quality Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance the adoption of a nationwide interoperable health information technology system and to improve the quality and reduce the costs of health care in the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wired for Health Care Quality Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-12-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="1418" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Biological warfare"/>
    <term name="Chronically ill"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Cost control"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information systems"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Information technology"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Patient satisfaction"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Quality of care"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Strategic planning"/>
    <term name="Telemedicine"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-13T21:21:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Wired for Health Care Quality Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of the National Coordinator of Health Information Technology to develop a nationwide interoperable health information technology infrastructure.

Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to: (1) establish the public-private American Health Information Collaborative to recommend uniform policies to support the widespread adoption of health information technology; and (2) adopt recommended modifications to standards for the electronic exchange of health information.

Prohibits any federal agency from expending federal funds to purchase health information technology that is inconsistent with adopted standards and requires all federal agencies collecting health data to comply with such standards.

Requires the Secretary to develop criteria to: (1) ensure uniform and consistent implementation of any standards voluntarily adopted by private entities; and (2) ensure and certify hardware, software, and support services compliance with adopted standards.

Allows the Secretary to award grants to: (1) facilitate the purchase and enhance the utilization of qualified health information technology systems; (2) implement regional or local health information plans; and (3) develop academic programs integrating qualified health information technology systems in the clinical education of health professionals.

Requires the heads of specified federal agencies to develop a system to measure the quality of care patients receive. Requires the Secretary to: (1) adopt and utilize such system; (2) disseminate recommendations and best practices derived from the analysis of quality measures; and (3) study methods to create efficient reimbursement incentives for improving health care quality.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Agency for Healthcare Quality and Research (AHRQ), to develop a Center for Best Practices to provide technical assistance and develop best practices to support and accelerate efforts to adopt, implement, and effectively use interoperable health information technology.

Reauthorizes appropriations for grants to reduce statutory and regulatory barriers to telemedicine.</summary>
</bill>
