<bill session="117" type="h" number="3852" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">William Collins Jet Fuel Exposure Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for a presumption of toxic exposure for certain veterans who, while serving in the Armed Forces, were consistently exposed to jet fuel, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">William Collins Jet Fuel Exposure Recognition Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001209"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000687" joined="2021-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2021-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-20T14:20:23Z" status="Introduced in House">William Collins Jet Fuel Exposure Recognition Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA), for purposes of wartime disability compensation and VA health care, to presume that covered veterans were exposed to toxic substances, chemicals, and airborne hazards during military service, unless there is affirmative evidence that the veterans were not exposed to such substances in connection with their service. Under the bill, covered veterans are those who worked for a cumulative period of at least two years in active service in a military occupational specialty that involved consistent exposure to jet fuel.

In adjudicating claims for compensation for a service-connected disability related to jet fuel exposure with evidence of a disability and a presumption of toxic exposure during active service, the VA must (1) provide a medical examination and request a medical opinion for service-connection; and (2) direct the medical provider to consider the exposure of the veteran to toxic substances during all military deployments and the synergistic effect of all combined toxic substances through inhalation, dermal exposure, and ingestion.

Every other year for a period of eight years, the VA must make publicly available a report related to the effect of jet fuel used by the Armed Forces on the health of individuals. In evaluating claims for compensation for service-connected disabilities, the VA must take into consideration the findings of such reports.</summary>
</bill>
