<bill session="117" type="h" number="4954" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Department of Homeland Security, in consultation with other agencies, to develop guidance for firefighters and other emergency response personnel on best practices to protect such personnel from exposure to PFAS and to limit and prevent the release of PFAS into the environment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PFAS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Firefighters from Adverse Substances Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000624"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2021-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001188" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001215" joined="2022-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2021-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001216" joined="2021-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2022-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="231" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-22T14:43:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Firefighters from Adverse Substances Act or the PFAS Act 

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to develop guidance for firefighters and other emergency response personnel on training, education programs, and best practices to protect them from exposure to perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances, commonly referred to as PFASs, from firefighting foam and to prevent the release of PFASs into the environment. These substances are man-made and may have adverse human health effects. A variety of products contain the compounds, such as nonstick cookware or weatherproof clothing.

DHS shall make available a curriculum designed to

 reduce and eliminate exposure to PFAS from firefighting foam and personal protective equipment (PPE); prevent the release of PFAS from firefighting foam into the environment; and educate firefighters and other emergency response personnel on foams and non-foam alternatives, PPE, and other firefighting tools and equipment that do not contain PFAS. The U.S. Fire Administration shall make recommendations to DHS on the content of the curriculum.

DHS must create an online public repository containing tools and best practices to reduce, limit, and prevent the release of and exposure to PFASs.</summary>
</bill>
