<bill session="110" type="s" number="2875" updated="2020-01-29T20:30:46Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2008-09-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-04-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Wolf Livestock Loss Prevention and Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Gray Wolf Livestock Loss Mitigation Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Wolf Livestock Loss Prevention and Mitigation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to provide grants to designated States and tribes to carry out programs to reduce the risk of livestock loss due to predation by gray wolves and other predator species or to compensate landowners for livestock loss due to predation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001261" joined="2008-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000243" joined="2008-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000858" joined="2008-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001142" joined="2008-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3082"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-04-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands and Forests. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 110-572.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-16">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Bingaman with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2008-09-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="989">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 989.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Wolves"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-05T22:46:46Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Gray Wolf Livestock Loss Mitigation Act of 2008 - Authorizes the Secretary to the Interior, acting through the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, to provide grants to states and Indian tribes to pay the federal share of carrying out programs to compensate livestock producers for activities undertaken to reduce the risk of livestock loss as a result of a predatory species.

Directs the Secretary to designate the states of Montana, Wyoming, and Idaho, and such other states and Indian tribes as the Secretary determines from among states and tribes as having populations of predatory species, as eligible to receive such grants.

Limits the federal share of the cost of carrying out such a compensation program to half of its total annual cost.</summary>
</bill>
