<bill session="119" type="s" number="1696" updated="2025-09-17T11:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2025-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deregulating Restrictions on Interstate Vehicles and Eighteen-wheelers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration from issuing a rule or promulgating a regulation requiring certain commercial motor vehicles to be equipped with speed limiting devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000880" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000577" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001242" joined="2025-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2025-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2025-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-17T14:44:53Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Deregulating Restrictions on Interstate Vehicles and Eighteen-wheelers Act or the DRIVE Act

This bill prohibits the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration (FMCSA) from issuing any rule or regulation to require a commercial motor vehicle to be equipped with a speed limiting device set to a maximum speed.&#160;The&#160;FMCSA issued an advance notice of supplemental proposed rulemaking on this subject on May 4, 2022.

A commercial motor vehicle includes a vehicle operating in interstate commerce that&#160;(1) has a gross vehicle weight of 10,001 pounds or more, (2) is designed or used to transport more than 8 passengers&#160;for compensation, (3) is designed or used to transport more than 15 passengers and is not used to transport passengers for compensation, or (4) is used to transport certain quantities of hazardous materials.</summary>
</bill>
