<bill session="117" type="s" number="454" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:35Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">K2 Veterans Care Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide health care and benefits to veterans who were exposed to toxic substances while serving as members of the Armed Forces at Karshi Khanabad Air Base, Uzbekistan, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">K2 Veterans Care Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2021-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2021-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1355" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="Uzbekistan"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-30T16:56:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">K2 Veterans Care Act of 2021

This bill establishes a presumption of service-connection for certain diseases becoming manifest in a veteran who served on active duty at Karshi-Khanabad (K2) Air Base in Uzbekistan between January 1, 2001, and December 31, 2005. Specifically, there must be a presumption of service-connection for veterans who manifest illnesses that have a positive association with exposure to jet fuel, volatile organic compounds, high levels of particulate matter, depleted uranium, asbestos, or lead-based paint, as determined by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (NASEM). Under a presumption of service-connection, specific conditions diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.

Veterans who served at K2 Air Base during the specified period are eligible for Department of Veterans Affairs hospital care, medical services, and nursing home care for an illness that has been determined by NASEM to have a positive association with exposure to jet fuel, volatile organic compounds, high levels of particulate matter, depleted uranium, asbestos, or lead-based paint.</summary>
</bill>
