<bill session="116" type="h" number="8544" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:34Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STRONG Support for Children Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Services and Trauma-informed Research of Outcomes in Neighborhoods Grants for Support for Children Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STRONG Support for Children Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Health Service Act to support the development and implementation of programs using data analysis to identify and facilitate strategies to improve outcomes for children in geographic areas with a high prevalence of trauma from exposure to adverse childhood experiences, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000617"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2020-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000172" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2020-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2020-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2020-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000482" joined="2020-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2020-12-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Community life and organization"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-12-23T15:48:46Z" status="Introduced in House">Services and Trauma-informed Research of Outcomes in Neighborhoods Grants for Support for Children Act of 2020 or the STRONG Support for Children Act of 2020

This bill establishes two grant programs for governmental health departments to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma and adverse childhood experiences.

For the first program, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must award grants to health departments to use data analysis methods to identify interventions to prevent and mitigate childhood trauma. Grant activities include, among others, using data analysis to identify geographic areas with a high prevalence of adverse childhood experiences and to implement strategies to improve outcomes for infants, children, and adolescents.

For the second program, HHS must award grants to local or tribal governments to establish or expand early childhood trauma-informed care coordination services, including by instituting risk and needs assessments to respond to adverse childhood experiences.

For both grants, the bill prohibits the use of funds for certain purposes, such as using the data analysis methods to inform individual case decisions, including child removals, or increasing the presence of law enforcement.

In addition, HHS must evaluate and report on these programs and make findings and recommendations publicly available on its website.</summary>
</bill>
