<bill session="118" type="h" number="3257" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:10Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Election Integrity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Integrity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit States from using in the administration of an election for Federal office proprietary voting system hardware or software which prevents the system from meeting the voluntary voting system guidelines for interoperability and auditability issued by the Election Assistance Commission under such Act, a voting system whose hardware and software components are manufactured, maintained, or serviced outside the United States, or a voting system which is connected to the internet.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-01T16:35:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Election Integrity Act of 2023

This bill prohibits the use of a voting system in a federal election that

 has proprietary hardware or software that does not meet the Election Assistance Commission's voluntary voting system guidelines for interoperability and auditability, has hardware and software components that are not manufactured and maintained in the United States, is produced by a foreign entity, connects to the internet, or directly tabulates a ballot that was transmitted online.</summary>
</bill>
