<bill session="108" type="h" number="1230" updated="2023-01-15T22:33:38Z">
  <state datetime="2003-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cleveland National Forest Responsible Electricity Transmission Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide an environmentally sound process for the expeditious consideration and approval of a high-voltage electricity transmission line right-of-way through the Trabuco Ranger District of the Cleveland National Forest in the State of California and adjacent lands under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cleveland National Forest Responsible Electricity Transmission Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000059" joined="2003-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Recreation and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA, Interior.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Cleveland National Forest Responsible Electricity Transmission Act - Directs the Secretaries of the Interior and of Agriculture (the "Secretaries") to issue the necessary grants, easements, permits, plan amendments, and other approvals to allow for the siting and construction of a high-voltage electricity transmission line in part of the Cleveland National Forest in California and adjacent lands (except any identified wilderness area) under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and the Forest Service.Instructs the Secretaries to give a preference to any application or preapplication proposal for a transmission line right-of-way submitted before December 31, 2002, over all other applications and proposals for the same or similar right-of-way submitted on or after that date.</summary>
</bill>
