<bill session="111" type="s" number="3160" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRECAUTION Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide information, resources, recommendations, and funding to help State and local law enforcement enact crime prevention and intervention strategies supported by rigorous evidence.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECAUTION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention Resources for Eliminating Criminal Activity Using Tailored Interventions in Our Neighborhoods Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2010-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2021"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2022-2024" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-29T15:50:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Prevention Resources for Eliminating Criminal Activity Using Tailored Interventions in Our Neighborhoods Act of 2010 or the PRECAUTION Act - Establishes the National Commission on Public Safety Through Crime Prevention to: (1) carry out a comprehensive study of the effectiveness of certain crime and delinquency prevention and intervention strategies: and (2) make initial and final reports on such strategies to specified federal and state officials. Exempts such Commission from the Federal Advisory Committee Act.

Authorizes the Attorney General and the Director of the National Institute of Justice to make grants and coordinate federal efforts to implement and evaluate innovative crime or delinquency prevention or intervention strategies.

Provides for funding from the Department of Justice Assets Forfeiture Fund to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
