<bill session="117" type="h" number="4596" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:46Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education to establish record-management plans in order to be accredited or continue to be accredited, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Student Records Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Student Records Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001090"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000378" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2021-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2021-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-30T13:52:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Student Records Protection Act

This bill revises the requirements for an accrediting agency to be recognized by the Department of Education (ED) as a reliable authority on the quality of education being offered at an institution of higher education (IHE). It also requires an IHE to establish a records management plan for accreditation purposes.

Specifically, an accrediting agency must require an IHE to submit for approval a records management plan upon notification by the IHE that it intends to cease its operations. The plan must include a plan for the custody, continued access, and disposition of student records (e.g., student transcripts, billing, and financial-aid records). Further, the IHE must submit the plan to ED.

Under current law, an IHE must be accredited by an accrediting agency to participate in federal student-aid programs.</summary>
</bill>
