<bill session="108" type="s" number="1666" updated="2023-01-15T07:17:57Z">
  <state datetime="2003-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Diabetes Prevention and Treatment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish comprehensive State diabetes control and prevention programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Diabetes Prevention and Treatment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000567"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000711" joined="2004-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2004-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001042" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000064" joined="2004-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2004-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2003-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2003-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2004-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000550" joined="2004-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000123" joined="2004-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000146" joined="2004-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2004-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Access to health care"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Diabetes"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-27T22:35:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Diabetes Prevention and Treatment Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control (CDC), to award grants to support comprehensive State diabetes control and prevention programs.

Requires the Secretary to promote and coordinate diabetes research, including data collection and the development of best practices, early detection and prevention programs, and a national diabetes laboratory.

Gives priority to programs which reduce disparities in diabetes prevention and care for high-risk or underserved populations.

Requires the Secretary, acting through the Director, to award competitive grants to apply the best practices identified by the Secretary for diabetes prevention and control. Gives priority to programs to reduce disparities in prevention and control for high-risk or underserved populations.

Requires the Director to: (1) develop and update scientifically validated quality measures for assessing and improving clinical services related to diabetes; (2) establish a Diabetes Quality Improvement Program; and (3) incorporate diabetes in the annual quality and disparities reports.

Directs the Secretary, acting through the Diabetes Mellitus Interagency Coordinating Committee, to: (1) coordinate a national diabetes education program; and (2) develop and update a strategic research plan for diabetes.

Requires the expansion of research programs concerning diabetes in underserved populations and minority groups and in children and youths.

Requires the development or enhancement of data collection on the prevalence of type 1 and type 2 diabetes in children, including the support of long-term epidemiological studies in children.

Authorizes a report on diabetes by the Surgeon General.</summary>
</bill>
