<bill session="110" type="h" number="4175" updated="2023-01-11T20:11:47Z">
  <state datetime="2007-11-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-11-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to data privacy and security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Privacy and Cybercrime Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Privacy and Cybercrime Enforcement Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000602" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000445" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000553" joined="2008-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000185" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2007-11-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001156" joined="2007-11-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2415"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-11-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer hackers"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Extortion"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identity theft"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Sentencing guidelines"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-01-04T14:57:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Privacy and Cybercrime Enforcement Act of 2007 - Amends federal criminal code provisions relating to computer fraud and unauthorized access to computers to: (1) include computer fraud within the definition of racketeering activity; (2) provide criminal penalties for intentional failures to provide required notices of a security breach involving sensitive personally identifiable information; (3) expand penalties for conspiracies to commit computer fraud and extortion attempts involving threats to access computers without authorization; (4) provide for forfeiture of property used to commit computer fraud; and (5) require restitution for victims of identity theft and computer fraud.

Authorizes additional appropriations for investigating and prosecuting criminal activity involving computers.

Directs the U.S. Sentencing Commission to review and amend, if appropriate, its sentencing guidelines and policies related to identity theft and computer fraud offenses.

Authorizes the Attorney General and state attorneys general to bring civil actions and obtain injunctive relief for violations of federal laws relating to data security.

Requires federal agencies as part of their rulemaking process to prepare and make available to the public privacy impact assessments that describe the impact of proposed agency rules on the privacy of individuals.

Authorizes the Office of Justice Programs of the Department of Justice (DOJ) to award grants to states for programs to increase enforcement efforts involving fraudulent, unauthorized, or other criminal use of personally identifiable information.

Authorizes the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to improve the identification, investigation, and prosecution of criminal or terrorist conspiracies or activities that span jurisdictional boundaries, including terrorism, economic crime, and high-tech crime.</summary>
</bill>
