<bill session="118" type="s" number="4320" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Bessie Coleman Women in Aviation Advisory Committee.</title>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Bessie Coleman Women in Aviation Advisory Committee.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3935" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-11T12:22:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to establish the Bessie Coleman Women in Aviation Advisory Committee. The committee must&#160;advise DOT and the Federal Aviation Administration on matters and policies related to promoting the recruitment, retention, employment, education, training, career advancement, and well-being of women in the aviation industry and aviation-focused federal civil service positions.

Members of the committee must include individuals representing aviation-related businesses (e.g., aircraft manufacturers, air carriers, and airport owners), public and private aviation labor organizations, institutions of higher education, flight schools, and nonprofit organizations within the aviation industry.

All activities carried out by the committee must be in response to written terms of work from DOT or activities approved by the committee. The committee must submit annual reports to DOT and Congress that include (1) findings and associated recommendations for legislative and administrative actions, and (2) planned activities of the committee and proposed terms of work.</summary>
</bill>
