<bill session="117" type="h" number="2490" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:48Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Paycheck Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to provide more effective remedies to victims of discrimination in the payment of wages on the basis of sex, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Paycheck Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000522"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2242" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="205" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Contracts and agency"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC)"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Temporary and part-time employment"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Youth employment and child labor"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-21T14:22:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Paycheck Fairness Act

This bill addresses wage discrimination on the basis of sex. Specifically, it (1) limits an employer's defense that a pay differential is based on a factor other than sex to only bona fide job-related factors in wage discrimination claims, (2) enhances nonretaliation prohibitions, (3) makes it unlawful to require an employee to sign a contract or waiver prohibiting the employee from disclosing information about the employee's wages, and (4) increases civil penalties for violations of equal pay provisions.

Additionally, the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) and the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs must train EEOC employees and other affected parties on wage discrimination. The bill directs the Department of Labor to (1) establish and carry out a grant program for negotiation skills training for girls and women, (2) conduct studies to eliminate pay disparities between men and women, and (3) make available information on wage discrimination to assist the public in understanding and addressing such discrimination. The bill also establishes the Secretary of Labor's National Award for Pay Equity in the Workplace for an employer who has made a substantial effort to eliminate pay disparities between men and women. Finally, the bill requires the EEOC to issue regulations for collecting from employers compensation and other employment data according to the sex, race, and national origin of employees for use in enforcing laws prohibiting pay discrimination.</summary>
</bill>
