<bill session="116" type="s" number="2620" updated="2022-11-01T03:47:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-10-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-10-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">GROWTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Generating Real Opportunities for Workforce Training and Hiring Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">GROWTH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to bolster the domestic workforce by encouraging communication between career and technical education institutions and emphasizing potential employment opportunities, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to treat certain costs relating to career and technical education as qualified higher education expenses for purposes of section 529 programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001046" joined="2019-10-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4760" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Educational guidance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-07T17:57:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Generating Real Opportunities for Workforce Training and Hiring Act or the GROWTH Act

This bill sets forth provisions to promote career and technical education and establish highway construction workforce development initiatives.

Specifically the bill

 expands tax-exempt tuition programs (529 plans) to allow plans to pay transportation costs for attendance at workforce training programs and to repay student loan amounts, directs the Department of Transportation to make grants to establish highway construction workforce initiatives to attract, train, and place workers into highway construction careers, extends and expands the program for reimbursement of military spouses for professional relicensing costs due to a permanent change in duty station, and includes workforce development as an objective of the loan guaranty program of the Small Business Administration.</summary>
</bill>
