<bill session="109" type="h" number="2840" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:58Z">
  <state datetime="2006-06-07">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Federal Agency Protection of Privacy Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require that agencies, in promulgating rules, take into consideration the impact of such rules on the privacy of individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Agency Protection of Privacy Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000657" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000116" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000358" joined="2005-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2005-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2005-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000583" joined="2006-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commercial and Administrative Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-05-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by Voice Vote .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-25">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 109-675.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-25" calendar="Union" number="408">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 408.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU09" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Commercial and Administrative Law" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Bank records"/>
    <term name="Citizen participation"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Congressional-executive relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security numbers"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-08T22:28:54Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">Federal Agency Protection of Privacy Act of 2005 - Requires federal agencies: (1) when publishing a general notice of proposed rulemaking for any proposed rule or a notice of proposed rulemaking for an interpretative rule involving the internal revenue laws, and such rulemaking pertains to the collection, maintenance, use, or disclosure of personally identifiable information from ten or more individuals, other than agencies, instrumentalities, or federal employees, to prepare an initial assessment describing the rule's impact on individual privacy; and (2) when promulgating the final rule, to prepare a final privacy impact assessment that includes: (1) providing security for such information, including written notice to any individual whose privacy interests are compromised by the unauthorized release of personally identifiable information as a result of a breach of security at, or by, the agency; and (2) a summary of any significant issues raised by, and changes made pursuant to, public comments on the initial assessment. Instructs agencies to make copies of final assessments publicly available.

Allows the head of an agency to waive or delay the completion of some or all of: (1) these requirements to the same extent as for waiving or delaying the completion of requirements for regulatory flexibility analyses; and (2) certain of the preceding requirements under this Act for national security reasons, or to protect from disclosure, classified information, confidential commercial information, or information the disclosures of which may adversely affect a law enforcement effort. Requires that final assessments not made publicly available and unpublished final assessments and/or summaries be made available in classified form to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House and Senate.

Requires the head of an agency promulgating a rule that may have a significant privacy impact to assure that individuals have been given an opportunity to participate in the rulemaking. Requires each agency to: (1) carry out a periodic review of promulgated rules that have a significant privacy impact to determine whether each such rule can be amended or rescinded to minimize such impact while remaining in accordance with applicable statutes; (2) carry out such review according to a plan providing for the review of each rule every ten years; and (3) annually publish a list of the rules to be reviewed. Requires the list to: (1) include a brief description of each rule and the need for, and legal basis of, such rule; and (2) invite public comment upon the determination concerning the rule. Sets forth provisions governing judicial review of agency compliance with this Act. Requires congressional review of agencies' actions that are relevant to this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-675</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
