<bill session="117" type="h" number="9403" updated="2023-02-21T20:15:16Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide whistleblower protections to certain workers in the offshore oil and gas industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-21T20:05:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Offshore Oil and Gas Worker Whistleblower Protection Act

This bill prohibits an employer from discharging or discriminating against employees working in waters above the Outer Continental Shelf who report or testify about violations of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, including about unsafe conditions or the adequacy of any oil spill response plan required by law.

The bill establishes procedures for the filing, investigation, and adjudication of a whistle-blower complaint.

Additionally, employers are required to

 post a notice approved by the Department of Labor explaining employee rights and remedies in a conspicuous workplace location; provide training to employees about their rights within 30 days of employment, and at least once every 12 months thereafter; and provide employees with a card containing a toll-free telephone number for obtaining information or for filing a complaint.</summary>
</bill>
