<bill session="118" type="h" number="1473" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:29Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Targeting and Offsetting Existing Illegal Contaminants Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeting and Offsetting Existing Illegal Contaminants Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a program within the Forest Service to detect, document, monitor, and remediate the environmental damages caused by trespass cultivation on National Forest Lands, and amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to include criminal penalties for illegal pesticide application on Government property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2023-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-08">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committees on Natural Resources, and the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Crimes against animals and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-07T19:56:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Targeting and Offsetting Existing Illegal Contaminants Act

This bill provides for a program within the Forest Service to detect, monitor, and remediate the environmental damage caused by trespass cultivation of cannabis on National Forest System lands and increases criminal penalties for illegal pesticide application on government property.

Specifically, the bill directs the Forest Service to carry out a program of environmental remediation on its land, to be known as the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Remediation Program.

The Forest Service shall pay fees and charges imposed by state authorities for permits for the disposal of hazardous substances, pollutants, contaminants, improper pesticides, or other wastes on Forest Service lands to the same extent as nongovernmental entities.

The Forest Service may enter into agreements with certain entities to carry out the Forest Service's responsibilities under this program.

The bill establishes an account in the Treasury to collect amounts recovered from trespassers for response actions, as well as amounts from other sources. Funds in the account may only be used for environmental remediation.</summary>
</bill>
