<amendment session="112" chamber="s" number="277" updated="2022-02-03T05:58:37Z">
  <amends type="s" number="493" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-04-06">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000770"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-03-30"/>
  <description>To suspend, for 2 years, any Environmental Protection Agency enforcement of greenhouse gas regulations, to exempt American agriculture from greenhouse gas regulations, and to increase the number of companies eligible to participate in the successful Advanced Energy Manufacturing Tax Credit Program.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-04-06" how="roll" result="fail" roll="52">
      <text>Amendment SA 277, under the order of 4/5/2011, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 7 - 93. Record Vote Number: 52.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Amendment SA 277 proposed by Senator Landrieu for Senator Stabenow. (consideration: CR S2155-2157, S2178; text: CR S2155-2156) To suspend, for 2 years, any Environmental Protection Agency enforcement of greenhouse gas regulations, to exempt American agriculture from greenhouse gas regulations, and to increase the number of companies eligible to participate in the successful Advanced Energy Manufacturing Tax Credit Program.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 277 proposed by Senator Landrieu for Senator Stabenow.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2155-2157, S2178" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2155-2156" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 277, under the order of 4/5/2011, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 7 - 93. Record Vote Number: 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-06">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 277, under the order of 4/5/2011, not having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, the amendment was not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 7 - 93. Record Vote Number: 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-30">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
