<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>41</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:20:44Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:20:44Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-01-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-01-25T17:13:19Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000025</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inouye, Daniel K. [D-HI]</fullName>
        <firstName>DANIEL</firstName>
        <lastName>INOUYE</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>HI</state>
        <middleName>KEN</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Health and Human Services</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health promotion and preventive care</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Mental health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>National Institutes of Health (NIH)</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research administration and funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-02-22T20:31:14Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>National Office for Social Work Research Act - Amends the Public Health Service Act to establish the Office of Social Work Research in the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to conduct, support, and disseminate targeted research concerning social work methods and outcomes related to problems of significant social concern. Requires the Office to: (1) promote research and training to inform social work practices, and (2) provide policymakers with research to better understand complex social issues and make informed funding decisions about service effectiveness and cost efficiency.<br /> <br /> Sets forth duties of the Director of the Office, which shall include: (1) recommending an agenda for conducting and supporting social work research through the national research institutes and centers; (2) promoting coordination and cooperation among such institutes and centers; (3) promoting the sufficient allocation of NIH resources for such research; and (4) promoting and encouraging the establishment of a centralized clearinghouse for social work research to provide understandable information about this research to the public, social service professionals, medical professionals, patients, and families.<br /> <br /> Requires the Director to serve as the principal adviser to the Director of NIH and to provide advice to other relevant agencies. <br /> <br /> Authorizes the Director of the Office to enter into cooperative agreements with, and make grants to, public or private nonprofit entities to pay all or part of the cost of planning, establishing, or strengthening, and providing basic operating support for centers of excellence for clinical and psychosocial research, training in, and demonstration of social work research.<br /> <br /> </p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>National Office for Social Work Research Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>National Office for Social Work Research Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a National Office for Social Work Research.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>National Office for Social Work Research Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-01-25T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s41is/xml/BILLS-112s41is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-01-25</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
