<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="992" updated="2022-02-03T06:01:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3309" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-03-27T17:52:39-04:00">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001038"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-03-27"/>
  <description>Amendment sought to provide for, in the event that the FCC creates or amends a rule relating to baby monitors, the FCC to require the packaging of a new baby monitor to display a warning label so that families are informed that video and sounds captured by an analog baby monitor may be easily viewed or heard by potential intruders outside a consumer's home.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 112-422 to require, in the event that the FCC creates or amends a rule relating to baby monitors, the FCC to require the packaging of a new baby monitor to display a warning label so that families are informed that video and sounds captured by an analog baby monitor may be easily viewed or heard by potential intruders outside a consumer's home.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-03-27T17:52:39-04:00" how="roll" result="fail" roll="134">
      <text>On agreeing to the Crowley amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 219 (Roll no. 134).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T16:39:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Crowley.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1619-1620, H1624-1625" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1619" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:52:39-04:00">
      <text>Amendment failed in Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:52:39-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T17:52:39-04:00">
      <text>House amendment not agreed to: On agreeing to the Crowley amendment (A001) Failed by recorded vote: 196 - 219 (Roll no. 134).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27T16:39:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Mr. Crowley.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1619-1620, H1624-1625" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1619" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
