<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1081</number>
    <updateDate>2019-02-20T23:08:25Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-02-22T21:51:08Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-05-26</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
        <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-05-26T14:49:18Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssev00</systemCode>
            <name>Environment and Public Works Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M001153</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Murkowski, Lisa [R-AK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Lisa</firstName>
        <lastName>Murkowski</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AK</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment, monitoring, research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Historic sites and heritage areas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parks, recreation areas, trails</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Roads and highways</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-09-06T20:51:46Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011 - Authorizes a state to select without competitive bidding or the approval of the Secretary of Transportation (DOT) one or more proprietary, patented, or experimental products for use in a federal-aid highway project. Declares that state use of such products shall not affect the eligibility of the state or highway project to receive federal funding.</p> <p>Repeals certain parkland preservation requirements prohibiting the Secretary from approving a transportation program or project requiring the use of public park lands unless there is no feasible alternative to the use of such land.</p>  <p>Makes the lead agency responsible for determining the purpose of and need for a project.</p> <p>Decreases from 180 days to 90 days after publication in the Federal Register of a notice that a permit, license, or approval for a highway or public transportation capital project is final the deadline for filing a claim seeking judicial review of the permit, license, or approval. Places the burden of proof of the claim on the claimant.</p> <p>Authorizes a state to designate a highway project as a categorical exclusion (that does not involve significant environmental impact).</p> <p>Revises U.S. policy on public lands and wildlife and waterfowl refuges to exclude historic sites. Authorizes the Secretary to approve a transportation program or project (other than a park road or parkway project) requiring the use of a park, recreation area, or wildlife and waterfowl refuge only if the Governor of the state (or mayor or chief executive of the city, county, or borough with management responsibility for or ownership of the area) agrees that such project is the preferred alternative.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Project Delivery Improvement Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend titles 23 and 49, United States Code, to streamline the environmental review process for highway projects, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-05-26T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1081is/xml/BILLS-112s1081is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-05-26</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
