<bill session="119" type="h" number="2185" updated="2025-06-13T16:05:21Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mink VIRUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mink VIRUS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mink: Vectors for Infection Risk in the United States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To protect public health and human safety by prohibiting the farming of mink for their fur, to compensate farmers as they transition out of the industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000476" joined="2025-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Agriculture, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-13T16:03:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Mink: Vectors for Infection Risk in the United States Act or the Mink VIRUS Act

This bill prohibits the farming of mink for their fur beginning one year after the bill's enactment and establishes a compensation program.

Beginning 90 days after the bill's enactment, any termination of farmed mink must be done in a manner that (1) meets the definition of euthanasia specified in Department of Agriculture (USDA) regulations&#160;(i.e., the humane destruction of an animal accomplished by a method that produces rapid unconsciousness and subsequent death without evidence of pain or distress, or that utilizes anesthesia that causes painless loss of consciousness and subsequent death); and (2) is classified as acceptable by the American Veterinary Medical Association Guidelines for the Euthanasia of Animals.

This prohibition and these requirements do not preempt or limit any state law or regulation that is more restrictive. Further, any person in violation of this prohibition or these requirements is subject to civil penalties.

USDA must establish a payment program to compensate fur farm owners whose operations involve the farming of mink. Under the program, USDA must provide payments&#160;for (1) the reasonable costs incurred to comply with this bill, and (2) the market value of the portion of the&#160;farm involving mink farming (exclusive of the land). Fur farm owners may not use payment funds for fur farm operations. Further, the owner must provide USDA with a permanent property easement that prohibits the operation of any fur farm on the easement area.</summary>
</bill>
