<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>540</number>
    <updateDate>2022-02-03T05:30:50Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2022-02-03T05:30:50Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>House</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>H</originChamberCode>
    <type>HR</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-02-02</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
        <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-05-17T19:29:41Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
        <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <subcommittees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
            <activities>
              <item>
                <name>Referred to</name>
                <date>2005-02-16T21:35:11Z</date>
              </item>
            </activities>
          </item>
        </subcommittees>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-02-02T15:09:35Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer Act</title>
        <congress>109</congress>
        <number>310</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2006-08-03</actionDate>
          <text>Became Public Law No: 109-265.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-17</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sseg00</systemCode>
            <name>Energy and Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:04:55</actionTime>
        <text>The title of the measure was amended. Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38800</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:04:51</actionTime>
        <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H38310</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:04:45</actionTime>
        <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote. (text: CR H3278-3281)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H37300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>15:04:45</actionTime>
        <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.(text: CR H3278-3281)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>8000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:55:30</actionTime>
        <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 540.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H8D000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:55:27</actionTime>
        <text>Considered under suspension of the rules. (consideration: CR H3278-3283)</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionTime>14:55:18</actionTime>
        <text>Mr. Renzi moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
        <type>Floor</type>
        <actionCode>H30300</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-02-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii13</systemCode>
            <name>Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries Subcommittee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>1</code>
          <name>House committee actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-02-02</actionDate>
        <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>H11100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>2</code>
          <name>House floor actions</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>hsii00</systemCode>
            <name>Natural Resources Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-02-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>Intro-H</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-02-02</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in House</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>1000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>G000152</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Rep. Gibbons, Jim [R-NV-2]</fullName>
        <firstName>JIM</firstName>
        <lastName>GIBBONS</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>NV</state>
        <district>2</district>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <notes>
      <item>
        <text><![CDATA[For further action, see S.310, which became Public Law 109-265 on 8/3/2006.]]></text>
      </item>
    </notes>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Water Resources Development</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Agriculture and Food</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Aquifers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>California</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Canals</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of the Interior</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal aid to water resources development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Groundwater</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Infrastructure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Irrigation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Irrigation districts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Kansas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Land transfers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Maintenance and repair</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nebraska</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nevada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pipelines</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Public Lands and Natural Resources</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Rivers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Saline waters</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Texas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Waste water treatment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water districts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water supply</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Watersheds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Wells</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Water Resources Development</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-02-02</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in House</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-02-22T20:54:57Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p></p> <p>Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to convey to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District in Nevada real property within the Newlands Project, Nevada, known as 2666 Harrigan Road, Fallon, Nevada, after: (1) compliance with requirements relating to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and cultural resources; and (2) completion of necessary environmental site assessments, remediation, or removal.</p> <p>Directs that amounts received by the United States for the lease and sale of Newlands Project lands comprising the Fallon Freight Yard be treated as payment in full consideration for the property conveyed under this Act.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>36</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-05-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Passed House amended</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2005-06-20T19:01:38Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Title I: Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer </b>- Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer Act - (Sec. 102) Directs the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to convey to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District in Nevada real property within the Newlands Project, Nevada, known as 2666 Harrigan Road, Fallon, Nevada, after: (1) compliance with requirements relating to the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and cultural resources; and (2) completion of necessary environmental site assessments, remediation, or removal. </p> <p>Directs that amounts received by the United States for the lease and sale of Newlands Project lands comprising the Fallon Freight Yard be treated as payment in full consideration for the property conveyed under this Act.</p> <p>Requires the Secretary to report to Congress if the conveyance has not been completed within 12 months after this Act's enactment. Shields the United States from liability for damages arising out of any act or omission by the District or its employees, agents, or contractors relating to the property conveyed and occurring prior to, on, or after the date of conveyance. </p> <p><b>Title II: Inland Empire and Cucamonga Valley Recycling Projects </b>- (Sec. 201) Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative - Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary: (1) in cooperation with the Inland Empire Utilities Agency, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Inland Empire regional water recycling project; and (2) in cooperation with the Cucamonga Valley Water District, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the Cucamonga Valley Water District satellite recycling plants in Rancho Cucamonga, California, to reclaim and recycle approximately two million gallons per day of domestic wastewater. Limits the Federal share of the cost of each project to 25 percent. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions under this title 10 years after enactment. </p> <p><b>Title III: Riverside-Corona Feeder Water Project </b>- (Sec. 301) Authorizes the Secretary , in cooperation with the Western Municipal Water District, to participate in a project to plan, design, and construct the Riverside-Corona Feeder, which includes 20 groundwater wells and 28 miles of pipeline in San Bernardino and Riverside Counties, California. Limits the Federal share of the cost to: (1) plan, design, and construct the project to the lesser of 35 percent of the project's total cost or $50 million; and (2) complete the necessary planning study associated with the project to 50 percent of the total study cost. Directs that in-kind services performed by the District be considered a part of the local cost share to complete the project. </p> <p>(Sec. 302) Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary to participate in the design, planning, and construction of: (1) projects to treat impaired surface water, reclaim and reuse impaired groundwater, and provide brine disposal within the Santa Ana Watershed, in cooperation with the Yucaipa Valley Water District; and (2) a project to reclaim and reuse wastewater, including degraded groundwaters, within and outside of the service area of the City of Corona Water Utility, in cooperation with the City of Corona Water Utility. Limits the Federal share of each of the project costs to 25 percent.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations to carry out the projects within the Santa Ana Watershed as described above.</p> <p>Prohibits the Secretary from using or providing funds under this Act for project operation or maintenance.</p> <p>Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions under this title 10 years after enactment. </p> <p><b>Title IV: Ainsworth Unit, Sandhills Division, Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program - </b>(Sec. 401) Directs the Secretary to extend the water service contract for the Ainsworth Unit, Sandhills Division, Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, Nebraska, for four years.</p> <p><b>Title V: Wichita</b> <b>Project Equus Beds Division - </b>Wichita Project Equus Beds Division Authorization Act of 2005 - (Sec. 502) Authorizes the Secretary to assist in the funding and implementation of the Equus Beds Aquifer Recharge and Recovery Component of the Integrated Local Water Supply Plan, Wichita, Kansas (referred to as the Equus Beds Division). Requires that construction of the Division be in substantial accordance with the plans and designs. Makes operation, maintenance, and replacement of the Division, including funding for those purposes, the sole responsibility of the City of Wichita.</p> <p>Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) enter into, or agree to amendments of, cooperative or other appropriate agreements; and (2) charge an appropriate share related to administrative costs.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary: (1) before obligating funds for design or construction, to work cooperatively with the City to use plans, designs, and engineering and environmental analyses that have already been prepared by the City for the Division; and (2) to assure that such information is used in a manner consistent with applicable Federal laws and regulations, including principles and guidelines used in preparing feasibility level project studies.</p> <p>Authorizes as the Federal share an amount not to exceed 25 percent of the total cost of the Equus Beds Division or $30 million (January 2003 prices), whichever is less, plus or minus any amounts justified by reason of ordinary fluctuations in construction costs as indicated by engineering cost indexes applicable to the type of construction involved. Makes such sums nonreimbursable.</p> <p>Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions under this title 10 years after enactment.</p> <p><b>Title VI: Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement </b>- Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2005 - (Sec. 602) Amends the Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2000 to authorize specified additional projects, including projects for water conservation and improvement in Cameron, Hidalgo, Willacy, Hudspeth, and El Paso counties, Texas.</p> <p>Permits each project that the Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of the Bureau of Reclamation, conducts or participates in to include: (1) the replacement of irrigation canals and lateral canals with buried pipelines; (2) the impervious lining of irrigation canals and lateral canals; (3) the installation of water level, flow measurement, pump control, and telemetry systems; (4) the renovation and replacement of pumping plants; and (5) other activities that will result in water conservation or an improved water supply. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer and use for another such project up to ten percent of amounts made available for a project.</p> <p>(Sec. 603) Reauthorizes appropriations for Lower Rio Grande construction.</p> <p>(Sec. 604) Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out such additional projects authorized by this title 10 years after enactment.</p> <p><b>Title VII: Brownsville Public Utility Board Water Recycling and Desalinization Project </b>- (Sec. 701) Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretar, in cooperation with the Brownsville Public Utility Board, to participate in the design, planning, and construction of facilities to reclaim, reuse, and treat impaired water in the Brownsville, Texas, area. Limits the Federal share of project costs to 25 percent of the total. Prohibits funds provided by the Secretary from being used for project operation and maintenance.</p> <p>Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions of this title 10 years after enactment.</p> <p><b>Title VIII: El Paso, Texas, Water Reclamation, Reuse, and Desalinization Project </b>- (Sec. 801) Amends the Reclamation Wastewater and Groundwater Study and Facilities Act to authorize the Secretary to participate in the design, planning, and construction of the El Paso Water Reclamation, Reuse, and Desalinization project to reclaim and reuse wastewater and to treat and reuse impaired and brackish groundwater in the service area of the El Paso Water Utilities Public Service Board, El Paso, Texas. Limits the Federal share of the project's total cost to 25 percent. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds for operation and maintenance of the project.</p> <p>Terminates the Secretary's authority to carry out any provisions of this title 10 years after enactment.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District.</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Lower Rio Grande Valley Water Resources Conservation and Improvement Act of 2005</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Wichita Project Equus Beds Division Authorization Act of 2005</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Inland Empire Regional Water Recycling Initiative</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Passed House for portions of this bill</titleType>
        <title>Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility Transfer Act</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District.</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Titles as Amended by House</titleType>
        <title>To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to convey the Newlands Project Headquarters and Maintenance Yard Facility to the Truckee-Carson Irrigation District.</title>
        <chamberCode>H</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>House</chamberName>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Referred in Senate</type>
        <date>2005-05-17T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Engrossed in House</type>
        <date>2005-05-16T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats/>
      </item>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in House</type>
        <date>2005-02-02T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109hr540ih/xml/BILLS-109hr540ih.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-05-17</actionDate>
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
