<bill session="118" type="h" number="3220" updated="2025-11-19T04:07:44Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Correctional Facilities Occupational Safety and Health Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Correctional Facilities Occupational Safety and Health Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance coverage and oversight of occupational safety and health standards in correctional facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2024-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2023-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2023-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2024-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000400" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000602" joined="2023-07-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2024-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000617" joined="2024-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2023-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2023-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2024-01-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="518" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Labor standards"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-13T19:37:49Z" status="Introduced in House">Correctional Facilities Occupational Safety and Health Act of 2023

This bill extends federal workplace safety and health protections to incarcerated workers. These are individuals who (1) are incarcerated or detained in a federal, state, or local correctional facility (or a private facility operating under government contract); and (2) perform work offered or required by the correctional facility, such as prison work programs or work release programs.

States and territories that enforce their own workplace safety and health laws and standards under a plan approved by the Occupational Safety and Health Administration must include workplace protections for incarcerated workers in the plan. In addition, the Department of Labor must establish a grant program to assist states with amending their occupational safety and health laws to cover incarcerated workers and with enforcing those laws.

Furthermore, the Bureau of Prisons must ensure that its workplace safety and health program applies to incarcerated workers in the same manner as it applies to employees of the bureau.

Additionally, states and localities that participate in the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program must have workplace safety and health protections for incarcerated workers that are appropriately monitored and enforced. The bill reserves a portion of the grants for recipients to use to set up workplace safety and health protections for incarcerated workers.

The bill also requires periodic reports to Congress and the Department of Justice about the workplace and safety conditions at correctional facilities, including any potential noncompliance with relevant standards.</summary>
</bill>
