<bill session="116" type="hr" number="1154" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:27Z">
  <state datetime="2020-10-02T12:34:25-04:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-10-02T12:34:25-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Condemning QAnon and rejecting the conspiracy theories it promotes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Condemning QAnon and rejecting the conspiracy theories it promotes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2020-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000378" joined="2020-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000591" joined="2020-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000611" joined="2020-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T11:41:20-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1164 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 1153 and H. Res. 1154 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-01T21:23:37-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1164 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T10:06:45-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1164.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5652-5657" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T10:06:50-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H. Res. 1153 and H. Res. 1154 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T10:07:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 1154.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T10:45:14-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T10:45:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H. Res. 1154, the Chair put the question on adoption of the resolution and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Jayapal demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T11:50:15-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5659" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="218" datetime="2020-10-02T12:34:25-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 371 - 18, 1 Present (Roll no. 218).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5652-5653" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2020-10-02T12:34:29-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="1164" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="116" type="hr" number="1094" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against property"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Political movements and philosophies"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-21T10:48:36Z" status="Passed House">This resolution condemns QAnon and rejects the conspiracy theories it promotes.

The resolution condemns all other groups and ideologies that contribute to the spread of unfounded conspiracy theories and that encourage Americans to destroy property and attack law enforcement officers.

The resolution encourages federal law enforcement and homeland security agencies to continue to strengthen their focus on preventing violence, threats, harassment, and other criminal activity by extremists motivated by fringe political conspiracy theories.

Finally, the resolution encourages the intelligence community to uncover any foreign support, assistance, or online amplification QAnon receives, as well as any QAnon affiliations, coordination, and contacts with foreign extremist organizations or groups espousing violence.</summary>
</bill>
