<bill session="110" type="h" number="7074" updated="2018-11-08T23:37:59Z">
  <state datetime="2008-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Office Tax Deduction Simplification and Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="display">Home Office Tax Deduction Simplification and Improvement Act of 2008</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to simplify the deduction for use of a portion of a residence as a home office by providing an optional standard home office deduction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000544"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="6214" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="6972" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="3371" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Home offices"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Property tax"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-29T14:51:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Home Office Tax Deduction Simplification and Improvement Act of 2008 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a taxpayer who uses a residence to conduct a trade or business to elect a standard tax deduction equal to the product of a standard rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury and the square footage of the portion of a residence used to conduct a trade or business (home office tax deduction). Modifies the rules for the home office tax deduction to: (1) allow a deduction for the cost of dealing with patients, clients, or customers even if they are not physically present in the home office; and (2) establish a de minimis exemption for personal use of a home office.

Requires the Secretary to ensure that all self-employment tax forms and schedules separately state amounts attributable to real estate taxes, mortgage interest, and depreciation for purposes of the home office tax deduction.</summary>
</bill>
