<amendment session="109" chamber="s" number="5183" updated="2022-02-03T05:26:46Z">
  <amends type="s" number="3709" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2006-11-16">fail</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000061"/>
  <offered datetime="2006-11-16"/>
  <description>To require as a precondition to United States-India peaceful atomic energy cooperation determinations by the President that United States nuclear cooperation with India does nothing to assist, encourage, or induce India to manufacture or acquire nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2006-11-16" how="roll" result="fail" roll="268">
      <text>Amendment SA 5183 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 25 - 71. Record Vote Number: 268.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Amendment SA 5183 proposed by Senator Feingold. (consideration: CR S11010-11016, S11020; text: CR S11011) To require as a precondition to United States-India peaceful atomic energy cooperation determinations by the President that United States nuclear cooperation with India does nothing to assist, encourage, or induce India to manufacture or acquire nuclear weapons or other nuclear explosive devices.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 5183 proposed by Senator Feingold.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11010-11016, S11020" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11011" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 5183 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 25 - 71. Record Vote Number: 268.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Senate amendment not agreed to: Amendment SA 5183 not agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 25 - 71. Record Vote Number: 268.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-11-16">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
