<bill session="116" type="h" number="7644" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:55Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Juvenile Incarceration Reduction Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the use of risk and needs assessment tools in juvenile incarceration decisions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Juvenile Incarceration Reduction Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-16">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E636"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Juvenile crime and gang violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-11-02T16:22:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Juvenile Incarceration Reduction Act of 2020

This bill limits the use of risk and needs assessment systems in decisions related to juveniles in a criminal law context. (A risk and needs assessment system evaluates, among other things, a particular individual's risk of recidivism after release from prison and what programs may reduce that risk.)

Under the bill, such a system may not be used to determine whether a juvenile may or should be treated as an adult in a criminal proceeding. Such a system may also not be used (1) to determine the recidivism risk of a juvenile charged with a nonviolent offense, or (2) as the sole factor to determine the recidivism risk of a juvenile who has committed an act of juvenile delinquency that would be a felony if committed by an adult.

The bill also prohibits using such a system to (1) determine a juvenile should be taken into custody for an alleged act of juvenile delinquency prior to adjudication; or (2) establish, without additional evidence, a juvenile's eligibility or suitability for a recidivism reduction program.

If such a system is used to determine the recidivism risk of a juvenile who has committed an act of juvenile delinquency that would be a felony if committed by an adult, any evidence established by the system is inadmissible as evidence to establish that the juvenile committed the act in question.</summary>
</bill>
