<bill session="117" type="h" number="1566" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">AI/AN CAPTA</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to require that equitable distribution of assistance include equitable distribution to Indian tribes and tribal organizations and to increase amounts reserved for allotment to Indian tribes and tribal organizations under certain circumstances, and to provide for a Government Accountability Office report on child abuse and neglect in American Indian tribal communities.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AI/AN CAPTA</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Indian and Alaska Native Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000551"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Natural Resources, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="485" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1868" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-26T15:42:17Z" status="Introduced in House">American Indian and Alaska Native Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act or the AI/AN CAPTA

This bill establishes additional resources to assist tribal communities with preventing and treating child abuse and neglect.

First, the bill requires the Government Accountability Office to report on child abuse and neglect in tribal communities for the purpose of making recommendations to Congress regarding these issues.

Additionally, the Department of Health and Human Services must include Indian tribes and tribal organizations in its equitable distribution of assistance for programs and projects related to child abuse prevention and treatment.</summary>
</bill>
