<bill session="119" type="h" number="4904" updated="2025-10-07T08:05:23Z">
  <state datetime="2025-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PHASE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pedestrian Hazard, Awareness, and Safety Expansion Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PHASE Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology and the Secretary of Transportation to take certain actions to develop physical alternatives to better protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users against traffic incidents, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2025-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-08-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-08-06">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-22T13:18:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Pedestrian Hazard, Awareness, and Safety Expansion Act of 2025 or the PHASE Act of 2025

This bill directs the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST) and the Department of Transportation (DOT) to&#160;conduct studies and award grants&#160;to improve road safety for pedestrians and vulnerable road users.

Specifically, the bill directs NIST to transmit to DOT potential solutions to improve and enhance traffic control devices using innovative technologies in order to better equip vehicle operators (including bicycles) and protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users.&#160;

In addition, DOT must establish a program to provide grants to cities, Indian tribes, and municipalities to implement infrastructure that improves pedestrian safety (e.g., innovative technology for crosswalks, expanded buffer zones, and upgraded highway traffic signals).

DOT must also carry out a study on developing physical alternatives to better protect pedestrians and vulnerable road users from traffic incidents.</summary>
</bill>
