<bill session="112" type="h" number="1995" updated="2021-04-19T18:45:33Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="display">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an Office of Specialized Instructional Support in the Department of Education and to provide grants to State educational agencies to reduce barriers to learning.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000652" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001259" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2011-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2011-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2011-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2011-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2011-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2012-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2011-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000810" joined="2011-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000326" joined="2011-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2011-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-09-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance and assessments"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-03T18:47:39Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Barriers to Learning Act of 2011 - Amends the Department of Education Organization Act to create an Office of Specialized Instructional Support within the Department of Education to improve specialized instructional support services in schools.

Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to establish a Reduced Barriers to Learning program authorizing the Secretary of Education to award competitive matching grants to states to: (1) establish or expand specialized instructional support services and programs at the state level that are designed to provide technical assistance, coordination, and support to specialized instructional support services and programs addressing barriers to learning within local educational agencies and individual schools; and (2) hire and support specialized instructional support services coordinators to provide such assistance, coordination, and support.

Replaces references to pupil services and pupil services personnel with references to specialized instructional support services and specialized instructional support personnel.

Defines such services as those provided by school counselors, social workers, psychologists, and other qualified professionals that provide assessment, diagnosis, counseling, educational, therapeutic, and other necessary services as part of a comprehensive program to meet student needs.</summary>
</bill>
