<bill session="111" type="h" number="6085" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:41Z">
  <state datetime="2010-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to provide for Debbie Smith grants for auditing sexual assault evidence backlogs and to establish a Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SAFER Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001059" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000290" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001140" joined="2010-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001160" joined="2010-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000592" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2010-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2010-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000576" joined="2010-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000480" joined="2010-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2010-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1555"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Citizenship, Refugees, Border Security, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Genetics"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-09-16T19:18:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry Act of 2010 or the SAFER Act of 2010 - Amends the DNA Analysis Backlog Elimination Act of 2000 to: (1) allow states or local governments to use grant funds under such Act to conduct audits of samples of sexual assault evidence that are awaiting testing; and (2) provide funding in FY2011-FY2014 for such purpose. Authorizes the Attorney General to award grants for such audits only if the grant recipient (i.e., a state or local government) submits a plan for performing the audit of samples of sexual assault evidence and includes a good-faith estimate of the number of such samples.

Requires the Attorney General to: (1) establish a Sexual Assault Forensic Evidence Registry to include information about samples of sexual assault evidence awaiting testing and to track the testing and processing of such samples; and (2) develop and disseminate to law enforcement and other appropriate agencies a report on best practices for the testing and use of DNA evidence collected as part of a criminal investigation of sexual assault cases. Sets forth requirements relating to information required to be included in such Registry, the protection of personally identifiable information in the Registry, and the updating of information in the Registry.

Expresses the sense of Congress that law enforcement agencies and other appropriate entities should use the best practices developed by the Attorney General to develop, evaluate, and improve DNA evidence protocols.</summary>
</bill>
