<bill session="117" type="h" number="9676" updated="2023-02-21T21:45:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RARE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RARE Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rare disease Advancement, surveillance Research, and Education Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand and improve the programs and activities of the Department of Health and Human Services for awareness, education, research, surveillance, diagnosis, and treatment concerning rare diseases and conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1335-1336"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-21T21:36:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Rare disease Advancement, surveillance Research, and Education Act of 2022 or the RARE Act of 2022

The bill reauthorizes through FY2028 the National Institutes of Health Rare Disease Regional Centers of Excellence and expands activities to facilitate research and increase awareness of rare diseases and conditions. (Rare diseases and conditions are those with a prevalence&#160;of fewer than 200,000 individuals in the United States.)

The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention may expand infrastructure and activities to track the epidemiology of up to four rare diseases and conditions and incorporate&#160;this information into a National Rare Disease or Condition Surveillance System.

The Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality must expand its activities to increase health care providers' awareness of rare diseases and conditions.

The National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, or another appropriate entity, must update the 2010 report Rare Diseases and Orphan Products: Accelerating Research and Development.</summary>
</bill>
