<bill session="116" type="h" number="6892" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the CARES Act to add requirements for the Main Street Lending Program related to non-profit organizations, small businesses, minority depository institutions, and community development financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the CARES Act to add requirements for the Main Street Lending Program related to non-profit organizations, small businesses, minority depository institutions, and community development financial institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001281"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Federal Reserve System"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-26T16:26:54Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill expands existing COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) economic aid programs to include nonprofit organizations and institutions of higher education. Specifically, the Federal Reserve Board must make these organizations eligible for the Main Street Lending Program, which is currently available to small- and mid-sized businesses.

The board must create low-cost loan options for nonprofit organizations, as well offer loan forgiveness to certain nonprofit organizations that predominately serve low-income communities.

The Main Street Lending Program must offer loans that do not have a minimum loan size and includes the ability to defer payments without capitalization of interest to small businesses, nonprofits, and institutions of higher education. The board must authorize community development financial institutions to be eligible lenders.</summary>
</bill>
