<bill session="117" type="h" number="7854" updated="2022-12-30T00:04:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Venezuelan Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Venezuelan Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Homeland Security to adjust the status of certain aliens who are nationals of Venezuela to that of aliens lawfully admitted for permanent residence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000797" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000808" joined="2022-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-26T20:38:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Venezuelan Adjustment Act

This bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to grant lawful permanent resident status to qualifying nationals of Venezuela.

A national of Venezuela shall be eligible if that individual (1) applies for lawful permanent resident status no later than three years after this bill's enactment, (2) entered the United States on or before December 31, 2021, (3) has been continuously physically present in the United States for at least one year when filing their application, (4) is otherwise eligible to receive an immigrant visa, and (5) is not inadmissible under various grounds such as a conviction for an aggravated felony. Certain grounds for inadmissibility, such as the public charge ground, shall not apply.

The spouse, child, or unmarried son or daughter of an eligible individual shall also be eligible.

If an individual has applied for lawful permanent resident status under this bill and is subject to exclusion, deportation, or removal proceedings, DHS may not order that individual's removal unless DHS has made a final determination to deny the application.

DHS must provide work authorization to an individual whose application has been pending for more than 180 days, and may also provide authorization before that.</summary>
</bill>
