<bill session="117" type="h" number="8175" updated="2023-10-10T15:15:17Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Pills That Kill Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Pills That Kill Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit certain acts related to fentanyl, analogues of fentanyl, and counterfeit substances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001297"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2022-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2022-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2022-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2022-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000589" joined="2022-09-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000397" joined="2022-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2022-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000821" joined="2022-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4151" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-07T19:07:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Pills That Kill Act

This bill increases criminal penalties for offenses relating to the manufacture of fentanyl or counterfeit substances. It also establishes requirements for federal agencies to address the use of counterfeit substances.

Specifically, the bill applies an increased criminal penalty for possessing, manufacturing, or distributing certain equipment or materials that are used to illegally manufacture fentanyl, an analogue of fentanyl, or a counterfeit substance (the increased penalty is currently limited to offenses involving methamphetamine). The bill also requires the United States Sentencing Commission to review sentencing guidelines and amend them, if appropriate, to include an enhanced penalty for those who knowingly misrepresent counterfeit pills that have fentanyl, a fentanyl analogue, or methamphetamine as legitimate pills.

The Drug Enforcement Administration must establish and implement a plan to address counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances through law enforcement action and education and prevention efforts. In addition, the Department of Justice must annually report on the collection of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances by law enforcement and on related prosecutions.</summary>
</bill>
