<bill session="117" type="s" number="3971" updated="2023-11-25T22:42:56Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the America's Water Infrastructure Act of 2018 to modify a provision relating to cost-sharing requirements applicable to certain Bureau of Reclamation dams and dikes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the America's Water Infrastructure Act of 2018 to modify a provision relating to cost-sharing requirements applicable to certain Bureau of Reclamation dams and dikes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000024"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-07T18:59:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the federal government to fully fund the costs of dam safety modifications of certain dikes owned by the Bureau of Reclamation. The bill also requires the federal government to fully fund gate replacements or repairs for certain dams for the next 10 years. The bill applies to certain Reclamation-owned dams or dikes completed not later than December 31, 1948 (e.g., the Altus Dam and dikes in the W.C. Austin Project in Oklahoma).

Under current law, the federal government is required to fully fund the operation and maintenance costs of certain Reclamation-owned dikes that were completed not later than December 31, 1945. However, current law requires the federal government to fund only 85% of certain dam safety modifications.</summary>
</bill>
