<bill session="108" type="s" number="1523" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:47Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pathways to Independence Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to allow a State to treat an individual with a disability, including a substance abuse problem, who is participating in rehabilitation services and who is increasing participation in core work activities as being engaged in work for purposes of the temporary assistance for needy families program, and to allow a State to count as a work activity under that program care provided to a child with a physical or mental impairment or an adult dependent for care with a physical or mental impairment.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pathways to Independence Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001142"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001040" joined="2004-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2004-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000705" joined="2003-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10645-10647"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 8/1/2003 S10646" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adult day care"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Cash welfare block grants"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Employment of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of the disabled"/>
    <term name="Welfare work participation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-09-09T20:46:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pathways to Independence Act of 2003 - Amends part A (Temporary Assistance for Needy Families) of title IV of the Social Security Act to give States the option to: (1) treat an individual with a disability, including a substance abuse problem, who is participating in rehabilitation services as being engaged in work; and (2) count as a work activity certain care provided to a child with a physical or mental impairment or to an adult dependent with a physical or mental impairment. Limits to three months in any 24-month period the length of time an individual may be deemed as being engaged in work under this Act. Permits an additional three-month extension only if the individual engages in specified work activity for a State-determined appropriate number of hours per month.</summary>
</bill>
