<bill session="118" type="s" number="5000" updated="2025-09-17T11:10:02Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-18">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide for a memorandum of understanding to address the impacts of a certain record of decision on the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the use of amounts from the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund to implement a certain record of decision, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to provide for a memorandum of understanding to address the impacts of a certain record of decision on the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000577"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-11">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="639">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 639.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7166" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7167" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T17:27:24-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-19T18:06:21-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-17T11:09:13Z" status="Passed Senate">This bill directs the Bureau of Reclamation and the Western Area Power Administration, in consultation with the Glen Canyon Dam Adaptive Management Work Group, to enter into a memorandum of understanding to explore and address the potential impact that the final Supplemental Environmental Impact Statement (SEIS) for the Glen Canyon Dam Long-Term Experimental and Management Plan (LTEMP) has on the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund. The memorandum of understanding must include a plan to (1) explore and address the effects that the decision may have on the contents of the fund, (2) analyze and address the long-term impact that the decision may have on hydropower production at Glen Canyon Dam, and (3) protect the Colorado River Basin and any threatened or endangered species in the basin from the effects of invasive species and sustained drought.

By way of background, Reclamation published the SEIS under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 for the LTEMP in 2024.&#160;The&#160;SEIS revises the 2016 LTEMP Record of Decision to address two issues: (1) responding to the threat of the invasive smallmouth bass&#160;below Glen Canyon Dam, and (2) incorporating the latest sediment science to assess when high-flow experiments should be conducted in order to protect the endangered humpback&#160;chub.</summary>
</bill>
