<bill session="118" type="h" number="5069" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require Federal political appointees to sign a binding ethics pledge, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 5, United States Code, to require Federal political appointees to sign a binding ethics pledge, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000579"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-19T17:59:38Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill provides statutory authority for provisions of the executive order titled Ethics Commitments by Executive Branch Appointees, which was issued on January 28, 2017, and was revoked on January 20, 2021, by President Donald J. Trump. The order required political appointees in the executive branch to sign an ethics pledge that restricted lobbying and related activities during and after government employment, including a prohibition on appointees lobbying their former agencies for five years post-employment.

On January 20, 2021, President Joseph R. Biden, Jr. issued a new executive order titled Ethics Commitments by Executive Branch Personnel, which requires appointees to sign an ethics pledge with both similar and different provisions. Among other differences, the order's pledge restricts appointees from accepting cash payments or non-cash benefits from former employers that are contingent on government employment (also known as golden parachutes).</summary>
</bill>
