<bill session="109" type="h" number="5589" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:49Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-10T14:57:36-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-10T14:57:36-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to transfer to United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement all functions of the Customs Patrol Officers unit operating on the Tohono O'odham Indian reservation.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to transfer to United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement all functions of the Customs Patrol Officers unit operating on the Tohono O'odham Indian reservation.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001143"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000362" joined="2006-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2006-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Security, Infrastructure Protection, and Cybersecurity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:45:45-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Souder moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:45:55-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4928-4930" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:45:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 5589.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-10T14:57:36-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4928" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-10T14:57:47-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Border patrols"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug traffic"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and International Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-07-12T15:22:48Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security, within 90 days of enactment of this Act, to transfer to United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement all functions (including personnel, assets, and liabilities attributable to such functions) of the Customs Patrol Officers unit operating on the Tohono O'odham Indian reservation ("Shadow Wolves" unit).

Authorizes the Secretary to establish within United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement additional Customs Patrol Officer units.

States that the transferred Customs Patrol Officer unit, and any additional units established under this Act, shall operate on Indian lands to prevent the entry into the United States of terrorists, unlawful aliens, instruments of terrorism, narcotics, and other contraband.

Provides that: (1) a Customs Patrol Officer under this Act shall receive equivalent pay as a special agent with similar competencies within United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement pursuant to the Department of Homeland Security's Human Resources Management System; and (2) each unit under this Act shall be supervised by a Chief Customs Patrol Officer who shall have the same rank as a resident agent-in-charge of the Office of Investigations within United States Immigration and Customs Enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
