<bill session="116" type="h" number="9045" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Citizen Justice Restoration Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Citizen Justice Restoration Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit searches based on race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, or sex, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000379"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2020-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-23T18:51:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Citizen Justice Restoration Act of 2020

This bill prohibits decisions to search, seize, or scrutinize an individual that discriminate on the basis of race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, or sex.

Specifically, the bill

 prohibits a person acting under color of law from basing a decision to search, seize, or scrutinize an individual on actual or perceived race, ethnicity, national origin, religion, or sex, including sexual orientation, and makes evidence obtained as a result of such a search or seizure inadmissible, with exceptions; requires an application for a writ of habeas corpus on behalf of a person in custody pursuant to the judgment of a state court to be granted with respect to any federal claim that was adjudicated on the merits in state court proceedings, which adjudication was in error; makes a new rule of constitutional law announced by the U.S. Supreme Court, a U.S. Court of Appeals, or a U.S. District Court retroactive to cases on collateral review; and requires an ambiguity in a statute that provides protection against discrimination on the basis of race, color, ethnicity, national origin, religion, disability, or sex to be construed in the manner that will provide the greatest protection against such discrimination. The bill further creates a private right of action and provides for the award of a bounty for citizen lawsuits under specified circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
