<bill session="117" type="h" number="9339" updated="2022-12-29T13:48:54Z">
  <state datetime="2022-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Interactive Federal Review Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Interactive Federal Review Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve the environmental review process for Federal-aid highway projects through the use of interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000301"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-12-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000604" joined="2022-12-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001211" joined="2022-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-12T13:41:08Z" status="Introduced in House">Interactive Federal Review Act

This bill revises the environmental review process for federal-aid highway projects.

Specifically, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must

 encourage recipients of federal highway funding to utilize interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms when carrying out environmental reviews under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (NEPA); select at least 10 federal-aid highway projects to demonstrate the use of interactive, digital, cloud-based platforms in carrying out the environmental impact analysis and community engagement processes under NEPA; and publish technology-neutral best practice guidance to encourage sponsors of projects that receive federal funds from DOT to use an interactive, digital, cloud-based platform in carrying out the environmental impact analysis and community engagement processes required under NEPA.</summary>
</bill>
