<bill session="116" type="s" number="1468" updated="2022-02-09T00:28:58Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cambodia Accountability and Return on Investment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cambodia Accountability and Return on Investment Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to support the successful implementation of the 1991 Paris Peace Agreement in Cambodia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2019-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2019-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2019-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Cambodia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans and debt"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development programs"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Political parties and affiliation"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Rule of law and government transparency"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-02T15:54:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cambodia Accountability and Return on Investment Act of 2019

This bill imposes conditions for assistance to Cambodia and contains other provisions related to democracy in Cambodia.

No funds authorized for assistance to Cambodia may be made available unless the Department of State certifies to Congress that Cambodia has taken certain actions, including (1) strengthening regional security and stability, in particular in relation to the South China Sea and by enforcing sanctions against North Korea; (2) protecting its sovereignty from interference from China; and (3) respecting constitutionally protected rights and releasing political prisoners.

Various other benefits, such as Cambodia's designation as a beneficiary developing country for trade treatment purposes, shall also be suspended until such a certification is made.

The State Department shall report to Congress on the implementation of existing visa-blocking restrictions against individuals involved in undermining democracy in Cambodia.

The President shall take all actions necessary to direct U.S. financial institutions to promptly report to the Office of Foreign Assets Control as to holdings, transfers, or interests in property belonging to individuals involved in undermining democracy in Cambodia. The President may impose property-blocking sanctions on such individuals.

The bill authorizes the broadcast of Khmer-language internet content to inform the Cambodian people of various topics, such as China's undermining of Cambodia's sovereignty.</summary>
</bill>
