<bill session="112" type="hj" number="72" updated="2023-01-11T13:22:49Z">
  <state datetime="2011-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States giving Congress power to regulate campaign contributions for Federal elections.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Proposing an amendment to the Constitution of the United States giving Congress power to regulate campaign contributions for Federal elections.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001180"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2011-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2011-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2011-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2012-01-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2012-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000510" joined="2012-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on the Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU10" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Constitution and Limited Government" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="First Amendment rights"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-07-19T19:37:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Constitutional Amendment - Gives Congress the power to prohibit, limit, and otherwise regulate the contribution of funds or donation of in-kind equivalents: (1) to candidates standing for election to a federal office in the United States, and (2) used to support or purchase media advertisements intended to influence the outcome of any such election.

Gives each of the several states the power to prohibit, limit, and otherwise regulate the contribution of funds or donation of in-kind equivalents: (1) to candidates standing for election to public office in the state, and (2) used to support or purchase media advertisements intended to influence the outcome of any such election or plebiscite in the state.

Prohibits any person who is not a U.S. citizen or is a foreign government, or acts as an agent of one, from: (1) contributing funds or donating in-kind equivalents to candidates standing for election to public office in the United States, or (2) otherwise expending funds or donating in-kind equivalents in a manner intended to influence the outcome of an election for public office or plebiscite in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
