<bill session="117" type="h" number="6229" updated="2022-12-30T03:04:03Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Land and Water Conservation Fund Water Amendments Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land and Water Conservation Fund Water Amendments Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 54, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to make financial assistance to States under the Land and Water Conservation Fund available for water quality projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001199"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001257" joined="2022-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2021-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000472" joined="2022-01-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000593" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2021-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-12-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests, and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water, Oceans, and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3371" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-02T22:38:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Land and Water Conservation Fund Water Amendments Act of 2021

This bill authorizes the Department of the Interior to provide financial assistance for water quality improvement projects from amounts made available under the Land and Water Conservation Fund.

Interior shall only provide such financial assistance to projects that seek to improve water quality by improving, restoring, remediating, or developing natural hydrological systems, such as wetlands and living shorelines.

To be eligible for assistance, a state's comprehensive statewide outdoor recreation plan shall identify

 any body of water within the state for which a water quality control plan has been developed pursuant to the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and any proposed water quality project to be conducted with respect to such body of water.</summary>
</bill>
