<bill session="117" type="s" number="1140" updated="2023-01-11T13:49:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Seasonal Business PPP Parity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act to alter the maximum amount of a second draw loan under the Paycheck Protection Program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Seasonal Business PPP Parity Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000383"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2021-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1249" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business expenses"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Food industry and services"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Travel and tourism"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-20T15:41:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Seasonal Business PPP Parity Act

This bill increases the maximum loan amount for second draw loans under the Paycheck Protection Program, which was established to support small businesses in response to the COVID-19 pandemic.

Currently, program participants may receive second draw loans of up to $2 million. Under the program, certain small businesses (e.g., seasonal businesses) were eligible to receive increased amounts for first draw loans based on a revised calculation applicable to those businesses. However, a number of such businesses applied for and received loan forgiveness prior to the application of this revised calculation, which resulted in their receiving a lower amount than that to which they were entitled.

The bill allows businesses that received forgiveness for their first draw loan prior to the implementation of the revised calculation to take advantage of the new calculation in order to receive a larger amount for their second draw loan in addition to the standard loan amount of up to $2 million.</summary>
</bill>
