<bill session="116" type="h" number="9041" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:56Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Emergencies Reform Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Emergencies Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Emergencies Act to provide for a sunset of a national emergency declared by the President 2 days after the declaration unless Congress enacts a joint resolution affirming such declaration and the emergency powers approved for use by the President, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000367"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committees on Foreign Affairs, and Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="1720" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-09T19:54:33Z" status="Introduced in House">National Emergencies Reform Act

This bill revises provisions of the National Emergencies Act relating to the termination of presidentially-declared national emergencies. Specifically, the bill provides that any national emergency declared by the President shall terminate if (1) no joint resolution has been enacted affirming the declaration of such emergency before the expiration of the 48-hour period beginning on the first day after such emergency is declared and on which both houses of Congress are in session, (2) a joint resolution is enacted terminating the emergency, or (3) the President issues a proclamation terminating the emergency.

The date on which a presidentially-declared emergency terminates is 60 days after the President transmits to Congress the proclamation declaring the emergency or Congress affirms a previous renewal unless the President publishes in the Federal Register and transmits to Congress an executive order renewing the emergency, and a joint resolution is enacted affirming the renewal of the declaration.

A national emergency declared before the enactment of this bill shall be unaffected by the amendments made by this bill except that such emergencies shall terminate 60 days after enactment unless renewed.</summary>
</bill>
