<bill session="119" type="s" number="789" updated="2025-08-12T17:26:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Critical Minerals Security Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Critical Minerals Security Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require reports on critical mineral and rare earth element resources around the world and a strategy for the development of advanced mining, refining, separation, and processing technologies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2025-02-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-17T13:52:43Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Critical Minerals Security Act of 2025

This bill establishes requirements for the Department of the Interior related to securing U.S. access to critical minerals and rare earth element (REE) resources.&#160;Critical minerals mean any mineral, element, substance, or material designated as critical by the U.S. Geological Survey.&#160;REEs mean cerium, dysprosium, erbium, europium, gadolinium, holmium, lanthanum, lutetium, neodymium, praseodymium, promethium, samarium, scandium, terbium, thulium, ytterbium, and yttrium.&#160;

First, Interior must report on the critical mineral and&#160;REE resources, including recyclable or recycled materials containing those resources, around the world. Among other information, the&#160;report must include an assessment of the&#160;global ownership and supply of critical mineral and&#160;REE resources. Interior must submit the report within a year and every two years thereafter.

Next, Interior must establish a process to assist a U.S. person&#226;&#8364;&#8221;a U.S. citizen, a non-U.S. National (alien under federal law) lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or an entity organized under U.S. laws&#226;&#8364;&#8221;seeking to divest stock in mining, processing, or recycling operations for critical minerals and&#160;REEs in a foreign country with finding a purchaser that is not under the control of North Korea, China, Russia, or Iran.

Finally, Interior must develop (1) a strategy to collaborate with U.S. allies and partners to develop advanced mining, refining, separation, processing, and recycling technologies; and (2) a method for sharing related&#160;intellectual property with U.S. allies and partners to enable those countries to license those technologies and develop their resources.</summary>
</bill>
