<amendment session="111" chamber="h" number="186" updated="2022-02-03T06:07:50Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2410" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2009-06-10T17:54:47-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001157"/>
  <offered datetime="2009-06-10"/>
  <description>Amendment directs the President to develop and transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive interagency strategy and implementation plan to address the ongoing crisis in Sudan. This includes a description of how the United States assistance will be used to achieve a U.S. policy towards Sudan, financial plan, management of U.S. foreign assistance, and criteria used to determine their prioritization.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 6 printed in part C of House Report 111-143 to direct the President to develop and transmit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive interagency strategy and implementation plan to address the ongoing crisis in Sudan. This includes a description of how the United States assistance will be used to achieve a U.S. policy towards Sudan, financial plan, management of U.S. foreign assistance, and criteria used to determine their prioritization.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2009-06-10T17:54:47-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="322">
      <text>On agreeing to the McCaul amendment (A006) Agreed to by recorded vote: 429 - 0 (Roll no. 322).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T14:27:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. McCaul.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6487-6489, H6511" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6487" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T14:27:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. McCaul.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6487-6489, H6511" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H6487" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:54:47-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:54:47-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the McCaul amendment (A006) Agreed to by recorded vote: 429 - 0 (Roll no. 322).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10T17:54:47-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-10">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
