<bill session="111" type="h" number="4444" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:46Z">
  <state datetime="2010-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Defund the Crooks Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Federal Government from awarding contracts or grants to, entering into other agreements with, providing any other Federal funds to, or engaging in activities that promote, certain organizations.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defund the Crooks Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000556"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-12">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Government Management, Organization, and Procurement.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO24" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Government Operations and the Federal Workforce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3571" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1687" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="1751" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Business ethics"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-05T16:24:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Defund the Crooks Act - Prohibits any federal contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or other form of agreement from being awarded to or entered into with any organization that: (1) has been convicted of a violation of any federal or state law; (2) had its corporate charter revoked due to its failure to comply with federal or state laws; (3) has submitted a fraudulent claim to a federal or state agency; (4) knowingly employs an individual who has been convicted of a violation of federal or state law, hires any such individual as a contractor, or extends authority to such an individual to act on its behalf; or (5) is the parent company of, subsidiary of, or subsidiary of the parent company of, or owns 50% or more of, such an organization.

Prohibits: (1) any federal funds from being provided to such an organization, except for goods or services provided before this Act's enactment; and (2) any federal employee, in the course and scope of employment, or any federal contractor, during the performance of the contract, from promoting such an organization. Provides for the termination of contracts awarded before, or awarded to an entity that becomes such an organization after, enactment of this Act.

Requires the Federal Acquisition Regulation to be revised to carry out provisions of this Act relating to contracts.</summary>
</bill>
