<bill session="116" type="s" number="3742" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RELIEF for Main Street Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recharge and Empower Local Innovation and Entrepreneurs Fund for Main Street Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RELIEF for Main Street Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program in the Department of the Treasury to allocate funds to States, units of general local government, and Indian Tribes to provide assistance to certain small businesses, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2020-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2020-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000064" joined="2020-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6907" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="4818" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-16T16:59:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Recharge and Empower Local Innovation and Entrepreneurs Fund for Main Street Act or the RELIEF for Main Street Act

This bill establishes for one year the Small Business Local Relief Program, which shall allocate resources to states, local governments, and Native American tribes for providing assistance to certain small businesses and nonprofits that have lost revenue due to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill provides $50.5 billion for such assistance, of which (1) $35 billion shall be distributed based on the Community Development Block Grant formula (70% allocated to larger cities and counties and 30% to rural communities), (2) $15 billion shall be allocated to provide financing exclusively to businesses in rural areas, and (3) $500 million shall be for Native American Tribes.

These amounts shall be used to start or scale a local small business emergency fund or to support organizations that provide technical assistance to small businesses or nonprofits. Such local funds or organizations may then use the amounts to assist small businesses (including sole proprietorships, independent contractors, and self-employed individuals) and nonprofits that (1) employ no more than 20 full-time employees (50 if the recipient is located in a low-income community), (2) has experienced a loss of revenue because of COVID-19, and (3) satisfies any additional requirements imposed by the administrator of the fund.

A state, local government, or Native American tribe that receives funds under the bill must report specified demographic and disbursement information.</summary>
</bill>
