<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1848</number>
    <updateDate>2019-11-15T21:56:16Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2019-11-15T21:56:16Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2011-11-10</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
        <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2011-11-10T21:09:33Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>United Nations Transparency, Accountability, and Reform Act of 2011</title>
        <congress>112</congress>
        <number>2829</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2011-12-08</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 221.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfr00</systemCode>
            <name>Foreign Relations Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7373)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000595</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Rubio, Marco [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Marco</firstName>
        <lastName>Rubio</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>I000024</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Inhofe, James M. [R-OK]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jim</firstName>
        <lastName>Inhofe</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>OK</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-11-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000880</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Crapo, Mike [R-ID]</fullName>
        <firstName>Mike</firstName>
        <lastName>Crapo</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ID</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-11-10</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>R000584</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Risch, James E. [R-ID]</fullName>
        <firstName>James</firstName>
        <lastName>Risch</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>ID</state>
        <middleName>E.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2011-11-14</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>International Affairs</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Accounting and auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Appropriations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arab-Israeli relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arms control and nonproliferation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Asia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Australia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Canada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Conflicts and wars</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional oversight</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional tributes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime victims</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crimes against women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Czech Republic</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Europe</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Foreign aid and international relief</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Germany</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government ethics and transparency, public corruption</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government studies and investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Human rights</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Human trafficking</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International law and treaties</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International organizations and cooperation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Iran</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Israel</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Italy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Middle East</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military command and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military personnel and dependents</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Netherlands</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Zealand</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>North Korea</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear power</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear weapons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Oceania</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Palestinians</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Poland</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Racial and ethnic relations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Refugees, asylum, displaced persons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Religion</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sanctions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Sex offenses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Terrorism</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>United Nations</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>International Affairs</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2011-12-19T16:28:52Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United Nations Transparency, Accountability, and Reform Act of 2011 - Directs the President to use U.S. influence at the United Nations (U.N.) on a variety of issues, including to shift the funding mechanism for the regular budget of the U.N. from an assessed to a voluntary basis.</p> <p>Withholds up to 50% of nonvoluntary U.S. contributions to the regular budget of the U.N. unless the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that 80% of the total regular budget of the U.N. is apportioned on a voluntary basis.</p> <p>Requires the annual congressional budget justification to include a detailed itemized request in support of the U.S. contribution of the regular budget of the U.N. </p> <p>Sets forth requirements for the Comptroller General (GAO) with respect to audits and investigations of U.S. contributions to the U.N. and such contributions' use by U.N. entities.</p> <p>Prohibits the obligation or expenditure of a U.S. contribution to any U.N. entity unless the entity has provided the Comptroller General with a transparency certification and is in compliance with such certification.</p> <p>Prohibits making funds available: (1) to international organizations for any purpose other than an assessed U.S. contribution to a U.N. entity or other international organization; (2) to international organizations and programs for any purpose other than a voluntary U.S. contribution to a U.N. entity or other international organization; and (3) for international peacekeeping activities for any purpose other than a U.S. contribution to U.N. peacekeeping activities, to the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia (ICTY), or to the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda (ICTR).</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to withhold from the regular budget of the U.N. an amount equal to the amount of U.S. overpayments to the U.N.</p> <p>States that is U.S. policy to oppose any proposals on expansion of the Security Council that would: (1) diminish U.S. influence on the Security Council, or (2) include veto rights for new Security Council members.</p> <p>Withholds from U.S. contributions to the regular budget of the United Nations amounts that are proportional to the percentage of such budget that are expended for a U.N. human rights treaty monitoring body or committee that was established by a convention or an international covenant to which the United States is not party.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to withhold U.S. contributions from any U.N. entity that recognizes a Palestinian state or upgrades the status of the Palestinian observer mission at the U.N., the Palestine Liberation Organization (PLO), the Palestinian Authority (PA), or any other Palestinian administrative organization or governing entity prior to the achievement of a final peace agreement with Israel.</p> <p>Provides that until the Secretary makes a specified certification to Congress: (1) the Secretary shall withhold from a U.S. contribution to a regular budget of the U.N. an amount equal to the amount that would be allocated for the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC), (2) the Secretary shall not make a voluntary contribution to UNHRC, and (3) the United States shall not run for a UNHRC seat.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary to withhold from a U.S. contribution to a regular budget of the U.N. an amount equal to the amount that would be allocated for: (1) the U.N. Special Rapporteur on the situation of human rights in Palestinian territories occupied since 1967; and (2) any other U.N. Special Procedures used to display bias against the United States or Israel or to provide support for any member state which is subject to Security Council sanctions, under a Security Council-mandated human rights investigation, has repeatedly supported acts of international terrorism, or is a country of particular concern for religious freedom.</p> <p>States that it is U.S. policy to oppose any legitimization of the Goldstone Report and to lead a diplomatic campaign supporting its revocation.</p> <p>Prohibits funds from being used for U.S. participation in the Durban III meeting or any part of the Durban process.</p> <p> Withholds U.S. contributions to the United Nations Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East (UNRWA) or to any successor or related entity unless the Secretary makes specified certifications to Congress. <p>Prohibits any U.S. contribution to the International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) from being used to support Technical Cooperation program assistance to any country, including North Korea, that: (1) has repeatedly supported acts of international terrorism; or (2) is in breach of, or under investigation for breach of, obligations regarding its safeguards agreement with the IAEA, the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty, or any relevant Security Council resolution. <p>Directs the Secretary to withhold from the U.S. voluntary contribution to the IAEA an amount proportional to that spent by the IAEA in 2007-2008 on Technical Cooperation program assistance to such countries.<p>Sets forth U.S. policy regarding reform of U.N. peacekeeping operations. <p>Directs the President to use U.S. influence at the U.N. to oppose the creation of new, or expansion of existing, U.N. peacekeeping operations until the Secretary certifies to Congress that specified peacekeeping reforms have been adopted by the U.N. Department of Peacekeeping Operations or the General Assembly.]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>United Nations Transparency, Accountability, and Reform Act of 2011</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United Nations Transparency, Accountability, and Reform Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>United Nations Transparency, Accountability, and Reform Act of 2011</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to promote transparency, accountability, and reform within the United Nations system, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2011-11-10T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s1848is/xml/BILLS-112s1848is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2011-11-10</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
