<bill session="110" type="h" number="2154" updated="2023-01-11T15:47:59Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Energy for America Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance and improve the energy security of the United States, expand economic development, increase agricultural income, and improve environmental quality by reauthorizing and improving the renewable energy systems and energy efficiency improvements program of the Department of Agriculture through fiscal year 2012, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Energy for America Act of 2007</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001037"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2008-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2007-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2007-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000364" joined="2007-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001146" joined="2007-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2007-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-31">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Credit, Energy, and Research.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Agricultural subsidies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="Rebates"/>
    <term name="Rural education"/>
    <term name="School districts"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-05-09T20:32:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Rural Energy for America Act of 2007 - Amends the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 to rename the renewable energy systems and energy efficiency improvements program as the rural energy for America program (REAP).

Makes rural school districts eligible for REAP.

Authorizes REAP assistance to produce and sell electricity generated by new renewable energy systems.

Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to eligible entities to provide rebates for farmers, ranchers, rural school districts, and rural small businesses to purchase renewable energy systems and make energy efficiency improvements. Defines eligible entities as: (1) a state energy or agriculture office; (2) a nonprofit state-based energy efficiency or renewable energy organization that uses public funds provided directly or under contract with a state agency; (3) any other nonprofit organization with a demonstrated ability to administer a statewide energy efficiency or renewable energy rebate program; or (4) a consortium of such entities. Limits rebates to the lower of $10,000 or 50% of the cost to purchase a renewable energy system or an energy efficiency improvement. Extends REAP funding through FY 2012 with set-asides for the rebate program.

Expresses the sense of the Senate that the Secretary should implement a direct loan program to complement REAP grants.</summary>
</bill>
