<bill session="117" type="h" number="1102" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Easy Access to Mail Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 39, United States Code, to establish rules and procedures for the United States Postal Service regarding the use of centralized delivery of the mail with respect to residential housing units, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Easy Access to Mail Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001309"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001282" joined="2021-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001274" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000619" joined="2021-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001038" joined="2021-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000392" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000612" joined="2021-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001195" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Y000033" joined="2021-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Reform.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-20T17:53:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Easy Access to Mail Act

This bill establishes procedures for the U.S. Postal Service (USPS) regarding the use of centralized delivery of the mail with respect to residential housing units.

Specifically, the bill

 provides that, for any housing development with respect to which the primary mode of mail delivery is any such mode except for centralized delivery on the date of this bill's enactment, the USPS may not change such mode of delivery to centralized delivery; and prohibits the USPS from requiring centralized delivery with respect to any housing development constructed after this bill's enactment without prior approval from the local legislative body, or, in the absence of a local legislative body, the legislature of the state with jurisdiction over the affected property. If approval for centralized delivery is granted, at least 60 days before commencing such delivery the local postmaster shall provide (1) written notice to any other units of local government and any planning commissions located within the applicable county; and (2) a period of 60 days for public comment from residents, property owners, and home builders within such county regarding the use of centralized delivery at the applicable housing development.

The Postal Regulatory Commission shall ensure that the USPS does not change any USPS policy in effect on the date of enactment that would result in a disproportionate negative affect on rural, lower income, elderly, disabled, or predominately minority communities.</summary>
</bill>
