<bill session="109" type="s" number="1352" updated="2020-02-10T17:00:25Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improved Workplace and Community Transition Training for Incarcerated Youth Offenders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Improved Workplace and Community Transition Training for Incarcerated Youth Offenders Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants to States for improved workplace and community transition training for incarcerated youth offenders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2005-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2005-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7835"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-29T15:03:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improved Workplace and Community Transition Training for Incarcerated Youth Offenders Act of 2005 - Amends the Higher Education Amendments of 1998 to authorize the Secretary of Education to establish performance objectives and reporting requirements necessary to assess program effectiveness for state correctional education agencies receiving grants for transition training for incarcerated youth offenders.

Requires grant applications to describe specific performance objectives and evaluation methods that the state agency will use, including: (1) specific and quantified student outcome measures that are referenced to outcomes for non-program participants with similar demographic characteristics; and (2) measures of program completion, knowledge and skill attainment, attainment of and success in employment, and recidivism. Requires descriptions of how the proposed programs will consider or utilize technology.

Directs each state agency receiving a grant to: (1) report annually to the Secretary on the results of the evaluations and additional performance objectives and on evaluation methods as necessary to document the attainment of performance objectives; and (2) expend on each participating eligible student for an academic year not more than the maximum federal Pell grant for such year, which shall be used for tuition, books, essential materials, and related services such as career development, substance abuse counseling, parenting skills training, and health education.

Makes youth offenders age 35 (currently, 25) or younger eligible for participation. Allows related services to continue for up to one year after release from confinement.</summary>
</bill>
