<bill session="111" type="s" number="19" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:25Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oil Sands Energy Security Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to promote energy security through the production of petroleum from oil sands, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oil Sands Energy Security Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000359"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000286" joined="2010-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-06T21:52:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Oil Sands Energy Security Act of 2010 - Amends the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 to repeal the prohibition against any federal agency contract for procurement of an alternative or synthetic fuel, including a fuel produced from nonconventional petroleum sources (such as oil sands), for any mobility-related use (other than for research or testing) unless the contract specifies that the lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions associated with the production and combustion of the fuel supplied under the contract must, on an ongoing basis, be less than or equal to greenhouse gas emissions from the equivalent conventional fuel produced from conventional petroleum sources.

Makers a conforming amendment to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act of 2008 to repeal the exception to such prohibition National Air and Space Administration (NASA) contracts to purchase a generally available fuel that is not an alternative or synthetic fuel or predominantly produced from a nonconventional petroleum source, if certain conditions are met.</summary>
</bill>
