<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>921</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:19:21Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:19:21Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2009-04-28</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>hshm00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security Committee</name>
        <chamber>House</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Legislative interest</name>
            <date>2010-09-22T16:38:00Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
        <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2009-04-28T22:32:40Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Federal Information Security Amendments Act of 2010</title>
        <congress>111</congress>
        <number>4900</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2010-05-20</actionDate>
          <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-04-28</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssga00</systemCode>
            <name>Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S4824-4828)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-04-28</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S4818)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2009-04-28</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C000174</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Carper, Thomas R. [D-DE]</fullName>
        <firstName>Thomas</firstName>
        <lastName>Carper</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>DE</state>
        <middleName>R.</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>B001266</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Burris, Roland [D-IL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Roland</firstName>
        <lastName>Burris</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>IL</state>
        <sponsorshipDate>2009-07-06</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Administrative law and regulatory procedures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Computer security and identity theft</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive Office of the President</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Executive agency funding and structure</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government information and archives</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2009-04-28</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2009-05-29T18:47:49Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>United States Information and Communications Enhancement Act of 2009 or the U.S. ICE Act of 2009 - Replaces two subchapters of federal law on information security with provisions to establish in the Executive Office of the President the National Office for Cyberspace (Office) to serve as the principal office for coordinating an assured, reliable, secure, and survivable global information and communications infrastructure and related capabilities. </p> <p>Requires the Office's director to develop and implement a comprehensive national cyberspace strategy. </p> <p>Authorizes the Office, not withstanding any provision of law or policy, to direct the sponsorship of security clearances for federal officers and employees whose responsibilities involve critical national security infrastructure.</p> <p>Requires the Office to: (1) oversee the implementation of policies, standards, and guidelines on information security; and (2) require agencies to identify and provide appropriate information security protections.</p> <p>Makes the head of each agency responsible for providing appropriate information security protections.</p> <p>Requires each agency to have an annual independent information security effectiveness evaluation.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Commerce to prescribe guidelines and compulsory standards for information systems, including national security systems. Allows the President to disapprove or change the guidelines and standards. Allows the Office and the head of an agency to use more stringent standards.</p> <p>Requires each agency to coordinate with the United States Computer Emergency Readiness Team (US-CERT). Allows US-CERT's director, notwithstanding any law or policy, to direct the sponsorship of the security clearances for federal officers and employees whose responsibilities involve critical national security infrastructure.</p> <p>Requires the components of each executive branch department or agency (except the Department of Defense or any such component performing any national security function) to establish an automated reporting mechanism allowing its chief information security officer and security operations center at the agency level to implement and monitor the component's security policies, procedures, and controls.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>U.S. ICE Act of 2009</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>U.S. ICE Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend chapter 35 of title 44, United States Code, to recognize the interconnected nature of the Internet and agency networks, improve situational awareness of Government cyberspace, enhance information security of the Federal Government, unify policies, procedures, and guidelines for securing information systems and national security systems, establish security standards for Government purchased products and services, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>U.S. ICE Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>United States Information and Communications Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2009-04-28T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s921is/xml/BILLS-111s921is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2009-04-28</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S4824-4828)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
