<bill session="117" type="s" number="4435" updated="2023-11-25T14:15:09Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">FIND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">FIND Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firearm Industry Non-Discrimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 41, United States Code, to prohibit the Federal Government from entering into contracts with an entity that discriminates against firearm or ammunition industries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001079" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000024" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2022-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001217" joined="2022-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-28T15:55:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Firearm Industry Non-Discrimination Act or the FIND Act

This bill prohibits the federal government from entering into contracts with an entity that discriminates against firearm trade associations or businesses that deal in firearms, ammunition, or related products.

 Specifically, the bill requires a federal agency to include in each contract for the procurement of goods or services awarded by the agency a clause requiring the prime contractor to certify that it (1) has no policy, practice, guidance, or directive that discriminates against a firearm entity or firearm trade association; and (2) will not adopt a policy, practice, guidance, or directive that discriminates against a firearm entity or firearm trade association during the term of the contract.

The bill establishes (1) a similar requirement with respect to subcontracts, and (2) penalties for violations.

The bill makes such prohibition inapplicable to a contract for the procurement of goods or services that is a sole-source contract.</summary>
</bill>
