<bill session="118" type="h" number="9155" updated="2025-08-19T13:45:52Z">
  <state datetime="2024-07-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-07-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-07-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wildfire Victim Tax Relief and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wildfire Victim Tax Relief and Recovery Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To exclude certain amounts relating to compensating victims of the Texas Panhandle fires, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000304"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-07-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-07-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-19T13:44:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Wildfire Victim Tax Relief and Recovery Act&#160;

This bill allows farmers to defer taxes on gain from the sale or exchange of livestock because of a fire. (Conditions apply.) The bill also allows individuals to exclude from gross income (for tax purposes) certain disaster relief payments received in connection with specific Texas wildfires.

Currently, farmers may defer gain on the sale or exchange of livestock (other than poultry) held for draft, breeding, or dairy purposes due to drought, flood, or other weather-related conditions for two years (four years if attributable to a federally-declared disaster). Otherwise, under current law, gain on the sale of livestock (including poultry) due to such weather-related conditions attributable to a federally-declared disaster may be deferred for one year. (Conditions apply.)

The bill adds fire to the list of circumstances for which the gain on the sale or exchange of livestock may be deferred, thus allowing farmers to defer such gains for up to four years (depending on the type of livestock and whether the sale is attributable to a federally-declared disaster).

The bill also allows individuals to exclude from gross income payments received from federal, state, or local government agencies or Xcel Energy (or any subsidiary, insurer, or agent of Xcel Energy) as compensation for unreimbursed losses, damages, and certain expenses attributable to the

Smokehouse Creek, 687 Reamer, and Roughneck Fires (Hutchinson County, Texas, February and March 2024);Windy Deuce Fire (Moore County, Texas, February 2024); andGrape Vine Creek Fire (Gray County, Texas, February 2024).</summary>
</bill>
