<bill session="108" type="s" number="1552" updated="2023-01-15T06:17:46Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting the Rights of Individuals Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, and the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to strengthen protections of civil liberties in the exercise of the foreign intelligence surveillance authorities under Federal law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting the Rights of Individuals Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2003-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="3352" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Counterintelligence"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Discovery (Law)"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Student records"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Warrants (Law)"/>
    <term name="Wiretapping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-06T17:51:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting the Rights of Individuals Act - Amends the USA PATRIOT Act to revise the conditions under which delayed notice of the issuance of a warrant may be permitted by: (1) limiting applicable offenses to acts dangerous to human life and constituting a Federal crime of terrorism; (2) requiring a finding that providing immediate notice will endanger a person's life or safety or result in flight from prosecution or the destruction of evidence; and (3) requiring notice to be given within seven days of execution of the warrant, with extension authorized. Requires the Attorney General to make public a report concerning all requests for delays.

Requires each application for access to business records for foreign intelligence and international terrorism investigations: (1) to include a statement of the facts and circumstances relied upon to justify the belief that the person to whom the records pertain is a foreign power or an agent thereof; and (2) in the case of medical, library, or specified other records, to state that on the basis of the facts submitted there is probable cause to believe that the person is a foreign power or agent.

Prohibits a library from being treated as a wire or electronic communication service provider required to supply subscriber information and toll billing records or electronic communication transactional records at the request of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.

 Permits electronic surveillance to be conducted at a facility or place that is unknown at the time the order is issued only when the presence of the target at a particular location has been ascertained. Requires an application for a wiretap to include a statement of specific and articulable facts that indicate that a crime has been, is being, or will be committed.

Prohibits data-mining activity by a Government agency except pursuant to specific statutory authorization.

Amends the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 to prescribe a public reporting requirement with respect to orders granted, modified, or denied under such Act.

Amends the General Education Provisions Act and the National Education Statistics Act of 1994 to require that an applicant seeking disclosure of educational records set forth specific and articulable facts indicating that such records are likely to contain information relevant to an authorized terrorism investigation or prosecution.</summary>
</bill>
