<bill session="116" type="s" number="3038" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:52Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRICE Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">PRICE Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRICE Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote innovative acquisition techniques and procurement strategies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2020-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000285" joined="2020-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2019-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-14">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Johnson without amendment. With written report No. 116-315.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-12-14" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="618">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 618.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget (OMB)"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-16T14:31:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Rigorous and Innovative Cost Efficiencies for Federal Procurement and Acquisitions Act of 2019 or the PRICE Act of 2019

This bill directs the Management Directorate of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to publish an annual report on a DHS website on projects that have used innovative procurement techniques within DHS to accomplish specified goals.

Such goals are

 improving or encouraging better competition, reducing time to award, achieving cost savings, achieving better mission outcomes, or meeting the goals for contracts awarded to small business concerns. The Management Directorate shall (1) develop and disseminate guidance and offer training for specified personnel concerning when and how to use such techniques, and (2) share best practices across DHS and make available to other federal agencies information to improve procurement methods and training.

The Office of Federal Procurement Policy shall convene a Chief Acquisition Officers Council to examine best practices for acquisition innovation in contracting in the federal government.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-315</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
