<bill session="118" type="s" number="4451" updated="2025-11-18T12:03:14Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RESERVE Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RESERVE Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equal Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">RESERVE Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equitable Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">RESERVE Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equitable Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Interior to enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to carry out a study on reservation systems for Federal land.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-12">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Public Lands, Forests, and Mining. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 118-394.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Manchin with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="626">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 626.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2024-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7218" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7218-7219" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20T16:53:30-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-20T17:04:36-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSEG03" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Public Lands, Forests, and Mining" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="10162" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-27T14:15:06Z" status="Passed Senate">Review and Evaluation of Strategies for Equitable Reservations for Visitor Experiences Federal Land Act or the RESERVE Federal Land Act

This bill requires the Departments of Agriculture and the Interior and the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers to jointly enter into an agreement with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study&#160;of federal reservation systems used to book or permit recreational activities on federal land. &#160;

Under the bill, federal land generally includes National Forest System land, units of the National Park System or the National Wildlife Refuge System, sites administered by the Bureau of Reclamation or the U.S. Army Corps of Engineers, and other land owned by the United States and administered by the Bureau of Land Management. Federal reservation systems are platforms used by managers of federal land to manage the quantity, type, distribution, and timing of recreational activities, including permitting, pricing, and lottery systems.&#160;

The study must review the history of federal reservation systems, including a review of the considerations that led to the establishment of such systems, iterations of such systems over time, and visitor feedback. The study must also address

the benefits and challenges of implementing federal reservation systems to achieve management goals for federal land,the availability of data on the demand for recreation on federal land,how fees have been collected over time to meet agency needs, andhow federal reservation systems can be improved to reduce missed reservations and increase use in periods of high demand.</summary>
</bill>
