<bill session="118" type="s" number="576" updated="2025-11-19T03:31:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Railway Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Railway Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Safe Freight Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Railway Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Safe Freight Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance safety requirements for trains transporting hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-05-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001089" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000137" joined="2023-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-13">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-12-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="284">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 284.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="8996" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1674" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-14T22:28:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Railway Safety Act of 2023

This bill addresses safety requirements for rail carriers and trains transporting hazardous materials.

Specifically, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must issue safety regulations for trains carrying hazardous materials to require that rail carriers or shippers (1) provide state emergency response commissioners with advanced notice and information about the hazardous materials; (2) reduce blocked rail crossings; and (3) comply with certain requirements regarding train length and weight specifications, track standards, speed restrictions, and response plans.

DOT must also establish requirements for wayside defect detectors. These are used by railway systems alongside the tracks to detect defects and failures (e.g., wheel bearing failures). Current federal regulations do not require their use, but federal guidance does address their placement and use. Under the bill, DOT must issue regulations establishing requirements for the installation, repair, testing, maintenance, and operation of wayside defect detectors for each rail carrier operating a train carrying hazardous materials.

The bill also

 increases the maximum fines DOT may impose on rail carriers for violating safety regulations, requires DOT to update rail car inspection regulations and audit the federal inspection program, requires a minimum two-person crew for certain freight trains, phases out certain railroad tank cars by May 1, 2025 (four years sooner than required under current law), expands training for local first responders, imposes a new fee on certain rail carriers, and provides funding for research and development to improve railway safety.</summary>
</bill>
