<bill session="117" type="s" number="3539" updated="2023-08-17T13:45:23Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Watershed Results Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Watershed Results Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to carry out watershed pilots, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2807" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-08T20:14:52Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Watershed Results Act

This bill provides funding for the Department of the Interior, in coordination with the Department of Agriculture and the Environmental Protection Agency, to establish a total of not less than two and not more than five watershed pilot programs in certain western states that use pay-for-performance contracts.

Interior is required to designate a management team for each watershed pilot project. Each team must develop and implement a five-year plan for carrying out the applicable pilot.

Interior and the management team for each watershed pilot must use advance watershed analytics throughout the planning, implementation, measuring, and monitoring of projects within the pilot. This technical analysis must be conducted to identify quantifiable outcomes, costs, feasibility, and impacts of the projects before making funding available for a watershed pilot.

Further, Interior and the management team for a watershed pilot are required to set and publish minimum per-unit outcome prices. Interior must also enter into a pay-for-performance contract to achieve outcome-based goals described in the plan developed for the pilot.

Interior must also submit specified annual and five-year reports to Congress.</summary>
</bill>
