<bill session="117" type="s" number="2384" updated="2023-01-01T23:43:18Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint coins in commemoration of the semiquincentennial anniversary of the establishment of the United States.</title>
    <title type="display">Semiquincentennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Semiquincentennial Commemorative Coin Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001095" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2021-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000790" joined="2021-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4429" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-12T15:41:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Semiquincentennial Commemorative Coin Act

This bill directs the Department of the Treasury to mint and issue $25.00 gold coins, $2.50 silver coins, 25 cent clad coins, and proof silver $2.50 coins in commemoration of the 250th anniversary of the establishment of the United States.

The designs of the coins shall be emblematic of the semiquincentennial anniversary of the establishment of the United States of America and celebrate 250 years of our nation.

On each coin there shall be

 a designation of the value of the coin; an inscription of the years 1776-2026; and inscriptions of the words Liberty, In God We Trust, United States of America, and E Pluribus Unum. Treasury may issue coins under this bill only during the period beginning on January 1, 2026, and ending on December 31, 2026.

All sales of coins issued shall include a surcharge as prescribed by this bill.

All surcharges received by Treasury from the sale of such coins shall be paid to the America 250 Foundation to fund the restoration, rehabilitation, and interpretation of units of the U.S. National Park System and its related areas, as a legacy of the semiquincentennial commemoration.</summary>
</bill>
