<bill session="118" type="h" number="4994" updated="2024-08-02T21:38:03Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PACT with Ukraine Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PACT with Ukraine Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Partnership and Cooperative Transparency with Ukraine Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish officials and institutions for the strengthening of the partnership and cooperative transparency between the United States and Ukraine.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000466"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="Q000023" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-02T21:37:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Partnership and Cooperative Transparency with Ukraine Act or the PACT with Ukraine Act

This bill establishes the Special Envoy for Partnership with Ukraine and two entities to evaluate U.S. assistance to Ukraine.

The special advisor shall support the official U.S. diplomatic presence in Ukraine and be responsible for bolstering the U.S.-Ukraine relationship. The special envoy shall also serve as a primary advisor to the President on issues including (1) cultural preservation, (2) economic opportunity, (3) post-conflict reconstruction, and (4) promoting peace in Ukraine.

Next, the bill establishes the Commission on Cooperative Transparency with Ukraine. The commission is responsible for examining aspects of U.S. financial and material aid to Ukraine, including the effectiveness and any misuse or waste of such aid. The bill authorizes the commission to subpoena, take testimony, and collect evidence for carrying out its responsibilities. The commission must report to Congress on a quarterly basis.

Finally, the bill establishes the Ukraine Oversight Interagency Working Group within the U.S. Agency for International Development. The working group must report monthly to Congress about U.S. aid to Ukraine. Specifically, the report must detail how much aid was provided, the amount expended or destroyed, the amount used, the time elapsed between the receipt of aid and its expenditure, and instances of misuse.</summary>
</bill>
