<bill session="117" type="s" number="2124" updated="2022-12-31T05:26:55Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the award of Federal Government contracts to inverted domestic corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">American Business for American Companies Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Business for American Companies Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2021-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4627-4627" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3987" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-21T18:56:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">American Business for American Companies Act of 2021

This bill makes permanent and expands restrictions that prohibit federal agencies from awarding contracts to inverted domestic corporations. (Similar restrictions have historically been included in annual appropriations measures.)

Specifically, an agency may not award a contract for the procurement of property or services (including a defense contract) to (1) any foreign incorporated entity determined to be an inverted domestic corporation or any subsidiary of such entity, or (2) any joint venture more than 10% of which is held by such an entity or subsidiary.

 An inverted domestic corporation is a company that was previously incorporated in the United States or was a partnership in the United States but is now incorporated in a foreign country despite (1) a majority of the company being owned by the owners of the former domestic entity, or (2) management of the company primarily occurring in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
