<bill session="118" type="s" number="2702" updated="2025-01-14T16:41:20Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Voice for Farm Workers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Voice for Farm Workers Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 to reauthorize the position of Farmworker Coordinator.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000145"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001288" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001320" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2023-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3765" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-10T16:58:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Voice for Farm Workers Act of 2023

This bill reauthorizes and&#160;expands the duties of the Farmworker Coordinator at the Department of Agriculture (USDA). (Part of the Office of Partnerships and Public Engagement, the coordinator identifies challenges faced by farmworkers and coordinates with USDA programs and other federal agencies to address&#160;the community&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s needs.)

Specifically, the bill reauthorizes the position of Farmworker Coordinator through FY2029.&#160;Under the bill, the coordinator must

assess the effectiveness of USDA farmworker outreach programs,develop and implement a plan to coordinate USDA farmworker outreach activities and services,collaborate with USDA's agencies and offices on farmworker-related programmatic and policy decisions,communicate to employers of farmworkers information about federal programs for employees,identify research priorities to inform USDA farmworker-related research activities,measure and analyze the outcomes of USDA farmworker programs and activities, andrecommend new initiatives and programs to USDA.&#160;Further, the bill expands the coordinator's existing duties to include (1) serving as a liaison&#160;to institutions of higher education and local educational agencies, and (2) consulting with community-based nonprofit organizations on areas such as technical skills and job training programs.

The bill also directs the coordinator to hire such staff as necessary to carry out the coordinator's activities.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
