<bill session="117" type="h" number="2801" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">METHANE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a durable framework for achieving long-term reductions in methane emissions from the oil and gas sector through advanced detection, measurement, and abatement technologies and practices, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">METHANE Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Methane Emissions Technology to Help Achieve Net-zero Emissions Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000608"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-07T18:31:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Methane Emissions Technology to Help Achieve Net-zero Emissions Act of 2021 or the METHANE Act of 2021

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish standards and related requirements to reduce methane emissions from certain oil and gas facilities.

Specifically, the EPA must establish methane intensity standards that become increasingly stringent over time. Initial standards must be established within four years. For purposes of establishing the standards, the EPA must categorize the facilities and base the standards on the types of methane emissions from those categories.

As part of the process of establishing methane intensity standards, the EPA must establish regulations that prohibit routine flaring of natural gas from the facilities such that greenhouse gas emission from nationwide routine flaring are (1) reduced by at least 80% below 2017 levels by 2028, and (2) eliminated by 2030.

In addition, the EPA must determine whether commercially available detection and measurement technologies are sufficiently robust to provide the frequency and accuracy of methane emissions monitoring, detection, and measurement to support a tradable methane intensity credit program. If the EPA determines the technologies are sufficient, then it must establish such a program. Under the program, facilities that emit more than the standards may obtain (e.g., purchase) emission credits from those that emit less. Finally, the EPA must set forth requirements concerning efforts to measure and verify the emission reductions.</summary>
</bill>
