<bill session="118" type="h" number="2526" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:49Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">S.O.S. Veterans Caregivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">S.O.S. Veterans Caregivers Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Support Our Services to Veterans Caregivers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to clarify that caregivers for veterans with serious illnesses are eligible for assistance and support services provided by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000599"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T23:17:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Support our Services to Veterans Caregivers Act or the S.O.S. Veterans Caregivers Act

This bill expands eligibility for assistance under the Department of Veterans Affairs Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers. Specifically, the bill expands eligibility for such assistance to caregivers of veterans who have a serious illness that was incurred or aggravated during active military, naval, or air service. Under current law, such assistance is already provided to caregivers of veterans who sustained serious injuries in the course of their military, naval, or air service.

The bill also requires the provision of an annual multidimensional assessment to measure burdens felt by family caregivers who are designated as the primary providers of personal care services to such veterans.</summary>
</bill>
