<bill session="119" type="h" number="3425" updated="2025-09-23T21:26:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-09-08T19:02:53-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-09-08T19:02:53-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">POST Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">POST Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the Federal Protective Service to establish processes to strengthen oversight, performance, and accountability of contract security personnel engaged in the protection of certain buildings and grounds, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000403"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000481" joined="2025-06-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-05-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 119-239.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2025-09-08" calendar="Union" number="196">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 196.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T17:16:48-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Barrett moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T17:17:05-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3877-3879" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T17:17:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3425.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T17:26:04-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T18:56:46-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3881-3882" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="241" datetime="2025-09-08T19:02:53-04:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 402 - 0 (Roll no. 241).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3877-3878" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-09-08T19:02:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-09-09">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-08T14:01:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Personnel Oversight and Shift Tracking Act of 2025 or the POST Act of 2025

The bill directs the Federal Protective Service (FPS) to improve the performance of security personnel contracted to protect federal buildings and to report on such efforts to Congress.

Within one year after the bill's enactment, FPS must establish performance testing and improvement protocols for contract security personnel. Specifically, FPS shall (1) establish standards for the collection, maintenance, and analysis of covert testing data; (2) conduct quarterly analytical reviews of covert testing data to identify trends and opportunities for operational improvement; (3) establish a mandatory, cause-specific corrective training and performance improvement plan for any individual who fails a covert test; and (4) update security training guidance to address failed covert tests, emerging threats, and best practices. FPS must&#160;report to Congress about implementation upon&#160;completion and annually thereafter.&#160;

Within&#160;180 days after the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment, FPS must assess whether to replace or upgrade its tracking system for managing and monitoring the deployment availability of contract security personnel. FPS must&#160;develop (1) an implementation plan that includes a timeline for the replacement or update;&#160;and (2) procedures to ensure timely and accurate communication to building tenants regarding contract security personnel absences or other gaps in coverage.&#160;FPS must report to Congress on the assessment within one year after the bill's enactment&#160;and annually for the next three years.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 119-239</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
