<bill session="118" type="h" number="3531" updated="2025-11-19T04:02:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STOP NJ CONGESTION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STOP NJ CONGESTION Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Taxation of Overburdened People from New Jersey by Correcting Obnoxious New Gimmick and Ensuring the Stability of Transportation Infrastructure from Obstinate Neighbors Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide sanctions for States using certain congestion pricing systems, to amend the Intermodal Surface Transportation Efficiency Act of 1991 to require consent of affected States in carrying out value pricing pilot projects, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000096"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000398" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001226" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000188" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2023-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1746" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-28T22:43:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Taxation of Overburdened People from New Jersey by Correcting Obnoxious New Gimmick and Ensuring the Stability of Transportation Infrastructure from Obstinate Neighbors Act or the STOP NJ CONGESTION Act&#160;This bill requires the Department of Transportation (DOT) to withhold 50% of National Highway Performance Program funds and Surface Transportation Block Grant program funds from each state that implements a congestion pricing system similar to that described in the environmental assessment titled Final Environmental Assessment and Draft Finding of No Significant Impact (FONSI) for Central Business District (CBD) Tolling Program, Manhattan, New York.&#160;The bill also prohibits the implementation of projects under a DOT value pricing pilot program unless the project sponsor receives the consent of each affected state. Value pricing (also called congestion pricing)&#160;involves charging drivers on congested roadways during peak periods.</summary>
</bill>
