<bill session="112" type="h" number="6453" updated="2019-11-15T21:28:19Z">
  <state datetime="2012-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To facilitate planning, permitting, administration, implementation, and monitoring of pinyon-juniper dominated landscape restoration projects within Lincoln County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate planning, permitting, administration, implementation, and monitoring of pinyon-juniper dominated landscape restoration projects within Lincoln County, Nevada, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-10-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on National Parks, Forests and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-11-09T20:10:05Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Lincoln County Land Act of 2000 (the Act) to require implementation of a multispecies habitat conservation plan in Lincoln County, Nevada.

Amends the Act and the Lincoln County Conservation, Recreation, and Development Act of 2004 to make certain amounts available for pinyon-juniper dominated landscape restoration projects within the county, consistent with the Ely Resource Management Plan.

Requires a portion of the proceeds from land sales under the above Acts to be used for economic development in Lincoln County.

Excludes specified public lands within certain utility corridors in Lincoln and Clark Counties, Nevada, from being withdrawn from public land, mining, and mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws.</summary>
</bill>
