<bill session="117" type="s" number="3126" updated="2023-01-21T05:13:42Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-06">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to address the hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Grand Ronde Reservation Act to address the hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights of the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2021-11-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-16">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 117-518.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-06" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="6346" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-12T16:28:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill provides a process by which the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon and Oregon may negotiate to amend or replace the existing agreement defining the tribe's hunting, fishing, trapping, and animal gathering rights.

The current agreement, which was made effective by a January 12, 1987, consent decree by the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon, serves as the exclusive and final determination of the tribe's hunting, fishing, trapping, and gathering rights. This bill instead allows a December 2, 1986, agreement between the United States, Oregon, and the tribe (known as the Grand Ronde Hunting and Fishing Agreement) to define the tribe's rights until and unless it is amended or replaced upon mutual agreement of the tribe and Oregon.

The bill allows the tribe and Oregon to return to the U.S. District Court for the District of Oregon to request the modification or termination of the January 12, 1987, consent decree.</summary>
</bill>
