<bill session="112" type="s" number="2207" updated="2020-02-12T18:54:41Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoring Integrity and Good-Heartedness in Traveler Screening Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RIGHTS Act</title>
    <title type="display">RIGHTS Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Office of the Ombudsman of the Transportation Security Administration to appoint passenger advocates at Category X airports to assist elderly and disabled passengers who believe they have been mistreated by TSA personnel and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001035" joined="2012-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2012-04-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2012-12-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aging"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-05-09T16:21:19Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Restoring Integrity and Good-Heartedness in Traveler Screening Act or RIGHTS Act - Directs the Office of the Ombudsman of the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), in addition to its existing duties, to: (1) record complaints from the public regarding TSA screening practices, (2) determine best practices to resolve frequent passenger complaints and assist in training TSA agents regarding such practices, (3) resolve complaints of mistreatment by TSA employees, and (4) field advance notification calls with individuals with medical conditions or disabilities and arrange for airport screening procedures for such individuals that ensure flight safety without causing them undue hardship.

Directs the Ombudsman to appoint TSA passenger advocates for each Category X airport (an airport with 100% advance technology x-ray screening at all check points). Requires Office duties to be performed by such passenger advocates under the Ombudsman's superivison.

Requires every Category X airport to: (1) have at least one TSA passenger advocate on duty during operating hours, and (2) place clearly visible signs at each gate explaining that a passenger advocate may be summoned (including how to summon one) if passengers believe that a TSA employee has mistreated them on the basis of advanced age or disability.</summary>
</bill>
