<bill session="117" type="s" number="33" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BRICKS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, by increasing the maximum term of imprisonment for the offense of rioting, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blocking Rioters and Insurrectionists from our Cities to Keep us Safe Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BRICKS Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001095"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="687" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil disturbances"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Firearms and explosives"/>
    <term name="Protest and dissent"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-21T16:29:48Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Blocking Rioters and Insurrectionists from our Cities to Keep us Safe Act of 2021 or the BRICKS Act of 2021

This bill increases criminal penalties for rioting and related offenses (e.g., inciting a riot).

First, the bill increases from 5 to 10 years the statutory maximum prison term for a rioting offense.

Second, it establishes higher statutory maximum penalties for rioting offenses that involve certain aggravating characteristics. Specifically, it provides

 a prison term of up to 25 years for a rioting offense that results in serious bodily injury or includes a dangerous weapon, explosives, or fire; and a prison term of any years or for life for a rioting offense that results in death or includes kidnapping, attempt to kidnap, aggravated sexual abuse, attempt to commit aggravated sexual abuse, or attempt to kill.</summary>
</bill>
