<bill session="112" type="h" number="1598" updated="2020-02-14T19:19:56Z">
  <state datetime="2011-04-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-04-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solar Opportunity and Local Access Rights Act</title>
    <title type="display">Solar Opportunity and Local Access Rights Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to promote energy independence and self-sufficiency by providing for the use of net metering by certain small electric energy generation systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001050"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2011-04-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Oversight and Government Reform, Financial Services, and Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform     .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insurance, Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO30" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Technology, Information Policy, Intergovernmental Relations and Procurement Reform" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC)"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public utilities and utility rates"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation and home repair"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-06-27T19:28:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Solar Opportunity and Local Access Rights Act - Amends the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (PURPA) to require each state regulatory authority with ratemaking authority, and each nonregulated electric utility, to conduct a hearing, and on the basis of such hearing, adopt a net metering standard.

Requires retail electric suppliers to make net metering available to retail customers on a first-come-first-served basis.

Prescribes implementation requirements regarding: (1) net energy measurement, (2) billing practices, (3) ownership of credits, (4) safety and performance standards, and (5) determination of compliance.

Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to publish model interconnection standards for the physical connection between local distribution systems and qualified generation units and qualified electric generation units that do not exceed 5 megawatts of capacity. Requires states to adopt such model standards, subject to FERC approval.

Prohibits a state or nonregulated utility from adopting or enforcing any standard or requirement concerning net metering or interconnection that restricts access to the electric power transmission or local distribution system by qualified generators beyond those established under this Act.

Allows states to adopt or enforce additional incentives or requirements to encourage qualified generation and net metering, including any that afford: (1) greater access to the electric power transmission and local distribution systems by qualified generators, or (2) greater compensation or credit for electricity generated by qualified generators.

 Authorizes a contract for renewable energy for public buildings and properties for a maximum period of 30 years.

Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to condition receipt of certain community development block grant (CDBG) funds upon grantee certification that the cost of any permit or license, for construction or installation of any solar energy system for any structure, complies with certain requirements.

Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) to issue regulations to prohibit any restriction impairing the ability of the owner or lessee of a one-family residential structure to install or use a solar energy system upon such property.

Instructs the Secretary of Energy (DOE) to establish a Center for Advanced Solar Research and Development.

Directs the Secretary to issue regulations also requiring that the application for approval of such a system: (1) be processed and approved in the same manner as an application for approval of an architectural modification to the property, and (2) not be willfully avoided or delayed.</summary>
</bill>
