<bill session="117" type="h" number="3936" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Perimeter Transparency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Defense and the Secretaries of the military department to monitor real property ownership and occupancy in the vicinity of United States military installations inside and outside of the United States to identify instances of ownership or occupancy by a foreign adversary.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Perimeter Transparency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4350" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-31T19:44:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Perimeter Transparency Act

This bill requires the Department of Defense and each military department to monitor real property ownership and occupancy in the vicinity (within a 10-mile boundary) of military installations inside and outside of the United States to identify instances in which a foreign adversary owns or occupies (or is seeking to own or occupy) real property in the vicinity of a military installation. For purposes of this bill, a foreign adversary is any foreign government or foreign nongovernment person engaged in a long-term pattern or serious instances of conduct significantly adverse to the national security of the United States or security and safety of United States persons.</summary>
</bill>
