<bill session="116" type="h" number="8883" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:02Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">REPAIR Academia Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify certain requirements with respect to nonimmigrants admitted under subparagraph (F), (J), or (M) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">REPAIR Academia Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reporting Exogenous Participation Among Incoming Researchers in Academia Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="International exchange and broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-04-12T16:30:04Z" status="Introduced in House">Reporting Exogenous Participation Among Incoming Researchers in Academia Act or REPAIR Academia Act

This bill imposes certain reporting requirements on the sponsor of an F, M, or J (student or exchange visitor) visa and authorizes the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to revoke such a visa in certain instances.

The Department of State shall require a sponsor of a J visa to report any change to the visa holder's primary field of study. The State Department and DHS shall require a sponsor of an F, M, or J visa to report when the visa holder is participating in a federally funded research program.

DHS may review and revoke an F, M, or J visa in certain instances, such as finding that (1) the visa holder misrepresented an intention to pursue a field of study, or (2) the visa holder's participation in a federally funded research program poses a national security risk. The bill also imposes certain limits on the ability to appeal such a revocation decision.</summary>
</bill>
