<bill session="109" type="h" number="2621" updated="2019-11-15T21:33:34Z">
  <state datetime="2005-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bounty Hunter Responsibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="display">Bounty Hunter Responsibility Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To clarify that bail bond sureties and bounty hunters are subject to both civil and criminal liability for violations of Federal rights under existing Federal civil rights law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="6179" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bail"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil rights enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal liability"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in criminal justice administration"/>
    <term name="Employment tests"/>
    <term name="Ex-offenders"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification of criminals"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-22T22:35:06Z" status="Introduced in House">Bounty Hunter Responsibility Act of 2005 - Declares that a surety on a bail bond, an agent of such surety, or any bounty hunter seeking to obtain or exercise custody over a person admitted to bail under state law is acting under color of law for purposes of establishing civil or criminal liability for the deprivation of federally protected rights. Considers a bounty hunter as an agent of the surety if such bounty hunter is acting as an independent contractor or employee of the surety.

Requires each surety on a bail bond, agent of such surety, and bounty hunter to inform the local law enforcement agency of the presence of such agent, surety, and bounty hunter and of that individual's intention to seek to obtain or exercise custody over a person admitted to bail outside that state, before commencing activities in the state.

Directs the Attorney General to publish model guidelines for state control and regulation of persons employed or applying for employment as bounty hunters, which shall include recommendations as to whether a person seeking employment as a bounty hunter should be: (1) allowed to obtain such employment if that person has been convicted of a felony; (2) required to complete a basic certification course in the criminal justice system or a handgun training course; or (3) required to submit to a criminal background check.</summary>
</bill>
