<bill session="108" type="h" number="1816" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:03Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Flood Insurance Program Fairness Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to ensure homeowners are provided adequate notice of flood map changes and a fair opportunity to appeal such changes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Flood Insurance Program Fairness Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000810"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-12">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E765"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Housing and Community Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA04" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="Housing and Insurance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Floodplains"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">National Flood Insurance Program Fairness Act - Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to replace requirements for the notification of changes to flood insurance map panels (thus, repealing them) with new requirements for the notification and appeal of such changes.Allows a community affected by the change to appeal the change.Requires the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, if an owner of real property affected by a change to panels incurs expense in connection with the services of surveyors, engineers, or similar services (but not legal services) in effecting any request to the Director to remove the property from inclusion within the base flood elevations established under panels, and granted by the Director in whole or in part, to reimburse such individual for such expense.Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to set forth new requirements (thus, repealing the current requirement) for the publication or notification of proposed flood elevation determinations.</summary>
</bill>
