<bill session="118" type="s" number="1649" updated="2025-01-14T18:51:33Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">LICENSE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">LICENSE Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Licensing Individual Commercial Exam-takers Now Safely and Efficiently Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Transportation to modify certain regulations relating to the requirements for commercial driver's license testing and commercial learner's permit holders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000377" joined="2023-05-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3013" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-06T12:37:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Licensing Individual Commercial Exam-takers Now Safely and Efficiently Act of 2023 or the LICENSE Act of 2023 

This bill provides statutory authority for waivers of training, testing, and other requirements for commercial driver's licenses (CDLs) that were issued by the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic.

Specifically, this bill allows a state or third-party examiner who has maintained a valid CDL test examiner certification and has previously completed a CDL skills test examiner training course to administer the CDL knowledge test, so long as they have completed one unit of the CDL knowledge test training course.

The bill also allows a state to administer a driving skills test to any CDL applicant regardless of the applicant's state of domicile or where the applicant received driver training.</summary>
</bill>
