<bill session="108" type="h" number="2864" updated="2023-01-15T05:47:33Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Reforming, Accelerating, and Protecting Interstate Design (RAPID) Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 23, United States Code, to provide increased flexibility to donor States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reforming, Accelerating, and Protecting Interstate Design (RAPID) Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001248"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000755" joined="2003-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001051" joined="2003-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2003-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001036" joined="2004-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2003-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000182" joined="2003-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000250" joined="2003-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways, Transit and Pipelines.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bridges"/>
    <term name="Consultants"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Local laws"/>
    <term name="Road construction"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Toll roads"/>
    <term name="Tunnels"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-10-29T19:41:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Reforming, Accelerating, and Protecting Interstate Design (RAPID) Act - Authorizes a State transportation department or local transportation agency to award a multimodal transportation project that is located within the boundaries of a donor State (a State that receives a percentage of Highway Trust Fund apportionments and allocations that is less than the percentage attributable to tax payments from highway users in that State), that is within a network of interconnected corridors, that is privately financed, and that contains multiple transportation modes (including highway and rail and utility corridors), using any procurement process permitted by applicable State and local law.

Allows a donor State to authorize a consultant under a contract for such a project to prepare an environmental impact assessment relating to a segment of the project of less than independent utility and without logical termini.

Increases the Federal cost share of certain activities carried out within a donor State. Makes a limitation on the use of toll revenues inapplicable to a donor State.

Allows the total amount of funds paid from the Highway Account to a State for construction of a highway, bridge, or tunnel within the boundaries of that State to be repaid to the Secretary of Transportation.</summary>
</bill>
