<bill session="109" type="h" number="4301" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:41Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-24T15:22:22-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-24T15:22:22-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-11-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to convey certain parcels of land acquired for the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal features of the initial stage of the Oahe Unit, James Division, South Dakota, to the Commission of Schools and Public Lands and the Department of Game, Fish, and Parks of the State of South Dakota for the purpose of mitigating lost wildlife habitat, on the condition that the current preferential leaseholders shall have an option to purchase the parcels from the Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E2335"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-11-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-02-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-06-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-20">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-588.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-07-20" calendar="Union" number="339">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 339.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:18:12-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Walden (OR) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:19:12-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5616-5618" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:19:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4301.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-24T15:22:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed/agreed to in House: On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5616-5617" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-24T15:22:22-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2006-07-24T15:22:22-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5616-5617" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2006-07-25">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="2205" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Habitat conservation"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-10-25T14:42:48Z" status="Passed House amended">Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Land Conveyance Act of 2006 - Deauthorizes the Blunt Reservoir feature of the Oahe Unit, James Division, authorized as part of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River Basin Program.

Allows preferential leaseholders of parcels of the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal features an option to purchase the land they lease from the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation, or the Commission of Schools and Public Lands of South Dakota. Prescribes terms for such purchases, the option exercise period, and the basis for parcel valuation. Directs the Secretary to convey all preferential lease parcels not purchased by the leaseholder and the nonpreferential leased parcels and unleased parcels of the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal to the South Dakota Department of Game, Fish, and Parks, to be used for mitigating the wildlife habitat that was lost as a result of the development of the Pick-Sloan project. Authorizes: (1) the state of South Dakota to accept certain conditions of conveyance, including that it receives the land conveyed in "as is" condition and accepts liability accruing as a result of ownership, operation, and maintenance of the features; and (2) the Commission, with the Department's concurrence, to allow a person to exchange other land in South Dakota for a nonpreferential lease parcel or unleased parcel at Blunt Reservoir or Pierre Canal. Directs the Secretary to transfer all archeological and cultural resource items collected from the Blunt Reservoir and Pierre Canal Features to the South Dakota State Historical Society. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-588</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
