<bill session="110" type="h" number="2117" updated="2023-01-11T15:48:00Z">
  <state datetime="2007-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Freedom Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act concerning foods and dietary supplements, to amend the Federal Trade Commission Act concerning the burden of proof in false advertising cases, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Freedom Protection Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000583"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000191" joined="2007-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000533" joined="2007-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000452" joined="2007-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000364" joined="2007-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001152" joined="2007-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2007-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001144" joined="2007-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E925"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-05-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Arthritis"/>
    <term name="Bone fractures"/>
    <term name="Calcium"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular diseases"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Dietary supplements"/>
    <term name="Drug advertising"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medicinal plants"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Oils and fats"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-06-14T21:26:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Freedom Protection Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (FFDCA) to provide that a food or dietary supplement is not a drug solely because the label or labeling contains a claim to cure, mitigate, treat, or prevent disease.

Prohibits the Secretary of Health and Human Services from: (1) restricting the reprinting and distribution or sale of any U.S. government publication or any accurate quotations of such a publication, including content concerning nutrients and disease treatment or prevention; or (2) construing the distribution or sale of, or accurate quotation from, such a publication in connection with the sale of a food or dietary supplement as evidence of an intent to sell that food or dietary supplement as a drug.

Requires the Secretary to allow claims on food or nutrient labeling that characterize the relationship of a nutrient to the cure, mitigation, treatment, or prevention of a disease (with no more than a three-sentence disclaimer) unless the Secretary proves by clear and convincing evidence that: (1) there is no scientific evidence that supports the claim; and (2) the claim is inherently misleading and incapable of being rendered nonmisleading through the addition of a disclaimer.

Authorizes the use of specified health claims on the label of all foods and dietary supplements, including claims related to saw palmetto, omega-3 fatty acids, glucosamine, and calcium.

Allows a statement for a dietary supplement to include words that are recognized as signs or symptoms of disease so long as the statement does not include the name of a specific disease.

Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to exempt from being regulated as advertising: (1) government publications exempted from reprinting or distribution restrictions under FFDCA; or (2) accurate summaries of scientific publications. Places the burden of proof that an advertisement for a dietary supplement or ingredient is false and misleading on the Federal Trade Commission.</summary>
</bill>
