<bill session="116" type="h" number="6885" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Safe and Secure Medicine Supply for Hardworking Americans Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prohibit the importation of a drug or device that was manufactured at a banned foreign facility, to create incentives for pharmaceutical or device companies to increase manufacturing capacity in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe and Secure Medicine Supply for Hardworking Americans Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000461"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001307" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2020-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000827" joined="2020-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-15">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Tariffs"/>
    <term name="Trade restrictions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T15:13:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Safe and Secure Medicine Supply for Hardworking Americans Act of 2020

This bill bans in certain instances the importation of drugs and medical devices from a foreign manufacturing facility that has been subject to a recall, imposes additional duties on imported drugs, and contains other related provisions.

The Food and Drug Administration shall ban drug or device imports from a foreign facility for a specified amount of time if a drug or device from that facility has been subject to a Class I or Class II recall. The bill imposes civil monetary fines for any individual or entity that violates such an import ban.

The bill also imposes, on top of any other duties, a 25% duty on drugs imported from China, a 20% duty on drugs imported from India, and a 10% duty on drugs imported from any other country.

The duties and fines established under this bill shall go into a fund for supporting and incentivizing new pharmaceutical or medical device manufacturing in the United States.

The bill also requires each drug sold to state on its label the country of origin of each active pharmaceutical ingredient.</summary>
</bill>
