<bill session="118" type="s" number="269" updated="2025-11-19T03:19:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect America's Children from Toxic Pesticides Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect America's Children from Toxic Pesticides Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to fully protect the safety of children and the environment, to remove dangerous pesticides from use, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001288"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2023-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5085" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Migrant, seasonal, agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-03T20:58:29Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protect America's Children from Toxic Pesticides Act

This bill amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) for various purposes, including to modify definitions, cancel or limit the registration of certain pesticides and active ingredients, and create a cause of action for individuals for FIFRA violations.

The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) must immediately suspend the registration of any active ingredient or pesticide product that is banned or otherwise prohibited from entering the market by the European Union, one or more countries in the European Union, or Canada.

The EPA must not permit the continued sale or use of existing stocks of a pesticide with a suspended or canceled registration or that is vacated or set aside by judicial decree.

The bill implements a reporting requirement and other protections related to farmworkers who are exposed to certain pesticide elements (e.g., active ingredients) that result in illness, injury, disability, or death.

Among other elements, the bill also

 creates a process by which an interested person may submit a rulemaking petition to designate an active ingredient or pesticide product as a dangerous pesticide; requires entities that have been granted conditional pesticide registrations to satisfy the conditions of the registration within two years; limits the ability of the EPA to grant emergency exemptions for certain active ingredients or pesticide products; cancels the registration of organophosphates, neonicotinoids, and paraquat; requires the disclosure of inert ingredients in the ingredient statement for pesticide products; and authorizes individuals to bring a civil action against the EPA for alleged failures to comply with provisions under FIFRA.</summary>
</bill>
