<bill session="109" type="s" number="2587" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:37Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Firefighters Special Operation Task Force Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the United States Fire Administration to provide assistance to firefighting task forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firefighters Special Operation Task Force Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5272" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fire departments"/>
    <term name="Fire fighters"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Petroleum refineries"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Weapons of mass destruction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-10T18:23:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Firefighters Special Operation Task Force Act - Amends the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 to authorize the Administrator of the U.S. Fire Administration to award grants to a task force (two or more fire services operating under a cooperative agreement to coordinate incident response within a geographic area) for: (1) salary and benefits to hire or rehire firefighting personnel to provide services to the task force; (2) expenses related to the participation of firefighting personnel in appropriate training courses offered by the Department of Homeland Security, the National Fire Academy, or a state or local fire academy; (3) training related to incident response; (4) appropriate equipment or support systems for task force members; or (5) improved communications between task force members and a local police department or hospital.

Requires the Administrator, in selecting grantees, to give priority to task forces serving geographic areas within 50 miles of: (1) a nuclear power facility; (2) a large facility that produces, treats, or refines chemicals or petroleum products; (3) a business district of national significance; or (4) a location with one or more critical infrastructures.

Requires grantees to provide non-federal matching funds of at least 55% of the amount awarded by the Administrator for each fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
