<bill session="117" type="h" number="1890" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Health Insurance Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act to require Exchanges to establish network adequacy standards for qualified health plans and amend the Public Health Service Act to provide protections for consumers against excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory increases in premium rates.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Insurance Consumer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">No More Narrow Networks Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Protecting Consumers from Unreasonable Rates Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001145"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-03T00:22:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Health Insurance Consumer Protection Act This bill requires health insurance exchanges to establish network adequacy standards for health insurance plans to meet. It also expands the review process for potentially unreasonable health insurance rates, including premiums. The review process, which currently covers only premium increases, is expanded to include the annual review of potentially excessive, unjustified, or unfairly discriminatory rates for health care coverage. If a rate is determined to be unreasonable, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), or the relevant state agency, must take corrective action before, or as soon as possible after, the rate takes effect. Corrective actions may include denying or modifying a rate or requiring the insurer to issue a rebate to consumers. HHS may apply civil monetary penalties to health insurers that fail to comply with a corrective action. Additionally, HHS may decertify the plan as a qualified health plan (i.e., a plan that is certified for sale on a health insurance exchange, is eligible for premium subsidies, and meets the requirements for minimum essential coverage).</summary>
</bill>
