<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="102" updated="2021-11-05T05:07:21Z">
  <amends type="h" number="4350" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2021-09-22T13:58:10-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <offered datetime="2021-09-21"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 11 printed in Part C of House Report 117-125 to strengthen servicemember consumer protections with regards to medical debt collections and credit reporting, including prohibiting the collection of medical debt for the first two years and prohibiting debt arising from medically necessary procedures from ever appearing on servicemember credit reports.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment to strengthen servicemember consumer protections with regards to medical debt collections and credit reporting, including prohibiting the collection of medical debt for the first two years and prohibiting debt arising from medically necessary procedures from ever appearing on servicemember credit reports.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2021-09-22T13:58:10-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="271">
      <text>On agreeing to the Tlaib amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 203 (Roll no. 271).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21T23:04:53-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A006) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21T22:57:30-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Ms. Tlaib.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4816-4818, H4881-4882" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4816-4817" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21"/>
    <action datetime="2021-09-22T13:58:10-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-22T13:58:10-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Tlaib amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 203 (Roll no. 271).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-22T13:58:10-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Tlaib amendment (A006) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 222 - 203 (Roll no. 271).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21T22:57:30-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A006) offered by Ms. Tlaib.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-21">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
