<bill session="118" type="h" number="4336" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Summer Meals REACH Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Summer Meals REACH Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Summer Meals Reaching Every Area&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Child Hunger Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to eliminate certain requirements under the summer food service program for children, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000394"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2024-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2024-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2024-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2023-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001225" joined="2024-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2024-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-18T01:25:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Summer Meals Reaching Every Area's Child Hunger Act of 2023 or the Summer Meals REACH Act of 2023 

This bill permanently extends certain modifications to the Summer Food Service Program that were authorized and implemented to respond to COVID-19. The changes generally expanded the program, which provides free meals to children in low-income areas when school is not in session.

Specifically, the bill permanently makes all children eligible to participate in the program. This includes requiring reimbursement to camps for meals served to all children.

The bill also specifically allows for non-congregate meal distribution, which is meal distribution outside of the typically required group, or congregate, setting (e.g., grab-and-go meal service).

Further, the bill expands eligible service institutions by allowing for on-site or off-site food service monitoring.</summary>
</bill>
