<bill session="115" type="h" number="3754" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:43Z">
  <state datetime="2017-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2017-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">VHA REHIRE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VHA REcruitment, HIring, and REtention Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">VHA REHIRE Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the recruitment, hiring, and retention of health professionals by the Veterans Health Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000289" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000578" joined="2017-11-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001195" joined="2017-11-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-09-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T15:00:10Z" status="Introduced in House">VHA REcruitment, HIring, and REtention Act of 2017 or VHA REHIRE Act of 2017

This bill authorizes the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to carry out a VA Student Loan Repayment Program to assist the Veterans Health Administration (VHA) meet staffing needs for health professional occupations for which recruitment or retention of qualified personnel is difficult.

A program participant must agree to serve as a full-time VHA employee for one year for every $10,000 of received benefits, with a minimum three-year commitment.

Program assistance may be in addition to assistance available under the VA Educational Assistance Program.

A participant in the VA Education Debt Reduction Program must agree to serve as a full-time VHA employee for at least three years.

A physician, dentist, podiatrist, chiropractor, optometrist, registered nurse, physician assistant, or dental auxiliary must agree to serve at least two years as a full-time VA employee in order to receive certain bonuses or allowances.

The VA shall offer employment to a qualified VHA applicant within 75 days after the last day applications are accepted for a position.</summary>
</bill>
