<bill session="117" type="s" number="230" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PREPARE LTC Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to codify certain infection control and emergency preparedness regulations, to prohibit a reduction in the frequency of surveys of skilled nursing facilities and nursing facilities, and to prohibit the waiver of certain reporting requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PREPARE LTC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Restoration of Emergency Preparedness and Advancing Response to Epidemics in Long-Term Care Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="828" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Long-term, rehabilitative, and terminal care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-02T17:02:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Restoration of Emergency Preparedness and Advancing Response to Epidemics in Long-Term Care Act or the PREPARE LTC Act

This bill provides statutory authority for certain infection control and emergency preparedness requirements for Medicare skilled nursing facilities and Medicaid nursing facilities, and expands certain requirements to apply to other infectious disease outbreaks beyond COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019).

Specifically, the bill provides statutory authority for regulations that require, and set standards for, infection control programs and emergency preparedness programs in such facilities. The bill requires facilities to report information concerning any infectious disease outbreak that results in a state or national emergency in accordance with the standards for COVID-19 reporting. It also prohibits the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services from reducing the frequency of compliance surveys or waiving direct care staffing reports during such outbreaks.

Additionally, the Government Accountability Office must report on deficiencies relating to COVID-19 infection control and direct care staffing requirements for skilled nursing facilities.</summary>
</bill>
