<bill session="111" type="s" number="2930" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:48Z">
  <state datetime="2009-12-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-12-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to deter terrorism, provide justice for victims, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000359" joined="2009-12-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-12-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-12-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S13885-13886"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-12-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-07-14">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary Subcommittee on Crime and Drugs. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 111-858.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSJU15" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Drugs" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-01-29T15:57:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Justice Against Sponsors of Terrorism Act - Amends the federal judicial code to: (1) expand the liability of foreign states for tortious acts committed against U.S. citizens during a terrorist act and allow civil actions against a foreign state that are now pending or that were dismissed to proceed in accordance with such expanded liability; and (2) impose liability on a foreign state for the acts or omissions of its officials or employees while acting within the scope of their office or employment.

Amends the federal criminal code to: (1) impose liability on any person who aids and abets an act of international terrorism, provides material support or resources to terrorist organizations, or conspires with terrorists; (2) grant U.S. district courts personal jurisdiction over such persons; (3) remove the prohibition against bringing a civil action against foreign states or foreign officials for damages related to acts of terrorism; (4) extend from 4 to 10 years the limitation period for bringing an action for civil damages resulting from an act of international terrorism; and (5) allow previously time-barred cases to be refiled within 90 days of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
