<bill session="118" type="h" number="4206" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:48Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-17">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Bank Safety Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bank Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Bank Safety Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Financial Stability Act of 2010 to require covered financial institutions to include elements of accumulated other comprehensive income when calculating capital for purposes of meeting capital requirements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2024-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-01">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Financial Services. H. Rept. 118-725.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-11-01" calendar="Union" number="612">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 612.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank accounts, deposits, capital"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-08T14:59:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Bank Safety Act of 2023 

This bill requires additional bank holding companies and insured depository institutions (i.e., those with over $100 billion in assets) to use certain information when calculating capital for purposes of meeting risk-based capital requirements. Specifically, these calculations must include certain unrealized gains and losses (i.e., accumulated other comprehensive income), except for accumulated net gains and losses on cash flow hedges related to items that are not recognized at fair value. Currently, only very large institutions are required to include this type of income in their capital calculations, while other institutions are allowed to opt out.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-725</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
