<bill session="117" type="h" number="5171" updated="2023-08-03T14:15:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-09-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-09-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 1951 of title 18, United States Code (commonly known as the Hobbs Act), and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">Freedom From Union Violence Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Freedom From Union Violence Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001104" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001115" joined="2021-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2021-09-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2021-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-09-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7194" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3889" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-03T14:02:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Freedom From Union Violence Act of 2021 This bill revises the federal criminal statute commonly known as the Hobbs Act, which prohibits the obstruction of interstate commerce by robbery or extortion (or by attempting or conspiring to commit robbery or extortion). Currently, an extortion offense includes obtaining property of another with consent through the wrongful use of force, violence, or fear. Typically, violations are investigated by the Federal Bureau of Investigation and prosecuted by the U.S. Attorney's Office. First, this bill broadens the scope of prohibited conduct by (1) eliminating the requirement that the means used to obtain property (i.e., the use of force, violence, or fear) must be wrongful, and (2) expanding extortion to include obtaining property of another by wrongful use of fear not involving force or violence. Second, the bill explicitly states that the maximum fine is $100,000. Third, the bill exempts from the federal prohibition conduct that (1) is incidental to peaceful picketing during a labor dispute, (2) consists solely of minor bodily injury or damage to property, and (3) is not part of a pattern of violent conduct or of a coordinated violent activity. A violation involving exempted conduct is subject to prosecution only by state and local authorities.</summary>
</bill>
