<bill session="110" type="h" number="6401" updated="2021-09-29T17:19:20Z">
  <state datetime="2008-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2008-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Energy Jobs and Security Act</title>
    <title type="display">Renewable Energy Jobs and Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To spur rapid and sustainable growth in renewable electricity generation in the United States through priority interconnection, renewable energy payments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="I000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000210" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2008-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2008-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2008-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000404" joined="2008-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Air Quality.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-06-26">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committees on Science and Technology, and Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY20" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy, Climate and Grid Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Biomass energy"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Electric power distribution"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Electric utility rates"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Methane"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Public utility regulation"/>
    <term name="Refuse as fuel"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-10-09T13:57:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Renewable Energy Jobs and Security Act - Amends the Federal Power Act to direct the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (FERC) to propose rules establishing standards for the physical connection between specified types of renewable energy facilities and transmission facilities of transmitting utilities subject to FERC jurisdiction. Requires such standards to: (1) include separate expedited procedures for interconnecting 10-kilowatt maximum renewable energy facilities and for expediting interconnection for 2000-kilowatt maximum facilities; and (2) address safety, reliability, performance, cost, and network upgrades. Allows FERC to consider a clustering approach that allows concurrent interconnection of facilities where requests are placed within succeeding six-month periods.

Amends the the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 to require each electric utility to: (1) adopt standards for interconnection with renewable energy facilities as are necessary to ensure that renewable energy facilities are given priority interconnection and priority access to available capacity on the utility's transmission and distribution system over non-renewable energy facilities; and (2) permit any renewable energy facility to apply to the state regulatory authority for an order requiring the interconnection of such facility with the system of the utility.

Requires the Secretary of Energy to transmit to Congress and to the Commission a report that spatially maps national renewable energy resources and conducts cost assessments for renewable energy facility development with respect to all available technologies.

Requires FERC to prescribe rules to encourage the purchase of electric energy by public utilities from renewable energy facilities on a priority basis, under a standard contract, and at rates established on a uniform national basis by FERC. Provides procedures for the setting and adjusting of such rates and for application of net metering.

Requires reports concerning interconnection of renewable energy facilities by utilities to the Energy Information Administration and by the Secretary to Congress and the public.

Requires FERC to design a regional cost redistribution mechanism consisting of a system benefits charge payable by every end-use consumer of an electric utility to the utility, to be transferred to a national renewable energy corporation for reimbursement of the costs associated with this Act's interconnection and power purchase requirements.</summary>
</bill>
