<bill session="117" type="h" number="2073" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:08Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACHE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To place a moratorium on permitting for mountaintop removal coal mining until health studies are conducted by the Department of Health and Human Services, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACHE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Appalachian Communities Health Emergency Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000062"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001292" joined="2021-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001090" joined="2021-08-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000197" joined="2021-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2021-08-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy and Mineral Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII06" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Energy and Mineral Resources" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Noise pollution"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-16T13:19:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Appalachian Communities Health Emergency Act or the ACHE Act

This bill places restrictions and requirements on certain mining projects until the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) determines whether such projects pose risks to human health. The bill applies to mountaintop-removal coal mining projects that use blasting with explosives in the steep slope regions of Kentucky, Tennessee, Virginia, and West Virginia.

Specifically, the bill requires the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences to conduct or support studies on the health impacts of mountaintop-removal coal mining projects on individuals in the surrounding communities. HHS must use these studies when making its determination on whether such mining presents any health risks to those individuals.

Until HHS makes its determination, entities carrying out such mining must monitor levels of soil, water, air, and noise pollution. HHS must make the results of this monitoring publicly available.

In addition, specified agencies may not issue permits for any mountaintop-removal coal mining project or expansion unless HHS determines that such mining does not present any health risk to individuals in the surrounding communities.

The Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement of the Department of the Interior must assess a one-time fee upon existing mining projects. The fee must cover the federal cost of the studies and pollution monitoring required by the bill.</summary>
</bill>
