<bill session="119" type="h" number="207" updated="2025-11-19T04:47:27Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-21T14:40:52-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-01-21T14:40:52-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">SHARKED Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Supporting the Health of Aquatic systems through Research Knowledge and Enhanced Dialogue Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">SHARKED Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short">Supporting the Health of Aquatic systems through Research Knowledge and Enhanced Dialogue Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SHARKED Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting the Health of Aquatic systems through Research Knowledge and Enhanced Dialogue Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a task force regarding shark depredation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SHARKED Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000804"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2025-01-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001200" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2025-01-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000806" joined="2025-01-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:28:30-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Westerman moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:28:39-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H240-242" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:28:41-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 207.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2025-01-21T14:40:52-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H240-241" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2025-01-21T14:40:56-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="2314" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-28T15:31:35Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting the Health of Aquatic systems through Research Knowledge and Enhanced Dialogue Act of 2025 or the SHARKED Act of 2025

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to establish a task force to address and report to Congress about critical needs with respect to shark depredation. (Shark depredation is the partial or complete removal of a hooked fish by a shark directly from a fishing line before the line is retrieved.)

The duties of the task force are, among other responsibilities, to (1) develop ways to improve coordination and communication across the fisheries management and shark research communities; (2) identify research priorities and funding opportunities; (3) develop recommended management strategies to address shark depredation; and (4) coordinate the development and distribution of educational materials.

The bill specifies that the task force must include representatives of each Regional Fishery Management Council, each Marine Fisheries Commission, the fish and wildlife agencies of coastal states, and the National Marine Fisheries Service. The task force must also include researchers&#160;and others with relevant expertise.

The task force must report its findings to Congress within two years after the bill's enactment and&#160;every two years thereafter until the task force is terminated. The task force sunsets within seven years after the date of its establishment.&#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
