<bill session="111" type="h" number="3028" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:45Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">First Responder Innovation and Support Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to establish a grant program to assist innovative natural disaster first responder programs, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">First Responder Innovation and Support Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2009-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2009-10-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-29T18:57:26Z" status="Introduced in House">First Responder Innovation and Support Act of 2009 - Amends the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to authorize the President, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA), to make grants to eligible entities (defined as any of the states, the District of Columbia, any federally recognized Indian tribe, and any U.S. territory or possession that has an approved mitigation plan for identifying and mitigating the natural hazards, risks, and vulnerabilities of the area of jurisdiction) to assist innovative natural disaster first responder programs.

Directs the President to establish selection criteria for making grants, which shall include consideration of: (1) the severity and frequency of natural disasters that affect the applicant; (2) whether existing natural disaster first responder systems would be improved; (3) whether the grant would provide natural disaster first responder support for special populations, including children, pregnant women, the elderly, and the disabled; and (4) whether the activity assisted is sustainable with non-federal amounts after such grant is made.

Requires the President to make grants annually on a competitive basis. Allows eligible entities to apply for multiple grants each year.</summary>
</bill>
