<bill session="109" type="h" number="2860" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:58Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Honesty in Budgeting Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage Members of Congress and the executive branch to be honest with the public about true on-budget circumstances, to exclude the Social Security trust funds and the Medicare hospital insurance trust fund from the annual Federal budget baseline, to prohibit Social Security and Medicare hospital insurance trust funds surpluses to be used as offsets for tax cuts or spending increases, and to exclude the Social Security trust funds and the Medicare hospital insurance trust fund from official budget surplus/deficit pronouncements.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Honesty in Budgeting Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000510"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2005-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Budget, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-15">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM02" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Budget surpluses"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional publications"/>
    <term name="Congressional publicity"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Off-budget expenditures"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-06-21T21:09:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Honesty in Budgeting Act of 2005 - Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that Members of Congress, executive branch officials, and their respective representatives should use on-budget numbers when making public statements regarding the federal budget.

Prohibits receipts and disbursements of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors, Disability, and Hospital Insurance Trust Funds from being counted as new budget authority, outlays, receipts, deficit, or surplus for purposes of the President's budget, the congressional budget, or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act).

Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to require official statements issued by the Office of Management and Budget or the Congressional Budget Office of federal surplus or deficit totals to exclude the receipts and disbursements totals of the Old-Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program and Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
