<bill session="111" type="h" number="5203" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:14Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tinnitus Research for Military Health Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Defense to establish a center of excellence for the study of tinnitus, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tinnitus Research for Military Health Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000466" joined="2010-05-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Hearing, speech, and vision care"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-05-21T15:53:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Tinnitus Research for Military Health Improvement Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense (DOD) to establish one or more centers of excellence for the study of tinnitus. Requires such centers to be established at military installations where members of the Armed Forces perform activities involving high rates of sound, including artillery instruction. Outlines center activities, including researching and enhancing treatments for members with tinnitus.

Requires the inclusion, within a current medical tracking system for members deployed overseas, of an aural screening which shall include an assessment of tinnitus.

Directs the Secretary to establish a grant program to assist eligible institutions in conducting research on recurrent, chronic, or severe tinnitus and peripheral neurological conditions. Makes eligible for such grants: (1) a hospital with an approved teaching program as defined under the Social Security Act; or (2) an educational institution with demonstrated expertise in tinnitus research.

Requires the Secretary to designate a senior DOD official to act as the executive agent for tinnitus.</summary>
</bill>
