<bill session="110" type="s" number="1571" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:49Z">
  <state datetime="2007-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Rural Aviation Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the essential air service program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Aviation Improvement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001028" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2007-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000174" joined="2007-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000261" joined="2008-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000180" joined="2007-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000590" joined="2007-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2007-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2007-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7344"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3004" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Access to airports"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Charter airlines"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-08-03T15:06:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Rural Aviation Improvement Act - Repeals the Essential Air Service Local Participation Program.

Prohibits the Secretary of Transportation from compensating an air carrier for providing essential air service to an eligible community in the 48 contiguous states if such community: (1) is located fewer than 70 miles from the nearest large or medium hub airport; or (2) is fewer than 210 miles from the nearest large or medium hub airport and requires a per passenger subsidy for such service in excess of $200 for calendar year 2008, including any increase for each ensuing calendar year.

Authorizes a state or local government to submit a proposal to the Secretary to: (1) compensate an air carrier for essential air service to an eligible community above the $200 per passenger subsidy cap; (2) compensate a preferred air carrier for providing such service (i.e., an air carrier preferred by the affected community although it is not the lowest bidder); and (3) restore the eligibility of a community to receive subsidized essential air service.

Requires the Secretary, in determining compensation (or eligibility for it) for essential air service based on highway mileage, to use the highway mileage of the most commonly used route between the eligible community and the nearest medium hub airport or large hub airport.

Establishes within the Office of the Secretary the Office of Rural Aviation.

Extends through FY2011 the Secretary's authority under the essential air service program to make agreements to provide assistance to underserved airports.

Requires adjustment of compensation to air carriers for providing essential air service in order to take into account significant increases in fuel costs.

Directs the Secretary to treat passenger boardings on aircraft operated by charter air carriers at airports receiving essential air service as passenger boardings for purposes of making apportionments of airport improvement grant funds.</summary>
</bill>
