<bill session="115" type="h" number="4943" updated="2023-01-11T13:40:35Z">
  <state datetime="2018-02-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2018-02-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2018-02-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CLOUD Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 18, United States Code, to improve law enforcement access to data stored across borders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLOUD Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001093"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000617" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000294" joined="2018-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001065" joined="2018-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000056" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000294" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001179" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2018-02-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2018-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000810" joined="2018-03-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2018-02-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-02-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="2383" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="115" type="h" number="1625" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-16T17:34:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Clarifying Lawful Overseas Use of Data Act or the CLOUD Act

This bill amends the federal criminal code to specify that an electronic communication service (ECS) or remote computing service (RCS) provider must comply with existing requirements to preserve, backup, or disclose the contents of an electronic communication or noncontent records or information pertaining to a customer or subscriber, regardless of whether the communication or record is located within or outside the United States.

An ECS or RCS provider may challenge a domestic warrant that compels disclosure of the contents of an electronic communication if:

 the customer or subscriber is not a U.S. citizen or national, lawful permanent resident, corporation, or other unincorporated entity; the customer or subscriber does not reside in the United States; and the required disclosure creates a material risk that the provider violates the laws of a foreign government with which the United States has in effect an executive agreement on data access. In response to an order from a foreign government with which the United States has an executive agreement on data access, an ECS or RCS provider may:

 intercept or disclose the contents of an electronic communication, and disclose the contents of a stored electronic communication or noncontent records or information pertaining to a subscriber or customer. It establishes a framework to allow the United States to enter into executive agreements with foreign governments to govern data access. To be valid, an executive agreement must meet certain requirements, including that the foreign government affords robust procedural privacy protections and adopts minimization procedures.

This bill does not preclude a foreign authority from obtaining assistance in a criminal investigation or prosecution.</summary>
</bill>
