<bill session="118" type="s" number="836" updated="2025-11-19T03:23:08Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sunshine in Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sunshine in Product Safety Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Consumer Product Safety Act to strike provisions that limit the disclosure of certain information by the Consumer Product Safety Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1686" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-26T17:55:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sunshine in Product Safety Act

This bill repeals provisions that restrict the disclosure of certain information by the Consumer Product Safety Commission (CPSC).

Specifically, the bill repeals provisions that prohibit the CPSC from disclosing certain information about a consumer product that may reveal the identity of the product's manufacturer without first taking reasonable steps to ensure that the information is accurate, the disclosure of the information is fair in the circumstances, and that releasing the information to the public serves the purposes of the laws administered by the commission. The provisions also (1) require the CPSC to provide the manufacturer with an opportunity to comment on the accuracy of the information prior to disclosure, and (2) allow the manufacturer to file a lawsuit in federal court to block a disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
