<bill session="119" type="s" number="113" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:50Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting New Bank Formation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting New Bank Formation Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the appropriate Federal banking agencies to establish a 3-year phase-in period for de novo financial institutions to comply with Federal capital standards, to provide relief for de novo rural community banks, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001079"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001232" joined="2025-01-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-16T18:56:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting New Bank Formation Act of 2025

This bill eliminates and reduces certain requirements applicable to new financial institutions, certain rural community banks, and federal savings associations.

Under the bill, federal banking agencies must issue rules allowing new financial institutions to meet capital requirements within three years. During this period, a financial institution may request to deviate from an approved business plan and the appropriate agency has 30 days to approve or deny the request.

In addition, the community bank leverage ratio&#226;&#8364;&#8221;a way of evaluating debt levels&#226;&#8364;&#8221;is reduced for new rural community banks. Specifically, new rural community banks must have a ratio of 8%, with a three-year phase-in of the rate. After this period, the ratio rises to its current level of 9%.&#160;

Finally, the bill removes certain restrictions to allow federal savings associations to invest in, sell, or otherwise deal in agricultural loans.</summary>
</bill>
