<bill session="109" type="h" number="3051" updated="2023-01-13T04:47:52Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pima County Land Adjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for a land exchange involving certain Bureau of Land Management lands in Pima County, Arizona, for the purpose of consolidating Federal land ownership within the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pima County Land Adjustment Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2005-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forests and Forest Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII20" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Forests and Forest Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="5016" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Endangered species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Public Works"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-08-25T18:57:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Pima County Land Adjustment Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to convey to Las Cienegas Conservation, LLC, the Sahuarita property, which consists of approximately 1,280 acres, in exchange for the Empirita-Simonson property, which consists of approximately 2,490 acres. Requires the Secretary to modify the boundaries of the Las Cienegas National Conservation to include the Empirita-Simonson property. Instructs the Secretary to provide to the Secretary of Agriculture a right of way for motorized public road access through the Empirita-Simonson property to the boundary of the Coronado National Forest.

Requires the Secretary to convey the Tumamoc Hill property, which consists of approximately 290 acres, to Pima County, Arizona upon the County paying the value of such property to the State of Arizona and the State Land Department.

Modifies the boundary of the Las Cienegas National Conservation Area to exclude the 40-acre tract presently leased by the Bureau of Land Management to the town of Elgin, Arizona, for a sanitary landfill.</summary>
</bill>
