<bill session="117" type="h" number="5680" updated="2023-01-01T23:50:30Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To repeal the sugar program under the Federal Agriculture Improvement and Reform Act of 1996 and certain other programs relating to sugar, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">SWEETER Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving Workers by Eliminating Economic Tampering and Ensuring Reliability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWEETER Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000605"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001052" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000302" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000376" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001184" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001199" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000165" joined="2021-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000812" joined="2021-10-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on General Farm Commodities and Risk Management.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG16" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="General Farm Commodities, Risk Management, and Credit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-19T11:07:34Z" status="Introduced in House">Saving Workers by Eliminating Economic Tampering and Ensuring Reliability Act or the SWEETER Act 

This bill eliminates certain Department of Agriculture (USDA) sugar subsidy programs.

Specifically, the bill eliminates (1) the price support loan program available to processors of domestically grown sugarcane and sugar beets; (2) the sugar marketing allotments and tariff-rate quotas that limit the quantities of domestically produced sugar that processors may sell and the sugar that may be imported under lower tariff rates; and (3) the feedstock flexibility program for bioenergy producers, which operates to avoid loan forfeitures to the USDA's Commodity Credit Corporation by requiring USDA to purchase surplus sugar from domestic processors for resale to bioenergy producers.</summary>
</bill>
