<bill session="118" type="h" number="1633" updated="2024-09-21T08:05:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">RAIL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">RAIL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reducing Accidents In Locomotives Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance safety requirements for trains transporting hazardous materials, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001260" joined="2023-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001126" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000631" joined="2023-05-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2024-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2023-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001222" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001221" joined="2023-10-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001223" joined="2023-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000463" joined="2023-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-29T19:07:26-05:00">
      <text>ASSUMING FIRST SPONSORSHIP - Mrs. Sykes asked unanimous consent that she may hereafter be considered as the first sponsor of H.R. 1633, a bill originally introduced by Representative Johnson (OH), for the purpose of adding cosponsors and requesting reprintings pursuant to clause 7 of rule XII. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Labor-management relations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-20T16:48:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Reducing Accidents In Locomotives Act or the RAIL Act

This bill addresses safety requirements for rail carriers and trains transporting hazardous materials.

Specifically, the Department of Transportation (DOT) must issue safety regulations for trains carrying hazardous materials to require that rail carriers (1) provide state emergency response commissioners with advance notice and information about the hazardous materials; (2) reduce blocked rail crossings; and (3) comply with certain requirements regarding train length and weight specifications, track standards, speed restrictions, and response plans.

DOT must also establish requirements for wayside defect detectors. These are used by railway systems alongside the tracks to detect defects and failures (e.g., wheel bearing failures). Current federal regulations do not require their use, but federal guidance does address their placement and use. Under the bill, DOT must issue regulations establishing requirements for the installation, repair, testing, maintenance, and operation of wayside defect detectors for each rail carrier operating a train carrying hazardous materials. Further, these regulations must establish requirements that safety placards be able to withstand heat in excess of 180 degrees.

The bill also

 increases the maximum fines DOT may impose on rail carriers for violating safety regulations, requires DOT to update rail car inspection regulations and audit the federal inspection program, phases out certain railroad tank cars by May 1, 2028 (one year sooner than required under current law), expands training for local first responders, and imposes a new fee on certain rail carriers.</summary>
</bill>
