<bill session="116" type="s" number="2316" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:16Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MICROCHIPS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Manufacturing, Investment, and Controls Review for Computer Hardware, Intellectual Property, and Supply Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MICROCHIPS Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require a plan for strengthening the supply chain intelligence function, to establish a National Supply Chain Intelligence Center, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000880"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2019-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Select Committee on Intelligence.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Director of National Intelligence"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-04T16:04:03Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Manufacturing, Investment, and Controls Review for Computer Hardware, Intellectual Property, and Supply Act of 2019 or the MICROCHIPS Act of 2019

This bill establishes the National Supply Chain Intelligence Center within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI) and contains other provisions related to supply chain intelligence and security.

The center shall (1) aggregate all-source intelligence relating to supply chains; (2) share supply chain-related warnings with the intelligence community, other parts of the federal government, at-risk industry partners, and U.S. allies; and (3) serve as the central resource for supply chain threats and related information.

The President may make funds available to eligible U.S. entities that produce components, products, or technology that will increase supply chain security.

The ODNI shall report to Congress a plan for strengthening supply chain intelligence functions.</summary>
</bill>
