<bill session="119" type="s" number="564" updated="2025-11-19T02:51:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2025-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to approve the settlement of water rights claims of the Zuni Indian Tribe in the Zuni River Stream System in the State of New Mexico, to protect the Zuni Salt Lake, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-02-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1444" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-16T16:06:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Zuni Indian Tribe Water Rights Settlement Act of 2025

This bill recognizes and settles certain water rights claims in New Mexico of the pueblo of Zuni and establishes and provides funding for a related settlement trust fund. It also requires federal actions related to the Zuni Salt Lake in New Mexico.

Specifically, the bill authorizes, ratifies, and confirms a specified water rights settlement agreement entered into by Zuni, New Mexico, and others, thus satisfying claims to water rights in the Zuni River Stream System in New Mexico.

The bill establishes and provides funding for the Zuni Tribe Settlement Trust Fund (and specified accounts) for purposes of carrying out this bill.

Additionally, the bill (1) specifies the water rights of the pueblo; and (2) outlines waivers, releases, and retentions of claims by the pueblo and the United States.

The bill also withdraws certain federal land in New Mexico from mineral development. The bill reserves this federal land for the following three purposes: (1)&#160;the protection of the Zuni Salt&#160;Lake and Sanctuary, (2) the protection of the quality and quantity of the Zuni Salt Lake's water supply, and (3) the protection of any cultural resources associated with the Zuni Salt Lake and Sanctuary. The Bureau of Land Management must manage this land.

The Department of the Interior must take certain land surrounding the Zuni Salt Lake into trust for the benefit of Zuni.</summary>
</bill>
