<bill session="116" type="s" number="2248" updated="2022-11-01T13:50:26Z">
  <state datetime="2019-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEROES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEROES Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Heroes Entering Roles Of Education Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to redesignate and expand the Troops-to-Teachers Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2019-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000618" joined="2019-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2869" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="2500" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1790" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Special education"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-02-25T23:34:32Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Heroes Entering Roles Of Education Service Act or the HEROES Act

This bill revises and expands the Troops-to-Teachers Program, which supports the transition of current and former military personnel to employment positions in education. The program places personnel in (1) elementary and secondary schools that serve more than a certain percentage of lower-income students or those who qualify for aid under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, and (2) Bureau of Indian Affairs-funded schools.

The bill renames the program as the Troops-to-Support-Education Program and expands the positions covered to include a number of teaching support, administrative, and security personnel. Excluded from eligibility are positions performed outside the grounds of a school or for a contractor. For placement in non-teacher positions, the service member must obtain credentials required by the state in which the position is located.

The bill increases the total number of stipends and bonuses provided. It also increases the limit on the amount of obligations for the program for each fiscal year. The Department of Defense may enter into partnership agreements with tax-exempt charitable organizations to assist with the placement of participants.</summary>
</bill>
