<bill session="119" type="s" number="23" updated="2025-11-19T00:22:34Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DRAIN THE SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Decentralizing and Reorganizing Agency Infrastructure Nation-wide To Harness Efficient Services, Workforce Administration, and Management Practices Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRAIN THE SWAMP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the head of each Executive agency to relocate 30 percent of the employees assigned to the headquarters of the Executive agency to duty stations outside the Washington metropolitan area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000295"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2025-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="1280" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-02-26T22:08:33Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Decentralizing and Reorganizing Agency Infrastructure Nation-wide To Harness Efficient Services, Workforce Administration, and Management Practices Act or the DRAIN THE SWAMP Act

This bill relocates 30% of&#160;employees of executive agencies who are based in the Washington, DC area&#160;and reduces the office headquarters of agencies by 30%. It also ends full-time telework for relocated&#160;employees and for those who remain based&#160;in the DC area.

Under the bill, each agency must relocate at&#160;least 30% of full-time employees based at the agency&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s headquarters, including full-time&#160;telework employees who receive DC-area locality pay (unless telework is an accommodation under the Americans with Disabilities Act). The bill does not apply to certain essential employees in the Executive Office of the President, the Department of Defense,&#160;the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, the Central Intelligence Agency, the Department of Energy, and the&#160;Department of Homeland Security.

In determining the new duty stations, each agency must promote geographic diversity and ensure adequate staffing throughout the regions of the agency. Compensation for relocated&#160;employees must be according to the locality pay scale for their new duty station. Agencies must provide their reduction plans to Congress within 180 days and complete the relocations within one year after the bill's enactment.

Further, the Office of Management and Budget must&#160;identify at least 30% of agency headquarters' office space (i.e., real property) to sell or to cease leasing. Agency heads must complete the space reduction within two years after the bill's enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
