<bill session="118" type="h" number="6192" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:51Z">
  <state datetime="2024-05-07T17:02:09-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-05-07T17:02:09-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act</title>
    <title type="short">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act</title>
    <title type="display">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to prohibit the Secretary of Energy from prescribing any new or amended energy conservation standard for a product that is not technologically feasible and economically justified, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000379" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001086" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000304" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000585" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001205" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001211" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000134" joined="2023-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000814" joined="2023-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-10-24">
      <text>Consideration and Mark-up Session Held by the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security Prior to Introduction and Referral</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 26 - 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-03-26">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-432.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-03-26" calendar="Union" number="357">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 357.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-05-06T20:05:41-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1194 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6192, H.R. 7109, H.J. Res. 109 and H.R. 2925. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6192 under a structured rule and H.R. 7109, H.J. Res. 109, and H.R. 2925 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 6192, H.R. 7109, and H.J. Res. 109, and thirty minutes of general debate on H.R. 2925. One motion to recommit allowed on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T14:50:39-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1194.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2896-2908" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2902-2903" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T14:50:44-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6192, H.R. 7109, H.J. Res. 109 and H.R. 2925. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6192 under a structured rule and H.R. 7109, H.J. Res. 109, and H.R. 2925 under a closed rule. Rule provides for one hour of general debate on H.R. 6192, H.R. 7109, and H.J. Res. 109, and thirty minutes of general debate on H.R. 2925. One motion to recommit allowed on each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T14:50:57-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1194 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T14:50:58-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable James C. Moylan to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T14:50:59-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 6192.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T15:53:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1194, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tony Gonzales (TX) amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T15:56:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1194, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:00:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1194, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kelly (PA) amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:46:16-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 6192.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:47:21-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:47:35-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:48:27-04:00">
      <text>Mrs. Fletcher moved to recommit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2906" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:48:39-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T16:55:46-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 202 - 206 (Roll no. 183).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="184" datetime="2024-05-07T17:02:09-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 195 (Roll no. 184).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-05-07T17:02:11-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-05-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1194" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h904"/>
    <amendment number="h903"/>
    <amendment number="h902"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-05-03T17:15:22Z" status="Reported to House">Hands Off Our Home Appliances Act

This bill modifies the process by which the Department of Energy (DOE) amends, revokes, or implements energy conservation standards for certain consumer products (other than automobiles), such as household appliances.

First, the bill eliminates the requirement under the Energy Policy and Conservation Act for DOE, within six years of issuing a final rule establishing or amending such standard, to issue a new proposed rule or publish a notice that the standard does not need to be amended. Instead, the bill allows DOE to publish a notice of proposed rulemaking for prescribing a new or amended energy conservation standard for a consumer product at any time.

Next, the bill specifies that DOE may grant a petition to revoke or amend energy conservation standards if it finds that the standards (1) result in additional costs to consumers, (2) do not result in significant conservation of energy or water, (3) are not technologically feasible, and (4) result in a product (e.g., gas stoves) not being commercially available in the United States to all consumers.

Finally, the bill modifies the criteria used to prescribe new or amended energy conservation standards. For example, new energy conservation standards must be technologically feasible and economically justified.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-432</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
