<bill session="117" type="s" number="2397" updated="2022-12-30T10:18:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Helping Students SOAR with Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to extend eligibility for child's benefits until age 26 for certain individuals who are at least half-time students at a post-secondary school, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Students SOAR with Social Security Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Helping Students Successfully Overcome Adversity and Rise with Social Security Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2021-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-24T14:09:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Helping Students Successfully Overcome Adversity and Rise with Social Security Act or the Helping Students SOAR with Social Security Act

This bill allows an eligible child of a retired, disabled, or deceased worker to receive applicable Social Security benefits on the worker's record until age 26 if the child is in at least half-time attendance as a student at a postsecondary school or a comprehensive transition and postsecondary program.

Under current law, a child's Social Security benefits generally terminate at age 18, although (1) a child who is a full-time elementary or secondary school student may receive benefits until age 19, and (2) a child with a disability that began before age 22 may continue receiving benefits after the age of 18.</summary>
</bill>
