<bill session="117" type="s" number="3496" updated="2022-12-30T04:04:47Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting ACCESS to Diagnostics Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting Access to Critical Countermeasures by Ensuring Specimen Samples to Diagnostics Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting ACCESS to Diagnostics Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve research and development of medical countermeasures for novel pathogens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000384" joined="2022-01-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3799" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-30T21:27:16Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Promoting Access to Critical Countermeasures by Ensuring Specimen Samples to Diagnostics Act or the Promoting ACCESS to Diagnostics Act

This bill directs the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to support the development of medical products and diagnostic tests for emerging infectious diseases.

Specifically, HHS must develop policies and procedures governing access by public and private entities to samples of pathogens (or suitable surrogates). The samples may be used for preparedness and response activities, developing medical products for emerging infectious diseases, and similar purposes.

Additionally, HHS may contract with public and private entities to increase the capacity to rapidly develop, validate, and disseminate diagnostic tests to health departments and other entities to respond to emerging infectious diseases with significant potential to cause a public health emergency.</summary>
</bill>
