<bill session="119" type="s" number="131" updated="2025-11-19T04:57:13Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PRECEPT Nurses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PRECEPT Nurses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Real-World Education and Clinical Experience by Precepting Tomorrow&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Nurses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to create a tax credit for nurse preceptors.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2025-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000312" joined="2025-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="392" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax credits"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-24T12:58:45Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Providing Real-World Education and Clinical Experience by Precepting Tomorrow's Nurses Act or the PRECEPT Nurses Act

This bill establishes a new, nonrefundable tax credit for eligible nurse preceptors, subject to limitations. The bill also requires the Internal Revenue Service (IRS) to report to Congress certain information about the tax credit for nurse preceptors.

Under the bill, a nonrefundable tax credit of $2,000 is allowed for an eligible nurse preceptor through 2032. An eligible nurse preceptor is defined as an individual who provides at least 200 certified hours of supervision and personalized experiential learning, training, instruction, and mentoring in the clinical practice of nursing to a nursing student, advanced practice registered nursing student, or newly hired licensed nurse in a community designated as a health professional shortage area.&#160;

The bill also requires the IRS to report to Congress

the number of taxpayers that claim the tax credit for nurse preceptors each year and the geographic distribution of such taxpayers,aggregated and averaged data on the preceptorships served by taxpayers as an eligible nurse preceptor, andthe effectiveness of the tax credit in increasing the number of nurse preceptors in the United States.</summary>
</bill>
