<bill session="118" type="h" number="4256" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Jordan McNair Student Athlete Heat Fatality Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jordan McNair Student Athlete Heat Fatality Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 485 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require venue-specific heat illness emergency action plans for any institution of higher education that is a member of an athletic association or athletic conference, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000687"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2023-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2024-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2024-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000483" joined="2023-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000131" joined="2023-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and the Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2081" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-03T18:12:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Jordan McNair Student Athlete Heat Fatality Prevention Act

This bill requires each institution of higher education (IHE) that participates in federal student aid programs and is a member of an athletic association or athletic conference to develop and implement a venue-specific heat illness emergency action plan for operating and using automatic external defibrillators and cold-water immersion equipment.

Specifically, each plan must include a symptom identification structure and a coordination of care plan for student athletes exhibiting signs of heat illness that is posted in each locker room, athletic training facility, weight room, and outdoor sports complex and stadium.

Additionally, each plan must

 be made available on the athletic program website or public website of the IHE at the beginning of each academic year; be distributed to local emergency responders; and be distributed to, and rehearsed in person, by specific individuals (e.g., student athletes, coaches, and athletic trainers) before the start of in-person training for each academic year. The bill also requires an IHE to submit an annual report that demonstrates compliance with this bill's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
