<bill session="117" type="h" number="6326" updated="2022-12-30T03:18:59Z">
  <state datetime="2021-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NEW START Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Necessary Entrepreneurship Workshops via the SBA to Transform and Assist Re-entry Training Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NEW START Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a pilot program awarding competitive grants to organizations administering entrepreneurial development programming to formerly incarcerated individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001125"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-02-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001127" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2022-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001159" joined="2022-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-18T18:02:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Necessary Entrepreneurship Workshops via the SBA to Transform and Assist Re-entry Training Act of 2021 or the NEW START Act of 2021

This bill establishes a pilot program for providing entrepreneurial development assistance to formerly incarcerated individuals.

Specifically, the bill requires the Small Business Administration to establish a pilot program whereby it awards grants to organizations or partnerships that create or support entrepreneurship programs for providing assistance to formerly incarcerated individuals. Such assistance shall be in the form of entrepreneurial development programming that includes the disbursement of microloans.

The Government Accountability Office must submit a report evaluating the (1) services that grant recipients provide to formerly incarcerated individuals, (2) oversight of the pilot program by the SBA, and (3) overall performance and impacts of the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
