<bill session="118" type="s" number="2367" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:45Z">
  <state datetime="2024-01-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-01-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CHECKPOINT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Continuing High-quality Evaluations of Concerning and Known Persons Of Interest through National Training updates Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">CHECKPOINT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Continuing High-quality Evaluations of Concerning and Known Persons Of Interest through National Training Updates Act</title>
    <title type="display">CHECKPOINT Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve border security through regular assessments and evaluations of the Checkpoint Program Management Office and effective training of U.S. Border Patrol agents regarding drug seizures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000174" joined="2024-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2023-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-01-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-09">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 118-272.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-12-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="675">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 675.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-26T22:41:24Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Continuing High-quality Evaluations of Concerning and Known Persons Of Interest through National Training updates Act or the CHECKPOINT Act

This bill requires the U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) to update certain offices and policies with respect to drug seizures and checkpoints.

For example, CBP must periodically assess the drug categories in its systems and update them to reflect the drug smuggling scenarios encountered by CBP agents, as necessary. CBP must also update immigration checkpoints with appropriate technology, such as license plate readers, and support intelligence centers on the southern border to combat transnational criminal organizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 118-272</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
