<bill session="117" type="h" number="4727" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for loan forgiveness for STEM teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">STEM K to Career Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STEM K to Career Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001193"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001281" joined="2021-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001111" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2021-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3920"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-19T16:23:36Z" status="Introduced in House">STEM K to Career Act

This bill provides for loan forgiveness and tax credits related to science, technology, engineering, or mathematics (STEM) education and addresses work-study for students employed in STEM fields.

The bill requires the Department of Education to forgive student loan obligations of borrowers employed as full-time teachers of STEM in elementary or secondary schools in which the number of low-income children exceeds a certain percentage. Portions of the student loan debt, including interest, shall be forgiven on the basis of years of service, with 100% forgiven for five years of teacher service.

The bill allows (1) an increased tax deduction for expenses of elementary and secondary school teachers for STEM education supplies; (2) a tax credit for the employment of STEM interns; and (3) a tax credit for employment of individuals who participated in an apprenticeship program in a STEM field, with the amount determined according to the degree of completion of the program.

Beginning with FY2022, an institution of higher education must use at least 7% of federal work-study funds to compensate students employed in STEM fields.</summary>
</bill>
