<bill session="116" type="h" number="8377" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:54Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CEO Accountability and Responsibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CEO Accountability and Responsibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to adjust the rate of income tax of a publicly traded corporation based on the ratio of compensation of the corporation's highest paid employee to the median compensation of all the corporation's employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000623"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-24">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Income tax rates"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-10-27T14:42:24Z" status="Introduced in House">CEO Accountability and Responsibility Act

 This bill amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the corporate income tax rate for publicly traded corporations that pay their chief executive officers or highest paid employees more than 100 times the median compensation of all their U.S. employees or that increase the number of contracted or foreign employees.

The bill also requires an executive agency, in the evaluation of bids or proposals for federal contracts, to give preference to a bidder that has a compensation ratio of highly paid to all employees of less than 50 to 1 in the previous calendar year.</summary>
</bill>
