<bill session="117" type="s" number="5267" updated="2023-05-04T03:45:51Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Asset Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Asset Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network to issue guidance on digital assets, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001198" joined="2022-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-03T18:47:08Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Digital Asset Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2022 

This bill directs specified federal financial agencies to establish rules regarding digital assets. The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network (FinCEN) must establish a rule classifying digital asset wallet providers, cryptocurrency miners, validators, and others as money service businesses. In addition, FinCEN must require U.S. persons to report cryptocurrency transactions through foreign accounts of over $10,000. FinCEN must also require digital asset kiosk owners and administrators to submit and update every three months the physical addresses of the kiosks.

The Department of the Treasury must prohibit financial institutions from handling, using, or transacting business with (1) digital asset mixers, privacy coins, and other anonymity-enhancing technologies; and (2) digital assets that have been anonymized by these technologies.

Treasury, the Securities and Exchange Commission, and the Commodity Futures Trading Commission must establish risk examination and review processes for anti-money laundering requirements for their respective regulated entities.</summary>
</bill>
