<bill session="108" type="s" number="2089" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:17Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to allow aliens who are eligible for diversity visas to be eligible beyond the fiscal year in which they applied.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to allow aliens who are eligible for diversity visas to be eligible beyond the fiscal year in which they applied.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000286"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2004-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001141" joined="2004-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04">
      <text>Committee on the Judiciary. Reported by Senator Hatch without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-10-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="766">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 766.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Fiscal year"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-29T21:43:57Z" status="Reported to Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to allow aliens eligible for diversity visas to remain eligible beyond the fiscal year in which they applied. Provides that such visas shall be counted against the worldwide diversity immigrant level for the fiscal year of selection, except for applications properly filed in FY 2003 for which visas shall be deemed available.

Makes this amendment applicable to immigrant visas available for FY 2004 and subsequent years, and allows for retroactive application to FY 1998 in those cases where the alien applicant or the Government moves to reopen the alien's case.</summary>
</bill>
