<bill session="118" type="h" number="1326" updated="2024-07-24T15:23:32Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SALT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SALT Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting Americans with Lower Taxes Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the limitation on the deduction by individuals of certain State and local taxes and to provide coverage for hearing and vision care under the Medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2024-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000593" joined="2023-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2023-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-19T16:32:11Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting Americans with Lower Taxes Act or the SALT Act

This bill modifies the cap on state and local tax deductions (the SALT deduction) and provides for Medicare coverage of hearing and vision services.

Current law caps the SALT deduction at $10,000 for single taxpayers and married couples filing jointly and $5,000 for married taxpayers filing separately; the cap applies to tax years 2018 through 2025.

The bill permanently (1) eliminates any cap for single taxpayers or married couples filing jointly who make less than $400,000 a year ($200,000 for married taxpayers filing separately); (2) increases the cap to $60,000 for single taxpayers or married couples filing jointly who make $400,000 or more a year ($30,000 for married taxpayers filing separately who make $200,000 or more a year); and (3) phases down the cap for filers who make more than $400,000 in a manner such that those who make $1 million or more do not qualify for the deduction.

The bill also provides for Medicare coverage of hearing and vision services, including hearing aids, glasses, and contact lenses, beginning in 2025. It also appropriates any amounts received as a result of the bill's changes to the SALT cap to Medicare's Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund and provides for specific fund transfers for FY2024 and FY2025 to support Medicare hearing and vision coverage.</summary>
</bill>
