<bill session="117" type="h" number="7687" updated="2022-12-30T00:04:06Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">21st Century Entrepreneurship Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to encourage entrepreneurship training in after school programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000616"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2022-10-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2022-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001072" joined="2022-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000032" joined="2022-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000306" joined="2022-11-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-06">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Small Business, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="384" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-13T20:15:03Z" status="Introduced in House">21st Century Entrepreneurship Act

This bill requires the Small Business Administration (SBA) to develop a curriculum for volunteers with the Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE) to teach underrepresented students (e.g., minority students, English learners, and children with disabilities) about entrepreneurship.

The SBA shall develop and implement a strategy to encourage partnerships between the SCORE program and community learning centers to teach this curriculum and, in developing the curriculum, collaborate with education specialists and groups with experience serving underrepresented children.

The SBA must submit a biennial report on partnerships between the SCORE program and community learning centers, the use of funds by the program, the number of students reached through the entrepreneurship curriculum, and plans for improving the curriculum.</summary>
</bill>
