<bill session="108" type="s" number="1007" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:22Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Better Nutrition for School Children Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A  bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to promote better nutrition among school children participating in the school breakfast and lunch programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Better Nutrition for School Children Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000174"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000072" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000504" joined="2003-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000361" joined="2003-09-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5787"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5787-5788" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food service"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="School lunch program"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Better Nutrition for School Children Act of 2003 - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (CNA) to revise nutritional requirements for the school breakfast program under CNA and the school lunch program under the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (NSLA).Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to base regulations for the school breakfast and lunch programs on sound nutritional science.Authorizes the Secretary, through such Federal regulations, to prohibit the sale of certain competitive foods in food service facilities or areas during the time of school breakfast or school lunch program service (by eliminating a provision of current law that bars such regulations from prohibiting such sale of competitive foods approved by the Secretary during such time).Requires Federal regulations relating to service of foods in schools participating in the breakfast or lunch programs to apply throughout the entire school, including the school grounds, until the end of the time of service of food under the school lunch program.Directs the Secretary, in promulgating such regulations, to consider: (1) the nutritional needs of students in various grade levels; (2) the proximity of any area where foods of minimal nutritional value may be sold, donated, or served without charge to the food service facilities or areas; (3) the extent to which students will likely substitute consumption of foods of minimal nutritional value for other food served in participating schools; and (4) the benefits to a school of permitting the sale, donation, or service without charge of foods of minimal nutritional value, including the extent to which the proceeds of such sales inure to the benefit of a school or an organization of students approved by a school.</summary>
</bill>
