<bill session="118" type="h" number="4821" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-11-03T11:07:33-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-11-03T11:07:33-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="senate calendar) bill text">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of the Interior, environment, and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001148"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Department of Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-29">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Department of Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Department of Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-10">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Department of Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies. Hearings held prior to introduction and/or referral. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 118-566.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-24">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-155, by Mr. Simpson.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-07-24" calendar="Union" number="123">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 123.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T08:19:30-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 838 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4821, H.R. 4820 and H.R. 6126. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4821 and H.R. 4820 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate for each bill. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6126, under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate. Each measure has one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:00:57-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 838.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5243-5297" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:01:02-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 4821, H.R. 4820 and H.R. 6126. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 4821 and H.R. 4820 under a structured rule with one hour of general debate for each bill. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6126, under a closed rule, with one hour of general debate. Each measure has one motion to recommit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:02:46-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 838 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:02:47-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable August Pfluger to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:03:31-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4821.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:46:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Simpson amendment en bloc.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:48:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Griffith amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T11:56:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:06:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 2, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Hageman demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:07:35-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Collins amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:15:34-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Collins amendment No. 15, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:16:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeSaulnier amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:23:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:34:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:39:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:44:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:50:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T12:54:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westerman amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:01:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:06:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 59, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:07:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 60.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:17:13-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 60, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:17:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 61.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:26:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 61, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the nays had prevailed. Mr. Perry demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:27:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rouzer amendment No. 62.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:29:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 63.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:36:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 64.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:43:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 65.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:54:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Harshbarger amendment No. 66.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T13:59:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Harshbarger amendment No. 66, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:00:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa amendment No. 67.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:07:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Malliotakis amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:19:12-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:23:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Perry amendment No. 70, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:24:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Arrington amendment No. 71.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:33:10-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Bentz amendment No. 72.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:39:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 73.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:39:26-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 73, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:45:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 74.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:52:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 74, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T14:53:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 75.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:00:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 76.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:06:50-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Boebert amendment No. 77.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:13:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 78.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:19:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Burgess amendment No. 78, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:20:25-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:20:42-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T15:21:35-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4821 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T16:33:24-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5306-5313" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T16:33:38-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T17:40:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T17:41:23-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T17:41:39-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4821 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:01:16-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5315-5359" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:01:29-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:03:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burlison amendment No. 79.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:14:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Burlison amendment No. 80.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:20:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cammack amendment No. 81.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:27:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 82.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:34:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 83.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:40:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Collins amendment No. 84.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:44:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 85.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:47:02-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Crane amendment No. 85, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:48:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Crane amendment No. 86.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:56:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Collins amendment No. 86, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Leger Fernandez demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T18:57:24-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fallon amendment No. 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:05:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fallon amendment No. 88.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:10:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Fulcher amendment No. 89.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:14:27-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Fulcher amendment No. 89, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:15:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gaetz amendment No. 90.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:19:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 91.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:23:40-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 91, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:24:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 92.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:30:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Graves (LA) amendment No. 93.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:39:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 94.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:48:24-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 94, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:49:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 96.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T19:54:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 97.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:00:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hageman amendment No. 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:06:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jackson (TX) amendment No. 99.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:14:01-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaMalfa amendment No. 100.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:22:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 101.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:29:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 101, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:31:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 102.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:39:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 102, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:39:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Miller (IL) amendment No. 103.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:43:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Miller (IL) amendment No. 103, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. McCollum demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:44:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Miller (IL) amendment No. 104.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:49:23-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 106.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T20:53:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 107.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:00:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 107, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:01:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Nehls amendment No. 108.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:06:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 109.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:11:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 110.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:13:48-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 110, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:14:33-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 111.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:17:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 112.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:25:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 112, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:27:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 113.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:33:30-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 113, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:34:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 114.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:36:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 115.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:45:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norman amendment No. 115, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:46:15-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 116.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:50:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 116, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:51:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 117.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T21:58:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 118.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:18:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 119.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:21:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 120.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:29:25-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 120, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:30:14-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Owens amendment No. 121.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:36:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Palmer amendment No. 122.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:43:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Perry amendment No. 123.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:48:13-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Posey amendment No. 124.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-02T23:53:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rose amendment No. 125.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T00:02:03-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Simpson moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T00:02:15-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T00:02:27-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4821 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:14:42-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5383-5393" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:15:59-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:17:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 126.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:28:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 126, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:28:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 127.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:39:16-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 127, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Pingree demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:39:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Schweikert amendment No. 128.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:49:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stauber amendment No. 129.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T09:57:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Stauber amendment No. 130.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:03:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 838, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Westerman amendment No. 131.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:52:26-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4821.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:53:02-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:53:33-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:54:29-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Leger Fernandez moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T10:54:46-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T11:01:00-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 201 - 215 (Roll no. 596).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="597" datetime="2023-11-03T11:07:33-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 213 - 203 (Roll no. 597).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T11:07:36-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-11-03T11:16:00-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 4821.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-11-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="239">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 239.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity=""/>
    <committee code="SSAP17" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies" activity="Hearings By (Subcommittee), Hearings By (Subcommittee), Hearings By (Subcommittee), Hearings By (Subcommittee)"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2605" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="524" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1043" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="838" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4366" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1061" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaska Natives and Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Animal protection and human-animal relationships"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Domestic violence and child abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Endangered and threatened species"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Hong Kong"/>
    <term name="Humanities programs funding"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands and resources rights"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Marshall Islands"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="National Capital Planning Commission"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="North Dakota"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Palau"/>
    <term name="Parks, recreation areas, trails"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Reptiles"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Solid waste and recycling"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council"/>
    <term name="U.S. history"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="World history"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h611"/>
    <amendment number="h610"/>
    <amendment number="h609"/>
    <amendment number="h608"/>
    <amendment number="h607"/>
    <amendment number="h606"/>
    <amendment number="h605"/>
    <amendment number="h604"/>
    <amendment number="h603"/>
    <amendment number="h602"/>
    <amendment number="h601"/>
    <amendment number="h600"/>
    <amendment number="h599"/>
    <amendment number="h598"/>
    <amendment number="h597"/>
    <amendment number="h596"/>
    <amendment number="h595"/>
    <amendment number="h594"/>
    <amendment number="h593"/>
    <amendment number="h592"/>
    <amendment number="h591"/>
    <amendment number="h590"/>
    <amendment number="h589"/>
    <amendment number="h588"/>
    <amendment number="h587"/>
    <amendment number="h586"/>
    <amendment number="h585"/>
    <amendment number="h584"/>
    <amendment number="h583"/>
    <amendment number="h582"/>
    <amendment number="h581"/>
    <amendment number="h580"/>
    <amendment number="h579"/>
    <amendment number="h578"/>
    <amendment number="h577"/>
    <amendment number="h576"/>
    <amendment number="h575"/>
    <amendment number="h574"/>
    <amendment number="h573"/>
    <amendment number="h572"/>
    <amendment number="h571"/>
    <amendment number="h570"/>
    <amendment number="h569"/>
    <amendment number="h568"/>
    <amendment number="h567"/>
    <amendment number="h566"/>
    <amendment number="h565"/>
    <amendment number="h564"/>
    <amendment number="h563"/>
    <amendment number="h562"/>
    <amendment number="h561"/>
    <amendment number="h560"/>
    <amendment number="h559"/>
    <amendment number="h558"/>
    <amendment number="h557"/>
    <amendment number="h556"/>
    <amendment number="h555"/>
    <amendment number="h554"/>
    <amendment number="h553"/>
    <amendment number="h552"/>
    <amendment number="h551"/>
    <amendment number="h550"/>
    <amendment number="h549"/>
    <amendment number="h548"/>
    <amendment number="h547"/>
    <amendment number="h546"/>
    <amendment number="h545"/>
    <amendment number="h544"/>
    <amendment number="h543"/>
    <amendment number="h542"/>
    <amendment number="h541"/>
    <amendment number="h540"/>
    <amendment number="h539"/>
    <amendment number="h538"/>
    <amendment number="h537"/>
    <amendment number="h536"/>
    <amendment number="h535"/>
    <amendment number="h534"/>
    <amendment number="h533"/>
    <amendment number="h532"/>
    <amendment number="h531"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2023-11-09T16:19:57Z" status="Passed House">Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 appropriations for the Department of the Interior, the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), and several related agencies.

The bill provides appropriations to Interior for

 the Bureau of Land Management, the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, the National Park Service, the U.S. Geological Survey, the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management, the Bureau of Safety and Environmental Enforcement, the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, the Bureau of Indian Affairs, the Bureau of Indian Education, the Bureau of Trust Funds Administration, Departmental Offices, and Department-Wide Programs. The bill also provides appropriations to the EPA and the Forest Service.

Within the Department of Health and Human Services, the bill provides appropriations for

 the Indian Health Service, the National Institute of Environmental Health Sciences, and the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry. The bill provides appropriations to several related agencies, including

 the Council on Environmental Quality and Office of Environmental Quality, the Chemical Safety and Hazard Investigation Board, the Office of Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation, the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development, the Smithsonian Institution, the National Gallery of Art, the John F. Kennedy Center for the Performing Arts, the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars, the National Endowment for the Arts, the National Endowment for the Humanities, the Commission of Fine Arts, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation. the National Capital Planning Commission, the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Museum, the World War I Centennial Commission, and the U.S. Semiquincentennial Commission. Additionally, the bill sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-155</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
