<bill session="117" type="h" number="3844" updated="2022-12-30T17:47:44Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fellowships and Traineeships for Early-Career AI Researchers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To support fellowships and traineeships for early-career artificial intelligence researchers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fellowships and Traineeships for Early-Career AI Researchers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000019"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000588" joined="2021-08-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2021-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2021-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-11">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY15" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="Research and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-21T01:12:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Fellowships and Traineeships for Early-Career AI Researchers Act

This bill directs the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award grants and fellowships to support students and researchers in fields related to artificial intelligence.

Specifically, the NSF must award grants to institutions of higher education to establish traineeship programs for graduate students who pursue artificial intelligence-related research leading to a masters or doctorate degree. Among other things, an institution of higher education shall use such grant funds to (1) provide traineeships to students who are pursuing research in artificial intelligence leading to a masters or doctorate degree; and (2) establish scientific internship programs for students receiving traineeships in artificial intelligence at for-profit institutions, nonprofit research institutions, or government laboratories.

The NSF shall award fellowships to masters and doctoral students and postdoctoral researchers at institutions of higher education who are pursuing degrees or research in artificial intelligence and related fields, including in the field of technology ethics.</summary>
</bill>
