<amendment session="117" chamber="h" number="195" updated="2022-05-12T07:16:19Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2499" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2022-05-11T15:04:09-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000295"/>
  <offered datetime="2022-05-11"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 3 printed in Part D of House Report 117-320 to add the Kenneth Meisel Public Servants Claimant Fairness Act, which amends the Federal Employees Compensation Act (FECA) to establish that claimants who have been asked by the Office of Workers Compensation Programs to provide additional evidence to support their occupational illness, traumatic injury, or death claim have at least 60 days to provide such evidence.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment adds the Kenneth Meisel Public Servants Claimant Fairness Act, which amends the Federal Employees Compensation Act (FECA) to establish that claimants who have been asked by the Office of Workers Compensation Programs to provide additional evidence to support their occupational illness, traumatic injury, or death claim have at least 60 days to provide such evidence.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2022-05-11T15:04:09-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="147">
      <text>On agreeing to the Joyce (OH) amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 419 - 0 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T13:52:26-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered on the amendment (A003) pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T13:49:06-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Joyce (OH).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4826" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="H4829"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4826" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T13:49:06-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A003) offered by Mr. Joyce (OH).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T15:04:09-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T15:04:09-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to by House: On agreeing to the Joyce (OH) amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 419 - 0 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-11T15:04:09-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Joyce (OH) amendment (A003) Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 419 - 0 (Roll no. 147).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
