<bill session="108" type="h" number="2126" updated="2023-01-15T15:33:26Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Teague Grant Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To recognize the importance of the Veterans' Administration Medical School Assistance and Health Manpower Training Act of 1972 in addressing shortfalls in the number of physicians and other health care professionals employed in the health care system of the Department of Veterans Affairs, to reauthorize the program of grants to medical schools affiliated with the Department, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Teague Grant Reauthorization Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000063"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000666" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000082" joined="2003-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000011" joined="2003-05-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-06-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2003-07-29T14:41:28Z" status="Introduced in House">Teague Grant Reauthorization Act - Recognizes: (1) the 30th anniversary of the enactment of the Veterans' Administration Medical School Assistance and Health Manpower Training Act of 1972; (2) the critical and historic role played by that Act towards alleviating the shortfall in the number of physicians and other health care professionals; and (3) the importance of continued growth in partnerships between the Department of Veterans Affairs and affiliated medical schools.

Adds as a purpose of current grants made by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to affiliated medical schools as a result of such Act the addressing of shortfalls in the number of physicians and other health care professionals employed in the Department's Veterans Health Administration. Designates such grants as "Teague Grants" in honor of Olin E. Teague, the most decorated veteran ever to have served in Congress.

Reauthorizes and extends the grant program for FY 2005 through 2009. Includes within criteria for grant approval a determination that proposed projects and programs will increase the number of medical and nursing students attending the affiliated school. Directs the Secretary to give a priority in grant awards to medical schools established under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
