<amendment session="110" chamber="s" number="4733" updated="2022-02-03T05:10:55Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2284" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-05-08">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-05-08"/>
  <description>To require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to enhance communication and outreach to States, Communities, and property owners about the effects of changes to flood risk maps and flood insurance purchase requirements, and to engage with communities to enhance communication and outreach to their residents on such matters.</description>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-05-08" how="Unanimous Consent" result="pass">
      <text>Amendment SA 4733 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3962" label="text as modified"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Amendment SA 4733 proposed by Senator Dodd for Senator Menendez to Amendment SA 4707. (consideration: CR S3962; text as modified: CR S3962) To require the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to enhance communication and outreach to States, Communities, and property owners about the effects of changes to flood risk maps and flood insurance purchase requirements, and to engage with communities to enhance communication and outreach to their residents on such matters.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 4733 as modified agreed to in Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3962" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 4733 proposed by Senator Dodd for Senator Menendez to Amendment SA 4707.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3962" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S3962" label="text as modified"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-08">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
