<bill session="112" type="hr" number="569" updated="2019-11-15T21:07:19Z">
  <state datetime="2012-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Recognizing the tenth anniversary of the tragic communal violence in Gujarat, India.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Recognizing the tenth anniversary of the tragic communal violence in Gujarat, India.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000288"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-05-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Middle East and South Asia .</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA13" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="Middle East, North Africa, and Central Asia" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="News media and reporting"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-03-13T20:06:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Recognizes the suffering of all those persons who were affected by the 2002 violence in Gujarat, India, including those persons who lost their lives in the Godhra train fire.

 Shares the Department of State opinion that the Gujarat government has not adequately pursued justice for the victims of the violence, and remains concerned by reports about Gujarat Chief Minister Narendra Modi's complicity in such violence.

Commends the U.S. government for denying a visa to Minister Modi in 2005.

 Applauds the Department of State and the United States Commission on International Religious Freedom for their monitoring of religious freedom in India and throughout the world.

 Commends the role of the Indian police officers, the media, the National Human Rights Commission, and the Indian Supreme Court in investigating the violence.

Recognizes the work of Indian and Indian-American civil society groups for educating people about human rights and religious freedom in India.

 Calls on the Gujarat government to restore religious freedom in Gujarat.</summary>
</bill>
