<bill session="111" type="h" number="5001" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:09Z">
  <state datetime="2010-04-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-04-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Benefit Adjustment of Social Security Income Compensation Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title II of the Social Security Act to provide that an individual's entitlement to any benefit thereunder shall continue through the month of his or her death (without affecting any other person's entitlement to benefits for that month) and that such individual's benefit shall be payable for such month only to the extent proportionate to the number of days in such month preceding the date of such individual's death.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BASIC Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Benefit Adjustment of Social Security Income Compensation Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001234"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000714" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000410" joined="2010-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001178" joined="2010-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2010-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2010-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2010-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM01" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="Social Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Social security and elderly assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-20T19:48:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Benefit Adjustment of Social Security Income Compensation Act of 2010 or the BASIC Act - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to provide that: (1) an individual's entitlement to any OASDI benefit shall continue through the month of his or her death (without affecting any other person's entitlement to benefits for that month); and (2) the benefit shall be payable for such month only to the extent proportionate to the number of days in the month preceding the date of death.

Revises the formula for computation of a lump-sum death payment to the widow or widower of a fully or currently insured individual.</summary>
</bill>
