<bill session="118" type="h" number="4678" updated="2025-01-15T18:51:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Provide Logistical Aid to airports via advanced Nuclear Energy Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Provide Logistical Aid to airports via advanced Nuclear Energy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to establish procedures for the deployment of microreactors at airports, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000026" joined="2023-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Energy, Climate and Grid Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF03" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Energy" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Electric power generation and transmission"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-05-10T12:46:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Provide Logistical Aid to airports via advanced Nuclear Energy Act or the PLANE Act

This bill directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC), the&#160;Federal Aviation Administration (FAA), and other agencies to establish procedures to deploy microreactors at airports.&#160;A&#160;microreactor&#160;is an advanced nuclear reactor, including a portable nuclear reactor, that has an electricity generating capacity of not more than 20 megawatts of electricity and not more than 100 megawatts of thermal energy.

Specifically, deployment procedures must be established to respond to a primary power source disruption event stemming from a natural disaster. The FAA, the NRC, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the Department of Energy must collaborate to establish these procedures to deploy microreactors&#160;as soon as practicable.&#160;

After these procedures are finalized, the FAA must update the agency's guidance to consider the use of&#160;microreactors in airport emergency plans. Further, the FAA must update the airport emergency plan requirements&#160;to encourage certified airports to consider utilizing&#160;microreactors to provide backup power in the case of an emergency event that results in a primary power source disruption.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
