<bill session="118" type="s" number="797" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:52Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-03">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish and implement a multi-year Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Strategy to reduce the negative environmental and social impacts of illicit gold mining in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000639" joined="2023-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported by Senator Menendez with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-05-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="57">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 57.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="5570" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Drug trafficking and controlled substances"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Ecuador"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Metals"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Peru"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Venezuela"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-02T23:12:37Z" status="Reported to Senate">United States Legal Gold and Mining Partnership Act

This bill requires the Department of State to develop a comprehensive strategy to combat illicit gold mining in the Western Hemisphere, with a focus on artisanal and small-scale mining (ASM), a form of mining typified by labor-intensive techniques, dangerous working conditions, and limited regulation.

The required strategy shall include policies, programs, and initiatives to (1) interrupt the linkages between ASM and illicit actors such as drug traffickers and foreign terrorist organizations; (2) deter ASM in environmentally protected areas; (3) build the capacity of foreign civilian law enforcement to counter linkages between illicit gold mining and money laundering, forced labor, sex work, child labor, and trafficking; (4) support efforts by foreign governments to increase regulation of the ASM sector; and (5) interrupt the illicit gold trade in Nicaragua. The strategy must also include policy recommendations for responding to linkages between the government of Venezuela and the illicit mining, trafficking, and commercialization of precious metals and stones.

Additionally, the bill requires the U.S. Agency for International Development to coordinate with democratically elected governments in the region to establish a public-private partnership to improve transparency and traceability in the international gold trade.</summary>
</bill>
