<amendment session="118" chamber="s" number="999" updated="2024-04-06T00:24:39Z">
  <amends type="s" number="2226" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-07-20">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001261"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-07-20"/>
  <description>To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a Nuclear Fuel Security Program, expand the American Assured Fuel Supply Program, establish an HALEU for Advanced Nuclear Reactor Demonstration Projects Program, and submit a report on a civil nuclear credit program, and to enhance programs to build workforce capacity to meet critical mission needs of the Department of Energy.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 999 under the order of 7/26/2023, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 202.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Amendment SA 999 proposed by Senator Barrasso to Amendment SA 935. (consideration: CR S3717-3718) To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a Nuclear Fuel Security Program, expand the American Assured Fuel Supply Program, establish an HALEU for Advanced Nuclear Reactor Demonstration Projects Program, and submit a report on a civil nuclear credit program, and to enhance programs to build workforce capacity to meet critical mission needs of the Department of Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20"/>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-20">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 999 proposed by Senator Barrasso to Amendment SA 935.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3717-3718" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Senate amendment agreed to: Amendment SA 999 under the order of 7/26/2023, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 202.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-27">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in Senate: Amendment SA 999 under the order of 7/26/2023, having achieved 60 votes in the affirmative, was agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96 - 3. Record Vote Number: 202.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
