<bill session="117" type="h" number="6487" updated="2023-10-12T12:45:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the inspection of certain foreign cranes before use at a United States port, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000559" joined="2022-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001077" joined="2022-05-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation and Maritime Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-26">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity, Infrastructure Protection, and Innovation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign property"/>
    <term name="Navigation, waterways, harbors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-25T16:50:57Z" status="Introduced in House">Port Crane Security and Inspection Act of 2022

This bill limits the operation at U.S. ports of foreign cranes. Foreign cranes are those (1) manufactured by companies that are subject to the control or influence of a country designated as a foreign adversary, and (2) using software or other technology that connects to ports' cyber infrastructure.

Foreign cranes that are contracted for on or after the date of the bill's enactment may not operate at a U.S. port. The bill also prohibits, effective five years after the date of the bill's enactment, foreign cranes at U.S. ports if the cranes use software or other technology manufactured by a company affiliated with a foreign adversary and connect to a port's cyber infrastructure.

Additionally, the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA) must (1) inspect foreign cranes before they are placed into operation for potential security vulnerabilities, and (2) assess the threat posed by security vulnerabilities on existing or newly constructed foreign cranes. CISA must also report to Congress about critical and high-risk security vulnerabilities posed by foreign cranes at U.S. ports.</summary>
</bill>
