<bill session="116" type="h" number="5947" updated="2022-08-10T23:36:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Invest in American Railroads Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to provide for the Secretary to pay certain credit risk premiums for loan or loan guarantees, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Invest in American Railroads Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000382"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000614" joined="2020-02-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001199" joined="2020-02-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW14" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Railroads, Pipelines, and Hazardous Materials" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Transportation programs funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-28T13:18:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Invest in American Railroads Act

This bill revises and expands the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing program of the Department of Transportation (DOT).

Specifically, the bill

 authorizes DOT to pay certain credit risk premiums for loans or loan guarantees; requires DOT to set aside at least $100 million for passenger rail projects in a given fiscal year; directs DOT to provide loans and loan guarantees to private entities with controlling ownership in one or more freight railroads other than Class I carriers; expands eligibility under the loan program to include reimbursement of planning, permitting, and design expenses related to acquiring, improving, or rehabilitating intermodal or rail equipment or facilities; sets forth collateral and appraisal standards under the program; and allows loan repayment terms to be extended up to 50 years after the date of substantial completion of a project, or the estimated useful life of the rail equipment or facilities to be acquired, rehabilitated, improved, developed, or established.</summary>
</bill>
