<bill session="118" type="s" number="1393" updated="2025-11-19T00:55:04Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sunlight in Workplace Harassment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sunlight in Workplace Harassment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to require disclosure of payments for settlements of disputes regarding sexual abuse and certain types of harassment and discrimination, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000817"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2023-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2023-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3078" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-12T13:57:00Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sunlight in Workplace Harassment Act 

This bill requires issuers of securities to annually disclose to the public information about certain alleged acts of sexual abuse, harassment, or discrimination in the workplace or between employees. Specifically, the issuer must disclose settlements, judgements, and active complaints regarding alleged acts of sexual abuse, harassment, or discrimination as defined by the bill. These disclosures must include the number of settlements, judgements, or active complaints; the number of these that involve acts committed by a corporate executive; the total dollar amount paid out; and the date on which the alleged act occurred.

The bill limits the required disclosure by the issuer if the victim of the alleged act objects to its reporting.</summary>
</bill>
