<bill session="116" type="s" number="3899" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:17Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Economic Recovery Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Economic Recovery Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a retraining assistance program for unemployed veterans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000934"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2020-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2020-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2020-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2020-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2020-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2020-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7111" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Educational technology and distance education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Labor market"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-28T16:35:26Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Veterans Economic Recovery Act of 2020

This bill addresses the employment and retraining of veterans, specifically during the COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019) public health emergency.

The bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a program under which the VA must provide up to 12 months of nontransferable retraining assistance to up to 35,000 eligible veterans for the pursuit of a specified program of education. Under the bill, an eligible veteran is an individual who, among other requirements, is unemployed due to COVID-19. Veterans who receive retraining assistance may only use such assistance to pursue specified programs, including those designed to provide training for high-demand occupations.

The Government Accountability Office must report on the outcomes and effectiveness of the retraining assistance program.

The bill provides access to the National Directory of New Hires to the VA and the Department of Labor for the purpose of tracking the employment of veterans.

The bill makes updates to the VA's High Technology Pilot Program, including by expanding the class of providers of high technology education programs.

The bill reauthorizes and expands the program for the provision of off-base transition training for veterans and their spouses, including by requiring a preference for participation by states with economies significantly impacted by COVID-19.

Finally, the bill implements a five-year grant program requiring the VA to make grants to organizations for the provision of transition assistance to members of the Armed Forces who are separated, retired, or discharged from the Armed Forces, and spouses of such members.</summary>
</bill>
