<bill session="117" type="h" number="7242" updated="2023-03-09T17:47:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-04-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Community Disaster Resilience Zones Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Disaster Resilience Zones Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Community Disaster Resilience Zones Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the President to develop and maintain products that show the risk of natural hazards across the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000629"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2022-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000788" joined="2022-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-08">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure. H. Rept. 117-609.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-08" calendar="Union" number="440">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 440.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW13" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Economic Development, Public Buildings, and Emergency Management" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3875" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Geography and mapping"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Presidents and presidential powers, Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-03-02T16:16:25Z" status="Reported to House">Community Disaster Resilience Zones Act of 2022

This bill requires the President to continue to maintain a natural hazard assessment program that develops and maintains publicly available products to show the risk of natural hazards across the United States.

Such products shall show the risk of natural hazards and include ratings and data for loss exposure, social vulnerability, community resilience, and any other element determined by the President.

The President shall (1) review the underlying methodology of any product that is a natural disaster hazard risk assessment, and (2) consider including additional data in any product that is a natural hazard risk assessment. Additionally, the President must conduct such reviews to evaluate and update the assessments at least every five years.

Using the reviewed assessments, the President must periodically identify and designate community disaster resilience zones (CDRZs), which shall be (1) the 50 census tracts assigned the highest individual hazard risk ratings; and (2) in each state, not less than 1% of census tracts that are assigned a high individual risk rating, taking into consideration specified geographic balance.

The President may provide financial, technical, or other assistance to an eligible entity (a state, Indian tribal government, or local government) that plans to perform a resilience or mitigation project within, or that primarily benefits, a CDRZ.

The Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) must develop criteria (taking into consideration the economic effects) to assess damage caused by a harmful algal bloom and report to Congress describing such criteria.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 117-609</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
