<bill session="117" type="s" number="4559" updated="2022-12-29T18:48:40Z">
  <state datetime="2022-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">SUPER Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SUPER Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen and enhance the competitiveness of American manufacturing through the research and development of advanced technologies to reduce steelmaking emissions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4599" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-16T14:36:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Steel Upgrading Partnerships and Emissions Reduction Act of 2022 or the SUPER Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Energy (DOE) to establish a program to reduce greenhouse gas emissions from the production of iron, steel, and steel mill products. Specifically, DOE must establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of advanced tools, technologies, and methods for low-emissions steel manufacturing. In carrying out the program and in collaboration with industry partners, institutions of higher education, and its national laboratories, DOE must support an initiative for the demonstration of low-emissions steel manufacturing.</summary>
</bill>
