<bill session="118" type="h" number="3801" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:44Z">
  <state datetime="2024-12-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-12-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Employer Reporting Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to streamline and improve the employer reporting process relating to health insurance coverage and to protect dependent privacy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001172"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2023-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-07" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 37 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-13">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Ways and Means. H. Rept. 118-111.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-06-13" calendar="Union" number="86">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 86.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21T19:02:32-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Smith (MO) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21T19:03:38-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3048-3050" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21T19:03:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 3801.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2023-06-21T19:09:59-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3048-3049" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-06-21T19:10:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-12-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Finance discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2024-12-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S6935" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-12-11">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2024-12-17">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2024-12-23" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="118-168" type="public" datetime="2024-12-23">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 118-168.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3204" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-08T16:01:40Z" status="Public Law">Employer Reporting Improvement Act

This act modifies provisions under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act that require employers and health insurance providers to prepare tax forms showing proof of minimum essential coverage (1095-B and 1095-C tax forms).

Generally, employers and health insurance providers that provide minimum essential coverage must report this information for each covered individual to the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), including the covered individual's name and tax identification number (TIN). Employers and providers must also send a copy of this information to the covered individual (through 1095-B and 1095-C tax forms) by January 31 of each year.

The IRS allows for an individual's date of birth to be substituted for the individual's TIN if the TIN is not available. The IRS also allows employers and providers to send 1095-B and 1095-C tax forms to individuals electronically&#160;upon obtaining consent from the individual to do so. (Individuals may revoke consent at any time.)

This act provides statutory authority for the substitution of an individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s full name and date of birth for the individual&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s TIN on 1095-B and 1095-C tax forms and the electronic transmission of these forms when prior affirmative consent is provided by the individual.

Additionally, large employers (generally those with 50 or more full-time employees) are subject to an assessment by the IRS if they do not offer affordable minimum essential coverage&#160;(sometimes referred to as the employer mandate or the pay-or-play penalty).

The act requires the IRS to give large employers at least 90 days to respond after sending its first letter that informs the employer of the proposed assessment (Letter 226-J).&#160;(Previously, the IRS generally allowed 30 days to respond, unless an extension was granted.)

Finally, the act establishes a six-year statute of limitations for assessing&#160;amounts for failure to offer affordable minimum essential coverage.&#160;</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-111</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
