<bill session="108" type="s" number="1996" updated="2023-01-15T09:17:37Z">
  <state datetime="2004-11-19">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance and provide to the Oglala Sioux Tribe and Angostura Irrigation Project certain benefits of the Pick-Sloan Missouri River basin program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Rehabilitation and Development Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000077" joined="2004-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2004-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2004-02-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16134"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S16134-16135" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 108-625.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Campbell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-311.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="654">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 654.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-11-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S11566-11584" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11578-11579" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S11577-11578" label="text of measure as reported in Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20T11:24:34-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-20">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-11-30">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and Community Development"/>
    <term name="Indian economic development"/>
    <term name="Indian education"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian medical care"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Restoration ecology"/>
    <term name="Riparian ecology"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-12-23T15:18:50Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on July 20, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Oglala Sioux Tribe Angostura Irrigation Project Modernization and Development Act - Title I: Modernization - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) carry out the modernization and improvement of irrigation facilities at the Angostura Unit as described in a specified report; and (2) provide for the delivery of water saved through such modernization and improvement for fish and wildlife purposes and environmental restoration on the Pine Ridge Indian Reservation, South Dakota.

Title II: Development - (Sec. 201) Establishes the Oglala Sioux Tribal Development Trust Fund in the Treasury. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to make specified deposits into the Fund and payments from it to the Tribe beginning in the 11th fiscal year after enactment of this Act.

Requires the governing body of the Tribe to prepare a development plan that provides for the manner in which the Tribe shall expend such payments to promote: (1) economic development; (2) infrastructure development; (3) the educational, health, recreational, and social welfare objectives of the Tribe and its members; or (4) any combination of these activities.

Requires the Tribal Council to make a copy of the plan available for review and comment by members of the Tribe before it becomes final.

Authorizes the Tribal Council to revise and update the plan on an annual basis, subject to review and comment procedures.

States that activities of the Tribe in carrying out the plan shall be audited as part of the annual single-agency audit that the Tribe is required to prepare pursuant to a specified Office of Management and Budget circular.

Requires a copy of the audit findings to be inserted into the Tribal Council's published minutes of proceedings.

Prohibits distribution of any portion of any payment to the Tribe to any member on a per capita basis.

(Sec. 202) States that no payment made to the Tribe shall result in the reduction or denial of any service or program under Federal law with respect to which: (1) the Tribe is otherwise entitled because of its status as a federally recognized Indian tribe; or (2) any individual is entitled because of his or her status as a member of the Tribe.

(Sec. 204) States that nothing in this Act: (1) affects any rights, benefits, privileges or claims (including water rights or claims to water rights) of the Tribe, whether located on or off the Reservation, based on treaty, Executive order, agreement, Act of Congress, aboriginal title, the Winters doctrine, or otherwise; (2) validates or invalidates any assertion of the existence, nonexistence, or extinguishment of any water rights or claims to such rights held by the Tribe or any other Indian tribe or individual Indian under Federal or State law; or (3) affects any other water rights in existence on the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-311</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
