<bill session="111" type="h" number="1399" updated="2019-11-15T20:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maple Tapping Access Program Act</title>
    <title type="display">Maple Tapping Access Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to support State and tribal government efforts to encourage owners and operators of privately held farm, ranch, and forest land containing maple trees to make their land available for access by the public for maple-tapping activities under programs administered by States and tribal governments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000472"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000800" joined="2009-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E592"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Department Operations, Oversight, Nutrition and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG22" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Commodity Markets, Digital Assets, and Rural Development" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="552" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Food supply, safety, and labeling"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-23T19:52:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Maple Tapping Access Program Act - Amends the the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to support state and tribal government efforts to encourage owners and operators of privately held farm, ranch, and forest land to: (1) initiate or expand maple-tapping activities; or (2) voluntarily make the land available to the public for maple-tapping activities.

Gives priority to states and tribal governments that propose to: (1) maximize participation by offering program terms likely to meet with landowner acceptance; (2) increase maple-tapping activities and maple syrup production; (3) ensure that enrolled land has appropriate tree stock; and (4) use additional federal, state, tribal, or private resources in carrying out the program.</summary>
</bill>
