<bill session="117" type="s" number="1838" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:01Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Building Credit Access for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a pilot program on using alternative credit scoring information for veterans and members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Credit Access for Veterans Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001184"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2021-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2022-09-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Veterans' Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8758" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Housing finance and home ownership"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-11-22T15:34:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building Credit Access for Veterans Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to implement a pilot program to assess the feasibility and advisability of using alternative credit scoring information or models to improve the determination of creditworthiness of certain individuals and to increase the number of such individuals who are able to obtain VA housing and small business loans. Specifically, the program is for veterans or members of the Armed Forces who are eligible for VA housing or small business loans and have insufficient credit history.

Under the program, the VA must assess the feasibility and advisability of establishing criteria for acceptable commercially available credit scoring models to be used by lenders for the purpose of guaranteeing or insuring a VA housing or small business loan.

Participation is voluntary on an opt-in basis for lenders, borrowers, and individuals.

The VA must conduct outreach to lenders and individuals to inform them of the pilot program.</summary>
</bill>
