<bill session="112" type="hr" number="638" updated="2019-11-15T21:41:55Z">
  <state datetime="2012-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2012-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Supporting the efforts of the National Association of State Fire Marshals to raise awareness of proper bonding for yellow corrugated stainless steel tubing to the specifications of the National Fire Protection Association Code.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Supporting the efforts of the National Association of State Fire Marshals to raise awareness of proper bonding for yellow corrugated stainless steel tubing to the specifications of the National Fire Protection Association Code.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000636"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000613" joined="2012-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="sr" number="483" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Housing industry and standards"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2012-06-15T19:49:37Z" status="Introduced in House">Commends efforts to promote and enhance public safety and consumer awareness on the proper bonding of yellow corrugated stainless steel tubing (CSST), as defined in the National Fire Protection Association Code, namely that CSST should be permanently bonded to the electrical grounding system in the structure.

Urges state authorities having jurisdiction over building and housing construction and inspections to include requirements within their rules, regulations, and codes for proper bonding of yellow CSST gas piping in accordance with specified national fuel gas and electric and local codes.

Encourages further education efforts of the public, relevant building and housing officials, homeowners, and construction professionals on the need to properly bond yellow CSST retroactively in structures already containing CSST.</summary>
</bill>
