<bill session="117" type="sr" number="611" updated="2022-12-29T17:03:55Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution expressing the sense of Congress that the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT) continues to make an invaluable contribution to the United States and international security, and recognizing that the United States will seek a successful Ninth Review Conference of the Parties to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of Congress that the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT) continues to make an invaluable contribution to the United States and international security, and recognizing that the United States will seek a successful Ninth Review Conference of the Parties to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2280-2281" label="text"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control and nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Australia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military operations and strategy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oceania"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="United Kingdom"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-23T18:43:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This resolution specifies that the United States should&#160;(1) encourage all parties to the Treaty on the Non-Proliferation of Nuclear Weapons (NPT) to comply with it fully; (2) pursue a verifiable and comprehensive arms control agreement with Russia and China on strategic and nonstrategic nuclear weapons capabilities; and (3) advance critical U.S. security partnerships like the one among Australia, the United Kingdom, and the United States (commonly known as AUKUS) to provide Australia with naval nuclear propulsion technology to better deter against military aggression in the Indo-Pacific.

The resolution also encourages the President to work with other parties to the NPT to (1) strengthen compliance and enforcement mechanisms, and (2) develop collective responses in the UN Security Council and in any other relevant multilateral forums to any notification of withdrawal from the NPT.</summary>
</bill>
