<bill session="111" type="h" number="1876" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:36Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military LEEDs Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 10, United States Code, to require the incorporation of Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design (LEED) principles in military construction projects carried out in the United States or overseas, to require a specific goal regarding the use of renewable energy sources on all military installations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military LEEDs Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001245"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000208" joined="2009-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-27">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS03" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Readiness" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Energy efficiency and conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental technology"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-01T21:38:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Military LEEDs Act of 2009 - Requires the Secretary of Defense, for each military construction or housing project authorized after FY2009, to incorporate the design criteria promulgated in the Leadership in Energy and Environmental Design Green Building Rating System, as developed by the United States Green Building Council, to achieve not less than the silver standard.

Directs the Secretary of the military department concerned, in designing any new facilities, to consider the use of sustainable construction materials.

Requires military construction renewable energy goals to include specific goals to increase the use of renewable energy sources on all military installations in the United States and overseas.</summary>
</bill>
