<bill session="119" type="h" number="1604" updated="2025-11-19T03:10:01Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farm and Food Cybersecurity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm and Food Cybersecurity Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to periodically assess cybersecurity threats to, and vulnerabilities in, the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector and to provide recommendations to enhance their security and resilience, to require the Secretary of Agriculture to conduct an annual cross-sector simulation exercise relating to a food-related emergency or disruption, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000475"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001298" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000487" joined="2025-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG03" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Nutrition and Foreign Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="s" number="754" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-09T18:30:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Farm and Food Cybersecurity Act of 2025

This bill directs the Department of Agriculture (USDA) to (1) assess&#160;cybersecurity threats in the agriculture and food&#160;critical infrastructure&#160;sector, and (2) conduct annual crisis simulation exercises for food-related emergencies or disruptions. The agriculture and food&#160;critical infrastructure&#160;sector&#160;includes (1) any activity relating to the production, processing,&#160;distribution, storage, transportation, consumption, or disposal of agricultural or food products; and (2) any entity involved in any of these activities.

Specifically, USDA must conduct a risk assessment every two years on the&#160;cybersecurity threats to, and security vulnerabilities in, this sector. The risk assessment must include any recommendations for federal legislative or administrative actions to address related threats and vulnerabilities.

USDA must also conduct an annual simulation exercise relating to a food-related emergency or disruption in coordination with&#160;the Department of Homeland Security (DHS), the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS), and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence (ODNI).

Among other things, the exercise must (1) involve a realistic and plausible scenario that simulates a food-related emergency or disruption that affects multiple sectors and jurisdictions, and (2) incorporate input from experts and stakeholders from various disciplines and sectors (e.g., agriculture, public health, emergency management, transportation, and energy).&#160;

USDA, in consultation with DHS, HHS, and ODNI, must submit a report to Congress on each simulation exercise, including recommendations to enhance the&#160;cybersecurity and resilience of the agriculture and food critical infrastructure sector.</summary>
</bill>
