<bill session="117" type="h" number="5739" updated="2022-12-30T07:34:00Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to change certain Federal Pell Grant requirements for certain students with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to change certain Federal Pell Grant requirements for certain students with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001223" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2021-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2022-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000192" joined="2022-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-05-11T21:42:43Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill revises certain requirements under the Federal Pell Grant Program for students with disabilities.

Currently, Pell Grant awards are based on enrollment status and a student must attend an institution of higher education (IHE) on a full-time basis in order to receive the maximum award amount. This bill provides an exception for a student with a disability who is receiving appropriate and reasonable accommodations for such disability. Specifically, the bill requires the amount of a Pell Grant to be calculated as if such a student is attending an IHE on a full-time basis, without regard to whether the student is attending less than full time.

Additionally, the bill extends the period of time during which a student with a disability may receive a Pell Grant. In particular, the bill allows a student to exceed the current 12-semester limit to complete the first undergraduate baccalaureate course of study if required by the student's accommodations.</summary>
</bill>
