<bill session="111" type="hr" number="87" updated="2022-02-03T06:06:42Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-27T14:30:33-05:00">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2009-01-27T14:30:33-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Providing for consideration of the bill (S. 181) to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, and to modify the operation of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, to clarify that a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice that is unlawful under such Acts occurs each time compensation is paid pursuant to the discriminatory compensation decision or other practice, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Providing for consideration of the bill (S. 181) to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, and to modify the operation of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, to clarify that a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice that is unlawful under such Acts occurs each time compensation is paid pursuant to the discriminatory compensation decision or other practice, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-26">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 111-5, by Ms. Pingree (ME).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-26T20:56:55-05:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of S. 181 with 1 hour of general debate. Previous question shall be considered as ordered without intervening motions except motion to recommit. Measure will be considered read. Bill is closed to amendments.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2009-01-26" calendar="House" number="4">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 4.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T12:15:12-05:00">
      <text>Considered as privileged matter.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H532-535" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T12:15:13-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H. Res. 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T12:47:39-05:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on H.Res. 87, the Chair put the question on ordering the previous question and by voice vote the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Lincoln Diaz-Balart demanded the yeas and nays and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of ordering the previous question until later in the legislative day.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T13:56:52-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H543-544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T14:21:58-05:00">
      <text>On ordering the previous question Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 175 (Roll no. 32).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="33" datetime="2009-01-27T14:30:33-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>On agreeing to the resolution Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: 252 - 174 (Roll no. 33).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H532" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2009-01-27T14:30:35-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="181" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-27T09:04:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Sets forth the rule for consideration of the bill (S. 181) to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 and the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967, and to modify the operation of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, to clarify that a discriminatory compensation decision or other practice that is unlawful under such Acts occurs each time compensation is paid pursuant to the discriminatory compensation decision or other practice.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-5</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
