<bill session="111" type="h" number="261" updated="2020-02-10T16:49:07Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chemical Facility Security Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Chemical Facility Security Improvement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide that no Federal funds may be used by the Secretary of Homeland Security to approve a site security plan for a chemical facility, unless the facility meets or exceeds security standards and requirements to protect the facility against acts of terrorism established for such a facility by the State or local government for the area where the facility is located, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000032"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000193" joined="2009-01-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Homeland Security, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Homeland Security</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-14">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-02-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Transportation Security and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM07" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Transportation and Maritime Security" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Industrial facilities"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-01-23T23:18:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Chemical Facility Security Improvement Act of 2009 - Prohibits federal funds from being used by the Secretary of Homeland Security to approve a site security plan for a chemical facility unless the facility meets or exceeds security standards and requirements to protect it against terrorist acts established by the state or local government for the area where it is located.

Amends the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2007 to: (1) repeal a provision prohibiting the Secretary from disapproving a site security plan based on the presence or absence of a particular security measure; (2) require vulnerability assessments and site security plans to be treated as sensitive security information; and (3) repeal a provision limiting to the Secretary any right of action against a chemical facility owner or operator to enforce security measures.</summary>
</bill>
