<bill session="118" type="h" number="3756" updated="2025-01-24T18:06:37Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Environmental Justice in Recreation Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Justice in Recreation Permitting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture to complete an interagency report on the effects of special recreation permits on environmental justice communities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000481"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001218" joined="2023-05-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-30">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Natural Resources, and in addition to the Committee on Agriculture, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-31">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2670"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAG15" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Forestry and Horticulture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSII10" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Federal Lands" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Land use and conservation"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-10-04T19:42:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Environmental Justice in Recreation Permitting Act

This bill requires the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture to complete an interagency report on the use of special recreation permits by recreation service providers serving environmental justice communities.

The bill defines an environmental justice community as a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or tribal and indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects than other communities.

Interior and USDA (1) shall contact all existing or prospective special recreation service providers to request a voluntary estimate of the number of user days used by, or, in the case of a prospective recreation service provider, expected to be used by, individuals from environmental justice communities; (2) shall request from recreation service providers and interested members of the public any other information required for the report; and (3) shall not use participation or the provision of information to Interior and USDA by a recreation service provider as a condition of a special recreation permit.</summary>
</bill>
