<bill session="115" type="h" number="4043" updated="2023-01-11T13:38:26Z">
  <state datetime="2018-03-06T15:45:58-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2018-03-06T15:45:58-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2017-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Whistleblower Protection Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Whistleblower Protection Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Whistleblower Protection Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Whistleblower Protection Extension Act of 2017</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to reauthorize the whistleblower protection program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001294"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2017-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2017-11-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-01-11">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform. H. Rept. 115-510.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-01-11" calendar="Union" number="380">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 380.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06T15:40:56-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Blum moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06T15:41:55-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1417-1418" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06T15:41:57-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4043.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2018-03-06T15:45:58-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1417-1418" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2018-03-06T15:46:08-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2018-03-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="340">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 340.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="115" type="s" number="1869" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2019-08-30T14:45:58Z" status="Introduced in House">Whistleblower Protection Extension Act of 2017

This bill permanently extends the requirement for inspectors general (IGs) to designate a Whistleblower Protection Ombudsman to educate agency employees about prohibitions on retaliation, and the rights and remedies against retaliation, for protected disclosures.

The bill renames the Whistleblower Protection Ombudsman as the Whistleblower Protection Coordinator. It also expands the responsibilities of a Whistleblower Protection Coordinator to include the following:

 educating employees about specific rights and remedies (e.g., the means by which an employee may seek review of an allegation of reprisal); assisting the IG in promoting the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures and allegations of reprisal; and assisting the IG in facilitating communication and coordination with other relevant persons and entities regarding timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures, allegations of reprisal, and other general matters. A Whistleblower Protection Coordinator must have direct access to the IG to accomplish such responsibilities.

The bill also expands the responsibilities of the Council on the Inspectors General on Integrity and Efficiency to include the following:

 facilitating the work of the Whistleblower Protection Coordinators; and developing best practices for promoting the timely and appropriate handling and consideration of protected disclosures, allegations of reprisal, and other matters. Finally, the bill adds reporting requirements for semiannual reports. Specifically, with respect to instances of whistle-blower retaliation by an official, an Office of Inspector General must report on (1) the actual consequences imposed on the official who engaged in retaliation, and (2) whether a settlement agreement was entered with that official.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 115-510</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
