<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2163</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-13T04:49:17Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-13T04:49:17Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2005-12-21</introducedDate>
    <congress>109</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
        <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2005-12-21T22:32:53Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-12-21</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssva00</systemCode>
            <name>Veterans' Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR 12/22/2005 S14327-14328)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-12-21</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR 12/22/2005 S14326-14327)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2005-12-21</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000148</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kerry, John F. [D-MA]</fullName>
        <firstName>JOHN</firstName>
        <lastName>KERRY</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MA</state>
        <middleName>FORBES</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Armed forces reserves</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Coast guard</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Governmental investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Iraq compilation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Military pay</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Payroll deductions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Recruiting and enlistment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Veterans' education</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2005-12-21</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2006-03-10T20:31:17Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Armed Forces Education Benefits Improvement Act - Increases for FY2005 and thereafter the amount of monthly basic educational assistance under the Montgomery GI Bill (GI Bill) for veterans whose obligated period of active duty for such entitlement is three years. Increases such amounts, for FY2006 and thereafter, by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of Defense to work expeditiously with the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that members of the Selected Reserve receive their educational benefits in a timely manner. Requires a study from the Secretary of: (1) Defense analyzing the effect of all GI Bill educational benefits on recruitment and retention; and (2) Veterans Affairs analyzing the effect of such benefits on the readjustment of veterans eligible for the increased benefits, above.</p> <p>Increases for FY2005 and thereafter the amount of monthly educational assistance for members of the Selected Reserve who agree to remain members for at least six years. Increases such amounts, for FY2006 and thereafter, by the percentage increase in the Consumer Price Index.</p> <p>Allows eligible members of the Armed Forces to make an irrevocable election to receive basic educational assistance under the GI Bill. Defines as eligible members those who: (1) first became a member or first served on active duty before July 1, 1985; (2) served on active duty without a break in service since such date; (3) continue to so serve during the one-year period following enactment of this Act; (4) have successfully completed the requirements of a secondary school diploma and the equivalent of 12 semester hours toward a standard college degree; and (5) when discharged or released, receive an honorable discharge.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Armed Forces Education Benefits Improvement Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Armed Forces Education Benefits Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to amend titles 10 and 38 of the United States Code, to increase and index educational benefits for veterans under the Montgomery GI bill to ensure adequate and equitable benefits for active duty members and members of the selected Reserve, and to include certain servicemembers previously excluded from such benefits.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Armed Forces Education Benefits Improvement Act</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2005-12-21T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-109s2163is/xml/BILLS-109s2163is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2005-12-21</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR 12/22/2005 S14327-14328)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
