<bill session="119" type="s" number="2077" updated="2025-07-25T16:22:30Z">
  <state datetime="2025-06-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-06-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Expanded Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Expanded Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to ensure health insurance coverage continuity for former foster youth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000608" joined="2025-06-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-06-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-06-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-25T16:22:02Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Expanded Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act

This bill modifies provisions relating to the coverage of former foster youths under Medicaid.

Under current law, a state Medicaid program must cover former foster youths until the age of 26 if the youths were in a state's foster care system at the age of 18 and were enrolled in a state's Medicaid program while in foster care. The bill requires state Medicaid programs to also cover former foster youths who were placed in a legal guardianship with a kinship caregiver or were emancipated from foster care before the age of 18. The bill repeals the provision that requires former foster youths to have been enrolled in a state Medicaid program while in foster care in order to qualify for Medicaid coverage until the age of 26.

The bill also requires states to establish Medicaid outreach and enrollment programs for former foster youths.</summary>
</bill>
