<bill session="111" type="h" number="6547" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:11Z">
  <state datetime="2010-12-21T19:43:58-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-21T19:43:58-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require criminal background checks for school employees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000725"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2010-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000309" joined="2010-12-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T11:04:15-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Miller, George moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T11:04:32-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8801-8802" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T11:04:34-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 6547.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T11:11:50-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T19:35:05-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8915" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="663" datetime="2010-12-21T19:43:58-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 314 - 20 (Roll no. 663).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8801" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-12-21T19:44:01-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-12-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Assault and harassment offenses"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Sex offenses"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-01-05T16:16:07Z" status="Passed House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)

Protecting Students from Sexual and Violent Predators Act - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require each state receiving funds under that Act to have in effect policies and procedures that: (1) require criminal background checks for school employees, including searches of state criminal registries or repositories, state-based child abuse and neglect registries and databases, the National Crime Information Center of the Department of Justice, the National Sex Offender Registry, and the Integrated Automated Fingerprint Identification System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); and (2) prohibit the employment of school employees who refuse to consent to a criminal background check, make false statements in connection with one, or have been convicted of one of a list of felonies or any other crime that is a violent or sexual crime against a child.

Lists those felonies as: (1) homicide; (2) child abuse or neglect; (3) crimes against children; (4) spousal abuse; (5) crimes involving rape or sexual assault; (6) kidnapping; (7) arson; and (8) physical assault, battery, or drug-related offenses, committed within the past five years.

Requires local educational agencies (LEAs) or state educational agencies (SEAs) to report to local law enforcement any applicants for school employment who are discovered to be sexual predators.

Requires periodic repetitions of such criminal background checks.

Requires such states to provide for a timely process under which school employees may: (1) appeal the results of a criminal background check to challenge the accuracy or completeness of the information produced; and (2) seek appropriate relief for any final employment decision based on materially inaccurate or incomplete information produced. Requires this appeals process, however, to deny the individual employment as a school employee during the process.</summary>
</bill>
