<bill session="117" type="s" number="2488" updated="2023-03-08T20:12:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to expand the capacity of the suicide prevention lifeline and mental health crisis centers.</title>
    <title type="display">Suicide and Crisis Outreach Prevention Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Suicide and Crisis Outreach Prevention Enhancement Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2021-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000295" joined="2021-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2021-07-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-22T16:48:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Suicide and Crisis Outreach Prevention Enhancement Act

This bill reauthorizes through FY2026 and otherwise revises the National Suicide Prevention Lifeline program by expanding program activities and placing requirements on telecommunications carriers. The program provides free and confidential support to people in suicidal crisis or emotional distress through either a nationwide three-digit or toll-free telephone number.

Expanded activities include increasing the program's capacity to provide prevention and intervention services, carrying out public awareness and outreach about the program, and collecting data on disparities in accessing the program and among individuals seeking help.

Furthermore, telecommunications carriers must transmit any calls made to the program to the caller's local crisis center. They must also transmit the call, if transferred by the local crisis center, to the applicable local emergency service, mental health resource, or similar support. The bill also prohibits telecommunications carriers from deducting minutes from a caller's pre-paid phone plan for calls made to the program.</summary>
</bill>
