<bill session="116" type="s" number="4185" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:40Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-07-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">End Surprise Medical Bills for Air Ambulances Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">End Surprise Medical Bills for Air Ambulances Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an independent dispute resolution process for surprise air ambulance bills, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000437"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Insurance industry and regulation"/>
    <term name="Transportation costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-14T20:39:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">End Surprise Medical Bills for Air Ambulances Act of 2020 This bill establishes an independent dispute resolution process for health insurances costs related to out-of-network air ambulance services. Specifically, this process requires health insurance plans (1) to pay the billed amount to the out-of-network air ambulance provider within 30 days of receipt of a bill for such services, or (2) to notify the provider and the patient who received service that the bill is being disputed and that the patient is not responsible for the disputed amount. The plan and the provider then must agree to an amount to be paid within 90 days, or they must enter into a dispute resolution process with an Independent Dispute Resolution Entity selected at random from the list of such qualified entities established by the Department of Health and Human Services.</summary>
</bill>
