<bill session="117" type="h" number="2523" updated="2023-09-05T17:28:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">THRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">THRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">THRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">THRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">THRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 to improve the COVID-19 Veteran Rapid Retraining Assistance program, to make certain technical corrections to the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 to improve the COVID&#226;&#8364;&#8220;19 Veteran Rapid Retraining Assistance program, to make certain technical corrections to the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001295" joined="2021-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Economic Opportunity.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T14:17:02-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Takano moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T14:17:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1965-1968" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1965-1967" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T14:17:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2523.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T14:31:54-04:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:50-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 330, proceedings on H.R. 2523 are considered vacated.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by special rule" type="vote" datetime="2021-04-20T18:20:51-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Pursuant to section 6 of H. Res. 330, and the motion offered by Mr. Hoyer, the following bills passed under suspension of the rules: H.R. 367; H.R. 370; H.R. 396; H.R. 397, as amended; H.R. 408; H.R. 490; H.R. 965, as amended; H.R. 1251, as amended; H.R. 1395; H.R. 1491; H.R. 1528; H.R. 1532; H.R. 1565; H.R. 1602; and H.R. 2523, as amended; and the following resolution was agreed to under suspension of the rules: H. Res. 124, as amended.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1979-1994" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1990-1992" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Senate Committee on Veterans' Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S3929-3930" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="2021-05-28" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2021-05-28">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2021-06-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2021-06-08" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-16" type="public" datetime="2021-06-08">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-16.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR10" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Economic Opportunity" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="hr" number="330" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2492" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Women's education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-04T10:54:42Z" status="Public Law">Training in High-demand Roles to Improve Veteran Employment Act or the THRIVE Act

This bill makes updates to Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) training and education policies and programs, including by amending the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 and the Johnny Isakson and David P. Roe, M.D. Veterans Health Care and Benefits Improvement Act of 2020.

(Sec. 2) In implementing the VA's rapid retraining assistance program, the list of high-demand occupations must be prepared in conjunction with the Department of Labor. The VA may add and remove occupations as appropriate.

The bill excludes programs pursued solely through distance learning on a half-time basis or less from the housing stipend available to those participating in the retraining program.

The VA must contact program participants to notify them about employment placement services after they begin the program and upon either completion of the program or termination of participation in the program.

The VA must seek to enter a memorandum of understanding with one or more qualified nonprofit organizations for the purpose of facilitating the employment of veterans who participate in the program. The Government Accountability Office must report on the outcomes and effectiveness of the retraining program.

(Sec. 3) The VA must provide veterans and members of the Armed Forces with information about whether (1) a postsecondary education institution is listed on the College Navigator website as being affiliated with a certain religion, (2) an institution is minority serving, and (3) an institution is gender-specific. The VA must provide information about postsecondary education and training opportunities in a searchable format.

(Sec. 5) The bill includes for-profit educational institutions that are converted to public educational institutions in the annual risk-based survey the state approving agency must conduct.

(Sec. 6) The VA must take certain disciplinary action when any person with whom an educational institution has an agreement for marketing, advertising, educational programs, recruiting, or admissions services engages in specified behaviors, such as providing a type of incentive payment to persons engaged in student recruiting. Under the bill, such disciplinary actions may include suspending the approval of courses and programs offered by the institution or revoking the approval of courses and programs.</summary>
</bill>
