<bill session="117" type="s" number="3934" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:28Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Homeowner Flood Insurance Transparency and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homeowner Flood Insurance Transparency and Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit policyholders under the National Flood Insurance Program to elect to have previous premium rates remain in effect until the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency satisfies certain conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001079"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001075" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001098" joined="2022-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000437" joined="2022-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7364" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-02T11:49:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Homeowner Flood Insurance Transparency and Protection Act 

This bill allows National Flood Insurance Program policyholders to elect to pay premiums at the rate in effect prior to the implementation of Risk Rating 2.0. Risk Rating 2.0 bases premium rates on an individual property's specific flood risk instead of the flood risk of a general location and property type.

Policyholders may elect to pay the previous rate until the Federal Emergency Management Agency performs several actions regarding Risk Rating 2.0, including

 publishing all data and methods used to calculate premium rates under Risk Rating 2.0, creating an online database where policyholders can see premium rates for their property using specified calculations, and publishing an assessment of the economic and social impacts of Risk Rating 2.0.</summary>
</bill>
