<bill session="116" type="h" number="8915" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:00Z">
  <state datetime="2020-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preparing Superfund for Climate Change Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preparing Superfund for Climate Change Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 to provide for the consideration of climate change, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001061"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001270" joined="2020-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-09">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-12-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water Resources and Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW02" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Water Resources and Environment" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2893" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Atmospheric science and weather"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-25T18:04:54Z" status="Introduced in House">Preparing Superfund for Climate Change Act of 2020

This bill requires the consideration of factors related to climate change when selecting remedial actions for the cleanup of Superfund sites (sites contaminated with hazardous substances). Specifically, the potential threat to human health and the environment associated with local natural disasters and extreme weather hazards, including those exacerbated by climate change, must be taken into account when selecting remedial actions.

Under current law, some remedial actions result in hazardous substances remaining at the site, so there must be a review every five years to assure that human health and the environment are being protected. The bill requires such review to include an assessment of whether the selected remedial action remains protective after taking into account local natural disasters and extreme weather hazards, including those exacerbated by climate change.</summary>
</bill>
