<bill session="109" type="s" number="1357" updated="2019-11-15T21:44:12Z">
  <state datetime="2005-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Meat and Poultry Pathogen Reduction and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Meat and Poultry Pathogen Reduction and Enforcement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect public health by clarifying the authority of the Secretary of Agriculture to prescribe performance standards for the reduction of pathogens in meat, meat products, poultry, and poultry products processed by establishments receiving inspection services and to enforce the Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Point (HACCP) System requirements, sanitation requirements, and the performance standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H000206"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2005-10-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000061" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2005-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000709" joined="2005-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/1/2005 S7850-7851"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3160" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Food safety"/>
    <term name="Foodborne diseases"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-09-06T19:27:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Meat and Poultry Pathogen Reduction and Enforcement Act - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act and the Poultry Products Inspection Act, respectively, to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to prescribe: (1) surveys to determine foodborne pathogen contamination levels for raw meat and raw poultry, and meat and poultry products processed in establishments inspected under such Acts; (2) public health goals; and (3) initial and final pathogen reduction performance standards to reduce pathogen contamination and achieve public health goals.

Directs the Secretary to: (1) identify, and publish a list of, such pathogens; (2) initiate pathogen surveys to determine existing levels of meat and poultry contamination; (3) establish public health goals and objectives to achieve foodborne illness reduction; and (4) report on the scientific feasibility of establishing health-based performance standards for pathogens.

Directs the Secretary to establish a National Advisory Committee for Microbiology Criteria for Foods.Directs the Secretary to enforce Hazard Analysis and Critical Control Point (HACCP) System requirements and other sanitation requirements in any official establishment. Authorizes the Secretary to prohibit non-complying establishments from labeling any meat or meat product, or poultry or poultry product, as "inspected and passed."</summary>
</bill>
