<bill session="116" type="h" number="2051" updated="2022-11-01T19:02:21Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-09T15:31:28-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-09T15:31:28-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for Federal coordination of activities supporting sustainable chemistry, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001306" joined="2019-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001289" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001117" joined="2019-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001124" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000624" joined="2019-10-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2019-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000459" joined="2019-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2019-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001083" joined="2019-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000126" joined="2019-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2019-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001207" joined="2019-08-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001208" joined="2019-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001215" joined="2019-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001201" joined="2019-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000469" joined="2019-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000133" joined="2019-07-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-04-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-10-17" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-26">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology. H. Rept. 116-312, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-26">
      <text>Committee on the Budget discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2019-11-26" calendar="Union" number="253">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 253.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:23:17-05:00">
      <text>Ms. Johnson (TX) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:23:31-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9359-9362" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:23:33-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 2051.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2019-12-09T15:31:28-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9359-9361" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2019-12-09T15:31:29-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="999" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government lending and loan guarantees"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Office of Science and Technology Policy"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and engineering education"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer and commercialization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-28T19:05:07Z" status="Passed House">Sustainable Chemistry Research and Development Act of 2019

(Sec. 3) This bill directs the Office of Science and Technology Policy to convene an interagency entity under the National Science and Technology Council with the responsibility of coordinating federal programs and activities in support of sustainable chemistry. Sustainable chemistry, also known as green chemistry, is focused on conserving resources and minimizing the generation and use of hazardous substances in chemical processes.

(Sec. 4) The entity shall develop a working framework of attributes characterizing and metrics for assessing sustainable chemistry.

The entity shall report to Congress and the Government Accountability Office on the present state and future of sustainable chemistry.

(Sec. 5) The agencies participating in the entity shall carry out activities in support of sustainable chemistry, including activities that incorporate sustainable chemistry into existing research, development, demonstration, technology transfer, commercialization, education, and training programs. Any financial support provided shall (1) be available for pre-competitive activities only; and (2) not be used to promote the sale of a specific product, process, or technology, or to disparage a specific product, process, or technology.

For FY2021-FY2030, no later than 90 days after submission of the President's annual budget request, the entity shall prepare and submit to Congress a report that includes a summarized agency budget in support of the activities carried out under this bill. (Sec. 6) The agencies participating in the entity may facilitate and support, through financial, technical, or other assistance, the creation of partnerships between institutions of higher education, nongovernmental organizations, consortia, or companies across the value chain in the chemical industry, including small- and medium-sized enterprises.

To be eligible for support, a partnership in sustainable chemistry shall include at least one private sector organization.

In selecting partnerships for support, the agencies participating in the entity shall also consider the extent to which the applicants are willing and able to demonstrate evidence of support for, and commitment to, the entity's goals.

Financial support provided to partnerships may not be used to (1) support or expand a regulatory chemical management program at an implementing agency under a state law; (2) construct or renovate a building or structure; or (3) promote the sale of a specific product, process, or technology, or disparage a specific product, process, or technology.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 116-312</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
