<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="468" updated="2022-02-03T05:24:00Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2829" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2007-06-28">offered</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000491"/>
  <offered datetime="2007-06-28"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following: TITLE IX--ADDITIONAL GENERAL PROVISIONS Sec. 901. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by the United States Government to seize or otherwise take possession of, other than for value given in a sale or exchange, any coin, medal or numismatic item made or issued by the United States Government before January 1, 1933, that, as of the date of the enactment of this Act, is not already in the possession of the United States Government.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 34 printed in the Congressional Record to prohibit the use of funds to be used by United States Government to seize or otherwise take possession of, other than for value givern in a sale or exchange, any coins, medal or numismatic item made by the U.S. Government.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28T10:52:48-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Serrano raised a point of order against the Lucas amendment (A015). Mr. Serrano stated that the amendment seeks to change existing law and constitutes legislation in an appropriationbill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28T10:49:10-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A015) offered by Mr. Lucas.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7349" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7349" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28T10:49:10-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A015) offered by Mr. Lucas.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7349" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7349" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-06-28">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
