<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="319" updated="2022-02-25T17:31:04Z">
  <amends type="h" number="1540" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-05-25T19:21:02-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000444"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-05-25"/>
  <description>At the end of subtitle H of title X, add the following:    SEC. 1085. SENSE OF CONGRESS REGARDING DEPLOYMENT OF NATIONAL GUARD TO SOUTHWESTERN BORDER OF UNITED STATES.    It is the sense of the Congress that the deployment of National Guard personnel (as defined in section 101(c) of title 10, United States Code) along the southwestern border of the United States for the purposes of assisting United States Customs and Border Protection in securing the international border between the United States and Mexico, should continue through the end of fiscal year 2011.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 39 printed in House Report 112-88 to add a Sense of Congress indicating that the deployment of National Guard personnel along the southwestern border should continue through the end of fiscal year 2011.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-05-25T19:21:02-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A019) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:17:16-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A019) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3638" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3638" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:17:16-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A019) offered by Mr. Flake.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H3638" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H3638" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:21:02-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Flake amendment (A019) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25T19:21:02-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-25">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
