<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2244</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T20:19:40Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T20:19:40Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2007-10-25</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2007-10-25T23:24:02Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-10-25</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-10-25</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S13456-13457)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-10-25</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>C001041</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Clinton, Hillary Rodham [D-NY]</fullName>
        <firstName>HILLARY</firstName>
        <lastName>CLINTON</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NY</state>
        <middleName>R</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Child health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy assistance for the poor</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy conservation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Families</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Federal advisory bodies</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government publicity</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Health education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing and Community Development</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing for the aged</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Housing for the disabled</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Income tax</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lead</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Lead poisoning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Low-income housing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medicaid</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical screening</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Medical tests</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minorities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Minority health</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Paints and varnishes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pregnant women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Risk</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Strategic planning</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tax credits</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Taxation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Women's health</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-10-25</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2008-01-09T19:00:50Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Lead Elimination, Abatement, and Poisoning Prevention Act of 2007 or the LEAPP Act of 2007 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out demonstration projects and outreach programs for the identification and abatement of lead hazards.</p><p>Requires the Secretary, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) and the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, to establish the Joint Task Force on Lead-Based Hazards.</p><p>Requires the President, in conjunction with the Administrator, to establish the Task Force on Children's Environmental Health and Safety.</p><p>Requires the Secretary to conduct outreach and education activities about lead exposure.</p><p>Requires the Secretary, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, to undertake pilot projects in states to provide lead poisoning risk assessments, blood-lead level screening, interventions to reduce exposure to lead-based hazards, and medically appropriate treatment to pregnant women enrolled in the Medicaid program under title XIX of the Social Security Act.</p><p>Amends the Residential Lead-Based Paint Hazard Reduction Act of 1992 to require a seller or lessor of housing to: (1) conduct a risk assessment or inspection for the presence of lead-based paint hazards (current law permits the purchaser a 10-day period to conduct such assessment or inspection unless the parties mutually agree on a different period); (2) disclose to the purchaser or lessee the results of such inspection or assessment and hazard control measures carried out; (3) remediate any lead-based paint hazards found; and (4) include in any contract for the purchase or lease of housing documentation of any inspection, risk assessment, or hazard control measure.</p><p>Includes within the meaning of the term &quot;target housing&quot; housing for the elderly or persons with disabilities or any zero bedroom dwelling. Redefines the term &quot;qualified allocation plan&quot; for purposes of the low-income housing tax credit.</p><p>Directs the Department of Energy (DOE) to require the conduct of lead hazard control measures during weatherization projects.</p><p>Authorizes appropriations for HUD's Lead Hazard Reduction Program.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>LEAPP Act of 2007</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to carry out demonstration projects and outreach programs for the identification and abatement of lead hazards, to establish the Joint Task Force on Lead-Based Hazards and the Task Force on Children's Environmental Health and Safety, to strengthen the authority of the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>LEAPP Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>LEAPP Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Lead Elimination, Abatement, and Poisoning Prevention Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2007-10-25T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s2244is/xml/BILLS-110s2244is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2007-10-25</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
