<bill session="118" type="h" number="749" updated="2025-11-19T03:53:13Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Turn OFF THE TAP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Turn Off Federal Funding of Threatening Entities that Thwart American Prosperity Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Turn OFF THE TAP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the provision of Federal funds to certain entities subject to sanctions imposed by the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000478"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001222" joined="2023-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="143" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-31T20:07:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Turn Off Federal Funding of Threatening Entities that Thwart American Prosperity Act or the Turn OFF THE TAP Act

This bill prohibits certain entities from receiving federal funds or contracts from an executive agency.

Specifically, this prohibition applies to (1) entities listed as specially designated nationals and blocked persons by the Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC) of the Department of the Treasury, (2) certain entities on the OFAC's Non-SDN Chinese Military-Industrial Complex Companies List, (3) entities identified on a Department of Defense list of Chinese military companies operating in the United States, (4) entities on the entity list maintained by the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, and (5) entities identified by the Federal Communications Commission as a telecommunications equipment or service provider that pose an unacceptable risk to U.S. national security.</summary>
</bill>
