<bill session="117" type="h" number="7978" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:39Z">
  <state datetime="2022-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Promoting and Advancing Communities of Color Through Inclusive Lending Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Promoting and Advancing Communities of Color Through Inclusive Lending Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To make reforms to provide support for minority depository institutions, community development financial institutions, and minority lending institutions to promote and advance communities of color through inclusive lending, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-06-08">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="2543" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-06T13:43:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Promoting and Advancing Communities of Color Through Inclusive Lending Act 

This bill expands the support of, and access to, community development financial institutions, minority lending intuitions, and minority depository institutions. These institutions provide financial services to economically distressed or minority communities.

The bill provides mandatory funding set-asides for assistance to minority lending institutions and establishes the Office of Minority Lending Institutions to administer these funds. The bill also establishes the Office of Diverse and Mission-Driven Community Financial Institutions to monitor and support institutions seeking certification.

Further, the bill provides for technology grants, a pilot program for establishing new institutions, and various studies and reports.</summary>
</bill>
