<bill session="118" type="h" number="3593" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a drone infrastructure inspection grant program and a drone education and workforce training grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2024-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2023-05-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2023-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3935" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-20T11:11:15Z" status="Introduced in House">Drone Infrastructure Inspection Grant Act

This bill establishes programs within the Department of Transportation (DOT) to support the use of small, unmanned aircraft systems (commonly known as drones)&#160;when inspecting, operating, repairing, or constructing road infrastructure, electric grid infrastructure, water infrastructure, or other critical infrastructure.

Specifically, DOT must award grants to state, tribal, or local governments; metropolitan planning organizations; or groups of those entities to purchase or otherwise use drones to support more efficient inspection, operation, construction, maintenance, modernization, and repair of critical infrastructure to improve worker safety&#160;related to critical infrastructure projects. Grant recipients must use domestically manufactured drones that are not made by certain foreign entities, including companies subject to influence or control from China or Russia.

DOT must also award grants to certain institutions of higher education for training students for careers using drones and related technologies.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
