<bill session="117" type="s" number="1018" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:54Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Access to TESTs Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for acquiring equipment and supplies capable of performing same-day clinical laboratory testing in a point-of-care setting, and to assist laboratories in meeting the cost of acquiring high-throughput equipment, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to Technology and Equipment for Same-day Tests (TESTs) Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Access to TESTs Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2021-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="747" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-20T13:42:17Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Access to Technology and Equipment for Same-day Tests Act or the Access to TESTs Act

This bill establishes grant programs to increase access to diagnostic tests.

Specifically, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) must award grants to hospitals, primary care facilities, and other health care providers to buy equipment and supplies to increase access to same-day diagnostic testing in point-of-care settings.

The CDC must also award grants to public health and other laboratories to buy high-throughput diagnostic equipment and supplies to increase testing capacity and expedite test results.</summary>
</bill>
