<bill session="117" type="h" number="1941" updated="2023-03-08T20:26:21Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to waive certain naturalization requirements for United States nationals, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to waive certain naturalization requirements for United States nationals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000600"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000582" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000610" joined="2021-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001204" joined="2021-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000822" joined="2022-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Citizenship and naturalization"/>
    <term name="Family relationships"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-01T01:17:08Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill waives certain requirements for U.S. nationals applying for citizenship.

Currently, individuals born in an outlying possession (i.e., American Samoa or Swains Island) are U.S. nationals but do not automatically acquire citizenship through birth in an outlying possession.

Under this bill, a U.S. national who otherwise qualifies may become a citizen upon establishing residence and physical presence in a U.S. outlying possession. Currently, U.S. nationals must become a resident of a state to qualify for naturalization.

The bill also waives certain naturalization requirements, including those related to English language proficiency and participation in a public ceremony, for individuals who have continuously resided in an outlying possession or state from birth to the approval of a naturalization application.

Furthermore, upon meeting other requirements, this bill allows a child born abroad of a U.S. citizen parent to acquire citizenship by establishing presence and residency in an outlying possession, where currently such a child must be lawfully present in the United States to acquire citizenship through this method.</summary>
</bill>
