<bill session="118" type="s" number="982" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to establish an FBI hotline to receive tips about persons trying to engage in certain activities in the United States on behalf of the Government of China or the Chinese Communist Party, and to criminalize the performance of the functions of a law enforcement agency in the United States on behalf of the Government of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an FBI hotline to receive tips about persons trying to engage in certain activities in the United States on behalf of the Government of China or the Chinese Communist Party, and to criminalize the performance of the functions of a law enforcement agency in the United States on behalf of the Government of China or the Chinese Communist Party.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001198"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-07T15:10:57Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Federal Bureau of Investigation to establish a hotline to receive anonymous tips about individuals who surveil, harass, intimidate, or coerce another individual, or perform law enforcement activities, in the United States on behalf of China or the Chinese Communist Party (CCP).

This bill also establishes federal criminal offenses for individuals in the United States who engage in one of the following on behalf of China or the CCP: (1) surveillance, harassment, intimidation, or coercion of another person in the United States; or (2) performance of any function of a law enforcement agency.</summary>
</bill>
