<bill session="116" type="s" number="3965" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:15Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Artificial Intelligence for the Armed Forces Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Artificial Intelligence for the Armed Forces Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accelerate the application of artificial intelligence in the Department of Defense and to strengthen the workforce that pertains to artificial intelligence, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2020-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advanced technology and technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-11T13:53:36Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Artificial Intelligence for the Armed Forces Act of 2020

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD) to (1) exercise authority and direction over the Joint Artificial Intelligence Center; (2) develop a training and certification program on software development, data science, and artificial intelligence that is tailored to the needs of the covered human resources workforce (i.e., the human resources professionals, hiring managers, and recruiters who are or will be responsible for hiring software developers, data scientists, or artificial intelligence professionals); (3) issue guidance to the secretaries of the military departments and the heads of the defense components on improved use of the direct hiring processes for artificial intelligence professionals and other data science and software development personnel; and (4) modify the Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery test to add a new subtest addressing computational thinking skills relevant to military applications.</summary>
</bill>
