<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>5293</number>
    <updateDate>2023-08-28T18:00:26Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-08-28T18:00:26Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2022-12-19</introducedDate>
    <congress>117</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
        <name>Finance Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2022-12-19T23:02:46Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2021</title>
        <congress>117</congress>
        <number>4510</number>
        <type>HR</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2021-07-20</actionDate>
          <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-12-19</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssfi00</systemCode>
            <name>Finance Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2022-12-19</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>P000145</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Padilla, Alex [D-CA]</fullName>
        <firstName>Alex</firstName>
        <lastName>Padilla</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>CA</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Health</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects/>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Health</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2022-12-19</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2023-08-28T17:57:42Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2022</b></p> <p>This bill provides for the designation of Health Enterprise Zones in certain geographic areas with documented and measurable health disparities. This designation, which expires 10 years after the date on which the first zone is designated, confers eligibility for certain grants, Medicare incentive payments, student loan repayment programs, and tax credits for those working to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in these zones. </p> <p>Specifically, community-based nonprofits or local government agencies, in coalition with health care providers, social service organizations, and others, may apply to the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) for the designation. The application must include a plan to reduce health disparities and achieve other outcomes.</p> <p>In implementing the program, HHS must consult with, among others, the Department of Housing and Urban Development. When approving applications, HHS shall consider factors including geographic diversity and the commitment of supporting funds from the private sector. HHS (1) may award grants to organizations or agencies that applied for the designation to support activities aligned with their plans, and (2) must carry out a student loan repayment program for health care providers who agree to provide services in a Health Enterprise Zone. </p> <p>In addition, the bill establishes tax credits for employers that hire, and individuals who work as, Health Enterprise Zone workers.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2022</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2022</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Title(s) as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Health Enterprise Zones Act of 2022</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to provide for the designation of areas as Health Enterprise Zones to reduce health disparities and improve health outcomes in such areas, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2022-12-19T05:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-117s5293is/xml/BILLS-117s5293is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2022-12-19</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
