<bill session="111" type="s" number="1777" updated="2023-01-11T13:17:44Z">
  <state datetime="2009-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Hardrock Mines Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate the remediation of abandoned hardrock mines, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Hardrock Mines Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000038"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001267" joined="2009-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000584" joined="2009-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10367-10368"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S10368-10372" label="text of measure introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3203" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Mining"/>
    <term name="Pollution liability"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-02-26T22:52:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Good Samaritan Cleanup of Abandoned Hardrock Mines Act of 2009 - Sets forth provisions to encourage the partial or complete remediation of inactive and abandoned mine sites for the public good by good samaritans (defined as individuals or entities who had no role in the creation of the historic mine residue or any resulting environmental pollution and are not legally responsible for the remediation of the historic mine residue). Defines "inactive or abandoned mine site" as a mine site located in the United States that is no longer actively mined and that was used for the production of a mineral other than coal and has historic mine residue.

Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (commonly known as the Clean Water Act) to authorize a permitting authority (i.e., the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency [EPA] or a state or Indian tribe with an approved good samaritan program) to issue good samaritan discharge permits. Sets forth requirements for the issuance of such permits, including the applicant's submission of a detailed remediation plan and a determination by a permitting authority that such plan preserves water quality. Grants a release from liability under such Act to good samaritans who comply with a discharge permit approved under the terms of this Act.

Terminates the authority to issue good samaritan discharge permits ten years after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
