<bill session="118" type="s" number="754" updated="2025-11-18T21:08:01Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Improving Mental Health and Wellness in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Improving Mental Health and Wellness in Schools Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to modify requirements for local school wellness policies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000367"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2023-05-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2023-03-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3331" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-08T19:25:44Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Improving Mental Health and Wellness in Schools Act

This bill incorporates mental health promotion and education into guidelines for school wellness policies that are used by local educational agencies participating in school meal programs.

Specifically, the Department of Agriculture (USDA) must issue further regulations for local educational agencies to (1) incorporate goals for mental health promotion and education, and (2) include reducing eating disorders as part of the nutrition guidelines for foods available on school campuses.

The bill also requires that local educational agencies establish multidisciplinary teams of school personnel to lead the development, periodic review, and updating of local school wellness policies. Further, the bill requires the involvement of registered dietitians and school-based mental health services providers (in addition to those already required to be involved) in the periodic review and updating of the local policy.

 USDA must also provide technical assistance to promote mental health, encourage mental health assessments, and establish resilient school environments.</summary>
</bill>
