<bill session="116" type="s" number="3042" updated="2022-10-28T01:45:57Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Small Passenger Vessel Safety Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Passenger Vessel Safety Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 46, United States Code, to require the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to prescribe additional regulations to secure the safety of individuals and property on board certain small passenger vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7029-7030" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="5413" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Emergency planning and evacuation"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Marine and inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-04-07T12:05:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Small Passenger Vessel Safety Act of 2019

This bill applies U.S. Coast Guard regulations regarding safety management systems to small passenger vessels and requires the Coast Guard to prescribe additional regulations to secure the safety of individuals and property on board certain small passenger vessels.

The regulations prescribed must include requirements for

 the addition of interconnected fire detection, protection, and suppression equipment, including fire extinguishers, in all areas to which passengers have access, including dining areas, sleeping quarters, and lounges; fire detection, protection, and suppression systems in unmanned areas with machinery or areas with other potential heat sources; fire detection, suppression, and control in all areas to which passengers have access, including dining areas, sleeping quarters, and lounges; all such vessels to have not less than two avenues of escape from all general areas accessible to passengers; marine firefighting training programs to improve crew member training and proficiency; and the handling, storage, and operation of flammable items, such as lithium ion batteries.</summary>
</bill>
