<bill session="118" type="h" number="4462" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:12Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Election Security Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Security Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Director of National Intelligence to submit a joint report on foreign threats to elections in the United States and to establish procedures to test for and monitor cybersecurity vulnerabilities in certain equipment used in the administration of elections for Federal office, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committees on Homeland Security, and Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-03">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHM08" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Protection" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="4563" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Subversive activities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-06-20T14:32:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Election Security Assistance Act

This bill addresses security threats to federal elections.

Specifically, the bill requires the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to jointly report on foreign threats to elections in the United States, including physical and cybersecurity threats. This annual report must be submitted to Congress and chief state election officials.

Additionally, the bill requires the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency and the Election Assistance Commission (EAC) to jointly establish a voluntary process to test for and monitor covered voting systems for cybersecurity vulnerabilities. The EAC must also establish a process to provide for the deployment of appropriate labeling available through the EAC's website to indicate that covered voting systems passed the most recent cybersecurity testing.

The bill requires federal entities to share information with DHS regarding election cybersecurity incidents.

The bill also requires DHS to share information with state and local officials regarding election cybersecurity incidents. &#160;&#160;</summary>
</bill>
