<bill session="118" type="h" number="4309" updated="2025-11-19T04:52:16Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ASPIRE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assisting Seekers in Pursuit of Integration and Rapid Employment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to reduce the waiting period for employment authorization for asylum applicants, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000486"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000599" joined="2023-08-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Financial Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1325" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2175" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-05T20:36:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Assisting Seekers in Pursuit of Integration and Rapid Employment Act or the ASPIRE Act 

This bill addresses issues related to asylum applicants and migrants, including by directing the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to provide employment authorization for eligible asylum applicants. Currently, asylum applicants are not entitled to employment authorization but may be granted such by the Department of Justice.

Such employment authorization is valid until the applicant receives a final denial of the application, including any administrative and judicial review. The bill also shortens the waiting period for receiving employment authorization to 30 days from the filing of the asylum application.

In addition, the bill authorizes U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services to take actions to address the asylum backlog, including by hiring additional asylum officers. The bill also authorizes DHS to provide funding to state and local governments and nonprofit organizations for support services for migrants (e.g., food and shelter).</summary>
</bill>
