<bill session="117" type="h" number="163" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:41Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protect Patriot Spouses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To render certain military spouses eligible for adjustment of status, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protect Patriot Spouses Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001200"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000299" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000574" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000587" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2021-02-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Marriage and family status"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="National Guard and reserves"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-15T14:37:23Z" status="Introduced in House">Protect Patriot Spouses Act

This bill makes certain alien military spouses eligible for adjustment to permanent residence status.

An eligible alien shall be an individual who is or was a spouse of a U.S. citizen who serves or served in the Armed Forces, either on active duty or in a reserve component. If the U.S. citizen has been discharged from the Armed Forces, such discharge must be under honorable conditions.

Certain factors that would otherwise make an alien inadmissible, such as having entered the United States without being admitted, shall not make such an alien spouse inadmissible or ineligible for permanent residence status under the bill. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) may also waive certain factors that would otherwise make an alien inadmissible, such as having misrepresented a material fact to secure a visa, if the alien does not pose a threat to the public and has not committed any crimes that are unrelated to immigration status.

The bill also requires DHS and the Department of State to allow a qualifying alien spouse to (1) apply for an immigrant visa to enter the United States under this bill; and (2) enter and stay in the United States to reunite with their U.S. citizen spouse while the application is pending, if the alien spouse does not pose a threat to the public or national security.</summary>
</bill>
