<bill session="118" type="hr" number="1023" updated="2024-07-24T15:19:11Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ride-Along Resolution</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ride-Along Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Requiring Members of the House of Representatives to serve one shift in a passenger seat of a law enforcement vehicle observing the work day of a local law enforcement officer once during each term as a Member of the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001119"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-20">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-03-02T02:34:33Z" status="Introduced in House">Ride-Along Resolution

This resolution requires each Member of the House of Representatives to participate in one shift in a passenger seat of a law enforcement vehicle observing the work day of a local law enforcement officer in the congressional district of the Member once during each term as a Member.

The Committee on House Administration must promulgate regulations to carry out this resolution.

If the Committee on Ethics determines that a Member has not satisfied the requirement to participate in such a ride-along by the deadline, the committee must

 publish the name of the Member on a readily available, public list on the committee's website; and cause to be published in the Congressional Record information with respect to the failure of the Member to satisfy such requirement.</summary>
</bill>
