<bill session="117" type="h" number="7845" updated="2023-07-14T12:45:30Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NIH Clinical Trial Diversity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NIH Clinical Trial Diversity Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the National Institutes of Health, to take certain steps to increase clinical trial diversity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000385"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001251" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001067" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001097" joined="2022-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2022-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="4486" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-08-23T20:58:06Z" status="Introduced in House">NIH Clinical Trial Diversity Act of 2022

This bill sets out requirements to increase the diversity of clinical trial participants. The bill also requires other activities to foster participation in clinical trials.

As a condition of funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH) for a clinical trial investigating a drug or device, a sponsor's application must include certain information related to diversity in its trial, such as

 goals for recruiting and retaining trial participants, plans for achieving the recruitment and retention goals and implementing less-burdensome clinical trial follow-up requirements, and education and training requirements related to diversity in clinical trials for researchers and other individuals who conduct or support the trial. A sponsor must also annually share demographic data of clinical trial participants with the NIH. The NIH must publish on its website information about the diversity of and other information concerning the clinical trials it funds.

If a sponsor fails to meet its goals or other requirements with respect to trial diversity, the sponsor must develop and implement a strategic plan to increase the diversity of the clinical trial participants.

Further, the NIH and the Food and Drug Administration must carry out a national campaign to increase awareness about the need for diverse clinical trials.

The bill also requires studies on barriers to participation in clinical trials. The Government Accountability Office must study actions taken by federal agencies to address such barriers while the NIH must study regulations that govern reimbursements of out-of-pocket expenses of and incentives for clinical trial participants.</summary>
</bill>
