<bill session="118" type="s" number="2182" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Wild USA Seafood Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Wild USA Seafood Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to establish a label designating fish harvested in the United States exclusive economic zone or navigable waters as wild USA seafood, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001153"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001198" joined="2023-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2208" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2354" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-13T14:26:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Wild USA Seafood Act of 2023

This bill establishes requirements for labeling fish as wild USA seafood or wild American seafood. The bill defines fish as finfish, mollusks, crustaceans, and all other forms of aquatic animal and plant life other than aquatic mammals and birds.

Specifically, a retailer of fish (or a person engaged in the business of supplying fish to a retailer) may label fish as wild USA seafood, wild American seafood, or any equivalent designation if the fish is

naturally born in the wild or hatchery-originated fish released in the wild;caught, taken, or harvested from within U.S. waters; andcaught, taken, or harvested by a vessel of the United States.If the Department of Agriculture (USDA) determines that a retailer is in violation of these labeling requirements, USDA must notify the retailer. The retailer has 30 days to comply with the labeling requirements. After 30 days, USDA may fine the retailer for an unfair or deceptive act or practice if the retailer (1) has not made a good faith effort to comply with the labeling requirements, and (2) continues to willfully violate the requirements.</summary>
</bill>
