<bill session="118" type="h" number="1616" updated="2025-11-19T04:55:36Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CARE for Long COVID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE for Long COVID Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Access to Resources and Education for Long COVID Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To address research on, and improve access to, supportive services for individuals with Long COVID.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001292"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001301" joined="2023-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="801" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Disability assistance"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and legal services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medical tests and diagnostic methods"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-06-28T14:40:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Comprehensive Access to Resources and Education for Long COVID Act or the CARE for Long COVID Act

This bill requires research, education, and other activities to support individuals who have Long COVID or related conditions that may result directly, or indirectly, from COVID-19 infection.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must support a voluntary patient registry to collect information about individuals with Long COVID and related conditions, such as their symptoms, treatments, and demographic characteristics. HHS must coordinate with the Patient-Centered Outcomes Research Institute on the registry.

HHS must also conduct or support research along with other agencies on how the U.S. health care system responds to Long COVID and related conditions. This includes research on the effectiveness of treatments and strategies to mitigate disparities in health outcomes.

In addition, HHS must (1) educate the public and health care providers about treatments for, conditions associated with, and other aspects of Long COVID and related conditions; and (2) disseminate information and resources on how Long COVID affects rights associated with employment, disability status, and education.

Last, the Administration for Community Living must award grants to or enter contracts with states, health care providers, legal services providers, and other eligible entities for expanding access to legal assistance for individuals with Long COVID and related conditions, including assistance with obtaining Social Security and other benefits and accessing medical care and services.</summary>
</bill>
