<bill session="111" type="h" number="2722" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:53Z">
  <state datetime="2009-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to modify and update provisions of law relating to nonprofit research and education corporations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000116"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001203" joined="2009-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR03" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="s" number="252" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="2770" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance and management"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Social work, volunteer service, charitable organizations"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-09-09T14:52:43Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Nonprofit Research and Education Corporations Enhancement Act of 2009 - Amends federal provisions concerning the establishment at Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) medical facilities of nonprofit research and education corporations (NRECs) to allow an NREC to facilitate the conduct of research or education, or both, at more than one VA medical center. States that such an NREC shall be known as a multi-medical center research corporation (MCRC).

Allows an NREC to act as a MCRC if: (1) the NREC board of directors approve a resolution permitting that NREC to act as a MCRC; and (2) the Secretary of Veterans Affairs approves the resolution.

Requires each NREC and MCRC (corporation) to be established in accordance with the nonprofit corporation laws of the state in which the VA medical center which it supports is located. States that neither such corporation shall be considered to be owned by, or an agent or instrumentality of, the United States.

Restates the purposes of the corporations.

Modifies the composition of, and standards applicable to, corporation boards of directors, including by changing applicable conflict of interest requirements.

Expands the required areas of experience or expertise with respect to non-VA members of corporation boards of directors.

Increases authorized corporate powers of the corporations to include entering into contracts and setting fees for education and training facilitated through a corporation.

Revises audit requirements to require submission of an Internal Revenue Service return form applicable to organizations exempt from income tax.</summary>
</bill>
