<bill session="118" type="s" number="2532" updated="2025-01-14T17:07:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to submit an annual report on certain out-of-cycle or premature personnel transfers.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to submit an annual report on certain out-of-cycle or premature personnel transfers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000062"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-09-11T10:44:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the Department of Defense (DOD) to report on the number and nature of out-of-cycle or premature personnel transfers carried out during the preceding fiscal year for specified individuals as a result of such individuals or their dependents being affected by certain issues.

Specifically, the report must focus on members of the Armed Forces on active duty, members of the Armed Forces in a reserve component, members of the National Guard, and civilian employees of DOD or dependents of the listed individuals who are being affected by (1) sexual assault or sexual harassment; (2) humanitarian or compassionate requests; (3) discrimination, harassment, bullying, reprisals, or threats based on the race, color, national origin, religion, sex (including gender identity) or sexual orientation of such individuals or dependents; (4) medical issues, including lack of access to care; or (6) child custody agreements.

Each report must be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex to protect sensitive information. Additionally,&#160;the reports must exclude personally identifiable information.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
