<bill session="108" type="s" number="2460" updated="2023-01-15T04:49:08Z">
  <state datetime="2004-09-15">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance to the State of New Mexico for the development of comprehensive State water plans, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000407"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2004-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5961"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S5961" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 108-668.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported by Senator Domenici under authority of the order of the Senate of 07/22/04 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 108-326.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="682">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 682.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2004-09-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9353-9354" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S9353-9354" label="text as passed Senate"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17T10:04:22-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-17">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-20">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII13" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water, Wildlife, and Fisheries" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hydrology"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Photography"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Natural Resources"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-11-10T19:01:14Z" status="Passed Senate amended">(This measure has not been amended since it was reported to the Senate on August 25, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

 New Mexico Water Planning Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, at the request of the Governor of New Mexico and acting through the Bureau of Reclamation and the U.S. Geological Survey, to: (1) provide to New Mexico technical assistance and grants for the development of comprehensive State water plans; (2) conduct water resources mapping in New Mexico; and (3) conduct a comprehensive study of groundwater resources in New Mexico to assess the quantity, quality, and interaction of groundwater and surface water resources. Lists types of technical assistance that may be provided, including acquisition of hydrologic data, expansion of groundwater monitoring networks, and coordination of Federal water management planning efforts.

Directs the Secretary to allocate specified funds: (1) to develop hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the New Mexico Rio Grande main stem sections and Rio Pueblo de Taos and Hondo, Rios Nambe, Pojoaque and Teseque, Rio Chama, and Lower Rio Grande tributaries; (2) to complete the hydrographic survey development of hydrologic models and acquire associated equipment for the San Juan River and tributaries and for Southwest New Mexico, including the Animas Basin, the Gila River, and tributaries; and (3) for statewide digital orthophotography mapping.

Sets the non-Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out using a grant under this Act at 50 percent, which may be in the form of in-kind services as determined by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 108-326</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
