<bill session="116" type="s" number="3826" updated="2023-01-11T13:42:37Z">
  <state datetime="2020-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">TRICARE Coverage for Doula Support Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">TRICARE Coverage for Doula Support Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to provide additional resources, including doula support, for pregnant beneficiaries under the TRICARE program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2020-05-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-05-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Military personnel and dependents"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-04T12:19:59Z" status="Introduced in Senate">TRICARE Coverage for Doula Support Act

This bill directs the Department of Defense (DOD), in providing maternity care for pregnant members and certain former members of the Armed Forces and their dependents under the TRICARE program, to provide to such beneficiaries additional resources for prenatal and postnatal communication and education, including doula support. DOD shall conduct a specified survey on members or spouses of such members of the Armed Forces who give birth.

The term doula means an individual who is trained to provide non-medical advice, information, emotional support, and physical comfort to an individual during the individual's pregnancy, childbirth, and postpartum period by an organization that has been established for not less than five years and that requires the completion of continuing education.</summary>
</bill>
