<bill session="117" type="s" number="2027" updated="2022-12-31T05:28:19Z">
  <state datetime="2021-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the expansion, intensification, and coordination of the programs and activities of the National Institutes of Health with respect to Tourette syndrome.</title>
    <title type="display">CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000639"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001169" joined="2021-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2021-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="3679" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Neurological disorders"/>
    <term name="Research administration and funding"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-13T18:52:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Collaborative Academic Research Efforts for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2021 or the CARE for Tourette Syndrome Act of 2021

This bill requires the National Institutes of Health (NIH) to carry out data collection and expand other research activities on Tourette syndrome. This is a neurological disorder characterized by sudden, repetitive, rapid, and unwanted movements or vocal sounds.

Specifically, the NIH must develop a system to collect epidemiological data and information on the availability of medical and social services for individuals with Tourette syndrome and their families.

In addition, the NIH must award various grants for research on Tourette syndrome, including to support Collaborative Research Centers for Tourette Syndrome.

The NIH must also designate a portion of its funding for Tourette syndrome programs and activities.</summary>
</bill>
