<bill session="108" type="h" number="3392" updated="2023-01-15T07:47:45Z">
  <state datetime="2003-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Veterans Claims Procedures Improvement Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the procedures for adjudication of claims for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Claims Procedures Improvement Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2003-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-13">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Benefits.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR06" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Benefits" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Department of Veterans Affairs"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-01-29T21:23:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Veterans Claims Procedures Improvement Act of 2003 - Prohibits payment or furnishing of veterans' benefits, if the Secretary of Veterans Affairs notifies a benefit claimant that certain information is necessary to complete the claimant's application and such information is not received by the Secretary within one year after such notification.

Requires written notification to a claimant by the Secretary of additional information or evidence needed to complete a claim application. (Current law requires notification, but does not specify that the notification must be written.) Requires the claimant to submit to the Secretary such additional information or evidence within the time period specified by the Secretary, which period shall end not less than 60 days after the date of such notification or one year from the date of application, whichever is later. Allows the Secretary to: (1) extend the time limits for good cause; and (2) decide a claim before the end of such limits.

Revises appellate review procedures applicable to filing a notice of disagreement with the Board of Veterans Appeals to require a claimant to be notified in writing to provide clarification on whether or not appellate review is desired or what issue or issues are being appealed.</summary>
</bill>
