<bill session="118" type="s" number="370" updated="2025-07-21T19:32:26Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting America From Spies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting America From Spies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 212 of the Immigration and Nationality Act to ensure that efforts to engage in espionage or technology transfer are considered in visa issuance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001098"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001319" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001305" joined="2023-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001096" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000393" joined="2023-02-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001190" joined="2023-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001227" joined="2023-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000278" joined="2023-02-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7476" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-24T22:44:22Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Protecting America From Spies Act

This bill expands the grounds for barring non-U.S. nationals (aliens under federal law) who have engaged in acts of espionage or sabotage from entering the United States.

Specifically, any individual shall be inadmissible if the individual has engaged in or will engage in an act that (1) violates a U.S. law relating to espionage or sabotage; (2) would violate any U.S. law relating to espionage or sabotage if it occurred in the United States; or (3) violates any U.S. law prohibiting the export of goods, technology, or sensitive information. Currently, an individual is inadmissible if the individual seeks to enter the United States to engage in such an action.

Furthermore, the bill expands these grounds of inadmissibility and other security-related grounds to cover the spouse or child of the barred individual if the act occurred in the last five years.

The bill also modifies the authority of the Department of Justice to waive certain security-related grounds of inadmissibility for an individual applying for a nonimmigrant visa.</summary>
</bill>
