<bill session="118" type="s" number="2739" updated="2025-11-18T17:52:06Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Mathematical and Statistical Modeling Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mathematical and Statistical Modeling Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to coordinate Federal research and development efforts focused on modernizing mathematics in STEM education through mathematical and statistical modeling, including data-driven and computational thinking, problem, project, and performance-based learning and assessment, interdisciplinary exploration, and career connections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2023-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1735" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-05T13:32:37Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Mathematical and Statistical Modeling Education Act

 This bill requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to take certain actions to increase mathematical and statistical modeling education in public elementary and secondary schools.

First, the NSF must provide competitive grants to institutions of higher education and nonprofit organizations for research and development to support high-quality mathematical modeling education (e.g., data science and computational thinking) in schools.

In addition, the NSF must seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to study and report on mathematical and statistical modeling education in schools.</summary>
</bill>
