<bill session="108" type="s" number="1078" updated="2023-01-15T15:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2003-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stable Transition in Education for Armed Services' Dependent Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for military charters between military installations and local school districts, to provide credit enhancement initiatives to promote military charter school facility acquisition, construction, and renovation, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stable Transition in Education for Armed Services' Dependent Youth Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000550"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
      <reference ref=" CR S6628-6631" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Charter schools"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="School buildings"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Stable Transitions in Education for Armed Services' Dependent Youth Act - Directs the Secretary of Defense to establish a five-year demonstration program for competitive matching grants to eligible State educational agencies (SEAs) for subgrants to eligible local educational agencies (LEAs) to establish and maintain high quality military charter schools as independent public elementary or secondary schools in areas of greatest need. Requires the commander of each military installation served by such a school to establish a nonprofit corporation or an oversight group to provide the applicable LEA with oversight and guidance regarding the day-to-day operations of the school.Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to direct the Secretary of Education to award at least four grants in each fiscal year to establish or improve innovative credit enhancement initiatives that assist military charter schools in acquiring, constructing, and renovating facilities. Requires such grants to be made to eligible entities, which may be a public entity such as a military installation, a private nonprofit entity, or a consortium of those two types of entities.Includes among requirements for military charter schools: (1) an admissions policy providing for at least 60 percent and at most 80 percent military dependent students, except where such percentages are impossible to maintain because of the demographics of the area around the military installation; (2) an intensive high-quality program including practices relating to the academic-passport concept to ease transitions for mobile students; and (3) a curriculum aligned with State student performance standards which may incorporate a curriculum from the Department of Defense Education Activity.</summary>
</bill>
