<bill session="117" type="h" number="5655" updated="2023-03-08T19:58:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to require providers of a covered service to provide location information concerning the telecommunications device of a user of such service to an investigative or law enforcement officer or an employee or other agent of a public safety answering point in an emergency situation involving risk of death or serious physical harm or in order to respond to the user's call for emergency services.</title>
    <title type="display">Kelsey Smith Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kelsey Smith Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000740" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000629" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000298" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000295" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000871" joined="2021-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2021-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000601" joined="2021-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-21">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Communications and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="466" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-25T18:14:56Z" status="Introduced in House">Kelsey Smith Act

This bill requires a mobile or internet voice service provider to disclose the location information of a device pursuant to certain requests.

Specifically, a provider must disclose this information at the request of an investigative or law enforcement officer (or public safety employee or agent on behalf of such officer) if the officer asserts (1) that the device was used to place a 911 call, or (2) reasonable suspicion that the device is in the possession of an individual who is in an emergency situation.

 A provider that discloses a device location in response to such a request may not be held liable in legal or administrative proceedings related to the disclosure.</summary>
</bill>
