<bill session="117" type="s" number="1622" updated="2023-01-11T13:50:14Z">
  <state datetime="2021-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALTH for MOM Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with the option to provide coordinated care through a pregnancy medical home for high-risk pregnant women, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Harnessing Effective and Appropriate Long-Term Health for Moms On Medicaid Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALTH for MOM Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000449"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2021-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5015" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Foreign language and bilingual programs"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Home and outpatient care"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Sex and reproductive health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-10-19T14:41:58Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Harnessing Effective and Appropriate Long-Term Health for Moms On Medicaid Act of 2021 or the HEALTH for MOM Act of 2021

This bill allows state Medicaid programs to cover services that are provided by maternity health homes (designated providers or health teams that provide pregnancy and postpartum coordinated care services).

Participating maternity health homes must meet standards set by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (CMS), including the ability to coordinate prompt access to services, develop individualized care plans, provide supportive services, and coordinate with pediatric care providers. States must conduct outreach to providers, pregnant women, and other relevant stakeholders on the availability of such health homes and must report specified information relating to the implementation and outcomes of such services.

The CMS must award grants to states to develop plans for implementation. The bill also temporarily increases the Federal Medical Assistance Percentage (i.e., federal matching rate) for maternity health home services.</summary>
</bill>
