<bill session="110" type="hr" number="839" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-04">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000800"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04">
      <text>The House Committee on Rules reported an original measure, H. Rept. 110-471, by Mr. Welch (VT).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-04T21:37:28-05:00">
      <text>Waiving a requirement of clause 6(a) of rule XIII with respect to consideration of certain resolutions reported from the Committee on Rules. The rule applies the waiver to any resolutions reported on the legislative day of Wednesday, December 5, 2007, providing for consideration of the Senate amendments to the bill (H.R. 6) to reduce our Nation's dependency on foreign oil by investing in clean, renewable, and alternative energy resources, promoting new emerging energy technologies, developing greater efficiency, and creating a Strategic Energy Efficiency and Renewables</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2007-12-04" calendar="House" number="161">
      <text>Placed on the House Calendar, Calendar No. 161.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2007-12-13T11:10:00-05:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 869, H. Res. 839 is laid on the table.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="6" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="hr" number="869" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-14T20:25:12Z" status="Reported to House without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Waives a specified requirement of Rule XIII (Calendar and Committee Reports) to allow consideration of the Senate amendment to H.R. 6 (Renewable Fuels, Consumer Protection, and Energy Efficiency Act of 2007) on the same day it is presented to the House.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 110-471</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
