<bill session="111" type="s" number="1568" updated="2023-01-11T13:18:10Z">
  <state datetime="2009-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">National Museum of Industrial History Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist in the establishment of an interpretive center and museum in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, to protect and interpret the history of the industrialization of the United States.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Museum of Industrial History Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2009-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8687-8688"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Museums, exhibitions, cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-12-10T21:57:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">National Museum of Industrial History Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to offer to enter into an agreement with an appropriate entity under which to provide federal assistance for the development and operation of an interpretive center and museum on the former Bethlehem Steel Plant Site in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania, to preserve, display, and interpret historical resources relating to industrialization in the United States and to promote other historical and cultural resources in the region through activities conducted at the interpretive center and museum.

Sets forth covered and prohibited uses of such financial assistance, including prohibiting the use of assistance for the acquisition of any item for the museum's collection.

Provides for a non-federal match from each party to an agreement.

 Requires the Secretary to submit annual reports to Congress that describe: (1) the current status of the development of the interpretive center and museum; (2) each project and activity funded; and (3) the unexpended balance, if any, of amounts made available to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
