<bill session="116" type="h" number="6198" updated="2022-02-08T23:25:49Z">
  <state datetime="2020-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Emergency Paid Leave Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide emergency paid leave benefits to certain individuals affected by COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Paid Leave Act of 2020</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001202"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001122" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000583" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001083" joined="2020-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000386" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000602" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001157" joined="2020-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000484" joined="2020-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="6201" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee leave"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-03-24T18:12:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Emergency Paid Leave Act of 2020 This bill requires the Social Security Administration (SSA) to provide emergency paid leave during each 30-day period that specified employees take leave due to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019). Specifically, an employee may apply to SSA for such leave payments if the employee

 has been diagnosed with COVID-19, is under self-quarantine at the direction of a governmental entity or health care provider, is caring for another individual who is under such self-quarantine, or is caring for that employee's child because the child's school or child-care provider is closed due to COVID-19. For each 30-day period, the SSA must pay two-thirds of an eligible employee's average monthly pay to a maximum of $4,000. Emergency paid leave benefits are available for up to 90 days from the period during which an employee first files an application for such leave. Available benefits for emergency paid leave are reduced proportionally by any amount of paid leave an employee receives from a state or employer during each 30-day period.

 Further, emergency paid leave benefits are available retroactively from January 19, 2020, until one year from the date of enactment of this bill. The bill also establishes penalties for fraudulent applications and provides for the review of the SSA&#8217;s application determinations.</summary>
</bill>
