<bill session="118" type="h" number="2561" updated="2024-07-24T15:22:50Z">
  <state datetime="2023-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Peer-Reviewed Report on Measuring Metrics and Thresholds</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Peer-Reviewed Report on Measuring Metrics and Thresholds</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Transportation to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to produce a report that identifies and recommends a system of measuring aviation noise, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001196" joined="2023-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2023-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-11">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-06T18:10:45Z" status="Introduced in House">Peer-Reviewed Report on Measuring Metrics and Thresholds

This bill requires the Department of Transportation to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to produce a report that identifies and recommends a system of measuring aviation noise.

This measurement system must, with a highly reliable relationship, categorize noise levels to determine compatibility for residential areas and high annoyance areas based on appropriate metrics. In addition, it must (1) have a highly reliable relationship between projected noise exposure and surveyed reactions of individuals, and (2) be applied uniformly in measuring noise at airports and the surrounding area.</summary>
</bill>
