<bill session="117" type="h" number="4659" updated="2022-12-31T05:05:26Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require providers of broadband internet access service and edge services to clearly and conspicuously notify users of the privacy policies of those providers, to give users opt-in or opt-out approval rights with respect to the use of, disclosure of, and access to user information collected by those providers based on the level of sensitivity of the information, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">BROWSER Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Balancing the Rights Of Web Surfers Equally and Responsibly Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BROWSER Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001136"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001291" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001104" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000086" joined="2021-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001214" joined="2021-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="113" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-07T16:48:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Balancing the Rights Of Web Surfers Equally and Responsibly Act of 2021 or the BROWSER Act of 2021

This bill establishes information privacy protections that require broadband internet access services and certain websites or mobile applications to provide users with the ability to opt-in or opt-out of the using, disclosing, or accessing of their user information depending on the sensitivity of the information.

Covered service providers must provide opt-in approval through express user consent to use sensitive information such as financial data, health information, browsing history, or other specified personally identifiable information. Such service providers must obtain opt-out approval for the use of non-sensitive user information by a user failing to object to such use after being provided notice of the provider's privacy policies. Service providers also must allow users to opt-in or opt-out of such approval at any time.

The bill permits service providers to use and disclose user information without approval for specified purposes, including for services necessary for provision of the service and to initiate, render, bill, and collect for the service.

The bill further prohibits providers from conditioning access to service on users' agreeing to waive their privacy rights.</summary>
</bill>
