<bill session="118" type="h" number="3408" updated="2025-11-18T11:18:14Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">DRIVE Safe Integrity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developing Responsible Individuals for a Vibrant Economy Safe Integrity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">DRIVE Safe Integrity Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish an apprenticeship program for commercial drivers under the age of 21, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2023-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000470" joined="2024-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000592" joined="2023-11-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000809" joined="2024-01-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Highways and Transit Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Discharged, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-01-30T18:01:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Developing Responsible Individuals for a Vibrant Economy Safe Integrity Act of 2023 or the DRIVE Safe Integrity Act of 2023

This bill directs the Department of Transportation (DOT) to promulgate regulations to implement an apprenticeship program for licensed commercial motor vehicle drivers under the age of 21. (The bill expands on the Safe Driver Apprenticeship Pilot Program, which allows certain 18-, 19-, and 20-year-old drivers to operate commercial vehicles in interstate commerce if certain training and safety requirements are met.)

Under the program, an apprentice must complete two probationary periods that total 400 hours of on-duty time, of which at least 240 hours must be driving time in a commercial motor vehicle. Additionally, the apprentice must be accompanied in the cab of the commercial motor vehicle by an experienced driver.

Further, the bill requires all commercial motor vehicles used in the program for training to be equipped with safety technology such as active braking collision mitigation systems and video event capturing systems.

An employer shall not knowingly allow, require, permit, or authorize a driver under the age of 21 to operate a commercial motor vehicle unless the driver is participating in, or has completed, an apprenticeship program that meets the requirements set forth in this bill.

DOT must report quarterly on the status of the program.</summary>
</bill>
