<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1202</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T19:40:50Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T19:40:50Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2007-04-24</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
        <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2007-04-24T22:49:36Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-04-24</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssju00</systemCode>
            <name>Judiciary Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-04-24</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>S001141</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Sessions, Jeff [R-AL]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jeff</firstName>
        <lastName>Sessions</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AL</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>K000352</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Kyl, Jon [R-AZ]</fullName>
        <firstName>Jon</firstName>
        <lastName>Kyl</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>AZ</state>
        <middleName>Llewellyn</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2007-05-01</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>False</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Bank accounts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Commerce</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer education</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Credit cards</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Data banks</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Debit cards</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Driver licenses</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fraud</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Identification devices</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Identity theft</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Law</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Parties to actions</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Right of privacy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social Welfare</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Social security numbers</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Transportation and Public Works</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Crime and Law Enforcement</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-04-24</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-06-06T14:13:18Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Personal Data Protection Act of 2007 - Defines &quot;identity theft&quot; to mean a fraud committed using the sensitive personal information of another individual with the intent to commit or to aid or abet unlawful activity that results in economic loss to that individual.</p><p>Requires any agency or person that owns or licenses computerized data containing sensitive personal information to: (1) develop, implement, and maintain reasonable security and notification procedures and practices (appropriate to the size and nature of the agency or person and the nature of the information) to ensure the security and confidentiality of the personal information and to protect sensitive personal information against unauthorized access, destruction, use, modification, or disclosure; and (2) notify any individual whose sensitive personal information was compromised (permits a federal law enforcement agency of domestic or foreign jurisdiction to delay notification if notification would impede a criminal or civil investigation).</p><p>Requires any agency or person in possession of computerized data containing sensitive personal information that it does not own or license to notify and cooperate with the owner or licensor upon discovery of a breach of the security of the system of such agency or person as expediently as possible. Authorizes an agency or person in possession of sensitive personal information to enter into an agreement with the owner or licensor of information regarding which person or entity will provide any notice required to an individual whose sensitive personal information was compromised. Requires the agency or person that owns or licenses computerized data containing sensitive personal information to provide any notice required if there is not such an agreement. Sets forth provisions regarding the timeliness of notification, the methods and contents of notice, and the duty to coordinate with consumer reporting agencies.</p><p>Establishes civil remedies for failure to provide notice of a security breach. Authorizes enforcement by state Attorneys General on behalf of residents of the state.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Personal Data Protection Act of 2007</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to require agencies and persons in possession of computerized data containing sensitive personal information, to disclose security breaches where such breach poses a significant risk of identity theft.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Personal Data Protection Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Personal Data Protection Act of 2007</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2007-04-24T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s1202is/xml/BILLS-110s1202is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2007-04-24</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
