<bill session="118" type="s" number="1788" updated="2025-01-14T17:12:38Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to update the Post-delisting Monitoring Plan for the Western Great Lakes Distinct Population Segment of the Gray Wolf, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to update the Post-delisting Monitoring Plan for the Western Great Lakes Distinct Population Segment of the Gray Wolf, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-06-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-28T20:19:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill requires the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (FWS)&#160;to delist the population of the gray wolf (Canis lupus) within the Northern Great Lakes Region (i.e., Minnesota, Wisconsin, and the Upper Peninsula of Michigan)&#160;under the Endangered Species Act of 1973, thus removing protection for the gray wolf in such region.

In 1978, the FWS published a rule reclassifying the gray wolf as an endangered population throughout the contiguous United States and Mexico, except for the Minnesota gray wolf population, which was classified as threatened.

Within a year of this bill's enactment, the FWS must update its 2008 Post-delisting Monitoring Plan for the Western Great Lakes Distinct Population Segment of the Gray Wolf.

The bill establishes an advisory committee to consult with the FWS on updating the monitoring plan, issuing the delisting rule, and monitoring the wolf population during the 5-year post-delisting monitoring period following the issuance of the rule.</summary>
</bill>
