<bill session="108" type="s" number="2765" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:25Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 to clarify the conditions under which the Secretary should enter into negotiations to correct currency manipulations by other countries.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 to clarify the conditions under which the Secretary should enter into negotiations to correct currency manipulations by other countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000601" joined="2004-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000126" joined="2004-07-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8754" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-08-30T21:07:05Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Amends the Exchange Rates and International Economic Policy Coordination Act of 1988 with respect to the conditions for required actions by the Secretary of the Treasury to initate expedited negotiations for exchange rate adjustments by a foreign country the Secretary considers to be manipulating the rate of exchange between its currency and the U.S. dollar in order to prevent effective balance of payments adjustments or gain unfair competitive advantage in international trade.

Repeals the requirement that such a country have a material global account surplus as well as a significant bilateral trade surplus with the United States. (Thus requires only that it have a significant bilateral trade surplus with the United States; that is, the Secretary is required to take action to initiate exchange rate adjustment negotiations with any country that has a significant bilateral trade surplus with the United States, regardless of its material global account status.)

Requires the Secretary's annual report to specified congressional committees to contain a detailed explanation of the test used to determine if a country is manipulating the rate of exchange between its currency and the dollar for such purposes.</summary>
</bill>
