<bill session="110" type="h" number="4750" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:31Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Tax Relief and Fulfilling Our Obligation to Patriotic Soldiers Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tax Relief and Fulfilling Our Obligation to Patriotic Soldiers Act of 2007</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exclude from gross income any enlistment, accession, reenlistment, retention, or incentive bonus paid to a member of the Armed Forces and to amend title 37, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Defense to continue to pay to a member of the Armed Forces who is retired or separated from the Armed Forces due to a combat-related injury certain bonuses that the member was entitled to before the retirement or separation and would continue to be entitled to if the member was not retired or separated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000210"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-17">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Ways and Means, and in addition to the Committee on Armed Services, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Military Personnel.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS02" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Military Personnel" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="3793" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2400" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Iraq compilation"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Recruiting and enlistment"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-06-01T18:09:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Tax Relief and Fulfilling Our Obligation to Patriotic Soldiers Act of 2007 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income payments made to members of the Armed Forces as enlistment and reenlistment bonuses.

Requires the Secretary of Defense to continue the payment to members of the Armed Forces who are retired or separated for disability due to a combat-related injury of certain bonuses to which such members were entitled immediately before retirement or separation and to which such members would continue to be entitled if they were not retired or separated.</summary>
</bill>
