<bill session="117" type="h" number="7308" updated="2022-12-29T22:18:24Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Justice for Vaccine Victims Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Justice for Vaccine Victims Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to investigate and report on the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000596"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000552" joined="2022-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-31">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-05">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4158"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Allergies"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health facilities and institutions"/>
    <term name="Health information and medical records"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Immunology and vaccination"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-24T21:02:48Z" status="Introduced in House">Justice for Vaccine Victims Act of 2022

This bill terminates the COVID-19 emergency and requires an investigation into adverse events associated with a COVID-19 vaccination. The bill also repeals federal income tax deductions for certain state, local, and foreign taxes paid by an individual.

The Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must terminate the COVID-19 emergency within three months of the bill's enactment. The bill also removes, within three months of that termination, liability protections that apply to the administration or use of certain medical countermeasures (e.g., vaccines) during the public health emergency.

Additionally, the HHS Office of Inspector General must investigate adverse events associated with a COVID-19 vaccine that are reported to the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System. In carrying out the investigation, the office must ask specified questions of (1) each individual (or the individual's survivors) who reported an adverse event, (2) each manufacturer of a COVID-19 vaccine distributed in the United States, and (3) a sample of health care providers. The office must report its findings and recommendations, and the report must include, among other matters, transcripts of all interviews with individuals, manufacturers, and health care providers. The office must also report on the costs of carrying out this investigation.</summary>
</bill>
