<bill session="116" type="s" number="1597" updated="2022-11-01T05:47:41Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Oregon as wilderness, to authorize certain land exchanges in the State of Oregon, and to convey certain Bureau of Land Management land in the State of Oregon to the city of Mitchell, Oregon, and Wheeler County, Oregon, for economic and community development purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001176"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Wilderness and natural areas, wildlife refuges, wild rivers, habitats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-01-13T18:26:51Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Sutton Mountain and Painted Hills Area Preservation and Economic Enhancement Act

This bill designates the Sutton Mountain Wilderness, Pat's Cabin Wilderness, Painted Hills Wilderness, and Dead Dog Wilderness in Oregon as wilderness areas and components of the National Wilderness Preservation System.

The Department of the Interior must provide an owner of private property within the boundary of a wilderness area designated by this bill&#160;adequate access to such property.

The bill prescribes requirements for the Collins, Faulkner, Quant, and Twickenham Livestock LLC land exchanges in Oregon.

The bill directs Interior to convey specified lands managed by the Bureau of Land Management to the city of Mitchell and Wheeler County in Oregon.</summary>
</bill>
