<bill session="117" type="h" number="1768" updated="2023-01-11T13:48:20Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farm to School Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to reauthorize the farm to school program, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm to School Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000610"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001313" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2021-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000449" joined="2021-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2022-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1328" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="8450" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Food assistance and relief"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Indian social and development programs"/>
    <term name="Minority and disadvantaged businesses"/>
    <term name="Nutrition and diet"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-01-31T22:16:55Z" status="Introduced in House">Farm to School Act of 2021

This bill modifies and expands the Department of Agriculture's (USDA's) Farm to School Program. The program currently provides grants and technical assistance to schools, state and local agencies, Indian tribal organizations, agricultural producers, and nonprofit entities to improve access to local foods in schools.

Among other things, the bill

 reauthorizes the program through FY2027; permits USDA to provide land-grant colleges and universities with grants, research, evaluation, and technical assistance under the program; expands the purposes for grants awarded under the program to include implementing educational activities relating to agriculture, nutrition, or food; requires USDA to provide technical assistance, research, and information to increase awareness of and participation in farm to school programs among agricultural producers, including beginning, veteran, and socially disadvantaged farmers; directs USDA to seek to improve local food procurement and distribution options for agricultural producers and eligible institutions; authorizes USDA to fund projects that include innovative approaches to aggregation, processing, transportation, and distribution; establishes new limitations on the amount and duration of grants; and limits funds that may be used for administrative costs.</summary>
</bill>
