<bill session="117" type="h" number="9555" updated="2023-08-25T22:47:52Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ZEVs Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zero-Emission Vehicles Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ZEVs Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Clean Air Act to create a national zero-emission vehicle standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000593"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001300" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2022-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001303" joined="2022-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001278" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001066" joined="2022-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001080" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000623" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000297" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000389" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000582" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000579" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2022-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000618" joined="2022-12-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="5263" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-08-25T19:57:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Zero-Emission Vehicles Act of 2022 or the ZEVs Act of 2022

This bill requires the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a zero-emission passenger vehicle standard. Specifically, the bill sets a schedule for increasing the percentage of zero-emission vehicles a vehicle manufacturer delivers for sale, culminating in a requirement to sell only zero-emission vehicles from 2035 on. The bill also requires the EPA to establish a zero-emission vehicle credit program that approves one zero-emission vehicle credit for each zero-emission vehicle delivered for sale in the United States and partial credits for qualified electric vehicles based on the estimated proportion of the mileage driven on the battery.

Manufacturers that fail to meet the minimum required percentage of zero-emission vehicle sales must submit to the EPA a quantity of zero-emission vehicle credits sufficient to offset the excess.

Credits may also be sold, transferred, exchanged, or retired in certain circumstances.

The bill imposes civil penalties for the failure to comply with zero-emission vehicle credit standards, with collected penalties being deposited into the Highway Trust Fund. After 2035, the EPA must issue injunctions on the manufacture of passenger vehicles other than zero-emission vehicles.</summary>
</bill>
