<bill session="110" type="h" number="3895" updated="2023-01-11T20:23:39Z">
  <state datetime="2007-10-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-10-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to extend the food labeling requirements of the Nutrition Labeling and Education Act of 1990 to enable customers to make informed choices about the nutritional content of standard menu items in large chain restaurants.</title>
    <title type="display">MEAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MEAL Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Menu Education and Labeling Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2007-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000287" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000324" joined="2008-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000009" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001143" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000725" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001145" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000215" joined="2007-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000738" joined="2007-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-10-22">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF14" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Health" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="s" number="2784" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diet"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Nutrition"/>
    <term name="Restaurants"/>
    <term name="Signs and signboards"/>
    <term name="Vending machines"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-12-17T15:18:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Menu Education and Labeling Act or the MEAL Act - Amends the Federal Food, Drug and Cosmetic Act to require restaurants that are a part of a chain with 20 or more locations doing business under the same trade name to disclose: (1) in a statement adjacent to each menu item, the number of calories, grams of saturated fat plus trans fat, and milligrams of sodium in a standard food serving; (2) other information designed to enable the public to understand the significance of the nutrition information provided in the context of a total daily diet; (3) that such information shall be provided in writing upon request; and (4) in a statement adjacent to the name of the food on a menu board, the number of calories in a serving of the food. Exempts condiments, items placed on a table or counter for general use, daily specials, temporary menu items, and irregular menu items from these requirements.

Requires restaurants that sell self-serve food, such as through salad bars or buffet lines, to place a sign that lists the number of calories per standard serving adjacent to each food offered.

Permits retail food establishments to voluntarily provide, and states to require, additional nutritional information.

Requires vending machine operators to provide a conspicuous sign disclosing the number of calories in each item of food offered.</summary>
</bill>
