<bill session="110" type="s" number="2419" updated="2023-01-11T13:15:26Z">
  <state datetime="2007-12-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-12-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Working Families Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Working Families Flexibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permit employees to request, and to ensure employers consider requests for, flexible work terms and conditions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000105"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2007-12-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2008-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000167" joined="2007-12-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14849-14850"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-12-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="110" type="h" number="4301" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal libraries"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Accountability Office (GAO)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2008-04-11T19:05:15Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Working Families Flexibility Act - Authorizes an employee to request from an employer a change in the terms or conditions of the employee's employment if the request relates to: (1) the number of hours the employee is required to work; (2) the times when the employee is required to work; or (3) where the employee is required to work. Sets forth certain employer duties with respect to such requests.

Makes it unlawful for an employer to interfere with any rights provided to an employee under this Act. Authorizes an employee to file a complaint with the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division of the Employment Standards Administration of the Department of Labor for any violations of such rights. Provides for the investigation and assessment of civil penalties or the award of relief for alleged violations, including the review in federal courts of appeal of orders of the Administrator.

Requires the Secretary of Labor to carry out a research, education, and technical assistance program for employers, labor organizations, and the general public regarding compliance with this Act.

Applies the requirements of this Act to certain classes of employees, including employees of the Government Accountability Office (GAO) and the Library of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
