<bill session="117" type="h" number="7175" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:48Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Asbestos Exposure in Housing Reduction Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asbestos Exposure in Housing Reduction Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require disclosure of asbestos hazards in the sale and lease of residential dwellings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000474"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2022-04-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Environment and Climate Change.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF18" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Environment, Manufacturing, and Critical Materials" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-11-08T17:01:44Z" status="Introduced in House">Asbestos Exposure in Housing Reduction Act of 2022

This bill requires the seller or lessor of a dwelling to disclose to the purchaser or lessee any known asbestos-based hazards in the dwelling and provide any available asbestos hazard evaluation report. The bill also requires the seller or lessor to allow the purchaser or lessee a 10-day period to conduct a risk assessment or inspection for asbestos hazards. Further, the bill requires that every contract for the sale or lease of a dwelling contain an asbestos warning statement and that every purchaser of a dwelling acknowledge that the purchaser has read and understands the warning statement and had the 10-day period to conduct a risk assessment or inspection.</summary>
</bill>
