<bill session="108" type="h" number="2752" updated="2023-01-15T05:47:36Z">
  <state datetime="2003-07-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-07-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-07-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Author, Consumer, and Computer Owner Protection and Security (ACCOPS) Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To encourage the development and distribution of creative works by enhancing domestic and international enforcement of the copyright laws, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Author, Consumer, and Computer Owner Protection and Security (ACCOPS) Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="popular">ACCOPS Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000714"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001231" joined="2003-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001055" joined="2003-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000627" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000792" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2003-07-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-07-17">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1496"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-09-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, the Internet, and Intellectual Property.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Computer crimes"/>
    <term name="Computer networks"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International Affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-03-05T22:02:30Z" status="Introduced in House">Author, Consumer, and Computer Owner Protection and Security (ACCOPS) Act of 2003 - Amends Federal law to require the National Intellectual Property Law Enforcement Coordination Council to develop guidelines to ensure that its component members share among themselves law enforcement information related to infringement of U.S. copyrighted work.

Requires the Attorney General to report biannually (currently, annually) to specified congressional committees on criminal copyright cases.

Requires the Attorney General, subject to specified limitations, to provide to a foreign authority evidence to assist it in: (1) determining whether a person has violated any of the copyright laws administered or enforced by the foreign authority; and (2) enforcing such laws.

Establishes criminal penalties for the unauthorized placing of a copyrighted work on a computer network accessible to members of the public who are able to copy the work through such access.

Establishes criminal penalties for any person who knowingly offers for download over the Internet enabling software (that, when installed on the user's computer, enables third parties to store data on that computer, or use that computer to search other computers' contents over the Internet) without warning any person downloading such software that it could create a security and privacy risk for the user's computer, and without obtaining the user's prior consent.

Establishes criminal penalties for persons who: (1) provides knowingly and intentionally fraudulent information in registering domain name; or (2) willfully infringe a copyright by the unauthorized reproduction or recording of a motion picture as it is being performed or displayed in a motion picture theater.

Declares that the knowing and intentional provision of material and misleading false contact information to a domain name registrar, domain name registry, or other domain name registration authority in registering such domain shall be considered evidence of willfulness regarding infringements committed by the domain name registrant through the use of such domain.</summary>
</bill>
