<bill session="118" type="h" number="3465" updated="2025-05-27T14:12:00Z">
  <state datetime="2023-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To enhance Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation transparency.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To enhance Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation transparency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001282"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000583" joined="2023-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="3556" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-16T19:03:19Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill requires additional notice and reporting by agencies when providing assistance to an insured depository institution. First, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC) must notify the appropriate congressional committees prior to taking action or providing assistance for the purpose of winding up an institution in receivership that presents the risk for serious adverse effects on economic conditions or financial stability. The bill also revises the basis for determining the least costly approach to satisfy the FDIC's obligations to depositors.

The Department of the Treasury must preserve specified information that documents a determination of an institution's potential to cause serious adverse effects on economic conditions or financial stability.

The Board of Directors of the FDIC, Treasury, and Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System must report to the appropriate congressional committees additional information on emergency determinations.</summary>
</bill>
