<bill session="117" type="s" number="2333" updated="2023-04-08T00:30:22Z">
  <state datetime="2023-01-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-01-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="display">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 2205 of title 36, United States Code, to ensure equal treatment of athletes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000127"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2021-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2021-07-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2021-07-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-06-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="593">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 593.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="2022-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S7081-7082" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S7081-7082" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-09">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12T14:12:01-05:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-12T14:24:14-05:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:17:01-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Nadler moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:17:12-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9923-9925" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:17:14-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 2333.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T14:23:48-05:00">
      <text>At the conclusion of debate, the Yeas and Nays were demanded and ordered. Pursuant to the provisions of clause 8, rule XX, the Chair announced that further proceedings on the motion would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T21:08:52-05:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9974-9975" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="532" datetime="2022-12-21T21:30:08-05:00" where="h" result="pass" suspension="1" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by the Yeas and Nays: (2/3 required): 350 - 59 (Roll no. 532).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H9923-9924" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-12-21T21:30:09-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-12-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2023-01-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-340" type="public" datetime="2023-01-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-340.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Olympic games"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Wages and earnings"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-08T00:22:11Z" status="Public Law">Equal Pay for Team USA Act of 2022

This bill requires that all athletes representing the United States in international amateur athletic competitions receive equal compensation and benefits for their work, regardless of gender.

Specifically, the bill requires, for a sport for which the U.S. Olympic and Paralympic Committees (the corporation) conduct separate programs for female and male athletes who represent the United States in international amateur athletic events, from funds directly provided by the corporation to the athlete (with exceptions), that there be equivalent and nondiscriminatory compensation, wages, benefits, medical care, travel arrangements, and payment or reimbursement for expenses.

It shall be permissible to (1) consider merit, performance, seniority, or quantity of play in determining contract or other terms of participation; and (2) provide more beneficial terms of participation to athletes to address disparities in outside income, or the need to foster underdeveloped programs or address documented and justifiable personal need on the part of specific athletes or teams.

The corporation must take all reasonable steps to advocate to international sports federations and other event organizers to equalize prizes, compensation, funding, and other support provided to athletes by such federations and organizers.

The corporation must report to Congress at least annually on compliance. Each report must include detailed information on the median, minimum, and maximum stipends and bonuses provided to athletes, disaggregated by gender, race, and status of participation on a professional sports team.

The bill requires full compliance within one year of this bill's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
