<bill session="111" type="h" number="5624" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:52Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Property Owners Access to Court Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To simplify and expedite access to the Federal courts for injured parties whose rights and privileges under the United States Constitution have been deprived by final actions of Federal agencies or other government officials or entities acting under color of State law, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Property Owners Access to Court Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000461" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001250" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001262" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001076" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001062" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001048" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000603" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000444" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000450" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000067" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001041" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000528" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000363" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001158" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000599" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000583" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000275" joined="2010-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001172" joined="2010-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction and venue"/>
    <term name="Property rights"/>
    <term name="State and local courts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-06T21:24:07Z" status="Introduced in House">Property Owners Access to Court Act of 2010 - Amends the federal judicial code to provide that, whenever a district court exercises jurisdiction in civil rights cases in which the operative facts concern the uses of real property, it shall not abstain from exercising such jurisdiction, or relinquish it to a state court, if the party seeking redress does not allege a violation of a state law, right, or privilege, and no parallel proceeding is pending in state court, at the time the action is filed in the district court, that arises out of the same operative facts as the district court proceeding.

Declares that in an action in which operative facts concern the uses of real property, the district court shall exercise jurisdiction even if the party seeking redress does not pursue judicial remedies provided by a state or territory. Provides for referral of an unsettled question of state law to the state's highest appellate court. Prohibits the district court from certifying a question of state law unless it is necessary to resolve the merits of the injured party's federal claim, and such question is patently unclear.

Declares that any claim or action to redress the deprivation of a property right or privilege secured by the Constitution shall be ripe for adjudication by the district courts upon a final decision rendered by any person acting under color of any law, regulation, custom, or usage of any state or U.S. territory that causes actual and concrete injury to the party seeking redress.

Declares that any claim founded upon a property right or privilege secured by the Constitution, but allegedly infringed or taken by the United States, shall be ripe for adjudication upon a final decision rendered by the United States which causes actual and concrete injury to the party seeking redress.

Amends the Revised Statutes of the United States and the federal judicial code with respect to certain constitutional property rights claims.

Provides for the liability of the United States for certain claims, brought under U.S. district court jurisdiction or Court of Federal Claims jurisdiction, where the claim is founded upon a property right or privilege secured by the Constitution.

Requires a federal agency, whenever it takes action limiting the use of private property that may be affected by the amendments made by this Act, to give notice to the owners of that property explaining their rights and the procedures for obtaining any compensation that may be due to them under such amendments.</summary>
</bill>
