<bill session="111" type="s" number="301" updated="2019-11-15T21:55:05Z">
  <state datetime="2009-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Physician Payments Sunshine Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">Physician Payments Sunshine Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XI of the Social Security Act to provide for transparency in the relationship between physicians and manufacturers of drugs, devices, biologicals, or medical supplies for which payment is made under Medicare, Medicaid, or SCHIP.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000386"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2009-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2009-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2009-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000305" joined="2009-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001170" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2009-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2009-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="U000039" joined="2009-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2009-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-22">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S787-788"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="h" number="3138" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical ethics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Product development and innovation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-13T20:19:11Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Physician Payments Sunshine Act of 2009 - Amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act to provide for transparency in the relationship between physicians and applicable manufacturers with respect to payments and other transfers of value and physician ownership or investment interests in manufacturers.

Requires any manufacturer of a covered drug, device, biological, or medical supply that makes a payment or another transfer of value to a physician, a physician medical practice, or a physician group practice to report annually, in electronic form, specified information on such transactions to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.

Requires any such manufacturer, or related group purchasing organization, also to report annually to the Secretary, in electronic form, certain information regarding any ownership or investment interest (other than in a publicly traded security and mutual fund) held by a physician (or an immediate family member) in the manufacturer or group purchasing organization during the preceding year.

Prescribes administrative penalties for failure to comply with these requirements.

Requires report submission procedures to ensure public availability of required information on a website.</summary>
</bill>
