<bill session="118" type="h" number="1158" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:39Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2023-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Elimination of Future Technology Delays Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Elimination of Future Technology Delays Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Elimination of Future Technology Delays Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act with respect to new critical energy resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001114"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000372" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001275" joined="2023-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000615" joined="2023-02-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000798" joined="2023-03-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-24">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Innovation, Data, and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-28">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee by the Yeas and Nays: 13 - 6 .</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 21.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-23">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Energy and Commerce. H. Rept. 118-14.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2023-03-23" calendar="Union" number="7">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 7.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Commerce, Manufacturing, and Trade" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="947" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2811" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Chemistry"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-04-24T22:20:02Z" status="Reported to House">Elimination of Future Technology Delays Act of 2023

This bill establishes new requirements for the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) when it makes certain determinations under the Toxic Substance Control Act (TSCA) related to chemical substances that are considered to be a critical energy resource (i.e., any energy resource that is essential to the U.S. energy sector and energy systems and has a vulnerable supply chain).

Currently, under TSCA, manufacturers and processors of chemical substances must notify the EPA before manufacturing a new chemical substance or before manufacturing or processing a substance for a significant new use. The EPA must review such notices and provide a determination on the substance or significant new use.

Under the bill, the EPA must consider economic, societal, and environmental costs and benefits when making determinations on notices for (1) new chemical substances that are considered to be a critical energy resource, or (2) significant new uses for such chemicals.

If the EPA fails to make a determination by the end of the applicable review period and the submitter has not withdrawn the notice, the submitter may proceed in manufacturing or processing the substance. Applicable fees must not be refunded if a submitter proceeds with manufacturing or processing.

The EPA may suggest the withdrawal of a notice for a chemical substance that is a critical energy resource, or request a suspension of the review period, if the EPA has conducted a preliminary review of the notice and provided a draft of determination to the submitter.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-14</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
