<bill session="116" type="s" number="2798" updated="2022-11-01T05:02:36Z">
  <state datetime="2019-11-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-11-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Whistleblower Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Whistleblower Protection Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure whistleblowers who are Government employees or contractors receive adequate protection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000603"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-11-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-04T14:12:38Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Whistleblower Protection Act of 2019

This bill retroactively prohibits a federal contractor from taking certain personnel actions with respect to specified employees.

Specifically, the bill prohibits a federal contractor from taking a personnel action against an employee who has lawfully disclosed information the employee reasonably believes shows (1) a violation of any law, rule, or regulation; or (2) gross mismanagement, waste of funds, abuse of authority, or substantial and specific danger to public health or safety.

Further, a federal contractor may not take a personnel action against an employee because of the employee's (1) lawful exercise of an appeal, complaint, or grievance right, or testifying or assisting in the exercise of such right; (2) cooperation with or disclosure of information to the agency's inspector general or special counsel; or (3) refusal to obey an order that would require the individual to violate a law, rule, or regulation.

A federal agency is prohibited from pressuring a federal contractor from taking any personnel action against an employee based on such disclosures or actions by the employee.</summary>
</bill>
