<bill session="119" type="hr" number="10" updated="2025-01-30T13:09:54Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Amending the Rules of the House of Representatives to establish a Committee on Health as a standing committee of the House.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">HEALTH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">House Endeavor to Accelerate a Legislative Transformation of Healthcare Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03">
      <text>Submitted in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional operations and organization"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Education and Workforce"/>
    <term name="House Committee on Energy and Commerce"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-01-14T17:15:24Z" status="Introduced in House">House Endeavor to Accelerate a Legislative Transformation of Healthcare Act or the HEALTH Act

This resolution establishes the Committee on Health, a standing committee of the House of Representatives, and specifies the subjects within its jurisdiction.&#160;

The Committee on Health is responsible for all legislation and other matters relating to biomedical research and development (including the Food and Drug Administration); health, health facilities, and health care supported by general revenues (except veterans&#226;&#8364;&#8482; hospitals, medical care, and treatment); and public health and quarantine (including the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention). The resolution also removes these topics from the jurisdiction of the Committee on Education and the Workforce and the Committee on Energy and Commerce.</summary>
</bill>
