<bill session="118" type="s" number="615" updated="2025-11-19T02:55:27Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Cabin Air Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cabin Air Safety Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the safety of the air supply on aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000062" joined="2023-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2023-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1293" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-05-02T15:26:04Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Cabin Air Safety Act of 2023

This bill directs the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to implement regulations regarding smoke or fume incidents on aircraft (excluding helicopters).

Specifically, the bill requires

 flight attendants, pilots, aircraft maintenance technicians, airport first responders, and emergency response teams to receive annual training on how to respond to incidents on aircraft; the FAA to develop a standardized form and system for reporting incidents involving smoke or fumes; the FAA to conduct an investigation after a report is submitted about incidents of smoke or fumes if anybody on the aircraft required medical attention; and air carriers to install and operate onboard detectors and other air quality monitoring equipment situated in the air supply system to enable pilots and maintenance technicians to locate the sources of air supply contamination, including carbon monoxide.</summary>
</bill>
