<bill session="117" type="s" number="953" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:34Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Water for Conservation and Farming Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for drought preparedness and improved water supply reliability.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Water for Conservation and Farming Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2021-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="SSEG07" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="Water and Power" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agricultural conservation and pollution"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Aquatic ecology"/>
    <term name="Birds"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Dams and canals"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Farmland"/>
    <term name="Fishes"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunting and fishing"/>
    <term name="Lakes and rivers"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Water resources funding"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water use and supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-20T18:58:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Water for Conservation and Farming Act

This bill establishes a funding source for certain water resources development projects in western states. The bill also reauthorizes and expands existing water resources development programs, as well as establishes new programs.

Specifically, the bill establishes the Bureau of Reclamation Infrastructure Fund to fund water-related programs, including water reclamation and reuse projects, dam safety projects, and the WaterSMART program (which provides assistance to eligible government entities to increase water supply). Each year from FY2031-FY2061, the Department of the Treasury must deposit $300 million of revenues into this fund that would otherwise be deposited into the Reclamation Fund (which currently funds irrigation works in western states).

The bill also expands the allowable uses for grants under the WaterSMART program.

Next, the bill revises the Reclamation Climate Change and Water program (which assesses the impact of climate change on water supplies) by requiring Reclamation to develop a strategy to address sustaining native biodiversity during periods of drought.

The bill also reauthorizes through FY2028 the Fisheries Restoration and Irrigation Mitigation program (which funds fish passage projects in certain areas that drain into the Pacific Ocean).

Finally, the bill establishes new programs directed at western states to

 provide assistance to agricultural producers to create and maintain waterbird and shorebird habitats, award grants to eligible government entities and nonprofit conservation organizations for habitat restoration projects that improve watershed health, and prepare plans to sustain the survival of critically important fisheries during periods of drought.</summary>
</bill>
