<bill session="116" type="s" number="4518" updated="2023-01-11T13:45:16Z">
  <state datetime="2020-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Pandemic Federal Telework Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pandemic Federal Telework Act of 2020</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal agencies to permit employees to telework full-time during the public health emergency relating to COVID-19, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000128"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000575" joined="2020-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001191" joined="2020-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-08-10">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Commuting"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-09-22T17:55:28Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Pandemic Federal Telework Act of 2020

This bill establishes several requirements for federal agencies with respect to telework.

Specifically, the bill requires each federal agency (executive, legislative, and judicial) to allow eligible employees to telework full-time during the public health emergency declared on January 31, 2020, relating to COVID-19 (i.e., coronavirus disease 2019). An employee is considered eligible if the employee has not received specified disciplinary action and is otherwise determined eligible by the agency.

Additionally, the Office of Personnel Management must, in coordination with the Department of Health and Human Services, develop an expansive telework policy for use in future outbreaks of infectious diseases.

The bill also requires executive agencies to ensure that all new managers and supervisors receive certain training on specified aspects of telework, including the benefits of telework, the technology involved, and information security.</summary>
</bill>
