<bill session="118" type="s" number="2382" updated="2025-11-19T04:17:53Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Farmland Security Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 to remove the limitation on the amount of a civil penalty, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmland Security Act of 2023</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001230"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2024-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2023-07-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6469" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-15T15:38:13Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Farmland Security Act of 2023

This bill&#160;authorizes increased civil penalties for violations of the Agricultural Foreign Investment Disclosure Act of 1978 (AFIDA)&#160;and increases Department of Agriculture (USDA) oversight and research into foreign investment in agricultural land.&#160;(AFIDA and the regulations that implemented the act require foreign investors who acquire, transfer, or hold an interest in U.S. agricultural land to report such holdings and transactions to USDA.)&#160;

In general, the bill allows USDA to determine an appropriate civil penalty amount for an&#160;AFIDA violation by removing the cap that currently&#160;prohibits the civil penalty from exceeding 25% of the fair market value of the interest in the land.

The bill provides an exception for a shell corporation (i.e., a corporation, company, association, firm, partnership, society, joint stock company, trust, or estate that has no or nominal operations). An&#160;AFIDA civil penalty for a foreign-owned shell corporation must be 100% of the fair market value of the interest in the agricultural land associated with the violation. The penalty does not apply if the shell corporation remedies a defective filing or failure to file within 60 days of USDA providing notice.&#160;&#160;

USDA must conduct annual compliance audits of at least 10% of the reports. Further, USDA must provide state and county-level personnel annual training in identifying agricultural land for which a report must be submitted.

USDA must also annually conduct research and submit a report to Congress on foreign investment in agricultural land, including trends in the purchase of U.S. agricultural land by foreign-owned shell corporations.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
