<bill session="111" type="h" number="1391" updated="2019-11-15T21:19:35Z">
  <state datetime="2009-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SMASH Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop M-Spam Abuse as a Sales Industry Habit Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="display">SMASH Act of 2009</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to revise the Telemarketing Sales Rule to explicitly prohibit the sending of a text message containing an unsolicited advertisement to a cellular telephone number listed on the national do-not-call registry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000550"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-03-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Commerce, Trade and Consumer Protection.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Marketing and advertising"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-03-23T21:13:50Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop M-Spam Abuse as a Sales Industry Habit Act of 2009 or the SMASH Act of 2009 - Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to issue regulations to revise the Telemarketing Sales Rule to explicitly prohibit, as an abusive telemarketing act or practice, the sending of any electronic commercial message containing an unsolicited advertisement to a telephone number that is assigned to a commercial mobile service and listed on the FTC's do-not-call registry.

Prohibits interpreting anything in this Act to preclude or override the applicability of specified provisions of the Communications Act of 1934 or the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 or rules prescribed under specified provisions of the Telemarketing and Consumer Fraud and Abuse Prevention Act.</summary>
</bill>
