<bill session="117" type="h" number="1100" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Online Accessibility Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to include consumer facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity, to establish web accessibility compliance standards for such websites and mobile applications, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Online Accessibility Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001305"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001067" joined="2021-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2021-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000609" joined="2021-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-19">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Consumer Protection and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF17" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Innovation, Data, and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Access Board"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Disability and paralysis"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-03-19T18:25:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Online Accessibility Act

This bill sets forth requirements for consumer-facing websites and mobile applications owned or operated by a private entity and guidance regarding standards for website accessibility by the disabled.

Specifically, the bill prohibits the exclusion of an individual, by reason of disability, from participation in or being denied the full and equal benefits of the services of such a website or application or from being subjected to discrimination by a private owner or operator of such a website or application.

Such a website or application shall be considered compliant if it is in substantial compliance with the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines 2.0 Level A and Level AA standard established by the Accessibility Guidelines Working Group. A noncompliant entity shall provide an alternative, equivalent means of access by individuals with disabilities. The Access Board must publish related standards.

The bill sets forth provisions regarding administrative remedies and reporting of violations and enforcement by the Department of Justice and through private rights of action.</summary>
</bill>
