<bill session="111" type="h" number="5392" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:08Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Council on Integration of Health Care Education Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To establish a Council on Integration of Health Care Education, to provide for implementation of the recommendations of the Council, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Council on Integration of Health Care Education Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000113"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001155" joined="2010-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Energy and Commerce</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Education and Labor, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-25">
      <text>Referred to House Education and Labor</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-29">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Higher Education, Lifelong Learning, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED13" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Higher Education and Workforce Development Subcomittee" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-07-19T20:12:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Council on Integration of Health Care Education Act of 2010 - Establishes the Council on Integration of Health Care Education in the Office of the Secretary in the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) to develop recommendations for the purpose of strengthening the capacity of health care professionals and behavioral health providers to deliver integrated, comprehensive health care. Requires such recommendations to identify: (1) the core competencies to be required of each type of health care professional and behavioral health provider with respect to mental health and substance use prevention and treatment services; and (2) the appropriate methods for incorporating such competencies into the curricula of institutions of higher education and of continuing education, the licensure and certification requirements for health care professionals and behavioral health providers, and the accreditation process for institutions of higher education providing terminal education for health care professionals and behavioral health providers.

Authorizes the Secretary to make grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or private nonprofit entities for the purpose of implementing the recommendations of the Council on continuing education for health care professionals and behavioral health providers.

Requires the Secretary to make grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to public or nonprofit private institutions of higher education for the purpose of implementing the recommendations of the Council on education curricula for health care professionals and behavioral health providers.</summary>
</bill>
