<bill session="119" type="s" number="134" updated="2025-08-06T03:41:15Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Saving the Civil Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Saving the Civil Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to place limitations on excepting positions from the competitive service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000384"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000382" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2025-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000479" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000273" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000383" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2025-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000133" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001176" joined="2025-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000145" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000033" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001181" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000128" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000805" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000817" joined="2025-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2025-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2025-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-21T19:12:20Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Saving the Civil Service Act

This bill generally prohibits changes to the classification of positions in the competitive service and excepted service unless certain conditions are met. (Competitive service positions are subject to competitive examination while excepted service positions are appointed under one of five schedules. Competitive service positions have notice and appeal requirements for adverse actions that are not applicable to most excepted positions, including those of a confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character under Schedule C.)

On October 21, 2020, President Donald Trump issued an executive order that placed executive agency positions that are of a confidential, policy-determining, policy-making, or policy-advocating character, and that are not normally subject to change as a result of a presidential transition, under a new Schedule F in the excepted service. The order was subsequently revoked by President Joe Biden.

The bill prohibits executive agency positions in the competitive service from being placed in the excepted service, unless such positions are placed in a schedule in the excepted service as in effect on September 30, 2020. The bill also prohibits positions in the excepted service from being placed in any schedule other than the aforementioned schedules.

Additionally, agencies may not (1) transfer occupied positions from the competitive or excepted service into Schedule C without the consent of the Office of Personnel Management, or (2) transfer employees in the excepted service to another schedule or transfer employees in the competitive service to the excepted service without employee consent.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
