<bill session="117" type="h" number="6775" updated="2022-12-30T04:33:57Z">
  <state datetime="2022-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting American Business from Foreign Adversaries Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting American Business from Foreign Adversaries Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 190 of title 28, United States Code, to require businesses with a principal place of business in a foreign country to register an agent for the service of process in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2022-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-06-25T00:31:16Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting American Business from Foreign Adversaries Act of 2022

This bill requires specified companies and other entities associated with a foreign country to register an agent with the Department of Commerce for service of process (i.e., the legal process for notifying a defendant that legal action has been taken against them) in the United States.

Specifically, a corporation or other commercial entity conducting business in the United States must register an agent if the entity (1) is organized under the laws of, or has its principal place of business in, a foreign country; (2) has a majority of shares held by an individual or a group of individuals who reside in a foreign country; or (3) is owned by individuals or entities who reside in or are headquartered outside of the United States and the majority of the entity's earnings are derived from commerce outside of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
