<bill session="108" type="s" number="216" updated="2023-01-15T21:34:09Z">
  <state datetime="2003-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Building Security Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the National Institute of Standards and Technology to develop improvements in building and fire codes, standards, and practices to reduce the impact of terrorist and other extreme threats to the safety of buildings, their occupants, and emergency responders, and to authorize the Department of Homeland Security to form a task force to recommend ways to strengthen standards in the private security industry, stabilize the workforce, and create a safer environment for commercial building and industrial facility occupants.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Building Security Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000286"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1492"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Buildings"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Emergency Management"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Building Security Act of 2003 - Requires the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology to establish a research and development program to provide for improved building and fire codes, standards, and practices. Requires the Director to: (1) work with industry, trade associations, and professional societies to research construction, material, and equipment standards and practices to reduce the impact of extreme threats to the safety of buildings, their occupants, and emergency responders and to study the best methods (such as tax incentives or grants) for ensuring full implementation of and compliance with such standards and practices; and (2) oversee a program for dissemination and implementation of such practices and standards.Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to establish a Private Security Industry Task Force to: (1) examine the limitations in training, screening, standard-setting, retention, and oversight practice in the private security industry; and (2) develop structural guidelines and standards of quality for the industry and determine the best way to help States implement them.</summary>
</bill>
