<amendment session="110" chamber="h" number="1055" updated="2022-02-03T05:20:43Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5658" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2008-05-22T18:10:53-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000551"/>
  <offered datetime="2008-05-22"/>
  <description>Amendment states that no provision in any status of forces agreement negotiated between the United States and the Government of Iraq that obligates the United States to the defense of Iraq from internal or external threats shall have any legal effect unless the agreement is in the form of a treaty requiring the advice and consent of the Senate, or is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 26 printed in House Report 110-666 to provide that no provision in any status of forces agreement negotiated between the United States and the Government of Iraq that obligates the United States to the defense of Iraq from internal or external threats shall have any legal effect unless the agreement is in the form of a treaty requiring the advice and consent of the Senate, or is specifically authorized by an Act of Congress.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2008-05-22T18:10:53-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="359">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lee amendment (A010) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 183 (Roll no. 359).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T16:19:29-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4774-4777, 5/23/2008 H4790" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4774" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T18:10:53-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T18:10:53-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lee amendment (A010) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 183 (Roll no. 359).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T18:10:53-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22T16:19:29-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A010) offered by Ms. Lee.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4774-4777, 5/23/2008 H4790" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4774" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2008-05-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
