<bill session="111" type="h" number="5568" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:53Z">
  <state datetime="2010-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Stop Waste by Eliminating Excessive Programs Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To create a means to review and abolish Federal programs that are inefficient, duplicative, or in other ways wasteful of taxpayer funds.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stop Waste by Eliminating Excessive Programs Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SWEEP Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000362" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000363" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001252" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001254" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000716" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001264" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001074" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000754" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001063" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000608" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000599" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000607" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000289" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000554" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000309" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001044" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000213" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001037" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001030" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000371" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000565" joined="2010-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001172" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001146" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001142" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001149" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001175" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001167" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001140" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001178" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000573" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001158" joined="2010-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001150" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001180" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001171" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001173" joined="2010-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000038" joined="2010-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000799" joined="2010-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000801" joined="2010-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Oversight and Government Reform</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, and in addition to the Committee on Rules, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-22">
      <text>Referred to House Rules</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-06-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR E1187-1188"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Budget process"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Legislative rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-19T15:22:12Z" status="Introduced in House">Stop Waste by Eliminating Excessive Programs Act of 2010 or the SWEEP Act - Declares that it shall not be in order in the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider any legislation that authorizes a program unless it provides budget authority for the program for 10 or fewer fiscal years.

Requires a federal agency to make the program performance report for each program under its control available to Congress upon request.

Establishes the Federal Program Sunset Commission, which shall: (1) submit to Congress a report analyzing the interaction between authorizing legislation and appropriations legislation and the effects of such interaction; (2) establish a schedule to review each activity or project (program) listed in the program and financing schedules of the annual federal budget every 10 years; (3) conduct a review of the efficiency of operation and public need for each such program according to that schedule; and (4) annually report to Congress on the programs reviewed, including recommendations regarding whether each program should be abolished or reorganized and whether the functions of any programs should be consolidated, transferred, or reorganized in an agency or among agencies and proposals for appropriate administrative or legislative action. Terminates the Commission 11 years after this Act's enactment unless reauthorized.

Requires the Comptroller General: (1) in cooperation with the Director of the Congressional Research Service (CRS), to submit to Congress and update annually an inventory of all federal programs, with budgetary information to be provided by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO); and (2) organize the inventory by program areas that are reflective of national needs and agency missions and that are appropriate for the exercise of the review requirements of this Act. Requires the Comptroller General, the Director of CRS, and the Director of CBO to permit the mutual exchange of information that would aid in inventory compilation.

 Sets forth requirements for, and procedures for congressional consideration of, proposed legislation to abolish programs.</summary>
</bill>
