<bill session="117" type="h" number="7231" updated="2022-12-29T22:03:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ECASH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ECASH Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electronic Currency And Secure Hardware Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of the Treasury to develop and pilot digital dollar technologies that replicate the privacy-respecting features of physical cash.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000370" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000586" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000617" joined="2022-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000481" joined="2022-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-09-13T18:38:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Electronic Currency And Secure Hardware Act or the ECASH Act 

This bill requires the Department of the Treasury to support the development of an electronic dollar.

The electronic dollar must be

 payable to the bearer; considered legal tender; an obligation of the United States; placed into circulation by Treasury; able to be directly used by the public; and capable of instantaneous, offline transactions using hardware devices not involving a third-party intermediary. The bill also provides for privacy requirements applicable to any hardware device used for electronic dollar transactions.

Merchants who accept physical currency and the federal government must accept electronic dollars as a form of payment.

The bill also establishes

 the Electronic Currency Innovation Program to direct the development and implementation of electronic currency, the Digital Dollar Council to coordinate Treasury's activities with other government entities, and the Monetary Privacy Board to review and evaluate the electronic dollar program. Finally, the bill provides for the establishment of a Treasury Electronic Currency Innovation Fund Account to carry out related programs.</summary>
</bill>
