<bill session="117" type="h" number="5147" updated="2023-01-01T20:18:39Z">
  <state datetime="2021-08-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-08-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-08-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the Secretary of Defense from procuring personal protective equipment from certain non-allied foreign nations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">To prohibit the Secretary of Defense from procuring personal protective equipment from certain non-allied foreign nations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000804"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-08-31">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-08-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="4350" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="2792" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military procurement, research, weapons development"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-04T20:27:37Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill prohibits the Department of Defense (DOD) from procuring any covered item from the Democratic People's Republic of North Korea, the People's Republic of China, the Russian Federation, or the Islamic Republic of Iran. Under the bill, covered items include sanitizing and disinfecting wipes, testing swabs, gauze, bandages, and personal protective equipment for use in preventing the spread of disease and the materials and components thereof.

The bill provides for an exception to the prohibition in circumstances where (1) DOD determines that covered materials of satisfactory quality and quantity cannot be procured from other nations at a specified time and reasonable price, (2) the procurement of covered items is for use outside of the United States, or (3) the purchase is for amounts not greater than $150,000. However, a proposed purchase or contract for an amount greater than $150,000 may not be divided into multiple purchases or contracts for lesser amounts to qualify for an exception.</summary>
</bill>
