<bill session="117" type="s" number="301" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:36Z">
  <state datetime="2021-02-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-02-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Verifiable, Orderly, and Timely Election Results Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to provide Federal standards for mail-in ballots and reporting of election results with respect to elections for Federal office.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Verifiable, Orderly, and Timely Election Results Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001217"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-02-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Elections, voting, political campaign regulation"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-06-24T19:41:14Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Verifiable, Orderly, and Timely Election Results Act

This bill establishes certain federal standards for voting by mail and reporting federal election results. It also requires states to establish certain election measures.

First, the bill establishes federal standards for (1) requesting a mail-in ballot; (2) confirming the identity, registration, and eligibility of an individual requesting a mail-in ballot; and (3) submitting a mail-in ballot. In particular, the bill requires mail-in ballots to be received by the time the polls close on election day.

In addition, the bill makes it unlawful to possess or return a mail-in ballot completed by another person (commonly referred to as ballot harvesting), with exceptions. A violator is subject to criminal penalties&#8212;a fine, a prison term of up to one year, or both.

The bill also establishes standards for reporting federal election results, including by requiring states to count all eligible ballots within 24 hours after the election.

Finally, each state must, in order to receive election assistance funds, have in effect certain laws related to voting. For example, states must require voters to present identification to cast a ballot in a federal election.</summary>
</bill>
