<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1024" updated="2022-02-03T06:00:51Z">
  <amends type="h" number="3523" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-04-26T17:41:23-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001182"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-04-26"/>
  <description>Amendment provides authority to the Federal Government to create reasonable procedures to protect privacy and civil liberties, consistent with the need of the Government to protect federal systems and cybersecurity and would also prohibit the Federal Government from retaining or using information shared pursuant to paragraph (b)(1) for anything other than a use permitted under the bill.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 8 printed in House Report 112-454 to provide clear authority to the government to create reasonable procedures to protect privacy and civil liberties, consistent with the need of the government to protect federal systems and cybersecurity. Would also prohibit the federal government from retaining or using information shared pursuant to paragraph (b)(1) for anything other than a use permitted under paragraph (c)(1).</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-04-26T17:41:23-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="188">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mulvaney amendment (A006) Agreed to by recorded vote: 416 - 0 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T16:08:23-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Mulvaney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2172-2173, H2181-2182" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2172" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T17:41:23-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T17:41:23-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Mulvaney amendment (A006) Agreed to by recorded vote: 416 - 0 (Roll no. 188).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T17:41:23-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26T16:08:23-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A006) offered by Mr. Mulvaney.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2172-2173, H2181-2182" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2172" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-04-26">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
