<bill session="118" type="h" number="3984" updated="2024-07-24T15:21:40Z">
  <state datetime="2023-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Feral Swine Eradication Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Feral Swine Eradication Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 to reauthorize the feral swine eradication and control pilot program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001087" joined="2023-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001130" joined="2023-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001224" joined="2023-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001185" joined="2023-09-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG14" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Conservation, Research, and Biotechnology" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAG29" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="1613" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural prices, subsidies, credit"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Mammals"/>
    <term name="Pest management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-12-06T19:48:42Z" status="Introduced in House">Feral Swine Eradication Act

This bill reauthorizes the feral swine eradication and control pilot program and removes the pilot program designation. This Department of Agriculture (USDA) program responds to the threat feral swine pose to agriculture, native ecosystems, and human and animal health.

The bill also directs USDA to require the Animal and Plant Health Inspection Service (APHIS) and the Natural Resources Conservation Service (NRCS) to continue monitoring an area for reoccurrence of feral swine for one year after USDA determines that feral swine has been eradicated from an eligible area.

The current even distribution of the program's funds between APHIS and the NRCS is amended to allocate 60% of the funds to APHIS and 40% of the funds to the NRCS.

Further, the bill includes new reporting requirements, which direct APHIS and the NRCS to submit a joint report to Congress on the program. This report must be publicly available on USDA's website.</summary>
</bill>
