<bill session="108" type="s" number="2131" updated="2023-01-15T10:03:16Z">
  <state datetime="2004-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Controlling Invasive and Unauthorized Software Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate the unauthorized installation of computer software, to require clear disclosure to computer users of certain computer software features that may pose a threat to user privacy, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Controlling Invasive and Unauthorized Software Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001126"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1684-1685"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S1685-1688" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="s" number="2145" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Computer security measures"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parties to actions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telemarketing"/>
    <term name="Web sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-04-14T18:13:07Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Controlling Invasive and Unauthorized Software Act - Makes it unlawful for any person who is not the user of a protected computer (any computer used in interstate or foreign commerce or communication) to install, or allow the installation of, software on that computer, unless: (1) the user of the computer has received notice and granted consent that satisfies the requirements of this Act; and (2) the computer software's uninstall procedures satisfies the requirements of this Act.

Requires the notice to include: (1) a clear notification, displayed on the screen until the user either grants or denies consent to installation, of the name and nature of the software to be installed; and (2) a separate disclosure with respect to each information collection, advertising, distributed computing, and settings modification feature contained in the software. Requires the consent to include: (1) consent to the software installation; and (2) separate consent to each of the above features of such software.

Prohibits any person who is not the user of a protected computer from using any such feature of software installed on a computer if: (1) the software was installed in violation of this Act; (2) the use falls outside of the scope described in the notice; or (3) the person using a software feature fails to protect the security and integrity of personal information so collected. Provides exceptions, including for software installed before the sale of such computer.

Provides administration and enforcement through the Federal Trade Commission. Authorizes actions by States on behalf of its residents.</summary>
</bill>
