<bill session="111" type="s" number="3399" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:58Z">
  <state datetime="2010-05-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-05-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fairness in Women-Owned Small Business Contracting Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remove the limit on the anticipated award price for contracts awarded under the procurement program for women-owned small business concerns, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fairness in Women-Owned Small Business Contracting Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2010-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4147"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-05-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S4147" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSSB" name="Senate Small Business and Entrepreneurship" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-06-28T17:55:56Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Fairness in Women-Owned Small Business Contracting Act of 2010 - Amends the Small Business Act with respect to the procurement program for women-owned small businesses (providing a federal procurement contracting preference to such businesses) to: (1) remove the requirement that the woman or women owning such business be economically disadvantaged; (2) remove contract award price limits; and (3) allow a contracting officer to award a sole source contract to such a business under the same conditions as such a contract may be awarded to a qualified HUBZone (historically underutilized business zone) small business.

Directs the Administrator of the Small Business Administration (SBA) to: (1) periodically conduct a study to identify any U.S. industry in which women are underrepresented; and (2) every five years, report study results to the congressional small business committees.</summary>
</bill>
