<bill session="118" type="s" number="900" updated="2025-11-19T03:06:58Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Conservation and Innovative Climate Partnership Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Conservation and Innovative Climate Partnership Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food, Agriculture, Conservation, and Trade Act of 1990 to establish a competitive grant program under which the Secretary of Agriculture provides grants to land-grant colleges and universities to support agricultural producers in adopting conservation and innovative climate practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2023-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2023-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="2719" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-11-17T14:47:54Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Conservation and Innovative Climate Partnership Act of 2023

This bill requires the Department of Agriculture to award competitive grants to land-grant colleges or universities to increase agricultural producers' voluntary adoption of conservation practices (e.g., alley cropping) and innovative climate practices (e.g., carbon sequestration). Projects may be carried out through public awareness campaigns, workshops, and specialized technical assistance.

Grantees must carry out activities in partnership with at least one other entity, such as the Natural Resources Conservation Service, a land-grant college or university, a state entity, or a nonprofit organization.</summary>
</bill>
