<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>2285</number>
    <updateDate>2020-02-10T17:00:03Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2020-02-10T17:00:03Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2012-04-16</introducedDate>
    <congress>112</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
        <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2012-04-16T22:59:02Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-04-16</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>sshr00</systemCode>
            <name>Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2012-04-16</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>M000639</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Menendez, Robert [D-NJ]</fullName>
        <firstName>Robert</firstName>
        <lastName>Menendez</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>NJ</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Education</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Crime prevention</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Criminal justice information and records</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Education programs funding</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Higher education</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Education</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2012-04-16</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2012-04-19T21:29:23Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Michael Pohle Jr. Campus Emergency Alert Act - Amends title IV (Student Assistance) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to revise the civil penalties applicable to institutions of higher education (IHEs) that fail to properly disclose campus security policies and crime statistics to current students and employees and, upon request, to any applicant for enrollment or employment.</p> <p>Sets a maximum penalty per violation and a limitation on the total amount an IHE can be penalized each year. </p> <p>Establishes a minimum penalty for each instance an IHE: (1) substantially misrepresents the number, location, or nature of the crimes it is required to report; (2) fails to notify the campus community of a significant emergency or dangerous situation that is an immediate threat to its health or safety, unless notice would compromise efforts to contain it; or (3) fails to provide the campus community with timely reports on crimes that are considered to be a threat to students and employees and are reported to campus security or the local police.</p> <p>Expresses maximum and minimum penalty amounts as percentages of the funds an IHE received from the Department of Education in the previous award year.</p> <p>Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a special account in the Treasury where these penalties are to be collected and from which they are to be disbursed for activities promoting campus safety.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Michael Pohle Jr. Campus Emergency Alert Act</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Michael Pohle Jr. Campus Emergency Alert Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Michael Pohle Jr. Campus Emergency Alert Act</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to increase civil penalties for institutions of higher education that fail to comply with the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2012-04-16T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-112s2285is/xml/BILLS-112s2285is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2012-04-16</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
