<bill session="108" type="s" number="2646" updated="2023-01-14T22:48:23Z">
  <state datetime="2004-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Sustainability Report Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Director of the National Park Service to prepare a report on the sustainability of the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor and the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Commission.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Sustainability Report Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001040"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2004-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2004-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-13">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8037-8038"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8038" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="5014" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental education"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Sports and Recreation"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-10-08T15:32:18Z" status="Introduced in Senate">John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor Sustainability Report Act - Requires the Director of the National Park Service (NPS) to prepare a report on the sustainability of the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Corridor in Rhode Island and Massachusetts.

Requires the report to: (1) document progress made in accomplishing the purpose of the law establishing the Corridor and the strategies and goals set forth in the Cultural Heritage and Land Management Plan for the Corridor, including historic preservation, interpretation and education, environmental recovery, recreational development, and economic improvement; (2) identify further actions and commitments needed to protect, enhance, and interpret the Corridor; (3) determine the extent of Federal funding and determine how such funds have leveraged additional Federal, State, local, and private funding for the Corridor since its establishment; and (4) evaluate the John H. Chafee Blackstone River Valley National Heritage Commission's form of authority and management structure for the Corridor, and identify and evaluate options for a permanent NPS designation or a State park or regional entity as a sustainable framework to achieve the national interest of the Blackstone Valley.

Directs that: (1) the Director prepare the report in coordination with the NPS Advisory Board; and (2) funding to prepare the report be made available from annual appropriations for the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
