<amendment session="109" chamber="h" number="567" updated="2022-02-03T05:36:09Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2123" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2005-09-22T16:11:25-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000096"/>
  <offered datetime="2005-09-22"/>
  <description>Page 110, after line 19, insert the following new subsection (and redesignate subsequent subsections proposed to be added by the relevant provision accordingly): \   "(h) The Secretary shall develop and implement an outreach program to train and recruit African-American and Latino-American men to become Head Start teachers in order to increase the provision of quality services and instruction to children with diverse backgrounds.".</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 5 printed in House Report 109-229 to direct the Secretary to implement an outreach program to train and recruit African-American and Latino-American men to become Head Start teachers in order to increase the provision of quality services and instructions to children with diverse backgrounds.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2005-09-22T16:11:25-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="490">
      <text>On agreeing to the Davis (IL) amendment (A005) Agreed to by recorded vote: 401 - 14 (Roll no. 490).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T13:43:37-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A005) offered by Mr. Davis (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8306-8307, H8321-8322" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8306" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T13:43:37-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A005) offered by Mr. Davis (IL).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8306-8307, H8321-8322" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H8306" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T16:11:25-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Davis (IL) amendment (A005) Agreed to by recorded vote: 401 - 14 (Roll no. 490).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T16:11:25-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22T16:11:25-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-09-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
