<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>1550</number>
    <updateDate>2017-12-14T23:21:49Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:32:25Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2007-06-05</introducedDate>
    <congress>110</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
        <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Reported original measure</name>
            <date>2007-06-05T21:53:28Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <relatedBills>
      <item>
        <title>National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
        <congress>110</congress>
        <number>1547</number>
        <type>S</type>
        <latestAction>
          <actionDate>2007-06-29</actionDate>
          <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 260.</text>
        </latestAction>
        <relationshipDetails>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>CRS</identifiedBy>
          </item>
          <item>
            <type>Related bill</type>
            <identifiedBy>House</identifiedBy>
          </item>
        </relationshipDetails>
      </item>
    </relatedBills>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 188.</text>
        <type>Calendars</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <text>Committee on Armed Services. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Levin. Without written report.</text>
        <type>Committee</type>
        <actionCode>14000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssas00</systemCode>
            <name>Armed Services Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000261</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Levin, Carl [D-MI]</fullName>
        <firstName>CARL</firstName>
        <lastName>LEVIN</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MI</state>
        <middleName>MILTON</middleName>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Arms control agreements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Arms control negotiations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Auditing</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Authorization</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Cold War</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congress and military policy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional investigations</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Congressional reporting requirements</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense budgets</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Defense contracts</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Department of Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Economics and Public Finance</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Energy</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental Protection</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Environmental assessment</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Fissionable materials</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government Operations and Politics</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government contractors</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Government trust funds</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Hazardous wastes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>History</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Idaho</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>International Affairs</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Laboratories</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Missile warheads</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nevada</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>New Mexico</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear energy research</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear fuels</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear nonproliferation</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear reactors</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear security measures</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Nuclear weapons</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Pennsylvania</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Plutonium</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Potable water</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Radioactive wastes</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Research and development facilities</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Russia</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Science, Technology, Communications</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Strategic forces</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Tennessee</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Texas</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Treaty-making power</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Warships</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Water Resources Development</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Armed Forces and National Security</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-08-07T19:33:10Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008 - Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY2008 for: (1) activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration in carrying out programs necessary for national security, with specified allocations for weapons activities, defense nuclear nonproliferation, naval reactors, the Office of the Administrator for Nuclear Security, and the International Atomic Energy Agency Nuclear Fuel Bank; and (2) environmental management activities in carrying out national security programs, with specified allocations for defense environmental cleanup, other defense activities, and defense nuclear waste disposal. Earmarks funds for the Reliable Replacement Warhead program.</p> <p>Authorizes appropriations for FY2008 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>80</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Reported to Senate without amendment</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2007-08-24T20:35:56Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p><b>(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary has been expanded because action occurred on the measure.)</b></p> <p>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008<b> - Title XXXI [<i>sic</i>]: Department of Energy National Security Programs - Subtitle A: National Security Programs Authorizations </b>- (Sec. 3101) Authorizes appropriations for the Department of Energy (DOE) for FY2008 for: (1) activities of the National Nuclear Security Administration in carrying out programs necessary for national security, with specified allocations for weapons activities, defense nuclear nonproliferation activities, naval reactors, the Office of the Administrator for Nuclear Security, and the International Atomic Energy Agency Nuclear Fuel Bank; and (2) environmental restoration and waste management activities in carrying out national security programs, with specified allocations for defense environmental cleanup, other defense activities, and defense nuclear waste disposal.</p> <p><b>Subtitle B: Program Authorizations, Restrictions, and Limitations </b>- (Sec. 3111) Authorizes specified DOE funds to be obligated or expended for the Reliable Replacement Warhead program, but not beyond phase 2A activities.</p> <p>(Sec. 3112) Prohibits any FY2008 fissile materials disposition program funds from being obligated or expended until the Secretary of Energy (Secretary) submits to the defense and appropriations committees a plan for the expenditure of such funds that remain available as of October 1, 2007. Prohibits the aggregate amount that may be obligated for such program within FY2008 program funds from exceeding the amount that the Secretary certifies to such committees will be obligated for that program in fiscal years 2008 and 2009. Provides conditions for the availability of unutilized funds: (1) absent the latter certification; and (2) under certification of partial use.</p> <p>(Sec. 3113) Amends the John Warner National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2007 relating to the availability of funds for the Waste Treatment and Immobilization plant to: (1) remove the requirement that the Defense Contract Management Agency review and recommend for implementation the earned value management system to be used by the construction contractor at the plant; and (2) instead require an independent entity to conduct such review.</p> <p><b>Subtitle C: Other Matters </b>- (Sec. 3121) Amends the: (1) National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2004 to repeal certain requirements with respect to the nuclear test readiness posture; and (2) Atomic Energy Defense Act to require the Secretary to report to the defense and appropriations committees on U.S. nuclear test readiness. (Under current law, the Secretary is required to report to Congress on costs and programmatic and other issues associated with the conduct of nuclear tests within specified time frames.)</p> <p>(Sec. 3122) Expresses the sense of Congress that, among other things: (1) the United States should reaffirm its commitment to the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Treaty (Treaty) and initiate talks with Russia to reduce its number of strategic and non-strategic nuclear weapons; (2) the United States and other Treaty parties should work to reduce the total number of nuclear weapons in their respective stockpiles; (3) the United States, Russia, and other states should work to negotiate and ratify a treaty for the cessation of production of fissile material; (4) the Senate should ratify the Comprehensive Nuclear-Test-Ban Treaty; (5) the United States should commit to dismantle as soon as possible all retired warheads; and (6) the United States and other Treaty parties should work to decrease the reliance on, and importance of, nuclear weapons.</p> <p>(Sec. 3123) Directs the: (1) Secretary to report to the defense and appropriations committees and the Comptroller General (CG) on the status of environmental initiatives undertaken to accelerate the reduction of environmental risks and challenges posed by the legacy of the Cold War; and (2) CG to review the report and report results to such committees.</p> <p>(Sec. 3124) Requires a report from the CG to the defense committees on the management of the protective forces of DOE.</p> <p><b>Title XXXII: Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board </b>- (Sec. 3201) Authorizes appropriations for FY2008 for the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Board.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Reported to Senate</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
        <chamberCode>S</chamberCode>
        <chamberName>Senate</chamberName>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>Department of Energy National Security Act for Fiscal Year 2008</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 2008 for defense activities of the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Placed on Calendar Senate</type>
        <date>2007-06-05T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-110s1550pcs/xml/BILLS-110s1550pcs.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2007-06-05</actionDate>
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 188.</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
