<bill session="118" type="h" number="5691" updated="2024-10-29T16:33:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Drought Assistance Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drought Assistance Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve drought related disaster assistance programs of the Department of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001125" joined="2024-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2024-02-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000591" joined="2023-10-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3836" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-10-29T16:32:51Z" status="Introduced in House">Drought Assistance Improvement Act

This bill modifies access to two Farm Service Agency (FSA) administered programs: the Livestock Forage Disaster Program (LFP) and the Emergency Assistance for Livestock, Honey Bees, and Farm-Raised Fish Program (ELAP).

The bill modifies the LFP to allow for one monthly payment when a county has four consecutive weeks of a D2 rating (severe drought) and two payments for eight consecutive weeks of D2. Currently, one payment is available for eight consecutive weeks of D2. (LFP makes payments to eligible livestock producers who have suffered grazing losses on drought-affected pastureland, including cropland planted specifically for grazing.)

The bill also expands coverage under ELAP for losses caused by adverse weather or drought. The bill includes under ELAP the loss of a crawfish harvest due to adverse weather or drought. (ELAP provides payments to producers of livestock, honey bees, and farm-raised fish as compensation for losses due to disease, adverse weather, feed or water shortages, or other conditions that are not covered under other programs.)

The FSA must&#160;establish ELAP documentation standards for (1) collecting data, (2) the production of crawfish,&#160;and (3) defining loss conditions due to drought.&#160; &#160;</summary>
</bill>
