<bill session="111" type="h" number="6215" updated="2023-01-11T13:21:34Z">
  <state datetime="2010-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Coast Act of 2010</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To authorize the Secretary of Commerce to establish a program to develop a coordinated and comprehensive Federal coastal mapping effort for the Nation's coastal zone to include all coastal State and territorial waters of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Coast Act of 2010</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000576"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting, cable, digital technologies"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-11-19T20:13:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Coast Act of 2010 - Defines "digital coast" as a constituent-driven platform provided by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to integrate geospatial data and address coastal and emergency management issues.

Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Director of Coastal Services Center of the NOAA, to establish coastal service centers to address the needs of local, state, and regional entities involved with coastal and ocean decisionmaking. Declares that such centers shall: (1) link people, information, and technology to support the environmental, social, and economic well-being of the coast; (2) collaborate with branches of NOAA and other federal and nongovernmental entities to bring data, information, services, and tools to coastal and ocean decisionmakers; and (3) address region-specific needs at local, state, and regional levels.

Authorizes the Secretary to enter financial agreements to carry out this Act.

Requires such projects to collect and integrate coastal data with specified data sources, surveys, and mappings. Requires the Secretary to coordinate activities with NOAA, state and local governments, the private sector, and federal efforts.</summary>
</bill>
