<bill session="117" type="h" number="9592" updated="2023-11-02T12:15:27Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Trucker Bathroom Access Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trucker Bathroom Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 49, United States Code, with respect to restroom access for certain drivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000026"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001085" joined="2022-12-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Highways and Transit.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW12" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Highways and Transit" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Motor carriers"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-02-24T19:29:29Z" status="Introduced in House">Trucker Bathroom Access Act

This bill expands access to restroom facilities for certain commercial truck drivers, including drayage truck operators. Drayage truck operator means the driver of any in-use on-road vehicle with a gross vehicle weight rating of greater than 33,000 pounds operating on or transgressing through port or intermodal rail yard property for the purpose of loading, unloading, or transporting cargo, including containerized, bulk, or break-bulk goods.

Specifically, the bill requires (1) retailers, warehouses, and other establishments to give commercial truck drivers access to existing restroom facilities when they are loading or delivering cargo; and (2) operators of ports and marine terminals to provide drayage truck operators with access to existing restrooms, additional restrooms if necessary, and parking while accessing such restrooms.</summary>
</bill>
