<bill session="111" type="sr" number="697" updated="2017-12-13T21:32:36Z">
  <state datetime="2010-12-08">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A resolution recognizing the 15th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution recognizing the 15th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000944"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-12-08">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2010-12-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S8655" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8655" label="text as passed Senate"/>
      <reference ref="CR S8642" label="text of measure as introduced"/>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Bosnia and Herzegovina"/>
    <term name="Commemorative events and holidays"/>
    <term name="Conflicts and wars"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Historic sites and heritage areas"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="Military assistance, sales, and agreements"/>
    <term name="Military history"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-12-09T21:16:38Z" status="Passed Senate without amendment">(This measure has not been amended since it was introduced. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

Recognizes the 15th anniversary of the Dayton Peace Accords.

 Encourages the government of Bosnia and Herzegovina to adhere to the membership requirements of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) so that Bosnia and Herzegovina may join the alliance without delay.

 Encourages the further integration of European countries with the goal of establishing peace and economic prosperity for all of the people of Europe.

 Renews the commitment of the United States to support the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina.

 Urges the continuation of constitutional reforms, market-based economic growth, and improved dialogue between the people of Bosnia and Herzegovina and the government of Bosnia and Herzegovina.

 Encourages the U.S. Air Force to take appropriate measures to provide historical interpretation of the site of the Dayton Peace Accords to educate the public on the historical significance of the Dayton Peace Accords and the importance of negotiation in world peace.</summary>
</bill>
