<bill session="118" type="s" number="290" updated="2025-09-29T14:06:25Z">
  <state datetime="2023-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Preserving Our Commitment to Homeless Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Preserving Our Commitment to Homeless Veterans Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to ensure that the supported housing program of the Department of Veterans Affairs has not fewer than one program manager for every 35 rental assistance cases under such program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000595"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-07-28T10:51:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Preserving Our Commitment to Homeless Veterans Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs (VA) to provide case management support to local housing authorities under the VA-supported housing program. The program assists veterans who are homeless and their families in finding and sustaining permanent housing.

The VA must ensure that no case manager is concurrently assigned to more than 35 veterans in each fiscal year, but may waive the requirement for a particular case manager in a particular fiscal year if it determines such a waiver is appropriate.

The VA must also ensure that each veteran to whom a case manager is assigned is located within a reasonable distance of the case manager.

If a case manager position within the Veterans Health Administration is vacant for a period of 180 days or more, the VA must seek to enter a contract with a qualified local service provider to furnish case management services until the position is filled.</summary>
</bill>
