<bill session="111" type="h" number="1999" updated="2023-01-11T13:19:33Z">
  <state datetime="2009-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Temporary Recession Aid for Schools and Taxpayers Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Secretary of Education to award grants to local governments that have experienced at least a 15 percent decrease in property tax revenues to fund certain elementary and secondary school education programs.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Temporary Recession Aid for Schools and Taxpayers Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001039"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-05-21">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED14" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="Early Childhood, Elementary, and Secondary Education" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Economic performance and conditions"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="State and local taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2009-05-27T15:30:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Temporary Recession Aid for Schools and Taxpayers Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to award three-year grants to local governments for elementary and secondary education programs within their jurisdiction if they experience at least a 15% decrease in property tax revenues from FY2008 to FY2009 or from FY2009 to FY2010.

Allows local governments to apply for two separate grants if they experience at least a 15% decrease in property tax revenues in each of such time periods.

Gives priority to local governments that experience the largest decreases in property tax revenues relative to their tax base and whose decrease is attributable to the permanent or temporary shutdown or closure of a large employer or several small employers.</summary>
</bill>
