<bill session="118" type="h" number="6733" updated="2025-11-18T18:52:31Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">American Investment Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Investment Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To monitor United States investments in entities that are controlled by foreign adversaries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001196"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000032" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001091" joined="2023-12-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000135" joined="2024-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000804" joined="2023-12-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-12">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Financial Services, and in addition to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3476" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-08-08T21:48:47Z" status="Introduced in House">American Investment Accountability Act

This bill requires periodic reporting on U.S. business and investment activity in countries of concern (i.e., China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Cuba, and Venezuela) and with covered entities. Under the bill, a covered entity (1) is an entity headquartered in, is subject to the jurisdiction of, or is owned or controlled by a country of concern; (2) is partially or wholly owned by a sanctioned entity; (3) has a subsidiary or parent organization headquartered in, or is subject to the jurisdiction of, a country of concern; or (4) has a specified interest in a sanctioned entity.

The Department of Commerce must report on the value of direct investments by U.S. persons in countries of concern and in covered entities, disaggregated by sector and state of origin, and accounting for investment occurring offshore. Commerce must also report on the number of large direct investments by U.S. persons in countries of concern.

The Department of the Treasury must report on the value of portfolio investments by U.S. persons in countries of concern and in covered entities, disaggregated by sector and state of origin, and accounting for investment occurring offshore. Treasury must also report on the number of large portfolio investments by U.S. persons in countries of concern and the value of U.S. portfolio investments in IPOs of covered entities.

The Securities and Exchange Commission must report on relationships (e.g. joint ventures, mergers, acquisitions, or investments) U.S. businesses have with countries of concern and covered entities.</summary>
</bill>
