<bill session="116" type="h" number="1800" updated="2022-11-01T18:02:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Solutions to End Homelessness Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To modify the minimum allocation requirement for the emergency solutions grants program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Solutions to End Homelessness Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001165"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Financial Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Financial Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="812" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development funding"/>
    <term name="Poverty and welfare assistance"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Urban and suburban affairs and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-02-26T19:55:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Solutions to End Homelessness Act of 2019

This bill reallocates to urban counties, under certain circumstances, Emergency Solutions Grant funds to help individuals and families regain permanent housing after experiencing a housing crisis or homelessness.

Currently, if such funds going to a metropolitan city or an urban county are less than a specified amount, the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) typically reallocates the funds to the state in which the city or county is located. The bill generally maintains this reallocation arrangement but also establishes certain circumstances when such funds shall go directly to the recipient or be reallocated elsewhere.

Generally, under the bill, if such aid going to a metropolitan city is less than a specified amount, HUD must reallocate the funds to the urban county in which the city is located if the county elects to receive, and has previously administered, such aid. However, the bill maintains an existing provision whereby a metropolitan city shall receive the funds directly if (1) the state does not have counties as local governments, (2) the city has a specified population, and (3) the city has previously received a certain amount of such funds.

Similarly, HUD must distribute these funds directly to an urban county receiving less than a specified amount if the county has previously received and administered such funds.

An urban county receiving reallocated funds must spend such funds for the benefit of the metropolitan cities located within the county.</summary>
</bill>
