<bill session="118" type="h" number="4639" updated="2025-05-27T14:15:11Z">
  <state datetime="2024-04-17T17:52:55-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-04-17T17:52:55-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fourth Amendment Is Not For Sale Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Fourth Amendment Is Not For Sale Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Fourth Amendment Is Not For Sale Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fourth Amendment Is Not For Sale Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend section 2702 of title 18, United States Code, to prevent law enforcement and intelligence agencies from obtaining subscriber or customer records in exchange for anything of value, to address communications and records in the possession of intermediary internet service providers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001302" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000298" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001184" joined="2023-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2023-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on the Judiciary, and in addition to the Committee on Intelligence (Permanent Select), for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported by the Yeas and Nays: 30 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15">
      <text>Reported by the Committee on Judiciary. H. Rept. 118-459, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-15">
      <text>Committee on Intelligence (Permanent) discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-04-15" calendar="Union" number="381">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 381.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16T09:28:50-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1149 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6323, H. Res. 1143, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, H.R. 6046 and H.R. 4639. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6323, H. Res. 1143, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, and H.R. 6046 under a closed rule, and for consideration of H.R. 4639 under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each measure and one motion to recommit on H.R. 6323, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, H.R. 6046, and H.R. 4639.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-16T14:13:28-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1149 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T12:22:04-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1149.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2459-2468" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H2463-2465" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T12:22:09-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 6323, H. Res. 1143, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, H.R. 6046 and H.R. 4639. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 6323, H. Res. 1143, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, and H.R. 6046 under a closed rule, and for consideration of H.R. 4639 under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of debate on each measure and one motion to recommit on H.R. 6323, H.R. 4691, H.R. 5947, H.R. 6046, and H.R. 4639.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T12:22:16-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1149 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T12:22:17-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Jerry L. Carl to act as Chairman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T12:23:32-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 4639.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:00:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:04:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Higgins (LA) amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:12:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1149, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the LaLota amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:20:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the LaLota amendment No. 3, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. LaLota demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:21:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Davidson moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:21:39-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T13:22:11-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 4639 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:01:32-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H2480-2481" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:01:52-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:42:13-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 4639.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:44:00-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:44:15-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="136" datetime="2024-04-17T17:52:55-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 219 - 199, 1 Present (Roll no. 136).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-04-17T17:52:56-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-04-18">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged From, Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Reported By, Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6570" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="2576" relation="identical"/>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1149" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h885"/>
    <amendment number="h884"/>
    <amendment number="h883"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-04-15T19:52:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Fourth Amendment Is Not For Sale Act

This bill expands prohibited disclosures of stored electronic communications under the Stored Communications Act.

The Stored Communications Act generally prohibits certain technology providers&#8212;remote computing service (RCS) providers and electronic communication service (ECS) providers&#8212;from disclosing the contents of stored electronic communications to anyone, including the government; and records or information pertaining to a customer or subscriber to a government entity.

This bill extends the general prohibitions on disclosure to an additional type of technology provider: intermediary service providers. Intermediary service providers (commonly referred to as data brokers) are companies that deliver, store, or process communications for RCS and ECS providers.

The bill also limits the authority of law enforcement agencies and intelligence agencies to access certain customer and subscriber records or illegitimately obtained information. With respect to such records, the bill

 prohibits law enforcement agencies and intelligence agencies from obtaining the records or information from a third party in exchange for anything of value (e.g., purchasing them); prohibits other government agencies from sharing the records or information with law enforcement agencies and intelligence agencies; and prohibits the use of such records or information in any trial, hearing, or proceeding. Additionally, the bill requires the government to obtain a court order before aquiring certain customer and subscriber records or any illegitimately obtained information from a third party.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-459</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
