<bill session="117" type="h" number="4322" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To identify and combat corruption in countries, to establish a tiered system of countries with respect to levels of corruption by their governments and their efforts to combat such corruption, and to evaluate foreign persons engaged in grand corruption for inclusion as specially designated nationals under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act.</title>
    <title type="display">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001061" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001068" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001120" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000616" joined="2021-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000168" joined="2021-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-07-01">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration and Citizenship.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="14" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5209" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crime victims"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure and sentencing"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy, foreign officials, Americans abroad"/>
    <term name="Employment discrimination and employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy storage, supplies, demand"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Germany"/>
    <term name="Government ethics and transparency, public corruption"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International law and treaties"/>
    <term name="International organizations and cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Russia"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty, recognition, national governance and status"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-12-14T17:34:18Z" status="Introduced in House">Combating Global Corruption Act of 2021

This bill requires the Department of State to address corruption, including related to the Nord Stream 2 pipeline (a national gas pipeline expected to increase Russia's natural gas export capacity).

The State Department must annually publish a ranking of foreign countries based on their government's efforts to eliminate corruption.

The bill outlines the minimum standards that the State Department must consider when creating the ranking. These considerations include, for example, whether a country has criminalized corruption, adopted measures to prevent corruption, and complied with the United Nations Convention Against Corruption and other relevant international agreements. Tier one countries meet the standards; tier two countries make some efforts to meet the standards; tier three countries make de minimis or no efforts to meet the standards.

If a country is ranked in the second or third tier, the State Department must designate an anti-corruption contact at the U.S. diplomatic post in that country to promote good governance and combat corruption.

The bill also requires the State Department, in coordination with the Department of the Treasury, to evaluate whether to impose asset- and visa-blocking sanctions against foreign persons engaged in significant corruption (1) in tier three countries, or (2) related to the Nord Stream 2 pipeline. The State Department must report to Congress about any sanctions imposed under this bill. The evaluation and reporting requirements concerning the Nord Stream 2 pipeline terminate after five years.</summary>
</bill>
