<bill session="119" type="h" number="2333" updated="2025-10-25T08:05:47Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Protecting Students with Disabilities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Protecting Students with Disabilities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of appropriated funds to eliminate, consolidate, or otherwise restructure any office within the Department of Education that administers or enforces programs under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M001231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001285" joined="2025-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001315" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001112" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001110" joined="2025-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001119" joined="2025-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000296" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000483" joined="2025-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001068" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000305" joined="2025-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000601" joined="2025-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000397" joined="2025-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001208" joined="2025-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001225" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000613" joined="2025-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000621" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000599" joined="2025-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001190" joined="2025-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000344" joined="2025-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2025-10-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000468" joined="2025-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000830" joined="2025-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Education and Workforce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-09-04T15:55:13Z" status="Introduced in House">Protecting Students with Disabilities Act

This bill prohibits the use of appropriated funds to eliminate the Department of Education's (ED's) oversight of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (IDEA). (The IDEA authorizes grant programs that support special education and early intervention services for children with disabilities. Currently, the IDEA is administered by the Office of Special Education Programs&#160;in the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services&#160;in ED.)

Specifically, the bill prohibits the use of appropriated funds to eliminate, consolidate, or otherwise restructure any office within ED that administers or enforces programs under the IDEA.

Further, appropriated funds may not be used to (1) terminate, reassign, or alter the responsibilities of any personnel of any such office; or (2) contract with, or delegate to, any entity outside of ED to administer or enforce IDEA programs.

(On March 20, 2025, President Donald Trump signed an executive order titled Improving Education Outcomes by Empowering Parents, States, and Communities, calling for the closure of ED and giving authority over education to the states. Further, the Trump Administration has announced plans to transfer ED's oversight of services for students with disabilities to the Department of Health and Human Services.)</summary>
</bill>
