<bill session="108" type="h" number="4011" updated="2023-01-15T10:32:58Z">
  <state datetime="2004-10-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2004-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To promote human rights and freedom in the Democratic People's Republic of Korea, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000169"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000022" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000104" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000410" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2004-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001149" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000266" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001053" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000830" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000597" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000275" joined="2004-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000250" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000448" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000021" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2004-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001034" joined="2004-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000090" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001147" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000149" joined="2004-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000373" joined="2004-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000585" joined="2004-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000409" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2004-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000487" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000364" joined="2004-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2004-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000260" joined="2004-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000314" joined="2004-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on International Relations, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-03-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Immigration, Border Security, and Claims.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-04">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on International Relations. H. Rept. 108-478, Part I.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-05-04">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 6, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-06">
      <text>House Committee on Judiciary Granted an extension for further consideration ending not later than July 16, 2004.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-16">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2004-07-16" calendar="Union" number="368">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 368.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:44:44-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:45:08-04:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6508-6515" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:45:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 4011.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2004-07-21T18:57:57-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H6508-6511" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-07-21T18:58:01-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-07-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-07">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-28">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S9805-9806" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote2" datetime="2004-09-28" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-29">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T19:10:23-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Leach moved that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T19:10:34-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 40 minutes of debate on the motion to suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment to H.R. 4011.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="pingpong" datetime="2004-10-04T19:28:08-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion that the House suspend the rules and agree to the Senate amendment Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7981-7986" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7981-7984 " label="text as House agreed to Senate amendment"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-10-04T19:28:09-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2004-10-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2004-10-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="108-333" type="public" datetime="2004-10-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 108-333.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU01" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Immigration Integrity, Security, and Enforcement" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Admission of nonimmigrants"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Food"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed Forces and National Security"/>
    <term name="Arts, Culture, Religion"/>
    <term name="Capital punishment"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties, Minority Issues"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Defectors"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Diplomacy"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Dissenters"/>
    <term name="East Asia"/>
    <term name="Economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Food as a weapon"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Informers"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International arbitration"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International relief"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Labor and Employment"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Legal aid"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Malnutrition"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nongovernmental organizations"/>
    <term name="Nonprofit organizations"/>
    <term name="North Korea"/>
    <term name="Orphans"/>
    <term name="Political persecution"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="President and foreign policy"/>
    <term name="Prostitution"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Repatriation"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Right of asylum"/>
    <term name="Rule of law"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Slavery"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Social Welfare"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="State-sponsored terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3728"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2004-12-07T20:39:09Z" status="Public Law">(This measure has not been amended since it was passed by the Senate on September 28, 2004. The summary of that version is repeated here.)

North Korean Human Rights Act of 2004 - Title I: Promoting the Human Rights of North Koreans - (Sec. 101) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the human rights of North Koreans should remain a key concern in future negotiations between the United States, North Korea, and other parties in Northeast Asia; (2) the United States should increase its support for radio broadcasting to North Korea; (3) the United Nations (UN) has a significant role to play in promoting and improving human rights in North Korea, and the United Nations Commission on Human Rights' adoption of Resolution 2003/10 on the North Korean human rights situation was a positive step, with additional UN attention needed; and (4) the United Sates should explore the possibility of a regional human rights dialogue with North Korea that is modeled on the Helsinki process.

(Sec. 102) Authorizes the President to: (1) provide grants to private, nonprofit organizations to promote human rights, democracy, rule of law, and the development of a market economy in North Korea, including educational and cultural exchanges; and (2) increase the availability of information inside North Korea by increasing the availability of information sources not controlled by the Government of North Korea. Authorizes FY 2005 through 2008 appropriations.

(Sec. 107) Directs the President to appoint within the Department of State a Special Envoy for human rights in North Korea. (States that such person shall be a person of recognized distinction in the field of human rights.)

Title II: Assisting North Koreans in Need - (Sec. 201) Directs the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID) and the Secretary of State to report annually (for the next three years) on: (1) U.S. humanitarian assistance to North Koreans; (2) improvements in humanitarian transparency and monitoring inside North Korea; and (3) specific efforts by the United States and U.S. grantees to secure better monitoring and access.

(Sec. 202) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) significant increases above current U.S. support levels for humanitarian assistance inside North Korea should be conditioned upon substantial improvements in transparency, monitoring, and access to vulnerable populations throughout North Korea; (2) humanitarian assistance should be monitored so as to minimize the possibility of its political or military diversion; and (3) the United States should encourage other countries that provide food and other humanitarian assistance to North Korea to do so through monitored, transparent channels, rather than through direct, bilateral transfers to the Government of North Korea.

Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) U.S. humanitarian assistance to the Government of North Korea shall be delivered and monitored according to internationally recognized humanitarian standards, be provided on a needs and not political basis, and be made available to all vulnerable groups in North Korea, no matter where in the country they may be located; and (2) U.S. nonhumanitarian assistance to North Korea shall be contingent upon North Korean progress toward human rights protection, family reunification, prison reform, decriminalization of political activity, and disclosure of information respecting the abduction of citizens of Japan and the Republic of Korea.

(Sec. 203) Authorizes the President to provide assistance to organizations or persons that provide humanitarian assistance or legal assistance to North Koreans who are outside of North Korea without the permission of the Government of North Korea. States that such assistance should be used to provide: (1) humanitarian assistance to North Korean refugees, defectors, migrants, and orphans outside of North Korea, which may include support for refugee camps or temporary settlements; and (2) humanitarian assistance to North Korean women outside of North Korea who are victims of trafficking, or are in danger of being trafficked. Authorizes FY 2005 through 2008 appropriations.

Title III: Protecting North Korean Refugees - (Sec. 301) Directs the Secretary to report on the North Korean refugee situation and U.S. policy toward North Korean refugees and defectors, including: (1) an assessment of whether North Koreans in China have effective access to personnel of the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, and of whether the Government of China is fulfilling its obligations under the 1951 Convention Relating to the Status of Refugees; (2) an assessment of whether North Koreans have effective access to U.S. refugee and asylum processing; and (3) the total number of North Koreans who have been admitted into the United States as refugees or asylees in each of the past five years.

(Sec. 302) States that for refugee or asylum status under the Immigration and Nationality Act, a national of the Democratic Republic of Korea shall not be considered a national of the Republic of Korea.

(Sec. 303) Directs the Secretary to facilitate the submission of refugee applications by citizens of North Korea.

(Sec. 304) Expresses the sense of Congress that: (1) the Government of China has obligated itself to provide the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees (UNHCR) with unimpeded access to North Koreans inside its borders to enable UNHCR to determine whether they are refugees and whether they require assistance, and that UNHCR donor countries should press China for such access; and (2) should China refuse such access, UNHCR should assert its right of access through arbitration with China.

(Sec. 305) Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of Homeland Security to report annually (for the next six years) on: (1) the numbers of North Koreans admitted as refugees or political asylees; and (2) measures taken to facilitate access to the U.S. refugee program by persons fleeing countries of particular concern for violations of religious freedom.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 108-478</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
