<bill session="117" type="h" number="6490" updated="2022-12-30T03:49:01Z">
  <state datetime="2022-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Banning Insider Trading in Congress Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Banning Insider Trading in Congress Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to prohibit transactions involving certain financial instruments by Members of Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2022-02-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001192" joined="2022-02-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-01-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-01-25">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="3504" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-10-26T16:13:52Z" status="Introduced in House">Banning Insider Trading in Congress Act

This bill prohibits a Member of Congress or spouse of a Member from holding, purchasing, or selling certain investments. Any profit made in violation of the prohibition must be disgorged to the Treasury and may subject the Member to a civil fine. A loss from a transaction or holding involving a covered financial instrument that is conducted in violation of this bill may not be deducted from the amount of income tax owed by the applicable Member or spouse.

The bill also requires each Member to submit an annual certification of compliance and requires the Government Accountability Office to conduct a compliance audit.

The prohibition does not apply to assets held in a qualified blind trust or to a sale by a Member or spouse within 180 days after the bill is enacted or within 180 days after the Member commences service, for any Member who commences service after the bill is enacted.</summary>
</bill>
