<amendment session="118" chamber="h" number="169" updated="2024-03-18T20:16:17Z">
  <amends type="h" number="734" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2023-04-20T10:34:02-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <offered datetime="2023-04-20"/>
  <description>An amendment numbered 1 printed in House Report 118-37 to require the Comptroller General carry out a study to determine the meaning of the phrase 'any other benefit' as used in subsection (d)(3) by looking at the adverse psychological, developmental, participatory, and sociological results to girls of allowing males to compete, be members of a sports team, or participants in athletic programs, that are designed for girls, including hostile environment creation, sexual assault, and sexual harassment.</description>
  <purpose>Amendment requires the Comptroller General to carry out a study to determine the adverse effects of allowing biological men to compete in women's sports. The amendment looks at the adverse psychological, developmental participatory, and sociological results to girls of allowing males to compete, be members of a sports team, or participants in athletic programs that are designed specifically for girls, including hostile environment creation, sexual assault, and sexual harassment.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2023-04-20T10:34:02-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="190">
      <text>On agreeing to the Mace amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 205 (Roll no. 190).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20T09:14:46-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A001) offered by Ms. Mace.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1891-1894" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1891" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20T09:14:46-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A001) offered by Ms. Mace.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1891-1894" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1891" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20T10:34:02-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20T10:34:02-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-04-20T10:34:02-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Mace amendment (A001) Agreed to by recorded vote: 216 - 205 (Roll no. 190).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
