<bill session="116" type="h" number="3139" updated="2022-11-01T06:47:29Z">
  <state datetime="2019-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">STRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To better support our early childhood educators and elementary school and secondary school teachers, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">STRIVE Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Supporting the Teaching profession through Revitalizing Investments in Valuable Educators Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="N000188"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001081" joined="2020-09-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2019-08-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000096" joined="2019-06-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-05">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and Labor, and in addition to the Committee on Ways and Means, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and the Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="1866" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Child care and development"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Education of the disadvantaged"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="School administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education, employment, rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' loans, housing, homeless programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-26T20:00:26Z" status="Introduced in House">Supporting the Teaching profession through Revitalizing Investments in Valuable Educators Act or the STRIVE Act

This bill provides qualifying teachers with a new, incremental&#160;loan-cancellation program.

Specifically, with respect to a 12-month period,&#160;the Department of Education (ED) must cancel a specified portion of a borrower's qualifying Federal Direct Loan program loans if the borrower (1) has made 12 consecutive on-time monthly payments, (2) is employed in a qualifying teaching position at the time of such cancellation, and (3)&#160;was employed in a qualifying teaching position during the period in which the borrower made the 12 payments.&#160;After&#160;a borrower has received such partial loan&#160;cancellation for&#160;a specified&#160;number of years, ED&#160;must cancel the borrower's eligible loans in full.&#160;&#160;

The bill also

 increases and extends funding for teacher training; establishes grants for mentoring and professional development; makes changes to the Teacher Education Assistance for College and Higher Education&#160;grant program, including by making early childhood teachers eligible for such grants; requires&#160;ED to award grants to institutions of higher education to subsidize teacher certification and licensing fees for low-income individuals who have accepted a teaching position; expands the Teacher Quality Partnership grant program to include early childhood educators; and expands the centers for excellence grant program to include early childhood educators and school leaders.</summary>
</bill>
