<bill session="117" type="s" number="3907" updated="2022-12-29T22:33:29Z">
  <state datetime="2022-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2022-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Find and Protect Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Find and Protect Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to identify obstacles to identifying and responding to children missing from foster care and other vulnerable foster youth, to provide technical assistance relating to the removal of such obstacles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001243" joined="2022-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2022-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001070" joined="2022-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2022-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000570" joined="2022-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000595" joined="2022-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000595" joined="2022-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000770" joined="2022-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="7210" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-07-12T18:17:23Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Find and Protect Foster Youth Act

This bill requires the Office of the Administration for Children &amp; Families to evaluate the protocols that states have developed to comply with the reporting requirements for locating a child missing from foster care.

Additionally, the administration, through the Children's Bureau, must provide states, Indian tribes, tribal organizations, and tribal consortia with information, advice, educational materials, and technical assistance relating to eliminating identified obstacles to identifying and responding to children missing from foster care and other vulnerable foster youth and providing such children and youth with effective services.</summary>
</bill>
