<bill session="119" type="h" number="812" updated="2025-04-08T08:05:44Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MAKERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAKERS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Making Advances Kinetic Education, Research, and Skills Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Director of the National Science Foundation to award grants for, and support research on, the development of makerspaces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S001157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001072" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000454" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000477" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000309" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000305" joined="2025-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000472" joined="2025-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000488" joined="2025-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000081" joined="2025-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space, and Technology" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-03-18T18:48:10Z" status="Introduced in House">Making Advances Kinetic Education, Research, and Skills Act or the MAKERS Act

This bill requires the National Science Foundation (NSF) to award competitive grants to institutions of higher education to support research and development related to makerspaces. Under the bill, makerspaces are defined as community spaces that provide learners and entrepreneurs with tools, technology, and knowledge, and support educational opportunities for personal growth, workforce training, and early-stage business ventures.

Grant funds may be used to support research on the effectiveness of makerspaces in engaging students and communities in science, technology, engineering, and math (STEM), among other functions.

In awarding&#160;grants, the NSF must prioritize certain applicants, including (1) community colleges and minority-serving institutions; and (2) institutions that apply in partnership with workforce development entities, high-need local educational agencies, or independent nonprofit or academic makerspaces.</summary>
</bill>
