<bill session="116" type="s" number="1853" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:20Z">
  <state datetime="2019-12-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2019-12-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-06-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">BADGES for Native Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">BADGES for Native Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bridging Agency Data Gaps and Ensuring Safety for Native Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BADGES for Native Communities Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bridging Agency Data Gaps and Ensuring Safety for Native Communities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal law enforcement agencies to report on cases of missing or murdered Indians, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="U000039"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001113" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001197" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001153" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001203" joined="2019-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000464" joined="2019-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-06-19">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-12-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported by Senator Hoeven with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 116-230.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2020-06-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="476">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 476.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="4289" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="116" type="s" number="2920" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Crimes against women"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Employee hiring"/>
    <term name="Evidence and witnesses"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Minority health"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Personnel records"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-06-26T20:01:42Z" status="Reported to Senate">Bridging Agency Data Gaps and Ensuring Safety for Native Communities Act or the BADGES for Native Communities Act

This bill modifies policies and procedures related to information sharing, reporting, and investigating cases of missing, unidentified,&#160;or murdered Indians.

Among other elements, the bill requires the Department of Justice to

 share information, after receiving certain permission, with the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System (NamUs) on missing persons, unclaimed remains, and unidentified remains; ensure that technical assistance and training are provided to the Bureau of Indian Affairs (BIA) and tribal law enforcement agencies to utilize the National Crime Information Center (NCIC) and other national databases; establish the Tribal Civil and Criminal Information Access Program to enhance the ability of tribal governments to access, enter information into, and obtain information from federal criminal information databases; establish a grant program for specified entities (e.g., tribes) to implement changes to enhance their responses to missing person cases and death investigations of interest to tribes; and work with the Department of Health and Human Services to ensure that federal training resources and culturally appropriate mental health and wellness programs are available to tribal and BIA law enforcement officers experiencing occupational stress. The bill expands access to (1) the national crime information database for NamUs, and (2) the NCIC for each tribal justice official.

Finally, the Department of the Interior must establish a five-year demonstration program for the purpose of conducting or adjudicating personnel background investigations for applicants for law enforcement positions in the BIA.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 116-230</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
