<bill session="112" type="s" number="274" updated="2023-01-11T13:20:29Z">
  <state datetime="2011-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medication Therapy Management Empowerment Act of 2011</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to expand access to medication therapy management services under the Medicare prescription drug program.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medication Therapy Management Empowerment Act of 2011</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="H001049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000069" joined="2011-09-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001265" joined="2011-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001268" joined="2012-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2011-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000141" joined="2011-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000567" joined="2012-04-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2011-07-05"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000457" joined="2011-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000555" joined="2011-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000025" joined="2011-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000177" joined="2011-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2011-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2011-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000148" joined="2011-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000663" joined="2011-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000802" joined="2011-05-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000779" joined="2011-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S546-547"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Drug therapy"/>
    <term name="Health care quality"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-02-14T20:23:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Medication Therapy Management Empowerment Act of 2011 - Amends part D (Voluntary Prescription Drug Benefit Program) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act (SSA), as amended by the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, to increase the number of diseases and conditions for which beneficiaries may be targeted for medication therapy management (MTM) services.

Requires a Prescription Drug Plan (PDP) sponsor to establish a process, subject to approval by the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS), for identifying individuals who are not targeted beneficiaries, are not otherwise offered MTM services, and whom a pharmacist or other qualified provider determines may benefit from MTM services. Requires any such individual to be treated as a targeted beneficiary.

Requires any MTM program to offer both comprehensive and targeted medication reviews to individuals dually eligible for both Medicare and Medicaid (under SSA title XIX), regardless of whether they are MTM-targeted beneficiaries.

Requires a PDP sponsor to offer any willing pharmacy in its network and any other qualified health care provider the opportunity to provide MTM services.

Requires the PDP sponsor to reimburse pharmacists and other qualified health care providers furnishing MTM services based on the resources used and the time required to provide such services.

Directs the Secretary of HHS to: (1) establish measures and standards for data collection by PDP sponsors to evaluate performance of pharmacies and other entities in furnishing MTM services; and (2) support the continued development and refinement of performance measures.

Provides pharmacies and other entities that furnish MTM services with additional incentive payments based on their performance in meeting quality measures established under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
