<amendment session="108" chamber="s" number="2152" updated="2022-02-03T04:58:36Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2861" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2003-11-17">withdrawn</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001041"/>
  <offered datetime="2003-11-12"/>
  <description>To permit the use of funds for the Capital Asset Realignment for Enhanced Services (CARES) initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs for purposes of enhanced services while limiting the use of funds for the initiative for purposes of the closure or reduction of services pending a modification of the initiative to take into account long-term care, domiciliary care, and mental health services and other matters.</description>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Proposed amendment SA 2152 withdrawn in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-17">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14932" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-12">
      <text>Amendment SA 2152 proposed by Senator Clinton to Amendment SA 2150. (consideration: CR S14496-14504, S14508-14510; text: CR S14496-14497) To permit the use of funds for the Capital Asset Realignment for Enhanced Services (CARES) initiative of the Department of Veterans Affairs for purposes of enhanced services while limiting the use of funds for the initiative for purposes of the closure or reduction of services pending a modification of the initiative to take into account long-term care, domiciliary care, and mental health services and other matters.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-12">
      <text>Senate amendment proposed (on the floor): Amendment SA 2152 proposed by Senator Clinton to Amendment SA 2150.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S14496-14504, S14508-14510" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S14496-14497" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-11-12">
      <text>Senate amendment submitted</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
