<bill session="118" type="h" number="7466" updated="2025-02-04T16:54:13Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Do Your Job Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Do Your Job Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to reduce the rates of pay of Members of Congress during a fiscal year if Congress has not agreed to a concurrent resolution on the budget for such fiscal year, to repeal the automatic appropriation of funds for the salaries of Members of Congress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001309"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-28">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on House Administration, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Accountability, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Committee on House Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-04-02T16:59:41Z" status="Introduced in House">Do Your Job Act 

This bill reduces the pay for Members of Congress in certain circumstances, and it eliminates the automatic appropriation of funds for specified purposes.

Specifically, if Congress does not agree to a budget resolution by the beginning of a fiscal year, each Member's annual pay shall be reduced to 90% of that Member's pay in the previous fiscal year. This reduction shall apply after the November 2024 general election.

In addition, the bill eliminates the automatic appropriation of funds for Members' compensation and for certain administrative expenses.</summary>
</bill>
