<bill session="119" type="s" number="508" updated="2025-11-19T04:58:14Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act relating to grants for beach monitoring, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="display">BEACH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">BEACH Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2025</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000779"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000476" joined="2025-02-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="119" type="h" number="583" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-07-29T20:51:47Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Beaches Environmental Assessment and Coastal Health Act of 2025 or the BEACH Act of 2025

This bill reauthorizes through FY2029 and expands an existing program of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) that awards grants to states and local governments to (1) monitor the water quality of coastal recreational waters adjacent to beaches or similar points of access that are used by the public; and (2) notify the public, local governments, and the EPA when the water is not safe for recreational activities.

Specifically, the bill expands the program to allow the EPA to award grants for identifying sources of contamination (i.e., pathogens) for coastal recreation waters. It also allows grants to be used for monitoring and notification of contamination in (1) shallow waters upstream from recreational waters, and (2) recreational waters on beaches.</summary>
</bill>
