<bill session="112" type="h" number="914" updated="2021-04-19T18:15:19Z">
  <state datetime="2011-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Internship Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Internship Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To improve Federal internships by expanding the conversion rate of Federal interns to full-time employees, establish consistent tracking mechanisms among Executive agencies for internship programs, and accelerate adoption of internship best management practices by Executive agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001078"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000461" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000984" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001137" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000523" joined="2011-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2011-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Government Reform.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-03-18">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Federal Workforce, U.S. Postal Service, and Labor Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSGO25" name="House Oversight and Accountability" subcommittee="Information Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-03-14T16:22:19Z" status="Introduced in House">Federal Internship Improvement Act - Directs the head of each federal agency operating an internship program to appoint an internship coordinator within the agency.

Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to make publicly available on the Internet: (1) the coordinator's name and contact information and information regarding application procedures and deadlines for the program, and (2) links to the websites where such information is displayed.

Requires OPM to establish a centralized electronic database that contains the names, contact information, and relevant skills of individuals who have completed or are nearing completion of an internship program and are currently seeking full-time federal employment.

Requires the agency operating an internship program to conduct an exit interview, and administer a survey, with each intern who completes the program.</summary>
</bill>
