<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="548" updated="2022-02-03T06:03:24Z">
  <amends type="h" number="2219" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2011-07-07T15:23:00-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000369"/>
  <offered datetime="2011-07-07"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following:    SEC.___. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to enter into a contract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, or provide a loan or loan guarantee to, any United States commercial air carrier if that contract, memorandum of understanding, cooperative agreement, loan, or loan guarantee allows the air carrier to charge baggage fees to any member of the Armed Forces who is traveling on official military orders and is being deployed overseas or is returning from an overseas deployment.</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to enter into a contract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, make a grant to, or provide a loan or loan guarantee to, any United States commerical air carrier if that air carrier charges baggage fees to any member of the Armed Forces who is traveling on official military orders.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2011-07-07T15:23:00-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Kissell amendment (A043) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07T15:20:08-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A043) offered by Mr. Kissell.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4707" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4707" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07T15:23:00-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Kissell amendment (A043) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07T15:20:08-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by: Amendment (A043) offered by Mr. Kissell.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4707" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4707" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-07-07">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
