<bill session="116" type="s" number="1385" updated="2022-02-08T23:21:46Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the awarding of a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that the contractor or grantee has no seriously delinquent tax debts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000393"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001310" joined="2019-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Debt collection"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-13T17:16:09Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Contracting and Tax Accountability Act of 2019

This bill prohibits an executive agency from awarding a contract or grant in excess of the simplified acquisition threshold unless the prospective contractor or grantee certifies in writing to the agency awarding the contract or grant that the contractor or grantee has no seriously delinquent tax debt. Simplified acquisition threshold means the dollar amount below which a nonfederal entity may purchase property or services using small purchase methods.

The bill (1) authorizes the Department of the Treasury to disclose to an agency whether such person has a seriously delinquent tax debt, and (2) subjects a person with such debt to suspension or debarment from the federal procurement process.

The bill defines seriously delinquent tax debt as a federal tax liability that has been assessed by the Internal Revenue Service and is collectible by levy or a court proceeding, with exceptions for a tax debt (1) that is being paid in a timely manner under an approved installment agreement or an offer-in-compromise, (2) for which a collection due process hearing has been requested or is pending, (3) for which a continuous levy has been issued or agreed to by an applicant for employment, or (4) with respect to which such a levy is released because it has been determined to be an economic hardship to the taxpayer.</summary>
</bill>
