<bill session="117" type="s" number="4101" updated="2022-12-31T05:17:14Z">
  <state datetime="2022-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2022-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Combating Human Rights Abuses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Combating Human Rights Abuses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Combating Human Rights Abuses Act of 2022</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Commerce to provide training and guidance relating to human rights abuses, including such abuses perpetrated against the Uyghur population by the Government of the People's Republic of China, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000571" joined="2022-04-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-25" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-12-15">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Cantwell without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-12-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="661">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 661.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="U.S. and foreign investments"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-23T15:46:37Z" status="Reported to Senate">Combating Human Rights Abuses Act of 2022

This bill requires the Department of Commerce to offer guidance to U.S. businesses, including those considering transactions with entities subject to the influence of countries where significant human rights abuses have occurred, about issues such as (1) the human rights abuses perpetuated by China's government, (2) risk factors that may be used to identify entities subject to the influence of governments implicated in human rights abuses, and (3) ways to avoid doing business with such entities.

Commerce must also provide training related to human rights issues to Commerce employees who provide counseling services to businesses.</summary>
</bill>
