<bill session="110" type="h" number="2961" updated="2023-01-11T21:19:55Z">
  <state datetime="2007-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2007-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the boundaries of the Wallkill National Wildlife Refuge located in Sussex county, New Jersey, and to authorize appropriations for the acquisition of lands and waters located within such expanded boundaries.</title>
    <title type="display">To expand the boundaries of the Wallkill National Wildlife Refuge located in Sussex county, New Jersey, and to authorize appropriations for the acquisition of lands and waters located within such expanded boundaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000548"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2007-07-16">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Fisheries, Wildlife, and Oceans.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII15" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Oversight and Investigations" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2007-08-29T20:25:20Z" status="Introduced in House">Expands the boundaries of the Walkill National Wildlife Refuge located in Sussex County, New Jersey, to include the Mt. Laurel property-added lands (including any water and interest in such lands).

Authorizes Secretary of the Interior to make such minor modifications to the boundary of the Refuge as the Director of the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service (USFWS) determines to be appropriate to: (1) achieve the goals of the USFWS relating to the Refuge; or (2) facilitate the acquisition of property within the Refuge.

Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for the acquisition of such lands. Requires any land, water, or interest acquired by the Secretary pursuant to this Act to become part of the Refuge.</summary>
</bill>
