<bill session="118" type="h" number="7271" updated="2025-05-27T14:13:29Z">
  <state datetime="2024-02-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2024-02-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-02-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Fiscally Responsible Israel Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fiscally Responsible Israel Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making emergency supplemental appropriations to respond to the attacks in Israel for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2024, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001302"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000825" joined="2024-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001116" joined="2024-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000595" joined="2024-02-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000190" joined="2024-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000175" joined="2024-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-02-07">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Appropriations, and in addition to the Committee on the Budget, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6126" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="7217" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="3210" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="6730" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-13T13:38:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Fiscally Responsible Israel Security Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2024

This bill provides FY2024 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) and the Department of State for activities to respond to the attacks in Israel. The bill designates the funding as emergency spending, which is exempt from discretionary spending limits.

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations to DOD for

 Military Personnel; Operation and Maintenance; Procurement; Research, Development, Test and Evaluation; Defense Working Capital Funds; and the Defense Health Program. The funding is provided for purposes such as

 supporting current U.S. military operations in the region; replacing defense articles that were provided to Israel; reimbursing DOD for defense services and training provided to Israel; and procuring Israel's Iron Dome, David's Sling, and Iron Beam defense systems to counter short-range rocket threats. The bill also provides appropriations to the State Department for

 Diplomatic Programs, Emergencies in the Diplomatic and Consular Service, and the Foreign Military Financing Program. The funding is provided to the State Department for purposes such as (1) increasing security at U.S. embassies impacted by the attacks on Israel, and (2) conducting emergency evacuations of U.S. government personnel and citizens in the region.

In addition, the bill includes provisions that expand the authorities of the President to transfer defense articles and services from DOD to Israel.

Finally, the bill rescinds specified unobligated funds that were provided for the Department of Commerce Nonrecurring Expenses Fund by the Fiscal Responsibility Act of 2023.</summary>
</bill>
