<bill session="118" type="s" number="779" updated="2025-11-19T03:45:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ACTION for National Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACTION for National Service Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s Call To Improve Opportunities Now for National Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an AmeriCorps Administration to carry out the national and volunteer service programs, to expand participation in such programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000122"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001230" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001277" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000944" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001088" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000622" joined="2023-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2023-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S774" label="Sponsor introductory remarks on measure"/>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="h" number="1588" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Health programs administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-02-29T23:08:35Z" status="Introduced in Senate">America's Call To Improve Opportunities Now for National Service Act or the ACTION for National Service Act

This bill reauthorizes and revises various national and community volunteer service programs.

Specifically, it (1)&#160;renames the Corporation for National and Community Service&#160;as the AmeriCorps Administration, converts it from a government corporation into an executive department, and revises its membership, leadership, and authority; (2) reauthorizes&#160;programs carried out by the administration; (3)&#160;establishes a National Service Foundation to accept and administer gifts on behalf of the administration; (4) generally increases the living allowance amounts for program participants and excludes the amounts from taxable income; and (5) makes the national service educational award amount equal to twice the national average yearly cost for in-state tuition and fees at public, four-year institutions of higher education.

Additionally, the bill creates an interagency Civilian Climate Corps, operated by the administration, to conduct service projects addressing climate change.</summary>
</bill>
