<bill session="116" type="h" number="5639" updated="2022-08-10T23:25:36Z">
  <state datetime="2020-07-30">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2020-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Chuck Osier Burial Benefits Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to furnish urns for the remains of certain veterans whose cremated remains are not interred in certain cemeteries.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chuck Osier Burial Benefits Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001308"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000466" joined="2020-01-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2020-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-01-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-02-07">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-07-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Discharged, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Veterans' organizations and recognition"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-02-24T16:25:17Z" status="Introduced in House">Chuck Osier Burial Benefits Act

This bill requires the Department of Veterans Affairs to furnish an urn or commemorative plaque in lieu of a headstone or marker to eligible deceased individuals if requested. Specifically, the United States must pay for an urn (in which the remains of such individual may be placed at private expense) or a commemorative plaque signifying the individual's status as a veteran.

Eligible deceased individuals are those who

 served in the Armed Forces on or after April 6, 1917; are buried in a private cemetery but eligible for burial in a national cemetery; are buried in a private cemetery and were entitled to a headstone, marker or medallion (or would have been but for their age); and were cremated and not interred in a national cemetery, a state veterans' cemetery, a tribal cemetery, or a private cemetery.</summary>
</bill>
