<bill session="117" type="h" number="2873" updated="2023-05-11T15:46:24Z">
  <state datetime="2021-09-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2021-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Affordable Prescriptions for Patients Through Promoting Competition Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to prohibit product hopping, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Affordable Prescriptions for Patients Through Promoting Competition Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001297" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000627" joined="2021-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000087" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000002" joined="2021-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000147" joined="2021-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-09-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 27 - 16.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="s" number="1435" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5260" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="5237" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition and antitrust"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Drug safety, medical device, and laboratory regulation"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Health care costs and insurance"/>
    <term name="Inflation and prices"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-03-18T16:28:01Z" status="Introduced in House">Affordable Prescriptions for Patients Through Promoting Competition Act of 2021

This bill prohibits product hopping by drug manufacturers and authorizes the Federal Trade Commission to sue in court or institute administrative proceedings to enforce this prohibition.

Generally, product-hopping describes a situation where, when the patents on a reference drug (or biological product) expire, the manufacturer switches to a follow-on product that is covered by a later-expiring patent. Under this bill, a follow-on product is a changed, modified, or reformulated version of the reference drug that shares an indication (what the drug is used for) with the reference drug.

The bill presumes product hopping has occurred when a reference drug manufacturer engages in a hard switch or a soft switch. A hard switch occurs when, after receiving notice of an application for Food and Drug Administration (FDA) approval to market a generic (or biosimilar) version of the reference drug, the manufacturer markets a follow-on product and (1) the FDA withdraws approval of the reference drug at the manufacturer's request, or (2) the manufacturer announces the withdrawal or discontinuance of the reference drug or destroys the drug's inventory in a manner that impedes generic competitors.

Furthermore, the bill presumes that a soft switch occurred if a reference drug manufacturer (1) markets a follow-on product, and (2) takes actions that disadvantage the reference drug relative to that follow-on product in a way that impedes competition from a generic drug.

A drug manufacturer may rebut these presumptions by demonstrating that its conduct was not intended to limit competition.</summary>
</bill>
