<bill session="118" type="s" number="3441" updated="2025-05-27T14:16:21Z">
  <state datetime="2023-12-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-12-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Terrorist Financing Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Terrorist Financing Prevention Act of 2023</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent Foreign Terrorist Organizations and their financial enablers, whether in currency or digital assets, from accessing financial and other institutions of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000805"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000122" joined="2023-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000615" joined="2023-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000605" joined="2023-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-02-08">
      <text>Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Hearings By (Full Committee), Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Currency"/>
    <term name="Digital media"/>
    <term name="Financial services and investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign and international banking"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Judicial review and appeals"/>
    <term name="Sanctions"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2024-07-23T21:06:50Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Terrorist Financing Prevention Act of 2023

This bill requires specified sanctions on foreign entities that facilitate financial transactions tied to foreign terrorist organizations.

The bill requires the Department of the Treasury to identify any foreign financial institution or foreign digital asset transaction facilitator that (1) has knowingly facilitated a significant financial transaction with a foreign terrorist organization or related person, or (2) has engaged in money laundering to carry out such a transaction.

The President must prohibit, or place restrictions on, opening or maintaining a U.S. correspondent or payable-through account by such an institution. Further, the President must prohibit any transactions between any person subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and a foreign digital asset transaction facilitator identified by Treasury under this bill.

The bill allows Treasury to prohibit or restrict certain fund transmittals if a foreign jurisdiction, institution, account, or transaction is of primary money laundering concern.</summary>
</bill>
