<bill session="112" type="h" number="1668" updated="2019-11-15T21:34:02Z">
  <state datetime="2011-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2011-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2011-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Danny McIntosh Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="display">Danny McIntosh Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To include nonprofit and volunteer ground and air ambulance crew members and first responders for certain benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="F000451"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001069" joined="2011-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2012-02-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2011-08-25">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="385" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="112" type="s" number="1696" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Employee benefits and pensions"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2011-05-16T18:57:14Z" status="Introduced in House">Danny McIntosh Emergency Medical Service Providers Protection Act - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1986 to include within the definitions of "member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew" and "public safety officer" for purposes of eligibility for public safety officers' benefits an officially recognized or designated employee or volunteer member of a rescue squad or ambulance crew that: (1) is a public agency or a nonprofit entity serving the public that is officially authorized or licensed to engage in rescue activity or to provide emergency medical services and that is officially designated as a prehospital emergency medical response agency, and (2) is engaging in rescue activity or in the provision of emergency medical services.

Cancels $12 million of unobligated balances available under the Department of Justice (DOJ) Assets Forfeiture Fund.

Makes this Act applicable to injuries sustained on or after June 1, 2009.</summary>
</bill>
