<bill session="116" type="h" number="7115" updated="2022-02-08T23:16:58Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Restoration of Civil Rights Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To expand the scope of section 1979 of the Revised Statutes, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Restoration of Civil Rights Act of 2019</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="V000131"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000288" joined="2020-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Due process and equal protection"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-07-10T14:02:32Z" status="Introduced in House">Restoration of Civil Rights Act of 2019

This bill expands remedies under provisions regarding civil actions for deprivation of rights under color of law.

Specifically, the bill provides that

 any person against whom such an action is filed for an act or omission taken in the person's official capacity may not raise as a defense that such act or omission did not violate a clearly established statutory or constitutional right; in any action filed in which a person is held liable for an act or omission taken in the person's official capacity, any state or territory (including the District of Columbia) of which the person is an employee shall be vicariously liable if the act or omission of the person is attributable to violations of the Fourteenth Amendment by the state or territory; any person who is an employee or contractor of a state or territory and is found to be liable for acts or omissions occurring in the course and scope of such person's employment or agreement is entitled to indemnification if the act or omission is taken in the person's official capacity and attributable to violations of the Fourteenth Amendment by the state or territory; and a U.S. Attorney may bring a civil action for a violation on behalf of any U.S. citizen or other person within the jurisdiction before the appropriate federal district court for appropriate relief.</summary>
</bill>
