<bill session="114" type="h" number="5485" updated="2023-01-11T13:32:46Z">
  <state datetime="2016-07-07T21:16:28-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2016-07-07T21:16:28-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2016-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">SOAR Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">SOAR Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2017</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">SOAR Reauthorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for financial services and general government for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2017, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001045"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2016-03-08">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-433.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-05">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-433.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-04-12">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations Senate Subcommittee on Financial Services and General Government. Hearings held. With printed Hearing: S.Hrg. 114-433.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-06-15">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 114-624, by Mr. Crenshaw.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-06-15" calendar="Union" number="484">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 484.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2016-06-21T21:41:11-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 794 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5485 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report, amendments en bloc described in section 3 of the resolution, and pro forma amendments described in section 4 of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-05T19:28:00-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 794 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T17:34:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 794.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4346-4392" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4362-4391" label="text of measure as reported in House"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T17:34:45-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 5485 with 1 hour of general debate. The resolution makes in order only those amendments printed in the report, amendments en bloc described in section 3 of the resolution, and pro forma amendments described in section 4 of the resolution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T17:34:57-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 794 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T17:34:58-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Cynthia M. Lummis to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T17:35:23-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 5485.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T18:35:43-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz raised a point of order against the content of the measure. Mr. Chaffetz raised a point of order against a provision in H.R. 5485, stating that it violated clause 2 of rule XXI, which prohibits changing existing law in an appropriations bill. The Chair sustained the point of order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T18:38:48-04:00">
      <text>Ms. Kaptur appealed the ruling of the Chair. The question was then put on sustaining the ruling of the Chair.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:12:21-04:00">
      <text>On sustaining the ruling of the Chair. Agreed to by recorded vote: 220 - 168 (Roll no. 356).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:12:32-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crenshaw moved that the commitee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:12:45-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the commitee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:12:55-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5485 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:14:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4419-4449" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:14:38-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:21:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:29:37-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:30:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duffy amendment No. 2.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:40:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Duffy amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Duffy demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:40:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Becerra amendment No. 3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:50:20-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Becerra amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Becerra demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T19:50:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:01:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Crenshaw demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:01:36-04:00">
      <text>UNANIMOUS CONSENT AGREEMENT - Mr. Crenshaw asked unanimous consent that amendments 5, 6, and 7 may be offered en bloc. Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:02:22-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to the previous unanimous consent request, Ms. Moore was recognized to offer amendments 5, 6, and 7.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:02:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore en bloc amendments #1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:10:34-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Moore amendments, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendments en bloc and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Moore demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendments until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:12:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Himes amendment No. 10.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:19:33-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Himes amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Himes demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:20:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the DeFazio amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:29:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the DeFazio amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Mr. DeFazio demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:29:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grayson amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:40:07-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grayson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Grayson demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:40:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Kildee amendment No. 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:50:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Kildee amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Kildee demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T20:51:02-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Eshoo amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:03:06-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Eshoo amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and announced by voice vote that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Eshoo demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:04:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment No. 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:13:42-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:14:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ellison amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:24:01-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ellison amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Ellison demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:25:06-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sewell amendment No. 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:35:54-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Sewell amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Sewell demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:36:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norton amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:49:25-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Norton amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Ms. Norton demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:50:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Amodei amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:57:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Amodei amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T21:59:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blackburn amendment No. 16.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T22:08:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blackburn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. McNerney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T22:09:56-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T23:23:35-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crenshaw moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T23:23:51-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-06T23:24:00-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5485 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:05:22-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR 7/6/2016 H4460-4464" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:05:48-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:06:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Blackburn amendment No. 22.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:19:21-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Blackburn amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:19:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Buck amendment No. 23.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:30:47-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Buck amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:34:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 749, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Davidson amendment No. 25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:42:17-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Davidson amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:42:39-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crenshaw moved that the Committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:42:54-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T00:43:05-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5485 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T14:30:09-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4497-4522" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T14:39:32-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T14:40:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Duffy amendment No. 26.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T14:50:16-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 20 minutes on the Crenshaw en bloc amendments No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T14:54:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett amendment No. 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:01:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett amendment No. 28, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:03:08-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Garrett amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:12:46-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Garrett amendment No. 29, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:13:37-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:23:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 31.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:30:44-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gosar amendment No. 31, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:32:32-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Guinta amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:41:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Guinta amendment No. 32, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:42:45-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hudson amendment No. 33.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T15:54:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 34.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:05:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 34, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:06:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 35.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:17:11-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Huizenga amendment No. 35, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:17:57-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Lance amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:26:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the King (IA) amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:38:12-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the King (IA) amendment No. 38, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:38:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Luetkemeyer amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T16:48:11-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question of adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:42:24-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Rogers (KY) moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:42:40-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:42:49-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5485 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:57:23-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4523-4536" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:57:35-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T17:58:31-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Messer amendment No. 40.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:07:55-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Messer amendment No. 40, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:08:27-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Palmer amendment No. 41.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:17:39-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Palmer amendment No. 41, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:18:48-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:22:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Mullin amendment No. 43, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:22:54-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Posey amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:33:53-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Posey amendment No. 44, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:34:21-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roskam amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:44:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roskam amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:54:49-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Sanford amendment No. 47.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T18:59:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Carney amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:06:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Carney amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Carney demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:07:51-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Zeldin amendment No. 51.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:14:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Zeldin amendment No. 52.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:20:29-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Yarmuth amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:26:59-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Yarmuth amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the noes had prevailed. Mr. Yarmuth demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:27:53-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Jenkins (WV) amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:31:04-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gallego amendment No. 68.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:36:57-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Gallego amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Gallego demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:37:18-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 794, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Hartzler amendment No. 70.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:45:18-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Hartzler amendment, the Chair put the question on adoption of the amendment and by voice vote announced that the ayes had prevailed. Mr. Serrano demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings on the question of adoption of the amendment until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:45:41-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Crenshaw moved that the Committee now rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:45:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the Committee now rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T19:46:07-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 5485 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:01:26-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4536-4544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:01:40-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:02:49-04:00">
      <text>UNFINISHED BUSINESS - The Chair announced that the unfinished business was the question on adoption of amendments which had been debated earlier and on which further proceedings had been postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:51:36-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 5485.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:52:18-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4542" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:52:34-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gross as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:53:26-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Peters moved to recommit with instructions to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4542-4544" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4542" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T20:53:40-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Peters (CA) motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to report the same back to the House forthwith with an amendment to provide an additional $5,000,000 in funding for the Office of Terrorism and Financial Intelligence (TFI) in order to enhance the agencys capability to combat terrorism, drug lords, weapons of mass destruction and other national security threats.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T21:04:28-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4543" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T21:10:32-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 183 - 241 (Roll no. 397).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4544" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="398" datetime="2016-07-07T21:16:28-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 239 - 185 (Roll no. 398).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2016-07-07T21:16:30-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-07-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="557">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 557.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity=""/>
    <committee code="SSAP23" name="Senate Appropriations" subcommittee="Financial Services and General Government" activity="Hearings"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="3067" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="2947" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="3784" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="4901" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="1840" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="1841" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="2867" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="hr" number="794" relation="procedurally-related"/>
    <bill session="114" type="s" number="3196" relation="unknown"/>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="6427" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative Conference of the U.S."/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Banking and financial institutions regulation"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Business investment and capital"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Election Assistance Commission"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission (FCC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation (FDIC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Election Commission (FEC)"/>
    <term name="Federal Labor Relations Authority"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Federal appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Federal district courts"/>
    <term name="General Services Administration"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Judicial procedure and administration"/>
    <term name="Merit Systems Protection Board"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="National Credit Union Administration"/>
    <term name="Office of Government Ethics"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management (OPM)"/>
    <term name="Office of Special Counsel"/>
    <term name="Postal Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board"/>
    <term name="Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC)"/>
    <term name="Selective Service System"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Specialized courts"/>
    <term name="State and local finance"/>
    <term name="Student aid and college costs"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Tax administration and collection, taxpayers"/>
    <term name="U.S. Postal Service"/>
    <term name="U.S. Sentencing Commission"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h1271"/>
    <amendment number="h1270"/>
    <amendment number="h1269"/>
    <amendment number="h1268"/>
    <amendment number="h1267"/>
    <amendment number="h1266"/>
    <amendment number="h1265"/>
    <amendment number="h1264"/>
    <amendment number="h1263"/>
    <amendment number="h1262"/>
    <amendment number="h1261"/>
    <amendment number="h1260"/>
    <amendment number="h1259"/>
    <amendment number="h1258"/>
    <amendment number="h1257"/>
    <amendment number="h1256"/>
    <amendment number="h1255"/>
    <amendment number="h1254"/>
    <amendment number="h1253"/>
    <amendment number="h1252"/>
    <amendment number="h1251"/>
    <amendment number="h1250"/>
    <amendment number="h1249"/>
    <amendment number="h1248"/>
    <amendment number="h1247"/>
    <amendment number="h1246"/>
    <amendment number="h1245"/>
    <amendment number="h1244"/>
    <amendment number="h1243"/>
    <amendment number="h1242"/>
    <amendment number="h1241"/>
    <amendment number="h1240"/>
    <amendment number="h1239"/>
    <amendment number="h1238"/>
    <amendment number="h1237"/>
    <amendment number="h1236"/>
    <amendment number="h1235"/>
    <amendment number="h1234"/>
    <amendment number="h1233"/>
    <amendment number="h1232"/>
    <amendment number="h1231"/>
    <amendment number="h1230"/>
    <amendment number="h1229"/>
    <amendment number="h1228"/>
    <amendment number="h1227"/>
    <amendment number="h1226"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2021-07-08T18:30:24Z" status="Introduced in House">Financial Services and General Government Appropriations Act, 2017 

Provides FY2017 appropriations to the Department of the Treasury, the Executive Office of the President, the judiciary, the District of Columbia, and several independent agencies.

Department of the Treasury Appropriations Act, 2017 

Provides appropriations to the Department of the Treasury, including the Internal Revenue Service.

Executive Office of the President Appropriations Act, 2017 

Provides appropriations to the Executive Office of the President and Funds Appropriated to the President.

Judiciary Appropriations Act, 2017 

Provides appropriations to the judiciary, including the U.S. Supreme Court, other federal courts, administrative offices, and the U.S. Sentencing Commission.

District of Columbia Appropriations Act, 2017 

Provides appropriations to the District of Columbia, including Federal Funds and District of Columbia Funds.

Provides appropriations to independent agencies, including:

 the Administrative Conference of the United States, the Consumer Product Safety Commission, the Election Assistance Commission, the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Election Commission, the Federal Labor Relations Authority, the Federal Trade Commission, the General Services Administration, the Merit Systems Protection Board, the National Archives and Records Administration, the National Credit Union Administration, the Office of Government Ethics, the Office of Personnel Management, the Office of Special Counsel, the Postal Regulatory Commission, the Privacy and Civil Liberties Oversight Board, the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Selective Service System, the Small Business Administration, the U.S. Postal Service, and the U.S. Tax Court. Sets forth permissible and prohibited uses for funds provided by this and other appropriations Acts.

Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Reauthorization Act or the SOAR Reauthorization Act 

Reauthorizes and amends the Scholarships for Opportunity and Results Act, which authorizes education funding for the District of Columbia, including the Opportunity Scholarship Program, public schools, and public charter schools.

SEC Small Business Advocate Act of 2016 

Establishes the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation and the Small Business Capital Formation Advisory Committee within the Securities and Exchange Commission.

Financial Institution Bankruptcy Act of 2016 

Amends the Bankruptcy Code to establish a new bankruptcy process for certain financial institutions.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 114-624</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
