<bill session="109" type="h" number="5144" updated="2023-01-13T04:48:44Z">
  <state datetime="2006-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To provide for supply chain security cooperation between Department of Homeland Security and the private sector, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To provide for supply chain security cooperation between Department of Homeland Security and the private sector, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="J000287"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-04-17">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Intelligence, Information Sharing, and Terrorism Risk Assessment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHM" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSHM05" name="House Homeland Security" subcommittee="Counterterrorism, Law Enforcement, and Intelligence" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Confidential communications"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Electronic data interchange"/>
    <term name="Electronic government information"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Private police"/>
    <term name="Public-private partnerships"/>
    <term name="Risk"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade secrets"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-05-31T19:54:36Z" status="Introduced in House">Directs the Secretary of Homeland Security to: (1) develop a secure electronic data interchange system to collect from and share risk information related to securing the supply chain with appropriate private sector entities; (2) establish uniform procedures for the receipt, care, and storage of supply chain security information that is voluntarily submitted to the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) through the system; and (3) develop protocols for determining appropriate private sector personnel who shall have access to the system, including designated security officers within companies determined to be low risk through participation in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection's Customs-Trade Partnership Against Terrorism program.

 Restricts the use and disclosure of such voluntarily submitted information and sets penalties for unauthorized disclosure by federal officers or employees.

Authorizes the Secretary to provide warnings to relevant companies, targeted sectors, other governmental entities, or the general public regarding potential risks to the supply chain.</summary>
</bill>
