<bill session="119" type="h" number="675" updated="2025-10-09T03:26:11Z">
  <state datetime="2025-01-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-01-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Domestic SUPPLY Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Security Using Production Partnerships and Lessons from Yesterday Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic SUPPLY Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in collaboration with the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response and the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and in coordination with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, to establish a program of entering into partnerships with eligible domestic manufacturers to ensure the availability of qualified personal protective equipment to prepare for and respond to national health or other emergencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="G000568"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-01-23">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Government Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Buy American requirements"/>
    <term name="Cardiovascular and respiratory health"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services and trauma care"/>
    <term name="Health personnel"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Health technology, devices, supplies"/>
    <term name="Infectious and parasitic diseases"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public-private cooperation"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Worker safety and health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-04-02T19:30:59Z" status="Introduced in House">Domestic Security Using Production Partnerships and Lessons from Yesterday Act of 2025 or the Domestic SUPPLY Act of 2025

This bill establishes a program and sets out other requirements to promote domestic manufacturing of personal protective equipment (PPE) to address&#160;infectious diseases and other public health emergencies.

Specifically, the Department of Health and Human Services (HHS) must establish a program to enter into purchasing agreements with eligible domestic manufacturers for PPE&#160;to prepare for and respond to public health emergencies. To be eligible, manufacturers must be majority owned and operated&#160;by U.S. citizens and must manufacture a majority of their contracted products domestically, with 100% of products manufactured domestically by 2028. HHS must coordinate with the Department of Defense and the Department of Homeland Security on this program.

In addition, the federal government must only procure, subject to limited exceptions, clothing or equipment that is produced domestically to prevent the transmission of an infectious disease. If using federal funds, states or localities must also procure such items&#160;domestically.

Further, the bill requires HHS to submit to Congress a report about changes to federal requirements for PPE since&#160;the beginning of the&#160;COVID-19 pandemic and the impact of those changes on health care workers who cared for patients in 2020 and 2021.</summary>
</bill>
