<amendment session="108" chamber="h" number="770" updated="2021-09-30T00:11:07Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5025" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2004-09-22T11:18:48-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="W000187"/>
  <offered datetime="2004-09-22"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill (before the short title), insert the following: \   SEC. __. None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to implement any sanction imposed by the United States on private commercial sales of agricultural commodities (as defined in section 402 of the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954) or medicine or medical supplies (within the meaning of section 1705(c) of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992) to Cuba (other than a sanction imposed pursuant to agreement with one or more other countries).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment numbered 12 printed in the Congressional Record to insert the follwing new section at the end of the bill before the short title: None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to implement any sanction imposed by the United States on private commercial sales of agricultural commodities (as defined in section 402 of the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954) or medicine or medical supplies (within the meaning of section 1705(c) of the Cuban Democracy Act of 1992) to Cuba (other than a sanction imposed pursuant to agreement with one or more other countries).</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2004-09-22T11:18:48-04:00" how="by voice vote" result="pass">
      <text>On agreeing to the Waters amendment (A020) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T10:45:00-04:00">
      <text>Amendment (A020) offered by Ms. Waters.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7336-7337, H7340" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7336" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T10:45:00-04:00">
      <text>House amendment offered/reported by : Amendment (A020) offered by Ms. Waters.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H7336-7337, H7340" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H7336" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T11:18:48-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22T11:18:48-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Waters amendment (A020) Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-09-22">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
