<bill session="108" type="s" number="463" updated="2023-01-15T22:18:42Z">
  <state datetime="2003-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to provide grants to ensure full and fair participation in certain decisionmaking processes of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants to ensure full and fair participation in certain decisionmaking processes of the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="D000388"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000304" joined="2003-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26">
      <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2863-2865"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="County politics and government"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Requires the Secretary of the Interior, if necessary to protect the interests of the Government or eligible entity and it would promote the interest of just administration in the Bureau of Indian affairs, to provide grants of up to $500,000 to eligible Indian groups or local governments to assist them in participating in the decision-making process relating to a pending action.Defines pending action as one in which: (1) an Indian group seeks Federal acknowledgment; (2) an Indian tribe seeks restoration to federally acknowledged status that has been terminated; (3) a federally acknowledged Indian tribe asserts trust status with respect to land within an area over which a local government exercises jurisdiction; (4) a federally acknowledged Indian tribe files a petition with the Secretary requesting that land within an area over which a local government exercises jurisdiction be taken into trust for the tribe's benefit; (5) an Indian group or federally acknowledged Indian tribe asserts a claim to land based on a treaty or a law specifically applicable to transfers of land or natural resources from, by, or on behalf of any Indian, Indian tribe, Indian group, or band of Indians; or (6) any other action or proposed action relating to an Indian group or federally acknowledged tribe determined likely to affect significantly the citizens represented by a local government.</summary>
</bill>
