<bill session="109" type="s" number="2179" updated="2023-01-13T04:49:15Z">
  <state datetime="2006-01-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2006-01-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-01-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">CLEAN UP Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require openness in conference committee deliberations and full disclosure of the contents of conference reports and all other legislation.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">CLEAN UP Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Curtailing Lobbyist Effectiveness Through Advance Notification, Updates, and Posting Act</title>
    <title type="popular">Reform Earmarks Process bill</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="O000167"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001233" joined="2006-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000468" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001041" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000596" joined="2006-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000563" joined="2006-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2006-01-30"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000148" joined="2006-01-31"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2006-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001163" joined="2006-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-01-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-01-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules and Administration.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional information resources"/>
    <term name="Congressional voting"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Internet"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Public meetings"/>
    <term name="Record votes"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-01-31T22:06:01Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Curtailing Lobbyist Effectiveness Through Advance Notification, Updates, and Posting Act or the CLEAN UP Act - Amends rule XXVII (Conference Committees, Reports, Open Meetings) of the Standing Rules of the Senate to require the joint explanatory statement by a conference committee to identify and explain separately each provision of the report in violation of the rule against inclusion of new or non-germane matter, and, if possible, identify the Member who proposed such provision.

Makes it out of order to consider a conference report unless the senior managers from the majority and minority parties on the part of the Senate include in the accompanying statement of managers a signed statement that: (1) all Senate managers have been afforded an opportunity at a meeting of the conference committee to vote on all amendments and other propositions considered; (2) roll call votes have been held in public meetings of the conferees on the matter contained in any motion to instruct conferees passed by the Senate; and (3) the minority was offered an opportunity to submit dissenting or minority views for the joint statement.

Declares that the reading in full of any bill, resolution, conference report, or amendment shall not be dispensed with unless such measure is available to all Members and made available to the general public by means of the Internet for at least 72 hours before its consideration.

Prohibits consideration of an appropriation bill unless a list of all earmarks in the bill and accompanying reports is available in the same manner.

Allows a waiver of such prohibitions by a two-thirds majority vote of Members.</summary>
</bill>
