<bill session="108" type="h" number="4123" updated="2023-01-15T04:48:38Z">
  <state datetime="2004-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2004-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Military Sexual Assault Crimes Revision Act of 2004</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend chapter 47 of title 10, United States Code (the Uniform Code of Military Justice), to bring military sexual assault crimes into parallel with Federal sexual assault crimes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Sexual Assault Crimes Revision Act of 2004</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="S000030"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000312" joined="2004-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2004-06-02">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Total Force.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSAS27" name="House Armed Services" subcommittee="Total Force" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="108" type="h" number="4709" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Child sexual abuse"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Military and naval offenses"/>
    <term name="Murder"/>
    <term name="Prison violence"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Rape"/>
    <term name="Sex crimes"/>
    <term name="Sodomy"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2004-05-07T20:37:21Z" status="Introduced in House">Military Sexual Assault Crimes Revision Act of 2004 - Amends the Uniform Code of Military Justice to rewrite current provisions concerning the military crime of rape and carnal knowledge to conform with Federal sexual assault crimes. Makes it a crime (aggravated sexual abuse) not only to use force to engage in a sexual act, but to obtain a sexual act by threatening or placing a person in fear that any person will otherwise be subjected to death, serious bodily injury, or kidnapping. Includes within the act of aggravated sexual abuse: (1) rendering another person unconscious, or administering a drug or intoxicant, prior to engaging in a sexual act; and (2) engaging in a sexual act with a person under 12 years of age.

Defines as the military crime of sexual abuse when a person: (1) causes another person to engage in a sexual act by threatening or placing that other person in fear; (2) engages in a sexual act with another person who is incapable of either appraising the nature of the conduct or declining such participation; or (3) engages in a sexual act with a person over 12 but under 16, or at least four years younger than the person.

States that, in the prosecution of either type of sexual abuse, it need not be proven that a person knew the age of the other person engaging in the sexual act, or the requisite age difference. Requires the accused to prove as an affirmative defense that the accused believed the other person to be at least 16 years of age.

Makes the above crimes punishable by court-martial.</summary>
</bill>
