<bill session="116" type="h" number="8403" updated="2023-01-11T13:44:53Z">
  <state datetime="2020-09-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-09-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Human Factors Improvements to the Aircraft Certification Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Human Factors Improvements to the Aircraft Certification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To require the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to better integrate human factors into the aircraft certification process through the deployment of necessary enhancements to improve aviation safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000560"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000577" joined="2020-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2020-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSPW05" name="House Transportation and Infrastructure" subcommittee="Aviation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="8408" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Licensing and registrations"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-05-18T18:47:09Z" status="Introduced in House">Human Factors Improvements to the Aircraft Certification Act 

This bill addresses the integration of human factors into the aircraft certification process.

The Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) must (1) evaluate tools and methods to support the integration of human factors into the aircraft certification process of flight deck and flight control systems for transport airplanes, and (2) develop a framework to implement such tools and methods with the objective of improving safety.

Additionally, the FAA must develop a human factors education program that addresses the effects of modern flight deck systems, including automated systems, on human performance for transport airplanes and the approaches for better integration of human factors in aircraft design and certification.

Each transport airplane manufacturer must (1) provide the FAA with information or findings on flight crew training to ensure it adequately includes consideration of human factors; and (2) identify any technical basis, justification, or rationale for such information and findings.</summary>
</bill>
