<bill session="119" type="h" number="2244" updated="2025-10-11T08:05:26Z">
  <state datetime="2025-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Michael Lecik Military Firefighters Protection Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Michael Lecik Military Firefighters Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish presumptions of service connection for diseases associated with firefighting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B001298"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001121" joined="2025-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000602" joined="2025-10-10"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="V000138" joined="2025-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-04-04">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSVR09" name="House Veterans' Affairs" subcommittee="Disability Assistance and Memorial Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-25T14:05:00Z" status="Introduced in House">Michael Lecik Military Firefighters Protection Act

This bill establishes a presumption of service-connection for specified diseases becoming manifest in certain military firefighter veterans to a degree of disability of 10% or more within 15 years of the veteran's separation from active military, naval, or air service. Under a presumption of service-connection, specific diseases or disabilities diagnosed in certain veterans are presumed to have been caused by the circumstances of their military service. Health care benefits and disability compensation may then be awarded.

Veterans addressed by this bill are those who (1) are trained in fire suppression, and (2) served on active duty in a military occupational specialty or career field with a primary responsibility of firefighting or damage control for at least five years in the aggregate.</summary>
</bill>
