<bill session="118" type="h" number="4647" updated="2025-07-21T19:44:15Z">
  <state datetime="2023-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2023-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">High-skilled Immigration Reform for Employment Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High-skilled Immigration Reform for Employment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand availability of H-1B nonimmgrant visas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="K000391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000562" joined="2023-07-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2023-07-14">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Education and the Workforce, and in addition to the Committee on the Judiciary, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Workforce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2023-09-25T20:50:24Z" status="Introduced in House">High-skilled Immigration Reform for Employment Act

This bill increases the annual cap on H-1B visas (nonimmigrant visas for workers in specialty occupations) and authorizes grants for education.

Specifically, the bill (1) increases the cap on such visas for each fiscal year from 65,000 to 130,000; and (2) exempts from this cap all visas for individuals with a postgraduate degree from a U.S. institution of higher education (currently, only up to 20,000 such visas are exempted each fiscal year).

The bill also modifies the criteria for determining whether an employer is an H-1B-dependent employer. (Such employers are subject to additional requirements.)

The Department of Education may make grants to states to support science, technology, engineering, and mathematics (commonly referred to as STEM) education.</summary>
</bill>
