<bill session="119" type="h" number="1495" updated="2025-06-23T13:31:37Z">
  <state datetime="2025-02-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2025-02-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Digital Economy Cybersecurity Advisory Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Digital Economy Cybersecurity Advisory Act of 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act to establish a Digital Economy and Cybersecurity Board of Advisors, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000048"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2025-02-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-06-23T13:21:25Z" status="Introduced in House">Digital Economy Cybersecurity Advisory Act of 2025

This bill establishes a Digital Economy and Cybersecurity Board of Advisors within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA).&#160;

The board must provide the NTIA with recommendations for (1) technical cybersecurity best practices to drive economic growth while securing information and communications networks; (2) policies to support the development and implementation&#160;of cybersecurity practices with respect to the internet and information and communications networks; (3) policies that promote security and resilience to cybersecurity incidents; and (4) policies to remove barriers to trust, security, innovation, and commercialization; among other topics.&#160;

The board must be composed of between 5 and 25 members, each of whom must have appropriate cybersecurity expertise. The NTIA must ensure board members provide balanced representation among specified sectors and positions, including chief cybersecurity officers, individuals who operate or maintain communications networks, software and equipment vendors, and individuals who operate or maintain internet applications. Board members must serve without compensation.&#160;

The board must terminate four years after the bill&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s enactment.&#160;</summary>
</bill>
