<bill session="118" type="h" number="8752" updated="2025-05-27T14:14:30Z">
  <state datetime="2024-06-28T10:53:58-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-06-28T10:53:58-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="display">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2025</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2025, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="A000369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-06-14">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-14">
      <text>The House Committee on Appropriations reported an original measure, H. Rept. 118-553, by Mr. Amodei.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2024-06-14" calendar="Union" number="456">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 456.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2024-06-25T21:01:22-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1316 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771 and H.R. 8752. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771, and H.R. 8752, all under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:09:07-04:00">
      <text>Rule H. Res. 1316 passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:14:40-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1316.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4167-4208" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H4171-4182" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:14:45-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771 and H.R. 8752. The resolution provides for consideration of H.R. 8774, H.R. 8771, and H.R. 8752, all under a structured rule. The resolution provides for one hour of general debate and one motion to recommit for each bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:14:56-04:00">
      <text>House resolved itself into the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union pursuant to H. Res. 1316 and Rule XVIII.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:14:57-04:00">
      <text>The Speaker designated the Honorable Mariannette Miller-Meeks to act as Chairwoman of the Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:15:54-04:00">
      <text>GENERAL DEBATE - The Committee of the Whole proceeded with one hour of general debate on H.R. 8752.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:53:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1316, the Committee of Whole proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Amodei en bloc amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T11:57:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H.Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Armstrong amendment No. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:04:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:11:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 4, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:12:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Biggs amendment No. 5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:21:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Cammack amendment No. 9.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:34:00-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 11.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:44:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Clyde amendment No. 11, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:45:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Feenstra amendment No. 12.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T12:49:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Robert Garcia (CA) amendment No. 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:00:11-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 18.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:07:00-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 18, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:07:56-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Greene (GA) amendment No. 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:15:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:22:50-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Grothman amendment No. 20, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:23:30-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the McCormick amendment No. 29.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:31:03-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Molinaro amendment No. 30.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:35:05-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Moore (AL) amendment No. 32.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:39:52-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Mullin amendment No. 37.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:48:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 38.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:53:25-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Norman amendment No. 39.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T13:58:46-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 42.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:04:17-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 43.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:10:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 43, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:11:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 44.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:14:07-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 45.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:20:29-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 45, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced that the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:21:43-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Ogles amendment No. 46.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:26:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Gottheimer amendment No. 48.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:32:28-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 50.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:37:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 53.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:43:31-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Rosendale amendment No. 53, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:44:22-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 54.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:50:35-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Roy amendment No. 54, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:52:42-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Roy amendment No. 55.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T14:56:41-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Amodei amendment No. 56.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:01:19-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Steube amendment No. 57.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:04:38-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Steube amendment No. 57, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:05:20-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 58.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:10:58-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 58, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:11:38-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - Pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 1316, the Committee of the Whole proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 59.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:16:22-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - At the conclusion of debate on the Tiffany amendment No. 59, the Chair put the question on agreeing to the amendment and by voice vote, announced the ayes had prevailed. Ms. Underwood demanded a recorded vote, and the Chair postponed further proceedings until a time to be announced.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:16:42-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Amodei moved that the committee rise.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:16:55-04:00">
      <text>On motion that the committee rise Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:17:06-04:00">
      <text>Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union rises leaving H.R. 8752 as unfinished business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:31:25-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4208-4216" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T15:31:53-04:00">
      <text>The House resolved into Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union for further consideration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:18:23-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 6(h) of rule XVIII, the Committee rose.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:26:22-04:00">
      <text>Pursuant to clause 6(h) of rule XVIII, the Committee of the Whole resumed its sitting.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:42:46-04:00">
      <text>The House rose from the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union to report H.R. 8752.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-26T16:44:32-04:00">
      <text>POSTPONED PROCEEDINGS - Pursuant to clause 1(c) of rule XIX, the Chair announced further proceedings on H.R. 8752 would be postponed.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:40:58-04:00">
      <text>Considered as unfinished business.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4423-4424" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:41:28-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:41:37-04:00">
      <text>The House adopted the amendments en gros as agreed to by the Committee of the Whole House on the state of the Union.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:42:22-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Magaziner moved to recommit to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4423" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:42:31-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit was ordered pursuant to clause 2(b) of rule XIX.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:48:47-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit Failed by the Yeas and Nays: 201 - 213 (Roll no. 332).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="333" datetime="2024-06-28T10:53:58-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by the Yeas and Nays: 212 - 203 (Roll no. 333).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T10:54:00-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-06-28T11:06:40-04:00">
      <text>The Clerk was authorized to correct section numbers, punctuation, and cross references, and to make other necessary technical and conforming corrections in the engrossment of H.R. 8752.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" subcommittee="" activity="Unknown, Unknown, Reported Original Measure"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="hr" number="1316" relation="procedurally-related"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Abortion"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Asia"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Border security and unlawful immigration"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Chemical and biological weapons"/>
    <term name="Child safety and welfare"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Crimes against children"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation, prosecution, interrogation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Homeland Security"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief and insurance"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA)"/>
    <term name="First responders and emergency personnel"/>
    <term name="Floods and storm protection"/>
    <term name="Government buildings, facilities, and property"/>
    <term name="Government corporations and government-sponsored enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government employee pay, benefits, personnel management"/>
    <term name="Government information and archives"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Homeland security"/>
    <term name="Homelessness and emergency shelter"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Latin America"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Military medicine"/>
    <term name="Missing persons"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural disasters"/>
    <term name="North America"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas"/>
    <term name="Prescription drugs"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
    <term name="Public transit"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Racial and ethnic relations"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sex, gender, sexual orientation discrimination"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials and reserves"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="U.S. territories and protectorates"/>
    <term name="User charges and fees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' pensions and compensation"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Visas and passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h999"/>
    <amendment number="h998"/>
    <amendment number="h1028"/>
    <amendment number="h1027"/>
    <amendment number="h1026"/>
    <amendment number="h1025"/>
    <amendment number="h1024"/>
    <amendment number="h1023"/>
    <amendment number="h1022"/>
    <amendment number="h1021"/>
    <amendment number="h1020"/>
    <amendment number="h1019"/>
    <amendment number="h1018"/>
    <amendment number="h1017"/>
    <amendment number="h1016"/>
    <amendment number="h1015"/>
    <amendment number="h1014"/>
    <amendment number="h1013"/>
    <amendment number="h1012"/>
    <amendment number="h1011"/>
    <amendment number="h1010"/>
    <amendment number="h1009"/>
    <amendment number="h1008"/>
    <amendment number="h1007"/>
    <amendment number="h1006"/>
    <amendment number="h1005"/>
    <amendment number="h1004"/>
    <amendment number="h1003"/>
    <amendment number="h1002"/>
    <amendment number="h1001"/>
    <amendment number="h1000"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2024-07-17T10:43:28Z" status="Reported to House">Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2025

This bill provides FY2025 appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security (DHS).

Specifically, the bill provides appropriations to DHS for Departmental Management, Intelligence, Situational Awareness, and Oversight, including

the Office of the Secretary and Executive Management;the Management Directorate;Intelligence, Analysis, and Situational Awareness; andthe Office of Inspector General.In addition, the bill provides appropriations for Security, Enforcement, and Investigations, including

U.S. Customs and Border Protection,U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement,the Transportation Security Administration,the U.S. Coast Guard, andthe U.S. Secret Service.The bill provides appropriations for Protection, Preparedness, Response, and Recovery, including

the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, andthe Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA).The bill provides appropriations for Research, Development, Training, and Services, including

U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services,the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers,the Science and Technology Directorate, andthe Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office.The bill also sets forth requirements and restrictions for using funds provided by this and other appropriations acts.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 118-553</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
