<amendment session="112" chamber="h" number="1366" updated="2022-02-03T05:58:59Z">
  <amends type="h" number="5972" sequence=""/>
  <status datetime="2012-06-29T12:32:33-04:00">pass</status>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="L000575"/>
  <offered datetime="2012-06-27"/>
  <description>At the end of the bill before the short title, insert the following:    SEC. ___. None of the funds made available by this Act may be used for the salary of any officer or employee of the Federal Highway Administration to implement, administer, or enforce the Migratory Bird Treaty Act (16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.) or Executive Order No. 13186 of January 10, 2001, with respect to, or to determine any action of the Administration to have a significant impact under section 102(C) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (42 U.S.C. 4332(C)) based on the effect of such action on, the cliff swallow or barn swallow (as listed in section 10.13(c)(1) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations).</description>
  <purpose>An amendment to prohibit the use of funds to be used by the Secretary of Transportation to implement, administer, or enforce the Migratory Bird Treaty Act, Executive Order No. 13186.</purpose>
  <actions>
    <vote datetime="2012-06-29T12:32:33-04:00" how="roll" result="pass" roll="447">
      <text>On agreeing to the Lankford amendment (A051) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 191 (Roll no. 447).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4632-4633" label="consideration"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29T12:32:33-04:00">
      <text>Amendment agreed to Committee of the Whole</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29T12:32:33-04:00">
      <text>Roll call votes on amendments in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-29T12:32:33-04:00">
      <text>House amendment agreed to: On agreeing to the Lankford amendment (A051) Agreed to by recorded vote: 234 - 191 (Roll no. 447).</text>
      <reference ref="CR H4632-4633" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2012-06-27">
      <text>House amendment offered</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
</amendment>
