<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>
<billStatus>
  <version>3.0.0</version>
  <bill>
    <number>3888</number>
    <updateDate>2023-01-11T13:21:22Z</updateDate>
    <updateDateIncludingText>2023-01-11T13:21:22Z</updateDateIncludingText>
    <originChamber>Senate</originChamber>
    <originChamberCode>S</originChamberCode>
    <type>S</type>
    <introducedDate>2010-09-29</introducedDate>
    <congress>111</congress>
    <committees>
      <item>
        <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
        <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
        <chamber>Senate</chamber>
        <type>Standing</type>
        <activities>
          <item>
            <name>Referred to</name>
            <date>2010-09-29T21:18:43Z</date>
          </item>
        </activities>
      </item>
    </committees>
    <actions>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <committees>
          <item>
            <systemCode>ssbk00</systemCode>
            <name>Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs Committee</name>
          </item>
        </committees>
        <sourceSystem>
          <name>Senate</name>
        </sourceSystem>
        <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7802)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Sponsor introductory remarks on measure. (CR S7801-7802, S7802)</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>B00100</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
      <item>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
        <type>IntroReferral</type>
        <actionCode>10000</actionCode>
        <sourceSystem>
          <code>9</code>
          <name>Library of Congress</name>
        </sourceSystem>
      </item>
    </actions>
    <sponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>F000457</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. Franken, Al [D-MN]</fullName>
        <firstName>Al</firstName>
        <lastName>Franken</lastName>
        <party>D</party>
        <state>MN</state>
        <isByRequest>N</isByRequest>
      </item>
    </sponsors>
    <cosponsors>
      <item>
        <bioguideId>L000572</bioguideId>
        <fullName>Sen. LeMieux, George S. [R-FL]</fullName>
        <firstName>George</firstName>
        <lastName>LeMieux</lastName>
        <party>R</party>
        <state>FL</state>
        <middleName>S.</middleName>
        <sponsorshipDate>2010-09-29</sponsorshipDate>
        <isOriginalCosponsor>True</isOriginalCosponsor>
      </item>
    </cosponsors>
    <policyArea>
      <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
    </policyArea>
    <subjects>
      <legislativeSubjects>
        <item>
          <name>Civil actions and liability</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Consumer credit</name>
        </item>
        <item>
          <name>Inflation and prices</name>
        </item>
      </legislativeSubjects>
      <policyArea>
        <name>Finance and Financial Sector</name>
      </policyArea>
    </subjects>
    <summaries>
      <summary>
        <versionCode>00</versionCode>
        <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
        <actionDesc>Introduced in Senate</actionDesc>
        <updateDate>2010-12-29T16:55:03Z</updateDate>
        <text><![CDATA[ <p> End Debt Collector Abuse Act of 2010 - Amends the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act to require a debt collector, in the absence of such information in an initial communication or payment of the debt, to include in a written notice to the consumer the following: (1) the date of the last payment to the creditor on the debt and the debt amount at the time of default; (2) the name and address of the last person to extend credit with respect to the debt; (3) an itemization of the principal, fees, and interest that comprise the debt and any other charges added after the date of the last payment; (4) a description of the rights of the consumer concerning the ceasing of debt collector communication with the consumer and having collection efforts stopped; and (5) the name and contact information of the person responsible for handling complaints on behalf of the debt collector.</p> <p>Revises procedures concerning disputed debts to require a debt collector, upon receipt of a notification that a debt is disputed by the consumer, to undertake a thorough investigation of the substance of the dispute and timely provide specific responsive information and verification of the disputed debt.</p> <p>Requires the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to provide inflation adjustments to damages awarded in cases of noncompliance with fair debt collection practices under the Act.</p> <p>Allows a court, in a civil action alleging violations of fair debt collection practices, to award appropriate relief, including injunctive relief.</p> <p>Deems as an unfair practice a request by a debt collector to a court or law enforcement agency for the issuance of a warrant for the arrest of a debtor or any other similar request that a debt collector knows or should know would lead to the issuance of an arrest warrant, in relation to collection of a debt.</p>]]></text>
      </summary>
    </summaries>
    <title>End Debt Collector Abuse Act of 2010</title>
    <titles>
      <item>
        <titleType>Display Title</titleType>
        <title>End Debt Collector Abuse Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Official Title as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>A bill to make improvements to the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act, and for other purposes.</title>
        <billTextVersionName>Introduced in Senate</billTextVersionName>
        <billTextVersionCode>IS</billTextVersionCode>
      </item>
      <item>
        <titleType>Short Titles as Introduced</titleType>
        <title>End Debt Collector Abuse Act of 2010</title>
      </item>
    </titles>
    <textVersions>
      <item>
        <type>Introduced in Senate</type>
        <date>2010-09-29T04:00:00Z</date>
        <formats>
          <item>
            <url>https://www.govinfo.gov/content/pkg/BILLS-111s3888is/xml/BILLS-111s3888is.xml</url>
          </item>
        </formats>
      </item>
    </textVersions>
    <latestAction>
      <actionDate>2010-09-29</actionDate>
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs. (text of measure as introduced: CR S7802)</text>
    </latestAction>
  </bill>
  <dublinCore xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
    <dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
    <dc:language>EN</dc:language>
    <dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
    <dc:contributor>Congressional Research Service, Library of Congress</dc:contributor>
    <dc:description>This file contains bill summaries and statuses for federal legislation. A bill summary describes the most significant provisions of a piece of legislation and details the effects the legislative text may have on current law and federal programs. Bill summaries are authored by the Congressional Research Service (CRS) of the Library of Congress. As stated in Public Law 91-510 (2 USC 166 (d)(6)), one of the duties of CRS is "to prepare summaries and digests of bills and resolutions of a public general nature introduced in the Senate or House of Representatives". For more information, refer to the User Guide that accompanies this file.</dc:description>
  </dublinCore>
</billStatus>
