<bill session="109" type="h" number="1866" updated="2022-02-03T05:34:46Z">
  <state datetime="2005-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2005-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To facilitate shareholder consideration of making Settlement Common Stock under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act available to Alaska Natives born after December 18, 1971, descendants of Alaska Natives born after December 18, 1971, missed enrollees, and Native Elders, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To facilitate shareholder consideration of making Settlement Common Stock under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act available to Alaska Natives born after December 18, 1971, descendants of Alaska Natives born after December 18, 1971, missed enrollees, and Native Elders, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="Y000033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="s" number="449" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indigenous peoples"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Stockholders"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-05-03T22:21:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Amends the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act with respect to procedures for considering amendments to the articles of incorporation of a Native Corporation to authorize the issuance of additional shares of Settlement Common Stock to Alaska Natives born after December 18, 1971 (or their descendants), missed enrollees, and Native Elders. Applies the same voting standards to Corporation shareholder approval of such an amendment as apply to a resolution to establish a Settlement Trust. (Thus requires an affirmative vote of shares representing: (1) a majority of the shares present or represented by proxy at the meeting; or (2) an amount of shares greater than a majority present or represented by proxy at the meeting (but not greater than two-thirds of the Corporation's total voting power), if the Corporation establishes such a level by an amendment to its articles of incorporation.)</summary>
</bill>
