<bill session="117" type="s" number="574" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:49Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">PROTECT Asbestos Victims Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, to promote the investigation of fraudulent claims against certain trusts, to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide penalties against fraudulent claims against certain trusts, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PROTECT Asbestos Victims Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Providing Responsible Oversight of Trusts to Ensure Compensation and Transparency for Asbestos Victims Act of 2021</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2021-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000386" joined="2021-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes and toxic substances"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Product safety and quality"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-08-31T17:00:21Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Providing Responsible Oversight of Trusts to Ensure Compensation and Transparency for Asbestos Victims Act of 2021 or the PROTECT Asbestos Victims Act of 2021

This bill modifies several aspects of the asbestos bankruptcy trust system. An asbestos bankruptcy trust is established when a company subject to asbestos-related liability files for bankruptcy under chapter 11.

 The bill allows the U.S. Trustee Program within the Department of Justice to investigate the administration and operation of asbestos bankruptcy trusts. Additionally, it creates new criminal offenses for making a false representation to, or a false claim for payment by, an asbestos bankruptcy trust.

Finally, an administrator of an asbestos bankruptcy trusts must report any Medicare benefits entitled to a claimant to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</summary>
</bill>
