<bill session="117" type="h" number="5822" updated="2023-05-11T15:45:15Z">
  <state datetime="2021-11-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-11-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-11-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To extend Federal recognition to the Edisto Natchez-Kusso Tribe of South Carolina, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To extend Federal recognition to the Edisto Natchez-Kusso Tribe of South Carolina, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="M000194"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-08">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee for Indigenous Peoples of the United States.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII24" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Indian and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-04-12T18:27:29Z" status="Introduced in House">This bill extends federal recognition to the Edisto Natchez-Kusso Tribe of South Carolina.

Specifically, the bill makes the tribe and its members eligible for services and benefits provided to federally recognized tribes, without regard to the existence of a reservation for the tribe. The delivery area for services and benefits shall be determined in coordination and consultation with the Department of the Interior.

Next, the bill sets forth requirements for the tribe regarding its membership roll, governing documents, and governing body.

Upon request of the tribe, Interior (1) must take into trust certain land in Dorchester and Colleton counties in South Carolina for the benefit of the tribe, and (2) may take into trust land in specified counties for the benefit of the tribe. Land taken into trust shall be considered part of the tribe's reservation.

Further, the bill prohibits the tribe from conducting gaming activities.</summary>
</bill>
