<bill session="114" type="s" number="2361" updated="2023-01-11T13:31:47Z">
  <state datetime="2015-12-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2015-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2015-12-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Airport Security Enhancement and Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance airport security, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Security Enhancement and Oversight Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Airport Security Enhancement and Oversight Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000250"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000368" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000127" joined="2015-12-07"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000174" joined="2016-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000293" joined="2015-12-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000367" joined="2015-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000032" joined="2015-12-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2015-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2016-03-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation. Reported by Senator Thune with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 114-222.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2016-03-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="382">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 382.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="114" type="h" number="636" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Accounting and auditing"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aviation and airports"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information and records"/>
    <term name="Customs enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Employee performance"/>
    <term name="Espionage and treason"/>
    <term name="Foreign labor"/>
    <term name="Fraud offenses and financial crimes"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Immigration status and procedures"/>
    <term name="Intelligence activities, surveillance, classified information"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Transportation employees"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety and security"/>
    <term name="Violent crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2016-06-16T19:36:27Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Airport Security Enhancement and Oversight Act

This bill directs the Transportation Security Administration (TSA) of the Department of Homeland Security (DHS) to assess the level of risk posed to the domestic air transportation system by individuals with unescorted access to a secure area of an airport.

The TSA shall:

 update DHS rules on access controls, and issue guidance to airport operators for placing expiration dates on each airport credential issued to a non-U.S. citizen. The TSA shall also revise certain regulations to enhance the eligibility requirements and disqualifying criminal offenses for individuals seeking or having unescorted access to an airport's Secure Identification Display Area (SIDA).

Both the TSA and the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) shall implement fully the FBI's Rap Back service for recurrent criminal history vetting of eligible TSA-regulated populations of individuals with unescorted access to any airport SIDA.

 The TSA and the Office of the Director of National Intelligence shall ensure that the TSA may receive automated, real-time access to additional Terrorist Identities Datamart Environment (TIDE) data and any other terrorism related category codes to improve the TSA credential vetting program.

DHS shall authorize direct access for each airport operator to the E-Verify program and the Systematic Alien Verification for Entitlements (SAVE) automated system to determine the eligibility of individuals seeking unescorted access to an airport SIDA.

The TSA shall develop performance metrics to measure the effectiveness of security for airport SIDAs, as well as a model and best practices for unescorted access security meeting specified criteria.

The TSA shall also:

 expand the use of TSA officers and inspectors to conduct physical inspections of airport workers in each airport SIDA and at each SIDA access point, and review airports that have implemented additional airport worker screening or perimeter security. The TSA may conduct a pilot program to test and validate best practices for comprehensive airport worker screening or perimeter security.

The TSA shall:

 increase the use of red-team, covert testing of access controls to any secure airport areas; and review every current security directive addressed to any regulated entity.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 114-222</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
