<bill session="118" type="h" number="9597" updated="2025-11-19T04:52:46Z">
  <state datetime="2024-11-12T18:16:55-05:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2024-11-12T18:16:55-05:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2024-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Acquisition Security Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Federal Acquisition Security Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="short">Federal Acquisition Security Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="display">Federal Acquisition Security Council Improvement Act of 2024</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend title 41, United States Code, to make changes with respect to the Federal Acquisition Security Council, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001108"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000391" joined="2024-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001194" joined="2024-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000606" joined="2024-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2024-09-16">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Oversight and Accountability.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-09-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute by the Yeas and Nays: 39 - 0.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12T18:09:43-05:00">
      <text>Mr. Higgins (LA) moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12T18:09:53-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5937-5940" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12T18:09:55-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on H.R. 9597.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote" datetime="2024-11-12T18:16:55-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill, as amended Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H5937-5939" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2024-11-12T18:16:58-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2024-11-13">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referred To"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Oversight and Government Reform" subcommittee="" activity="Markup By, Referred To"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="118" type="s" number="5310" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Computer security and identity theft"/>
    <term name="Computers and information technology"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive agency funding and structure"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Public contracts and procurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2025-08-27T19:58:14Z" status="Passed House">Federal Acquisition Security Council Improvement Act of 2024

This bill revises the structure and function of the Federal Acquisition Security Council (FASC), including by authorizing FASC to declare certain vendors associated with foreign adversaries ineligible to participate in federal procurement.

Specifically, Congress may designate for FASC review vendors (1) that are operating on behalf of, or are subject to the jurisdiction or control of, foreign adversaries; or (2) that pose a risk to national security based on their association with a foreign adversary&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s military or intelligence forces. The covered foreign adversaries are China, Iran, North Korea, and Russia.

FASC must review each designated vendor to determine whether to issue an order excluding the vendor from executive agencies&#226;&#8364;&#8482; procurement actions or requiring covered articles produced or provided by the vendor to be removed from agencies&#226;&#8364;&#8482; information systems. (Currently,&#160;covered articles include telecommunications equipment and services, information technology and information processing, and other systems or devices that include information technology.)&#160;Vendors subject to an exclusion or removal order may submit information in opposition for FASC&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s consideration before the order is finalized.&#160;

Separately, the bill broadens FASC&#226;&#8364;&#8482;s functions related to supply chain risk to include a focus on acquisition security and risks associated with the procurement and use of covered articles.&#160;

The bill also reallocates authorized funding for FASC from the Office of Management and Budget to the Office of the National Cyber Director (ONCD), and establishes a FASC program office within ONCD to provide subject matter expertise and administrative and legal support.</summary>
</bill>
