<bill session="111" type="h" number="4600" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:37Z">
  <state datetime="2010-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2010-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">To prohibit the use of funds to transfer or release an individual detained at Guantanamo Bay Naval Base to the custody of another country.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To prohibit the use of funds to transfer or release an individual detained at Guantanamo Bay Naval Base to the custody of another country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="R000435"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000589" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000377" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000676" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000210" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000274" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000508" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000587" joined="2010-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000583" joined="2010-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2010-02-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Correctional facilities and imprisonment"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Foreign aid and international relief"/>
    <term name="Military facilities and property"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2010-04-13T15:15:47Z" status="Introduced in House">Prohibits funds from being made available to any specified U.S. agency, instrumentality, or representative for the transfer or release any individual currently detained at Guantanamo Bay Naval Base to the custody of the individual's country of origin or a third country unless the President certifies to Congress that: (1) the government of the country controls all of its territory, does not allow its territory to be used as a safe haven by terrorists or insurgent groups, including Al Qaeda, and has effectively tracked the activities of all Guantanamo-detained individuals who are transferred into its custody; and (2) there is no confirmed case of any Guantanamo-detained individual who reengaged in any actual or planned act of terrorism against U.S. citizens or members of the U.S. Armed Forces.

Prohibits, with a national security waiver, funds made available to the Department of State from being used for assistance to the government of a country to which an individual currently detained at Guantanamo is to be transferred or released for use by such country's security forces unless the President makes such certification.</summary>
</bill>
