<bill session="116" type="s" number="847" updated="2022-11-01T18:02:35Z">
  <state datetime="2019-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Commercial Facial Recognition Privacy Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commercial Facial Recognition Privacy Act of 2019</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit certain entities from using facial recognition technology to identify or track an end user without obtaining the affirmative consent of the end user, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="B000575"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001194" joined="2019-03-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission (FTC)"/>
    <term name="Photography and imaging"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2020-08-11T18:15:49Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Commercial Facial Recognition Privacy Act of 2019 This bill prohibits entities from collecting, processing, storing, or controlling facial recognition data unless such entities (1) provide documentation that explains the capabilities and limitations of facial-recognition technology, and (2) obtain explicit affirmative consent from end users to use such technology after providing notice about the reasonably foreseeable uses of the collected facial-recognition data. Facial-recognition data includes attributes or features of the face that permit facial-recognition technology to uniquely and consistently identify a specific individual. Controllers of facial recognition data also are prohibited from (1) using such data to discriminate against end users, (2) using such data for a purpose that is not reasonably foreseeable to the end user, (3) sharing such data with a third party without the additional affirmative consent of the end user, or (4) conditioning the use of a product on an end user providing affirmative consent.</summary>
</bill>
