<bill session="117" type="h" number="77" updated="2023-01-11T13:43:22Z">
  <state datetime="2021-01-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-01-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">ADA Compliance for Customer Entry to Stores and Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 to promote compliance through education, to clarify the requirements for demand letters, to provide for a notice and cure period before the commencement of a private civil action, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ACCESS Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ADA Compliance for Customer Entry to Stores and Services Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C000059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000576" joined="2021-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000597" joined="2021-01-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000823" joined="2022-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-01-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-01">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Crime, Terrorism, and Homeland Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU08" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Crime and Federal Government Surveillance" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSJU03" name="House Judiciary" subcommittee="Courts, Intellectual Property, and the Internet" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Alternative dispute resolution, mediation, arbitration"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Disability and health-based discrimination"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Internet and video services"/>
    <term name="Internet, web applications, social media"/>
    <term name="State and local government operations"/>
    <term name="Telephone and wireless communication"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-25T18:30:38Z" status="Introduced in House">ADA Compliance for Customer Entry to Stores and Services Act or the ACCESS Act

This bill addresses access to public accommodations for persons with a disability.

The bill requires the Department of Justice (DOJ) to develop a program to educate state and local governments and property owners on strategies for promoting access to public accommodations for persons with a disability.

The bill authorizes an aggrieved person, after taking specified actions, to commence a civil action based on the failure to remove an architectural barrier to access an existing public accommodation. Specifically, the aggrieved person must have provided the owners or operators a written notice specific enough to identify the barrier and specify the circumstances under which public accommodation access was denied. The owners or operators must have (1) failed to provide the person a written description outlining improvements that will be made to improve the barrier, or (2) failed to remove the barrier or make substantial progress after providing such a description.

The Judicial Conference of the United States must develop a model program to promote alternative dispute resolution mechanisms to resolve claims involving architectural barriers to access for public accommodations.

Finally, the bill requires DOJ to complete a study of whether certain web content standards or information services for individuals with disabilities provided telephonically provide the same accommodations as would be available on a website.</summary>
</bill>
