<bill session="116" type="s" number="3987" updated="2023-01-11T13:46:13Z">
  <state datetime="2020-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2020-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2020-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide that COPS grant funds may be used for local law enforcement recruits to attend schools or academics if the recruits agree to serve in precincts of law enforcement agencies in their communities.</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to provide that COPS grant funds may be used for local law enforcement recruits to attend schools or academics if the recruits agree to serve in precincts of law enforcement agencies in their communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001056" joined="2020-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2020-06-17">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2020-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on the Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="116" type="h" number="7624" relation="identical"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement administration and funding"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-09-15T16:58:40Z" status="Introduced in Senate">This bill authorizes using certain grants to provide training to law enforcement recruits who agree to serve in their communities.

Specifically, the Department of Justice (DOJ) may provide such a grant for a local law enforcement agency to provide training for a recruit who agrees to serve as a full-time law enforcement officer (1) for at least four of the eight years after completing the training, and (2) at a local law enforcement agency within a certain distance of the place where the recruit has resided for at least five years.

The recruit must repay the costs of the training to the local law enforcement agency if the recruit does not meet these conditions. DOJ shall establish categories of extenuating circumstances that may excuse a recruit from repayment.</summary>
</bill>
