<bill session="108" type="h" number="1626" updated="2023-01-15T23:18:08Z">
  <state datetime="2003-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2003-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Local Voices on TV Act of 2003</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to ensure equity for all full-service television broadcasters and ensure the benefits of local programming for communities served by class A television broadcast stations by providing cable carriage rights for qualified class A television stations, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Local Voices on TV Act of 2003</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000258"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001044" joined="2003-05-15" withdrawn="2003-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000191" joined="2003-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000299" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000600" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000544" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000528" joined="2004-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000636" joined="2003-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="J000082" joined="2003-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000491" joined="2003-09-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000558" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000181" joined="2003-07-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="O000107" joined="2003-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000435" joined="2003-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S000522" joined="2003-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000267" joined="2003-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="W000672" joined="2003-09-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2003-04-10">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Telecommunications and the Internet.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF16" name="House Energy and Commerce" subcommittee="Communications and Technology" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Crime and Law Enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal Communications Commission"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Police communication systems"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Telecommunication rates"/>
    <term name="Television frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="Television stations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-11-28T17:35:40Z" status="Introduced in House">Local Voices on TV Act of 2003 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit a cable television operator (operator) from carrying the signal of a qualified class A television station (a station that provides local and specialized service and meets certain other requirements) in lieu of a full power analog or digital local commercial station. Requires that, if there are not sufficient signals of full power local commercial stations to fill the channels set aside for local programming, an operator with a system capacity of 35 or fewer channels must carry one qualified low power station (current law) or one qualified class A station. Requires: (1) an operator with a system capacity of more than 35 but less than 72 channels to carry two stations that are either class A or low power stations; and (2) an operator with a system capacity of more than 72 channels to carry three that are either type of stations. Grants carriage rights to all qualified class A stations in a designated market area if there are three or fewer commercial full power stations serving that area that do not substantially retransmit the signal of another broadcast station.Requires the Federal Communications Commission (FCC) to prescribe regulations to implement provisions for the application and granting of new class A television licenses in accordance with the Community Broadcasters Protection Act of 1999. Directs the FCC to consider whether the treatment of a low-power station as a class A station would meet the public interest, convenience, and necessity.Requires prompt FCC review and determination with respect to applications of advanced television services.</summary>
</bill>
