<bill session="109" type="h" number="5802" updated="2023-01-12T17:52:21Z">
  <state datetime="2006-07-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2006-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2006-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">NPS Concessions Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To amend the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998, to extend to additional small businesses the preferential right to renew a concessions contract entered into under such Act, to facilitate the renewal of a commercial use authorization granted under such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">NPS Concessions Reform Act of 2006</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NPS Concessions Reform Act of 2006</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000588"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-07-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported in the Nature of a Substitute (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2006-09-06">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Resources. H. Rept. 109-640.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2006-09-06" calendar="Union" number="380">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 380.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and Financial Sector"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Surety and fidelity"/>
    <term name="Tourism"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2006-12-04T20:38:00Z" status="Reported to House with amendment(s)">NPS Concessions Reform Act of 2006 - Amends the National Park Service Concessions Management Improvement Act of 1998 to increase the anticipated annual gross receipts eligible for a concessioner's preferential right of renewal.

Requires the Secretary of the Interior to provide to any entity that submitted a proposal and who was not awarded a proposed concessions contract a debriefing as to why it was not selected as submitting the best proposal for that concessions contract. States that, such debriefing must be requested and must be made within 90 days of the award of the concessions contract. Bars the Secretary from being required to disclose any proprietary information of the entity that was selected as submitting the best proposal and awarded such contract.

 Permits a leasehold surrender interest in a capital improvement upon U.S.-owned land within a unit of the National Park Service (NPS) under a concession contract to be pledged as security for NPS contracts using a combination of leasehold surrender interest if holding one or more contracts with the NPS, and prohibits the proceeds resulting from such pledged security from being restricted for use in the park or parks for which the leasehold surrender interest was pledged.

Revises guidelines governing commercial use authorizations.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 109-640</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
