<bill session="111" type="h" number="3644" updated="2023-01-11T13:16:28Z">
  <state datetime="2010-03-19T13:48:53-04:00">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2010-03-19T13:48:53-04:00"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2009-09-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Ocean, Coastal, and Watershed Education Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">To direct the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to establish education and watershed programs which advance environmental literacy, including preparedness and adaptability for the likely impacts of climate change in coastal watershed regions.</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ocean, Coastal, and Watershed Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ocean, Coastal, and Watershed Education Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bay-Watershed Education and Training (B-WET) Regional Program and National Environmental Literacy Grant Program Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001036"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="A000014" joined="2009-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B000574" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001245" joined="2009-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C000380" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001078" joined="2009-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="E000092" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000010" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000030" joined="2009-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="F000116" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="G000551" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000627" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001042" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001032" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="I000026" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000180" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000551" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="L000563" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001166" joined="2009-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001150" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000933" joined="2009-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="N000179" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000034" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000596" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000597" joined="2009-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000598" joined="2009-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="R000581" joined="2009-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001177" joined="2009-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001168" joined="2009-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="S001170" joined="2009-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="T000460" joined="2009-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24">
      <text>Introduced in House</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the House Committee on Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-09-28">
      <text>Referred to the Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-10-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Insular Affairs, Oceans and Wildlife Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2009-11-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended) by the Yeas and Nays: 22 - 13.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-01-12">
      <text>Reported (Amended) by the Committee on Natural Resources. H. Rept. 111-392.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2010-01-12" calendar="Union" number="229">
      <text>Placed on the Union Calendar, Calendar No. 229.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="2010-03-18T17:03:43-04:00">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H. Res. 1192 Reported to House. Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3644 and H.R. 1612. It shall be in order to consider in the House, H.R. 3644 and H.R. 1612. All points of order against consideration of each bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in each bill shall be considered as adopted. The bills, as amended, shall be considered read. Further amendments are in order. Each bill shall be debatable for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T10:59:30-04:00">
      <text>Considered under the provisions of rule H. Res. 1192.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1669-1674, H1675-1676, H1676-1686" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1669-1671" label="text of amendment in the nature of a substitute"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T10:59:31-04:00">
      <text>Rule provides for consideration of H.R. 3644 and H.R. 1612. It shall be in order to consider in the House, H.R. 3644 and H.R. 1612. All points of order against consideration of each bill are waived except those arising under clause 9 or 10 of rule XXI. The amendment in the nature of a substitute recommended by the Committee on Natural Resources now printed in each bill shall be considered as adopted. The bills, as amended, shall be considered read. Further amendments are in order. Each bill shall be debatable for one hour.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T11:00:59-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with one hour of debate on H.R. 3644.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T12:00:44-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 20 minutes of debate on the Capps amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T12:21:26-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Flake amendment to the Capps amendment in the nature of a substitute.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:10:54-04:00">
      <text>The previous question was ordered pursuant to the rule.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1684" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:11:35-04:00">
      <text>Mr. Chaffetz moved to recommit with instructions to Natural Resources.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1684-1686" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR H1684" label="text"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:12:36-04:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with 10 minutes of debate on the Chaffetz motion to recommit with instructions. The instructions contained in the motion seek to require the bill to be reported back to the House with sundry amendments which include adding a new paragraph to examine the impacts of natural gas and oil seeps on ocean, beaches, air quality, and the coastal environment and the possibility of mitigation of those impacts through resource and energy development. Also the motion adds a new section pertaining to limitation on use of funds.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:21:36-04:00">
      <text>The previous question on the motion to recommit with instructions was ordered without objection.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H1685" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:39:50-04:00">
      <text>On motion to recommit with instructions Failed by recorded vote: 200 - 215 (Roll no. 141).</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="142" datetime="2010-03-19T13:48:53-04:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>On passage Passed by recorded vote: 244 - 170 (Roll no. 142).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2010-03-19T13:48:54-04:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2010-03-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSII22" name="House Natural Resources" subcommittee="Fisheries, Wildlife, Oceans, and Insular Affairs" activity="Discharged, Hearings, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="111" type="hr" number="1192" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency (EPA)"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment, monitoring, research"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Marine and coastal resources, fisheries"/>
    <term name="Outdoor recreation"/>
    <term name="Performance measurement"/>
    <term name="Teaching, teachers, curricula"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation and habitat protection"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h589"/>
    <amendment number="h588"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary date="2010-05-28T18:01:50Z" status="Passed House amended">Ocean, Coastal, and Watershed Education Act - (Sec. 4) Directs the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to establish the Environmental Literacy Grant Program, a competitive grant program that provides financial assistance to: (1) expand the adoption of coastal, ocean, Great Lakes, and climate on all time scales education; (2) build administrative and technical capacity with coastal, ocean, and watershed communities and stakeholder groups to enhance their effectiveness; (3) encourage water- and wildlife-dependent and other outdoor recreation, experiential learning, and hands-on involvement with coastal and watershed resources as a method of promoting stewardship and sustainable economic development of those resources; and (4) develop and implement new approaches to advance coastal, ocean, Great Lakes, and climate on all time scales and education and environmental literacy.

Requires the Administrator to: (1) give priority, in awarding environmental literacy grants, to innovative, strategic, high-leverage projects that demonstrate strong potential for being sustained; and (2) publish guidelines regarding implementation of the Environmental Literacy Grant Program.

(Sec. 5) Directs the Administrator to conduct the Bay-Watershed Education and Training (B-WET) Program, including each of the regional programs conducted or under active consideration for creation under the B-WET Program. Authorizes the Administrator to create new regional programs under the B-WET Program. Requires the Administrator to issue and report to Congress on a strategy for establishing such new regional programs. Requires the Administrator, in creating new regional programs, to give priority to the needs of U.S. territories, the Great Lakes states, Alaska, and the mid-Atlantic region.

Authorizes the Administrator to modify or realign regional B-WET programs, based on specified factors. Makes the Administrator responsible for the selection, appointment, and replacement of regional program managers. Establishes managers' duties.

Requires the Administrator to create B-WET Program guidelines through which managers may: (1) enter into contracts to support projects to design, demonstrate, evaluate, or disseminate practices, methods, or techniques related to bay-watershed education and training; and (2) provide grants or a cooperative agreement to support projects that advance environmental literacy, develop public awareness and appreciation of the economic, social, recreational, and environmental benefits of coastal watersheds, and emphasize stewardship of critical coastal and marine resources.

Requires managers, in awarding grants under the B-WET Program, to give priority to projects that will: (1) promote bay-watershed education throughout the region concerned; (2) advance strategic initiatives to incorporate bay-watershed education into education systems; (3) build capacity within bay-watershed education communities and stakeholder groups for expanding and strengthening their work; (4) build bay-watershed education into professional development or training activities for educators; (5) broadly replicate existing, proven bay-watershed education programs; (6) be conducted by or benefit under-served communities and any community that has an inability to draw on other funding sources because of its small population or low income; and (7) require a federal share not exceeding 75% of the aggregate cost of such project.

Requires NOAA's Office of Education to work with managers on the following regional B-WET Program functions: (1) strategic planning efforts; (2) integration and coordination of programs; (3) coordination of national evaluation efforts; (4) promotion of network-wide communications; (5) selection of new managers; and (6) management, tracking, and oversight of the B-WET Program.

(Sec. 6) Requires the Administrator to report biennially to Congress on grant programs.

(Sec. 7) Authorizes appropriations for FY2011-FY2015 for the Environmental Literacy Grant Program and the B-WET Program. Prohibits such appropriated funds from being used for congressional earmarks.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>H. Rept. 111-392</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
