<bill session="117" type="s" number="1941" updated="2023-11-09T22:43:46Z">
  <state datetime="2022-12-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2022-12-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">MAPS Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Director of the Office of Management and Budget to standardize the use of core-based statistical area designations across Federal programs, to allow between 120 and 180 days for public comment on any proposed change to such designations, and to report on the scientific basis and estimated impact to Federal programs for any proposed change to such designations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="P000595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000934" joined="2021-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="P000449" joined="2021-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-11-03" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs. Reported by Senator Peters with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 117-98.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2022-04-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="349">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 349.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Unanimous Consent" type="vote" datetime="2022-05-26" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Unanimous Consent.</text>
      <reference ref="CR S2735-2736" label="consideration"/>
      <reference ref="CR S2735-2736" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-05-31">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-31T11:06:37-04:00">
      <text>Received in the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-05-31T11:11:23-04:00">
      <text>Held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14T17:29:45-05:00">
      <text>Mrs. Maloney, Carolyn B. moved to suspend the rules and pass the bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14T17:29:59-05:00">
      <text>Considered under suspension of the rules.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8483-8485" label="consideration"/>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14T17:30:02-05:00">
      <text>DEBATE - The House proceeded with forty minutes of debate on S. 1941.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by voice vote" type="vote2" datetime="2022-11-14T17:38:29-05:00" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>On motion to suspend the rules and pass the bill Agreed to by voice vote.</text>
      <reference ref="CR H8483-8484" label="text"/>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="2022-11-14T17:38:31-05:00">
      <text>Motion to reconsider laid on the table Agreed to without objection.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="2022-11-28">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="2022-12-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="117-219" type="public" datetime="2022-12-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 117-219.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Census and government statistics"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Public participation and lobbying"/>
    <term name="Regional and metropolitan planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2022-12-14T17:59:39Z" status="Public Law">Metropolitan Areas Protection and Standardization Act of 2021 or the MAPS Act of 2021

This act limits the automatic application of, and directs the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) to provide information about, changes to the standards for designating a core-based statistical area (CBSA). The standards are used to delineate metropolitan and micropolitan areas for statistical purposes.

Specifically, any change to the standards of CBSA delineations (1) shall not apply automatically for any nonstatistical use by any domestic assistance program, and (2) shall apply for such uses only if a relevant agency determines that the change supports the purposes of the program and is in the public interest and the change is adopted through rulemaking procedures.

The OMB must ensure that any change to the standards of CBSA delineations

 are accompanied by a public report that explains the scientific basis, criteria, and methodology for such change and the opinions of experts in statistics and demographics who were consulted regarding the change; are not influenced by any nonstatistical considerations; and are not applied automatically for any nonstatistical use by any domestic assistance program. Additionally, the OMB must collect information on the uses of CBSA delineations by domestic assistance programs for purposes including prime recipient and subrecipient eligibility for, and distribution of, any federal service, benefit, or funding.

The Government Accountability Office must submit a report assessing the information collected by the OMB pursuant to this act.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 117-98</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
