<bill session="109" type="s" number="1420" updated="2023-01-13T04:50:25Z">
  <state datetime="2005-07-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="2005-07-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2005-07-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Medical Device User Fee Stabilization Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to medical device user fees.</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Medical Device User Fee Stabilization Act of 2005</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medical Device User Fee Stabilization Act of 2005</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="E000285"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="B001135" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000294" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="D000388" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H000338" joined="2005-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="K000105" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M000702" joined="2005-07-18"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="M001111" joined="2005-07-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2005-07-18">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2005-07-25">
      <text>Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions. Reported by Senator Enzi with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 109-107. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="2005-07-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="173">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 173.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Reporting, Markup, Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="109" type="h" number="3423" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Biomedical engineering"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional reporting requirements"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and Public Finance"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government Operations and Politics"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Identification devices"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="Science, Technology, Communications"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2005-11-14T15:10:10Z" status="Reported to Senate with amendment(s)">Medical Device User Fee Stabilization Act of 2005 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to adjust medical device user fees.

Repeals the fee revenue target amounts for FY2006 and FY2007.

Eliminates the inflation, workload, compensating, and final year adjustments of revenues used for setting fees.

Sets the premarket application fee for devices for FY2006 and FY2007.

Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to use unobligated carryover balances from fees collected in previous fiscal years with notice to the appropriate congressional committees.

Increases the annual gross receipts or sales threshold below which businesses are eligible for reduced fees or a waiver of fees by the Secretary.

Removes the prohibition against the Secretary assessing fees unless certain cumulative fee revenues were met for FY2003 through 2006.

Requires the Secretary to include in its annual reports to Congress: (1) information on the number and total amount of fees paid for each different type of application or notification from small businesses; and (2) a certification by the Secretary that the amounts obligated for the performance of functions other than the review of device applications is not less than such amount for FY2002 multiplied by the adjustment factor.

Deems as misbranded any reprocessed single use device unless the device or an attachment identifies the manufacturer of the reprocessed device, or the identity of the manufacturer of the original device is provided by a detachable label intended to be affixed to the medical record of a patient.</summary>
  <committee-reports>
    <report>S. Rept. 109-107</report>
  </committee-reports>
</bill>
