<bill session="116" type="s" number="1281" updated="2022-03-02T16:21:34Z">
  <state datetime="2019-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2019-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Healthier Students for Stronger Campuses Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Healthier Students for Stronger Campuses Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide grants for institutions of higher education to prevent substance misuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="T000464"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="C001047" joined="2019-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor bioguide_id="H001076" joined="2019-05-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2019-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Drug, alcohol, tobacco use"/>
    <term name="Education programs funding"/>
    <term name="Government studies and investigations"/>
    <term name="Health promotion and preventive care"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-01-27T22:13:34Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Healthier Students for Stronger Campuses Act

This bill replaces a grant program for reducing and eliminating the illegal use of drugs and alcohol on college campuses with a grant program for preventing and addressing the effects of substance use on college campuses.

Specifically, it authorizes the Department of Education and the Department of Health and Human Services to award substance misuse prevention and treatment grants to institutions of higher education (IHEs) with regional high incidences of substance use disorders, overdoses, and deaths. It requires at least 25% of funds to be awarded to IHEs in rural areas.

The bill requires IHEs to use funds for evidence-based or promising interventions designed to address and prevent substance use disorders among enrolled students, such as recovery services, treatment or referral to treatment, and mental health counseling. IHEs receiving such grants must provide at least a 20% match of nonfederal funds.</summary>
</bill>
