<bill session="117" type="s" number="712" updated="2023-01-11T13:47:43Z">
  <state datetime="2021-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="2021-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="display">Dosha Joi Immediate Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act to provide for immediate eligibility for former foster youth under Medicaid.</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dosha Joi Immediate Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor bioguide_id="C001070"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11">
      <text>Introduced in Senate</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="2021-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" subcommittee="" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill session="117" type="h" number="1793" relation="unknown"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Adoption and foster care"/>
    <term name="Health care coverage and access"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary date="2021-07-20T20:52:41Z" status="Introduced in Senate">Dosha Joi Immediate Coverage for Former Foster Youth Act

This bill accelerates the application of certain changes that are scheduled to take effect under the Substance Use-Disorder Prevention that Promotes Opioid Recovery and Treatment (SUPPORT) for Patients and Communities Act relating to the coverage of former foster youth under Medicaid.

Under current law, a state Medicaid program must cover former foster youth until the age of 26 if the youth were in the state's foster care system at the age of 18 and were enrolled in the state's Medicaid program while in foster care; a state may choose to also cover former foster youth from other states. The SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act altered these provisions to require a state Medicaid program to cover former foster youth from other states until the age of 26; such changes apply to&#160;former foster youth&#160;who reach the age of 18 on or after January 1, 2023.

The bill instead applies these changes to&#160;former foster youth&#160;who reach the age of 18 on or after the date of enactment of this bill. States must also establish Medicaid outreach and enrollment programs for former foster youth.</summary>
</bill>
